<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1866/pa.fr.fr.1866.03.28">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>03/27</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1866-03-28">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>28</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.03.28.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Peril of the Republic</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"Hon. William D. Kelley delivered an address on the 'Dangers and Duties
                    of the Hour' recently in Concert Hall, Philadelphia, in which he exposes the
                    apostacy of the administration to Freedom and Loyalty in most conclusive and
                    pungent terms. We are complelled to omit portions of it, but what we can find
                    room for is more than sufficient to establish the premises assumed. The eloquent
                    speaker, after reviewing the aspect of political affairs, said:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A copy of Judge Kelly 's speech, which chronicles Andrew Johnson's previous
                    political affairs and criticizes his current performance as President.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.03.28.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A eulogy for George Chambers, who died at his residence in Chambersburg
                    last Sunday. Chambers, a native of Chambersburg and a direct descendent of the
                    town's founder, was a prominent local attorney and politician.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Andrew Johnson Unmasked</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>According to the editors, any pretense that President Johnson is not a
                    copperhead has vanished. In addition to his much-maligned speech of Feb. 22nd
                    and his veto of the Freedmen's Bill, Johnson has further outraged Republicans by
                    his decision to openly endorse the Democrats in Connecticut.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Valley Spirit</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Since President Johnson made clear his antipathy toward the Republican
                    cause, the Valley Spirit has promulgated a number of extreme policies, the
                    editorial claims. By demanding radical measures, such as ousting Congress, the
                    rival publication has highlighted its crass disregard for legitimate governance
                    and democracy. Even if the President wanted to implement the policies advocated
                    by the Democratic journal, it notes, he couldn't because, quite simply, he does
                    not have the power.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Civil Rights Bill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The bill to protect all persons in their civil rights and to furnish the
                        means for their vindication, has passed both houses of Congress and only
                        requires the signature of the President to become a law. As a good many
                        anticipate a veto of the act, its important provisions are herewith given:
                        The first section is as follows: All persons born in the United States and
                        not subject to any foreign power, excluding Indians, not taxed, are hereby
                        declared to be citizens of the United States; and such citizens of every
                        race and color without regard to any previous condition of slavery or
                        involuntary servitude, except as a punishment for crime, whereof the party
                        shall have been duly convicted, shall have the same right in every State and
                        territory of the United States, to make and enforce contracts, to sue
                        parties and give evidence, to inherit; purchase, lease or sell, hold and
                        convey real and personal property; and to full and equal benefit to all laws
                        and proceedings for the security of person and property as is enjoyed by
                        white citizens, and shall be subject to like punishment, pains and
                        penalties, and to none other, any law, statute, ordinance, regulation or
                        custom, to the contrary notwithstanding.</p>
                    <p>The second section is as follows: That any person who, under color of any
                        law, statute, ordinance, regulation or custom, shall subject or cause to be
                        subjected any inhabitant of any State or territory to the deprivation of any
                        right secured or protected by this act, or to different punishment, pains or
                        penalties, on account of such person having at any time been held in a
                        condition of slavery or involuntary servitude, except as a punishment for
                        crime, whereof the party shall have been duly convicted, or by reason of his
                        color or race than is prescribed for the punishment of such persons, shall
                        be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and on conviction shall be punished by a
                        fine not exceeding one thousand dollars, or imprisonment not exceeding one
                        year, or both in the discretion of the Court.</p>
                    <p>The third section gives the United States Courts exclusive jurisdiction of
                        the cases arising under this act, and also concurrently with the Circuit
                        Court of the United States, civil and criminal, affording persons who are
                        denied or cannot enforce in the Courts or judicial tribunals of the seat or
                        locality where they may be any of the rights secured to them by the first
                        section of this act, and of any suit or prosecution, civil or criminal had
                        been or shall be commenced in any State Court against any such person for
                        any cause whatever, by any officer, civil or military, or other person, for
                        any arrest or imprisonment, trespasses, or wrongs done or committed by
                        virtue of or under color of authority derived from this act or the act
                        establishing a bureau for the relief of freedmen and refugees, and acts
                        amendatory thereof; or for refusing to do any act upon the ground that it
                        would be inconsistent with this act, such defendant shall have the right to
                        remove such cause for trial to the proper District or Circuit Court in the
                        manner prescribed by the act relating to <emph rend="italic">habeas
                        corpus</emph> and regulating judicial proceedings in certain cases.</p>
                    <p>United States Marshals, District Attorneys and Agents of the Freedmen's
                        Bureau are empowered to prosecute cases under this bill. Severe penalties
                        are provided for all persons who may in any way hinder the operations of
                    it.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An outline of the provisions contained in the Civil Rights Bill, which is
                    expected to be vetoed by the President despite receiving strong support in both
                    houses of Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The brief piece notes that Quakers are being chased out of North Carolina
                    because of their pro-Unionist sympathies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.03.28.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--The Spring Elections</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fleck</ln>
                        <fn>John E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Goshorn</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piper</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stake</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sellers</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stark</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finley</ln>
                        <fn>Harris</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harvey</ln>
                        <fn>William T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gaston</ln>
                        <fn>A. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McEnaspy</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donnelly</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rinesmith</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>William J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burk</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>David J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGaughy</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gingrich</ln>
                        <fn>Moses</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hollar</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLaughlin</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cromer</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scott</ln>
                        <fn>James D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kunkelman</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haulman</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Benedict</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGaughy</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stitzell</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>James D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLaughlin</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Contains the returns from the election for the townships of Fannet and
                    Peters.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Recovery of the Remains of a Soldier</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rupley</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The remains of Sergt. Simon Rupley, a member of Co. K 126th Regt. Pa. Vols,
                    were interred in Greencastle last Saturday afternoon. Rupley was killed in the
                    Battle of Chancellorsville.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Bibulous</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>Henry S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rodes</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The new Burgess, Henry S. Stoner, and the recently elected members of the
                    Council, Messr. Hamilton and Rodes, were sworn in last Thursday evening by
                    Hamman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Enlarged</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Greencastle Pilot has enlarged and now presents itself to its readers
                    "in imperial dimensions."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Fire</head>
                <origin>Greencastle Pilot</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Householder</ln>
                        <fn>Harry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Harry Householder's house burned down last Friday night in Greencastle. No
                    one was injured in the blaze.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reber</ln>
                        <fn>Harry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hockersmith</ln>
                        <fn>Annie S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howe</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 13th, Harry Reber and Annie S.Hockersmith were married by Rev. W.
                    Howe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lott</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houghtlin</ln>
                        <fn>Joanna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>S. H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 22nd, Jacob Lott, of Adams county, and Joanna Houghtlin were
                    married by Rev. S. H. C. Smith.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickson</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 20th, William S. Keefer and Eliza A., daughter of John Huber, were
                    married by Rev. J. Dickson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ripple</ln>
                        <fn>James A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barkdoll</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Krebs</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 8th, James A. Ripple and Sallie A. Barkdoll, of Ringgold, Md.,
                    were married by Rev. W. E. Krebs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 25th, George Chambers, 80, died in Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rupley</ln>
                        <fn>Simon W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 3rd, 1861, Sergt. Simon, W. Rupley, 36, died. His remains were
                    interred in the German Reformed Burial Ground in Greencastle last Saturday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.03.28.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
