<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1866/pa.fr.fr.1866.05.16">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1866-05-16">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>16</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.05.16.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Southern Loyalty</head>
                <origin>New York Observer</origin>
                <commentary>"The New York Observer has ever been one of the most earnest and
                    thorough champions of what passes here for Conservatism. It has been
                    pro-Southern if not absolutely pro-slavery. Yet it speaks out in its act as
                    follows:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Despite the fact that it has led the campaign to re-admit the former rebel
                    states into the Union, even the New York Observer must now acknowledge that this
                    course of action is fraught with difficulties, particularly those imposed by
                    Southerners who do not appear prepared to accept their defeat. Most troubling of
                    all, relates the piece, is the fact that ministers are leading the movement
                    against reunion.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Johnson Against Johnson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>With excerpts from two of Johnson's earlier speeches to validate its claim,
                    the article highlights his reversal on reconstruction and land policies since
                    coming to office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.05.16.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>More Vetoes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It is no longer a matter of doubt that the President will veto two more bills
                        lately passed by Congress, for the reason that they do not serve the
                        interest of traitors and their sympathizers. The last Congress passed an
                        enabling act for the admission of Colorado as a State, and the people of
                        that territory proceeded to frame a constitution, ratify it by a vote of the
                        people, elect Governor and other State officers, and U. S. Senators and a
                        Representative. By some irregularity in the primary proceedings of the
                        people, President Johnson felt unwilling to admit Colorado by proclamation
                        as Congress had directed, and he referred the matter to Congress by a
                        special message asking a curative act so as to enable the State to be
                        admitted. He had not then perfected his compact with traitors and
                        copperheads, and he manifestly desired Colorado to become a State at an
                        early day. But since then he has assumed to control all the departments of
                        the government and to the success of his mad schemes of usurpation all else
                        must defer. He cannot corrupt and subordinate the popular branch of
                        Congress, for it derives its power directly from the people; but he must
                        control or subordinate the Senate so as to defeat the loyal hopes of the
                        nation, and Colorado confronts him in his despotism. She has been guilty of
                        electing a Union Governor, a Union legislature, two Union U. S. Senators who
                        can neither be intimidated or corrupted, and for this crime Andrew Johnson
                        has resolved that Colorado shall not be admitted. If not already vetoed, it
                        will be done within a very few days. Thus the measure he recommended to
                        Congress by special message but a few months ago, he will now defeat by the
                        exercise of the veto power, and solely because the Senators are loyal men
                        and not traitors.</p>
                    <p>It is a fact that will stand out with sad prominence in the history of this
                        government, that an Executive, chosen by loyal votes because of his most
                        earnest hostility to treason and traitors, has interposed the most despotic
                        power to destroy the just power of the loyal sentiment of the nation, while
                        he is exhausting his official patronage to the uttermost to bring into our
                        legislative halls the faithless men who made wanton war, and now come to
                        resume their fatal power crimsoned with the blood of our brethren. While
                        Andrew Johnson forbids the admission of Colorado, because it is a loyal
                        State, he insists upon the immediate admission of eleven disloyal States,
                        and would crown the bloody hands of treason with the highest honors, and
                        charge it with the destiny of the Republic just saved from dismemberment by
                        the most appaling sacrifices. If there is a deeper depths of perfidy, a
                        blacker shade of treason than that displayed by the Executive in his
                        deliberate and persistent efforts to surrender to rebel statesmen, the
                        government to which they have just surrendered the sword only when they were
                        powerless for further butchery, it has never been fathomed by one whose name
                        stains the history of the American people. It matters not by what pretexts
                        the President shall attempt to screen his faithless purpose. It will be well
                        understood. Every patriot will bow his head with consuming sorrow at the
                        consciousness that the fruits of wicked war are wasted by a wicked ruler,
                        while every traitor will shout his triumph over the blow aimed at the vitals
                        of the Republic he so cordially hates because it has vindicated its title to
                        Freedom.</p>
                    <p>Another bill in the hands of the Executive, which passed both branches by
                        nearly if not quite every Union vote, known as the Habeas Corpus act, will
                        be vetoed for the same reasons which dictate the defeat of the admission of
                        Colorado. It is distasteful to traitors, and hence it cannot be approved.
                        Rebels rule in all the State governments organized by Johnson's usurpation,
                        and Union officers of the army, and privates who enlisted in our army in the
                        rebel States and offered their lives to save the unity of the States, are
                        now at the mercy of the rebel governors, judiciary, sheriffs, juries and
                        intensely rebel laws. They are therefore indicted for every real or
                        imaginary destruction of property or injury to individuals while serving in
                        the army, and rebel vengeance gluts its fiendish fury upon them for their
                        triumphs under the flag of the Union. To protect such men--men who have been
                        faithful among the faithless, the act in question was passed, and as it is
                        designed to shield loyal citizens and not traitors, it is offensive to
                        Andrew Johnson, and he will veto it. In this he is but consistent, and
                        faithful to the infamy with which he has shadowed himself. Had Congress sent
                        him instead a bill to protect traitors from the just punishment their crimes
                        demand, it would have received his approval with alacrity; but to propose to
                        him any measure that protects a patriot from the cruel revenge of a traitor,
                        is to evoke the edict of the maddened despot forbidding it. It is well for
                        the Republic that it has been sorely tried before and the matchless fidelity
                        of the people established, or there would be few who love Freedom and
                        Justice who would not now yield to despair. But the same people who
                        maintained four years of gigantic war, with its wide-spread bereavements and
                        desolation will not turn from their broken circles or the untimely graves of
                        their holy sacrifices, to follow perfidious ambition in its effort to crown
                        treason with victory, and cloud the nation's living heroes and martyred dead
                        with dishonor. Since treachery must envelope the highest sanctuary of power,
                        we welcome it in its hideous nakedness, for it will arouse the People, <emph
                            rend="italic">and the People, as in times past,</emph> WILL SAVE THE
                        REPUBLIC!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Having "perfected his compact with traitors and copperheads," assert the
                    editors, Johnson will surely veto two more bills passed by Congress. The first
                    bill would admit Colorado into the Union as a state, a move the President
                    opposes because the new state would most likely come under the rule of
                    Republicans, thus granting the party an even larger majority in Congress. The
                    second bill is the Habeas Corpus Act, which was passed by Congress in an effort
                    to protect loyal men in the South who have been persecuted by local authorities
                    for their actions during the late war, including any "real or imaginary
                    destruction of property or injury to individuals."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Reconstruction Report</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The report of the joint Committee on Reconstruction, and the ratification of
                        the vital feature of the report by the decisive vote of the House on
                        Thursday last, present the great problem of restoration to the country in a
                        tangible form. The time is past now when the purpose of Congress can be
                        misrepresented by those who seek to serve the cause of traitors. After
                        patiently investigating the condition of the rebellious States--taking the
                        testimony of leading rebels and loyalists in those States, the committee
                        united every Republican on the amendments of the constitution and the bills
                        reported, and they declare to the nation and to the world, in substance if
                        not in form, the position of the Union party on the restoration of the rebel
                        States to fellowship.</p>
                    <p>There are many Union men who do not fully coincide with the entire report of
                        the committee. Some would liberalize the third amendment and thus leave
                        treason practically without a penalty; others would make the
                        disfranchisement cease only with the death of those who had waged war
                        against the government, and others would demand that the loyal men of the
                        South, without regard to color or condition, be clothed with the ballot as a
                        measure of justice alike to themselves and to the country. But while there
                        is great diversity of opinion as to the details of the proper policy of
                        reconstruction, we believe that the Union men will unite cordially and
                        earnestly in supporting any measure that may be accepted by the Union men of
                        Congress. What the loyal men of the nation most desire is to have some
                        definite policy, not wholly dictated by traitors, that can be made the fixed
                        and settled policy of the government. Considering that the President seems
                        to have no higher ambition than to clothe treason with honors and power, it
                        is well for the Union party to look to practical results and not sacrifice
                        all by refusing what can be attained. It is manifest that any penalty for
                        treason and any security against renewed discord and war, must be achieved
                        over the head and in defiance of the power and patronage of the President,
                        who reached his position by the suffrages of the millions of loyal people
                        whose convictions he now so fiercely antagonizes, and Congress must
                        therefore calculate well its position and make the future safe by securing
                        all that the present can give.</p>
                    <p>We have long since yielded confiscation and the punishment of criminality of
                        the leaders of the rebellion. They marked their desolated pathway of power
                        by the most vigorous confiscation, and punished unto death the avowal of
                        loyal sentiments in the dominions of treason, but with an Executive who is
                        clearly committed to save them harmless in person and property, it is
                        impracticable. The result is that loyal men must bear the crushing debt
                        created by treason, and the men who, in violation of all accepted rules of
                        war and every dictate of humanity, deliberately murdered thousands of Union
                        heroes in prison pens, are now, with the President, attempting to dictate to
                        the government that conquered them, the terms on which they will consent to
                        fill our legislative halls again. In this work the apostate Johnson and the
                        traitors who are flinging their insolence into the face of the nation under
                        the protection of the President, have the cordial sympathy and hearty
                        cooperation of the entire Democratic party, and its success will be the
                        success of treason and of the President in the pending struggle.</p>
                    <p>We trust that the Senate will take speedy action on the report of the
                        committee. Until Congress shall present to the country with its high
                        sanction, a practical solution of the great question, the power of treason
                        and its sympathizers will be potent to embarrass the government and divide
                        the people. But when both branches of Congress shall declare upon what terms
                        traitors shall be restored to the rights of property and citizenship, and
                        the appeal is made to the people to sustain that action, the contest will be
                        well nigh won. It cannot be doubted that every loyal State would promptly
                        call its legislature and ratify any amendment presented by Congress as
                        essential to the safety of the government, and with such an expression in
                        favor of Congress, treason would be glad to yield rather than have the
                        aroused resentment of the people whose forbearance has already been severely
                        tested. Let the country have the amendments speedily, and the Union men will
                        be fully prepared for the struggle. It will be desperate but decisive, and
                        it will be the last great struggle of traitors to subvert the government
                        they failed to destroy by causeless war.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors acknowledge that "there is a great diversity of opinion" among
                    Republicans as to "the detail of the proper policy of reconstruction," yet, they
                    maintain, "Union men will unite cordially and earnestly in supporting any
                    measure that may be accepted by the Union men of Congress." Reconstruction
                    policy represents a case in point; though there is much disagreement over the
                    best course of action to re-admit the former rebel states, Republicans agree
                    that "traitors" should not be allowed to dictate the terms of re-union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that a celebration took place in Richmond on May 10th to
                    mark the death of Stonewall Jackson and the anniversary of Jefferson Davis's
                    capture by Union troops. After local military companies paraded through the
                    city's streets, addresses were given by prominent former rebels, including
                    ex-Gov. Wise, "glorifying themselves for their rebellion against the
                    government."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>8</column>
                <head>The Memphis Riot</head>
                <origin>Nashville Press and Times</origin>
                <commentary>"The following letter is from a highly respectable citizen of Memphis.
                    Its truth is vouched for by high military authority:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following letter is from a highly respectable citizen of Memphis. Its
                        truth is vouched for by high military authority:</p>
                    <p>MEMPHIS, May 2, 1866.<lb/><emph rend="italic">Hon. W. G. Brownlow:</emph></p>
                    <p>DEAR SIR: Within the last twenty-four hours scenes have transpired in this
                        city which will send a thrill of horror throughout the Union. The diabolical
                        spirit which has been manifested by the rebel, negro-hating party is enough
                        to make one ashamed of his race. For a long time the Irish police have been
                        only too glad to get an opportunity to 'kill a nigger.' Anything was
                        sufficient to cause the arrest of one, and five dollars could procure his
                        release, according to report. The colored people have hated them, very
                        naturally, and some of the colored soldiers would fight them. Yesterday some
                        colored troops were paid off and got into a row with the police. One or two
                        were killed on both sides, and then the police were called for help, and
                        went into an indiscriminate slaughter of the blacks, <emph rend="italic"
                            >especially the soldiers, wherever found.</emph> From all that I can
                        learn, twenty-five or thirty blacks have been killed, nearly all of them
                            <emph rend="italic">without the least provocation.</emph> On several of
                        our streets last evening, if a black man appeared, quietly going home from
                        his day's labor, he was immediately followed and shot at, and in many
                        instances most brutally treated. The wicked ferocity of the mob stopped not
                        with the colored <emph rend="italic">men</emph>; several colored <emph
                            rend="italic">women</emph> were killed. Last evening, on South street,
                        some were shot, their houses broken open, trunks robbed, etc. A little girl
                        went to a store this morning, who left her mother dying from a stab received
                        from a white man last night. One colored woman was shot down on Union street
                        this morning for nothing. A white woman told me this morning that three
                        colored men were shot down near her gate for no provocation whatever. The
                        poor fellows had no arms. One of them said: "<emph rend="italic">Don't shoot
                            me, gentlemen! I have had nothing to do with any disturbance</emph>."
                        But the police cried out "Shoot him!" and at once three balls were fired
                        into him; and he fell there, and groaned before her gate until twelve
                        o'clock at night, when he died. This morning a man came out of his house and
                        shot down two negroes without the least occasion. The hellish spirit
                        manifested by many of the old rebels has been shocking in the last degree.
                        They are only too glad to get a chance to kill a nigger. They were out on
                        the street with revolvers in their hands, ready to kill at once. This I saw
                        myself. A report was started this morning that the freedmen's teachers
                        started the riot. An old traitor grumly asked me if it was true. Another
                        scoundrel, who ought long since to have had the halter, told me that if he
                        had his way, he would begin with the folks who had been preaching up these
                        things and putting arms into their hands. All this, you will perceive, is
                        significant. Loyal people here are not considered safe on the streets
                        to-day, but I have kept about and gathered other facts which I need not here
                        mention. The whole matter has been little else than a second Fort Pillow
                        massacre.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The letter provides an account of the recent riot in Memphis, which was
                    incited by the "rebel, negro-hating party." The orgy of destruction was a
                    product of the mounting tension between the city's Irish police officers, who
                    reportedly take any opportunity they get to 'kill a nigger,'" and the local
                    black population, particularly the black troops who vowed to put an end to the
                    continued persecution. During the course of the riot, police officers killed 25
                    or 30 blacks, "nearly all of them without the least provocation."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.05.16.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Southern Pennsylvania Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In addition to the surveying conducted last week in Franklin county, yet
                    another railroad line appears to be in the making. The proposed route will
                    connect to the Cumberland Valley Railroad, and will pass near the Franklin
                    Railroad Junction, popularly known as "Siberia," near Hollywell paper mill. The
                    editors express the hope that the line will be constructed because they assert
                    it would enable "Chambersburg to become one of the best manufacturing towns in
                    the State."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--A Sad Occurrence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dosch</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Frederick W. Dosch, a well-known resident of Stoufferstown,
                    committed suicide by hanging himself in his blacksmith shop last Friday evening.
                    Dosch had been suffering from depression in the months leading up to his tragic
                    end, brought upon by some financial dealings that had soured, leaving him out of
                    several hundred dollars.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Life Insurance</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Matthews</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that the Charter Life Insurance, based in Hartford, is among the
                    favored companies in Chambersburg because its system allows for dividends to be
                    paid in the first year of the policy, as opposed to numerous others that force
                    customers to wait up to four or five years before they can collect. The local
                    agent is A. Matthews.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--The Statue of Franklin and the Court House Bell</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Two new editions have been made to the appearance of downtown Chambersburg:
                    the statue of Franklin has been raised to its place on the cupola of the Court
                    House and the new bell has been hung.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Soldiers' Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The piece relates that local soldiers have called a meeting for the Tuesday
                    May 22nd, at the Court House, to select delegates to attend the Pittsburg
                    Military Convention to be held on June 5th. There is also talk among the
                    veterans of establishing a permanent organization of the brotherhood of Franklin
                    county soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Gone to Montana</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>Allison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>J. Porter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brand</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reid</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel D. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKnight</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>C. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The article reports on the departure of a contingent of Franklin county
                    residents who left this past week for the territory of Montana, in search of
                    their "El Dorado."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>James B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Messersmith</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruthrauff</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Emanuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>T. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davison</ln>
                        <fn>J. Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Downey</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gabby</ln>
                        <fn>William B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Immell</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                        <fn>D. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingerd</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davison</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>William G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bossert</ln>
                        <fn>Wiiliam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Farmers' and Mechanics' Industrial Association of Franklin county held
                    their annual convention last Tuesday where they selected the officers and
                    managers for the upcoming year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--I. O. G. T.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deitrich</ln>
                        <fn>J. L. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCulloh</ln>
                        <fn>Emma</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>J. Harper</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibson</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>W. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forbes</ln>
                        <fn>Mollie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oaks</ln>
                        <fn>Tillie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newman</ln>
                        <fn>D. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kirby</ln>
                        <fn>Kate M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Atherton</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>At the meeting of the McMurry Lodge, No. 119, I. O. G. T., on May 7th,
                    officers were selected for the upcoming year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Borough Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn>S. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fourthman</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crouse</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rider</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morganthall</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Formwalt</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhoyual</ln>
                        <fn>C. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The following individuals were selected at the most recent Borough election
                    in Waynesboro: S. R. Welsh, Chief Burgess; F. Fourthman, Jacob Crouse, and
                    Samuel Rider, George Morganthall, Daniel Formwalt, Councilmen; and C. C.
                    Rhodeyual, High Constable.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyer</ln>
                        <fn>Martin B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunkle</ln>
                        <fn>Melia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwix</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 8th, Martin B. Eyer and Melia Dunkle were married at the residence
                    of Daniel Gelwix by Rev. M. Snyder.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkholder</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLaughlin</ln>
                        <fn>Barbara A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Akers</ln>
                        <fn>J. Benson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 10th, William H. Burkholder and Barbara A. McLaughlin were married
                    by Rev. J. Benson Akers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deitrich</ln>
                        <fn>Mary B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hummelbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>H. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 8th, William F. Smith and Mary B. Deitrich were married by Rev. H.
                    Y. Hummelbaugh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dayhoff</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 4th, Samuel Dayhoff, 24, died.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lightner</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 11th, Henry Lightner, 72, died in Mercersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowan</ln>
                        <fn>George Grant</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowan</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On April 27th, George Grant, son of William and Rebecca Cowan, died in
                    Doddsville, Illinois. He was 5 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.05.16.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
