<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1866/pa.fr.fr.1866.07.18">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/24</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1866-07-18">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day>18</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.07.18.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Geary on Bounties</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article contains a letter from Gen. Geary to Henry Wilson, the chairman
                    of the Military Committee, in which the Union candidate for governor articulates
                    his position on granting bounties to returning soldiers. In his letter, Geary
                    calls for the government to provide "something more substantial than mere thanks
                    and gratitude" for the "sterling rank and file" soldiers who braved the "deadly
                    strife" and sustained the "glory and honor of the Republic." These men, he
                    contends, deserve to be rewarded for their efforts regardless of the impact on
                    the nation's economy, for if not for their sacrifices there would be no country.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.07.18.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that the Union men of Franklin county will hold a primary
                    election for local offices at their convention on August 4th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Jonah Swallows the Whale!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Using the parable of Jonah and the whale as an analogy, the editors predict
                    the imminent demise of the Democratic party and Andrew Johnson's political
                    career.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"Lieut. Gen. Grant don't [sic] seem to appreciate the loyalty of the
                    reconstructed brethren lately in rebellion. While Johnson, Seward, Cowan
                    &amp; Co., are daily announcing that the rebels are law abiding and loyal,
                    Gen. Grant tells the whole story in the following brief but pointed order just
                    issued, which virtually declares martial law in all the rebel States:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article contains a copy of General Order No. 44, the decree issued by
                    Gen. Grant which directs Department, District, and Post-Commanders in the South
                    to arrest anyone charged with a crime against officers, agents, citizens, and
                    inhabitants of the U. S., "irrespective of color," in those instances where the
                    local civil authorities have failed to act. Those arrested shall remain under
                    military confinement until an appropriate judicial tribunal can try them.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Letter From Gov. Curtin</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article contains a letter to Col. Jordan, chairman of the Union State
                    Committee, from Gov. Curtin, in which he articulates "his views on propriety of
                    calling for an extra session of the legislature to ratify the proposed
                    amendments to the constitution." Although Curtin supports the measure, he
                    expresses the belief that the ratification process should be put off until the
                    amendment's passage is guaranteed, which currently is not the case.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Loyalists in Council--A Call for a Convention of the Unionists of the
                    South<lb/> A Country's Destiny not to be left in the hands of those who, with
                    Might and Main, Sought to Destroy it.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">To the Loyal Unionists of the South!</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>The great issue is upon us. The majority in Congress, and its supporters,
                        firmly declare that "the rights of the citizens enumerated in the
                        Constitution, and established by the supreme law, must be maintained
                        inviolate."</p>
                    <p>Rebels and rebel sympathizers assert that "the rights of the citizens must be
                        left to the States alone, and under such regulations as the respective
                        States choose voluntarily to prescribe."</p>
                    <p>We have seen this doctrine of State sovereignty carried out in its practical
                        results until all authority in Congress was denied, the Union temporarily
                        destroyed, the constitutional rights of the citizens of the South nearly
                        annihilated, and the land desolated by civil war.</p>
                    <p>The time has come when the restricture of Southern State government must be
                        laid on constitutional principles or the despotism grown up under an
                        atrocious leadership be permitted to remain. We know of no other plan than
                        that Congress, under its constitutional powers, shall now exercise its
                        authority to establish the principles whereby protection is made
                        co-extensive with citizenship.</p>
                    <p>We maintain that no State, either by its organic law or legislation, can make
                        transgression on the rights of the citizen legitimate.</p>
                    <p>We demand, and ask you to concur in demanding, protection to every citizen of
                        this great Republic on the basis of equality before the law; and further,
                        that no State government would be recognized as legitimate under the
                        Constitution, so far as it does not, by its organic law, make impartial
                        protection full and complete.</p>
                    <p>Under the doctrine of "State sovereignty" with rebels in the foreground
                        controlling Southern Legislatures, and embittered by disappointment in their
                        schemes to destroy the Union, there will be no safety for the loyal element
                        of the South. Our reliance for protection is now in Congress, and the great
                        Union party that has stood and is standing by the nationality, by the
                        constitutional rights and by the beneficent principles of free government.</p>
                    <p>For the purpose of bringing the loyal Unionists of the South into conjunctive
                        action with the true friends of republican government in the North, we
                        invite you to send delegates in goodly numbers from all the Southern States,
                        including Missouri, Kentucky, West Virginia, Maryland and Delaware, to meet
                        at Independence Hall, in the city of Philadelphia, on the first Monday of
                        September next.</p>
                    <p>It is proposed that we should meet at that time to recommend measures for the
                        establishment of such government in the South as accords with and protects
                        the rights of all citizens. We trust this call will be responded to by a
                        numerous delegation of such as represent the true loyalty of the South. That
                        kind of government which gives full protection to all the rights of the
                        citizen, such as our fathers intended, we claim as our birthright. Either
                        the lovers of constitutional liberty must rule the nation, or rebels and
                        their sympathizers be permitted to misrule it.</p>
                    <p>Shall loyalty or disloyalty have the keeping of the destinies of the nation?
                        Let the responses to this call, which is now in circulation for signatures,
                        and is being numerously signed, answer.</p>
                    <p>Notice is given that gentlemen at a distance can have their names attached to
                        it by sending a request by letter, directed to<lb/> D. W. Bingham,
                        Washington, D. C.<lb/> W. B. Stokes, Tennessee<lb/> James Fowler,
                        Tennessee<lb/> James Gettys, Tennessee<lb/> C. B. Sabin, Texas<lb/> Henry G.
                        Cole, Georgia<lb/> John R. Kelso, Missouri<lb/> Geo. W. Anderson,
                        Missouri<lb/> J. Hamilton, Texas<lb/> Geo. H. W. Paschal, Texas<lb/> Lorenzo
                        Sherwood, Texas<lb/> G. W. Ashburn, Georgia<lb/> J. W. McClurg,
                        Missouri<lb/> John B. Troth, Fairfax C. H., Va.<lb/> J. M. Stewart,
                        Alexandria, Va.<lb/> W. M. Berkley, Virginia<lb/> Allen C. Harmon,
                        Virginia<lb/> J. W. Hunnicutt, Virginia<lb/> Burnham Wardell, Virginia<lb/>
                        Byron Laflon, North Carolina<lb/> Geo. Reese, Alabama<lb/> M. J. Saffold,
                        Alabama<lb/> Lewis McKensie, Virginia<lb/> John C. Underwood, Virginia<lb/>
                        Alexander M. Davis, Virginia<lb/> D. R. Goodloe, North Carolina<lb/> D. H.
                        Bingham, Alabama<lb/> J. H. Larcombe, Alabama</p>
                    <p>Washington, July 4, 1866.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A copy of a resolution signed by "loyal" white southerners calling for
                    delegates from southern states to attend a conference in Philadelphia on the
                    first Monday of September. The purpose of the meeting is to discuss ways to end
                    the continued dominance of the South by the region's "atrocious" antebellum
                    leadership.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.07.18.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Fire</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Messersmith</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sometime between nine and ten o'clock last Saturday evening, an arsonist
                    set fire to the back building of the First National Bank of Chambersburg.
                    Although the blaze caused considerable damage to the floor and roof of the
                    garret, its impact could have been far graver if not for the efforts of the
                    local fire companies, which managed to extinguish the fire before it could
                    spread to the surrounding property. The Directors of the bank have offered a
                    reward of $500 for the arrest and conviction of the incendiary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--The Public Schools</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Faff</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hockenberry</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eckert</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFadden</ln>
                        <fn>David S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richards</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>Mary J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reynolds</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wark</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jeffries</ln>
                        <fn>Sadie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seibert</ln>
                        <fn>Helen M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCulloh</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heffleman</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tolbert</ln>
                        <fn>Lidie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heck</ln>
                        <fn>Charlotte</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flory</ln>
                        <fn>Sadie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Directors of the Chambersburg school district have selected the
                    following teachers for the next school year: John R. Faff, William H.
                    Hockeberry, Joseph Eckert, David S. McFadden, Thomas Richards, Mary J. Stoner,
                    Sarah A. Reynolds, Mary E. Wark, Sarah Wright, Sadie Jeffries, Helen M. Seibert,
                    Mary Snyder, Maggie P. McCulloh, Mary E. Heffleman, Lidie Tolbert, Charlotte S.
                    Heck, Lizzie Gilmore, and Sadie Flory.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--National Bank of Chambersburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>According to the National Bank of Chambersburg's quarterly statement, the
                    institution will pay a semi-annual dividend of 6% to its subscribers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Base Ball</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Liberty Base Ball Club of Chambersburg lost its match against the
                    Dahlgreen Club of Greencastle by a difference of fifteen runs. The article
                    attributes Dahlgreen's victory to the fact that its players are "much stouter
                    men," which provided an advantage when batting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Balloon Ascension</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Light</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that John A. Light, "the renowned and daring Aeronaut," will take
                    off in his new balloon, the "'Flying Cloud'" on July 28th. He will leave from
                    the Diamond to embark on his sixty-third "successful aerial trip."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Electricity</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that Dr. Brown has begun to use electricity as "a remedial agent" to
                    treat patients for a number of "disorders which defy ordinary treatment." Brown,
                    the piece adds, is "experienced in the profession and administers it skillfully
                    and safely."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Installed</head>
                <origin>German Reformed Messenger</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. Samuel Philips, formerly pastor of Chambersburg's German Reformed
                    Church, took a position as the pastor of St. John's G. R. Church in Allentown on
                    June 27th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin>Greencastle Pilot</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davison</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the passing of James Davison, of Antrim township, who took up
                    arms during the War of 1812 and, later, served as a Commissioner of
                    Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Discharged</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Informs readers that Dr. Robinson and Samuel M. Seylor, both of whom were
                    arrested in Baltimore for passing counterfeit notes, were unconditionally
                    discharged on June 27th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>On August 1st, the "colored people" of Franklin county will celebrate the
                    emancipation of the slaves of Jamaica in Messersmith's woods.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Senseny</ln>
                        <fn>Alex H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On July 17th, Alex H. Senseny, 26, died in Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cooper</ln>
                        <fn>Alice M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cooper</ln>
                        <fn>John L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paxton</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paxton</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On July 12th, Alice M., wife of John L. Cooper and daughter of W.W. and
                    Mary C. Paxton, died in Santa Cruz, Cal. She was 28 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.07.18.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
