<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1869/pa.fr.fr.1869.05.19">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/06/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1869-05-19">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>19</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.05.19.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.05.19.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>To the Memory of the Patriot Dead</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>A year ago the survivors of the war to suppress the rebellion conceived and
                        carried into effect the beautiful idea of collecting together in bodies all
                        over the country, on the same day, and devoting it to decorating the graves
                        of their fallen comrades with fresh flowers. It was contemplated by the
                        originators that each succeeding year, when flowers were in bloom, and
                        nature was loveliest, and the hearts of men expanded with the beauty of
                        Spring, this sacred ceremony should be repeated until it grew into a custom,
                        in the perpetual observance of which might be kept green and fresh the
                        precious memory of those who fell victims to the rebellion. We notice in the
                        journals, throughout the country, that preparations are being made
                        everywhere, and that the observance of Saturday the 29th day of May will be
                        general, the 30th, the day which was last year observed, coming on Sunday.</p>

                    <p>The ceremony was inaugurated and carried into effect by the Grand Army of the
                        Republic, and organization composed of soldiers, extending throughout all
                        the States, with a Post in almost every town of prominence, and Major
                        General John A Logan, for its Commander. But many soldiers, perhaps the
                        majority of them, are not members of the Grand Army of the Republic, nor is
                        there a Post at this place. The ceremony here at least, cannot be conducted
                        under its auspices, and its successful observance will require that the
                        soldiers meet, regardless of secret or political organizations, and appoint
                        committees to obtain flowers and make all necessary provisions for its
                        observance. There should not be left a single Union Soldier's grave, on that
                        day, within the county, that is not visited by warm loving hearts, and
                        decked with sweet and fragrant flowers. Some lie in country graveyards, and
                        unfrequented places, but there must be sons or brothers or friends whose
                        hearts warm towards their dust, and whose hands will gladly perform this
                        sacred duty. We hope therefore that there will be but one sentiment among
                        the people on that day, and that all, whether they have mingled in the
                        scenes of carnage and blood and strife, where fell so many of our noble
                        heroes, or whether they labored in more gentle scenes for the safety and
                        perpetuity of their Government, will aid to make the solemn ceremonies of
                        this day successful and impressive. The ladies who responded bountifully to
                        the former call for flowers should again give their aid. If a personal
                        application is not made to every one they should not hesitate to do so
                        voluntarily. If needed, Repository Hall will again be opened as a place for
                        arranging and storing flowers.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper celebrates the observance of a "Memorial Day" for veterans and
                    encourages participation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper celebrates the Treasury Report that shows a reduction in the
                    national debt. The numbers show that Grant is holding true to his pledge of
                    "economy, retrenchment and reform in the administration of the affairs of the
                    Government."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The President has issued a proclamation directing that the new Constitution
                        of Virginia be submitted to the voters of the State for approval or
                        rejection, on the 6th day of July. On two clauses of the Constitution, that
                        relating to the test oath, and that disfranchising certain classes of
                        residents, a separate vote has been ordered. All the other parts of the
                        instrument will be voted on solid. An effort was made by the conservatives
                        to secure a separate vote on other sections, but it is thought that his
                        refusal will create much opposition among that class, against the whole
                        instrument. The Richmond <emph rend="italics">Inquirer</emph> of last week,
                        commenting on the terms of submission which the President was then thought
                        to entertain, said if the township, county and school clause be not voted on
                        separately "nothing will be left to the white people of Virginia, but to
                        rally together as one man, and vote down the whole of the Constitution, and
                        they will do it." It is to be presumed, however, that the experience they
                        have undergone, of "hanging on the verge of the Union," has given them such
                        an appreciation of the advantages and comforts of being within it, that they
                        will hesitate to adopt that unsatisfactory sort of revenge which consists
                        mainly in biting off thier noses to spite their faces.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The <emph rend="italics">Repository</emph> reports that Virginia will soon
                    vote on a new state constitution, one resisted by conservative factions within
                    the state. A test oath clause will also be up for a separate vote.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.05.19.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Cumberland Valley</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Petroleum V. Nasby priases the beauty and agricultural bounty of the
                    Cumberland Valley. He singles out Chambersburg, "containing a population of
                    nearly 8,000." as one of the area's beautiful towns. "Standing upon the
                    'Diamond' and looking out along the fine streets leading from this center, you
                    behold, for long distances, rows of newly built houses without the usual shade
                    trees in front. These new buildings, without the trees, mark the burnt district.
                    Here stands the stately Court House, re-built in the most substantial manner,
                    adorned with a cupalo on which stands the veritable old Ben." He also praises
                    the new Wilson Female College modeled upon Vassar.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Decoration Day</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>On Monday evening last a number of the honorably discharged soldiers of
                        Chambersburg, met in the Court House, for the purpose of arranging some
                        plans for the decoration of the graves of soldiers who are buried in the
                        Cemetery and different grave yards of our town. The meeting was organized by
                        electing Col. Theo. McGowan President and Lieut. S. W. Hays Secretary. After
                        considerable discussion, it was resolved that Saturday, the 29th of May, be
                        observed, as the occasion, for strewing flowers on the graves of our dead
                        heroes.</p>

                    <p>Col. Elder was unanimously elected Marshal of the occasion, with authority to
                        appoint his assistants.</p>

                    <p>On motion, the Housam Zouaves, were invited to assist in the duties of the
                        day.</p>

                    <p>On motion of the Citizens of Chambersburg and vicinity were invited to join
                        the precession.</p>

                    <p>On motion a committee of arrangements was appointed to solicit flowers and
                        boquets from the ladies, see to the marking of soldiers graves, and assist
                        the Marshal in carrying out his programme. The committee consists of the
                        following soldiers: Col. Theodore M'Gowan, Sergt. Thasseud M. Mahon, Lieut.
                        Geo. Platt, Lieut. Jas. Aughinbaugh, Sergt. John A. Seiders, Lieut. Thos. J.
                        Grimason, Maj. John Doebler, Sergt. H. Strickler, Sergt. Thos. Donavan,
                        Sergt. D. F. Leisher.</p>

                    <p>Repository Hall was offered as a place in which to deposit boquets and
                        flowers, and a vote of thanks and acceptance was tendered Messrs. Cook
                        &amp; Hays for their offer. It was further resolved, that the
                        proceedings of this meeting be published in the FRANKLIN REPOSITORY and
                            <emph rend="italics">Valley Spirit.</emph></p>

                    <p>The meeting adjourned to meet at the call of the chairman.</p>

                    <p>The Committee of Arrangements have agreed upon 3 o'clock, P. M., on the 29th
                        of May, as the hour for forming the procession.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGowan</ln>
                        <fn>Theodore</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>S. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahon</ln>
                        <fn>Thaddeus M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Platt</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Aughinbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seiders</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grimason</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doebler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strickler</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donavan</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leisher</ln>
                        <fn>D. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper recounts a recent meeting of Chambersburg veterans for the
                    purpose of planning commemoration for fallen soldiers on the upcoming Memorial
                    Day.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Suicide</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marshall</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Marshall, who resided near Keefer's Store in Hamilton, committed
                    suicide last Saturday. He was a "quiet, industrious citizen" and leaves a wife
                    and large family to mourn his loss. It appears he was upset about the payment of
                    some land he had purchased.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Cumberland Valley Homeopathic Medical Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The society met in Carlisle, Dr. Bowman of Chambersburg presiding. Four new
                    members joined who had converted from the "Old School" of medicine. Seven
                    additional homeopathic physicians have recently settled in the Valley. The group
                    discussed a number of medical topics.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Union Temperance Meetings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Rev. P. Coombe of Philadelphia will hold a series of temperance meetings in
                    Chambersburg. He is acting as an agent of the State Temperance Union. </summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>I.O.G.T.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahon</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fleagle</ln>
                        <fn>Laura</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolf</ln>
                        <fn>L. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Downey</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bittinger</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>D. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shively</ln>
                        <fn>Helen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Disert</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A number of officers were installed in Gilmore Lodge No. 358, I.O.G.T. in
                    Fayetteville on Thursday. "This Lodge is in a flourishing condition and doing
                    noble service in the great struggle, now going on in opposition to the mighty
                    encroachment of 'King Alcohol.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Appointments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scull</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Scull, the newly appointed US Assessor for the district including
                    Franklin took possession of his office on the 13th. </summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The County Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Franklin County Agricultural Society held its annual meeting on the
                    14th. The have fixed a date for the fair in October. "Now that the time of
                    holding the Fair has been set, our mechanical and industrial citizens, as well
                    as all other branches and trades, should commence preparations at once. This is
                    one of the best interests of our County, and should receive the encouragement of
                    every class of our citizens."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Internal Revenue</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Balsley</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Balsley, Deputy Collector of the Internal Revenue for Franklin, will
                    be at the Washington House June 1-7 to receive special taxes and taxes on
                    incomes. Licenses must also be paid there.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seidel</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kershman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A fire in Mercersburg destroyed Seidel and Kershman's sash and door
                    factory. The owners held $2,000 worth of insurance on the factory, but it does
                    nor cover the loss. </summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The performance of Skiff and Gaylord's Minstrels in Repository Hall on
                    Thursdya received excellent reviews. The audience was "delighted" with the
                    singing and dancing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Young Men's Christian Association will hold a business meeting in their
                    rooms on Thursday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reminds those who suffered from "rebel raids" that the citiznes
                    of the border counties will meet on the 1st of June to press their claims before
                    the legislature.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Pastor Elected</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gotwalt</ln>
                        <fn>William V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The members of the First Lutheran Church of Chambersburg extended a call to
                    serve as pastor to Rev. William V. Gotwalt of Ohio.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. William F. Eyster, pastor of the Lutheran Congregation of Greencastle,
                    has been selected principal of the Hagerstown Female Seminary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Appointments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>James C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Earley</ln>
                        <fn>Barnet</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James C. Eyster and Barnet Earley, both of Chambersburg, have been
                    appointed to clerkships in the US Assistant Treasurer's Department in
                    Philadelphia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper complains of the many hand-organ players performing in
                    Chambersburg on the Diamond and in front of Repository Building.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. George Miller has been appointed Postmaster of Greencastle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The foundation of the Central Presbyterian Church has been completed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Greencastle has a velocipede school.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>Robert C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carlile</ln>
                        <fn>Ellie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carlile</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert C. Moore of Pittsburgh and Miss Ellie M. Carlile of Chambersburg
                    were married on May 13th by the Rev. William Carlile.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newcomer</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newcomer</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Mary Newcomer, wife of Martin Newcomer, died in Chambersburg on May
                    2nd. She was 68 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.05.19.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
