
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1869/pa.fr.fr.1869.04.28">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/05/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1869-04-28">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day>28</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.04.28.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.04.28.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Quakers and the Indians</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper applauds General Grant's developing policy of using Quakers as
                    emissaries to the Indians. "By sending among the Indians agents whose religious
                    persuasion binds them to measures of peace, and whose history fully proves their
                    adherence to it, General Grant has taken a step far in advance of the former
                    Indian policy of the Government, and thereby pledges it to conciliation and
                    kindness. If it be possible to disarm the inborn, native hostility of the
                    Indians to the white race, to eradicate their love of butchery and bloodshed, to
                    teach them to abandon their thieving, roaming, idle, vagabond life, if it is
                    possible, in a word, to civilize them, then the policy inaugurated by the
                    President is incomparably the wisest and best yet suggested."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper criticizes Seantor Cameron for obstructing some of Grant's
                    appointments in an effort to secure posts for his friends.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper jokes that Senator Cameron's speech complainign that he has no
                    influence in the administration means that "the Administration have taken him at
                    what he is worth."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The County Superintendent</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>George E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumaker</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"Citizen" writes the Repository to suggest George E. Jones of Metal for the
                    office of County Superintendent. He gives a history of Jones' vast educational
                    training that included work under Prof. J. H. Shumaker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Register and Recorder</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shade</ln>
                        <fn>Henry S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strickler</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"Republican" writes to endorse the nomination of Henry S. Shade of St.
                    Thomas for the office of Register and Recorder. Shade performed admirably in
                    assisting Mr. Strickler, the present Register and Recorder, and deserves a shot
                    if Strickler steps down. Shade did much of the day-to-day work anyway, since
                    Strickler had lost an arm in the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>County Treasurer</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knisely</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"Republican" writes to recommend Samuel Knisely of Orrstown for the office
                    of County Treasurer. He cites his long service to the Republican Party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Register and Recorder</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>A. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"A Republican" writes to suggest A. A. Skinner of Fannettsburg as a
                    candidate for Register and Recorder, citing "eminent qualifications" and
                    devotion to the party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.04.28.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houser</ln>
                        <fn>M. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mains</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burns</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hillon</ln>
                        <fn>Hezekiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Willaims</ln>
                        <fn>Branton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gray</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Butler</ln>
                        <fn>Elias</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Ed</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duke</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patton</ln>
                        <fn>James C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Norris</ln>
                        <fn>Cambridge</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seiler</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Franklin</ln>
                        <fn>Josephine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trautman</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Philip Trautman, an insane man who escaped from the Chambersburg Poor
                    House, was found in Pittsburgh. He is a German immigrant who came to the US in
                    1852. He claims to be a millionaire who had great estates in Germany. He also
                    claims he commanded many men in his home country, and then commanded the US
                    armies during the Civil War.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Pennsylvania War Damages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Border Claim Commissioners delivered their report showing $1,821,031.04
                    in damages claimed, and $1,693,351.52 allowed. The following are the statistics
                    for Franklin: $3,122.22 in damage by Union troops to real property, and
                    $19,633.28 to personal property; $22,789.94 in damage by Confederate troops to
                    real property, and $703,854.79 in personal property. Franklin citizens claimed a
                    total of $838,162, $788,783.99 allowed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Railroad Surveys</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that engineers began surveying a proposed extension of
                    the railroad near Hagerstown. The paper urges Franklin citizens to follow the
                    citizens of Hagerstown in making efforts to secure improvements for their state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Thirtieth of May</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>In another column will be found the order of Gen. Logan, requesting the
                        observance of this day. As this day falls on the Sabbath this year, it is
                        left to the choice of the people to say whether they will observe Saturday
                        or Sunday. There certainly would be no impropriety in strewing flowers over
                        the graves of our departed heroes on the Sabbath day. The great majority of
                        them were at one time members of the different Sabbath Schools of our town,
                        some of them no doubt fell martyrs to the cause which they espoused, on this
                        holy day, and we, their survivors, could give no better token of our
                        admiration for their patriotism and of our sincere regret at their death,
                        than to participate in the solemn services of an occasion like this. If our
                        Ministers and Sabbath School Superintendents would unite in this matter with
                        the veterans of the late war, and the friends and relations of those who
                        fell that we might live, we feel confident that this decoration day would be
                        one long to be remembered. There has as yet been no programme made for these
                        interesting ceremonies, and we make the above suggestions, resting assured
                        that should they not be adopted, some arrangements will be decided upon that
                        will answer the purpose equally as well.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The upcoming Sunday will be the "observance day" urged by General Logan for
                    fallen veterans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Franklin County Horticultural Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryder</ln>
                        <fn>B. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Horticultural Society held their meeting in the rooms of the Ryder
                    Nursery Association on April 20th. B. L. Ryder read a paper on the potato. They
                    also discussed several other topics relating to agriculture.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Dogs</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper calls attention to the many stray dogs infesting Chambersburg.
                    Cases of hydrophobia have been reported, and bites are not uncommon. The editors
                    support levying a tax on owners for each dog. Those not paid for should be
                    killed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Bryan's Circus</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Bryan's "grand menagerie" and circus will exhibit in Chambersburg on May
                    5th. The circus boasts the largest elephant in the US. They also have many other
                    wild animals including lions, monkeys, and camels.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gov. Geary has approved an act to convert the town of Chambersburg into a
                    borough. Borough elections will be held in October and taxes assessed in May.
                    The town council will now have the ability to borrow money and the authority to
                    appoint a chief of police.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. Crawford delivered a sermon to young men. Rev. Barnes of the Methodist
                    Church will do the same in four weeks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Personal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Lean</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. Dr. M'Lean, former president of Lafayette College, preached in Falling
                    Spring Presbyterianc Church on Saturday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seilhammer</ln>
                        <fn>G. O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>G. O. Seilhammer, formerly of Chambersburg, is now on the editorial corps
                    of the New York Tribune. He visited town last week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sierer</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jarrett</ln>
                        <fn>Emma C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph Sierer and Miss Emma C. Jarrett, both of Chambersburg, were married
                    on April 22nd in the Methodist Church by the Rev. S. Barnes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Metcalf</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolf</ln>
                        <fn>Amanda C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowers</ln>
                        <fn>S. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel Metcalf and Miss Amanda C. Wolf, both of Mercersburg, were married
                    in Mercersburg on April 22nd by the Rev. S. A. Mowers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Claudy</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Youst</ln>
                        <fn>Millie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. M. Claudy of Potsville and Miss Millie M. Youst of Scotland were married
                    at the residence of the bride's parents on April 27th by Dr Schneck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Benedict</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah Emma</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Benedict</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Benedict</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sarah Emma Benedict, daughter of Dr. Jacob and Elizabeth A. Benedict, died
                    on April 19th. She was 10 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Cyrus D. Culbertson died in Chambersburg on April 25th after suffering a
                    lingering illness. He was 57 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>James Scott</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Scott Smith, infant son of Daniel and Margaret E. Smith, died in
                    Spring Run on April 15th. He was 6 weeks old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel Greenawalt died in Chambersburg on April 8th. He was 52 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stamy</ln>
                        <fn>Susannah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stamy</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Susannah Stamy, wife of Abraham Stamy, formerly from near Waynesboro,
                    died in Iowa on April 11th. She was 59 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Tribute of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Metz</ln>
                        <fn>Ab.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shillito</ln>
                        <fn>J. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spitel</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Ab. Metz and J. N. Shillito pass resolutions of sympathy and respect on
                    behalf of the Friendship Fire Company upon the death of Frank Spitel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Tribute of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutton</ln>
                        <fn>U. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spitel</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>G. W. Skinner and U. N. Hutton pass resolutions of sympathy and respect on
                    behalf of the Housum Zouaves upon the death of Frank Spitel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Communicated</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Clellan</ln>
                        <fn>William G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"G." from Upper Strasburg writes to pay tribute to William G. M'Clellan who
                    died suddenly of apoplexy on April 14th. He called him a "public and private
                    benefactor" who worked to enhance the quality of life in his native Franklin
                    County. He was a disciplined businessman, but generous nonetheless.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.04.28.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
