
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1869/pa.fr.fr.1869.12.01">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/19/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1869-12-01">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day>01</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.12.01.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.12.01.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>How General Butler is Loved</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>Two classes of people in these United States join hands and hearts in their
                        hatred of General Butler. They are the Democrats, and the ex-rebels. This
                        classification is imperfect, because the latter class includes many of the
                        former; though because many Democrats are not and never were rebels we
                        retain it, for want of a better. The Democrats hate him with a perfect
                        hatred, because, once high in the esteem of their party, his love of country
                        was stronger than love of party, and with the beginning of the rebellion, he
                        shook the Democratic dust from his feet, and with bitter denunciation of his
                        party's sympathy with traitors, drew his sword in the cause of the Union.
                        The ex-rebels hate him with the frantic but impotent hate of conquered and
                        powerless enemies. Like a venemous serpent with its fangs extracted, they
                        retain all their former desire to wreak their vengeance on him, but their
                        fangs have been extracted, and they are harmless. Hence the less able they
                        are to bite, the more vehemently do they hiss. General Butler had a way,
                        peculiar to himself, of making rebels feel that it was a costly business to
                        rebel against the Government. When in command at New Orleans, he taught that
                        as they made it necessary for the Government to keep a large standing army
                        there they should also bear its expenses. Acting on this plan instead of
                        drawing on the treasury of the United States, for necessary funds, he levied
                        heavy assessments on wealthy and notorious rebels, to defray the expenses of
                        his department. This they have never forgotten. They had a kind of pride
                        then, and that pride was touched.</p>

                    <p>Gen. Twiggs was an old officer of the regular army when the war broke out,
                        stationed with his command in Texas, and had received many honors from his
                        government, and some special marks of distinction. He was a traitor for all
                        this, and when the rebellion broke out instead of using his command to put
                        it down, he surrendered it, together with his fortifications and all his
                        supplies and munitions of war, to a turbulent mob of rebels. At New Orleans
                        Gen. Butler, in pursuance of his plan of making the rebellion pay the
                        expenses of its rather costly spree, seized three swords which had been
                        presented to Gen. Twiggs by the United States and by the States of Georgia
                        and Texas, for meritorious services rendered him in the Mexican war, and
                        some silver. As he had forgotten his obligations to his country, Gen. Butler
                        returned the swords to the President at Washington, and appropriated the
                        silver to pay the expenses of his department. Recently a niece of Gen.
                        Twiggs brought suit against Gen. Butler to recover the value of the swords,
                        which she valued at $34,000, and of the silver valued at $2,000. An order of
                        arrest was issued by a New York Judge, and his bail fixed at $15,000. Of
                        course nothing will come of it. Gen. Butler did exactly right in seizing the
                        property, as he did, and turning it over to the United States. But the
                        Democracy make the circumstance the occasion for showing their venom and
                        hatred for the man, and Oh! how they do pitch in. How dignified the terms
                        they employ, and how calmly and dispassionately they discuss him! They
                        cannot forgive the man whose patriotism was stronger than the ties of party.
                        As for the ex-rebels of New Orleans, they owe much to Butler, besides their
                        humiliation and subjection. They owe to him the protection of their
                        property, the security of their lives, the health of their city, and they
                        are indebted to him for the best municipal government they ever had. But all
                        this is as nothing in comparison with the fact that he made them feel and
                        obey the government of the United States.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper defends Gen. Benjamin Butler from his detractors who, the editors
                    assert, are composed solely of "rebels" and Democrats. His only "sin" is that he
                    forced supporters of the Confederacy to pay for the federal occupation of the
                    South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Bible in Schools</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The question of retaining the bible in our common schools, or of suppressing
                        it, has been pretty well discussed of late, owing to a renewal of the effort
                        by Catholics to effect a radical change in the common school system. The
                        subject is one of grave and serious import, and the impression which
                        prevails among the people, that the bone of contention is the presence and
                        use of the Protestant bible in the schools, is erroneous. If this were the
                        extent of the difficulty, the liberal and conciliating spirit manifested by
                        the friends of the common school system would reasonably lead one to believe
                        that it might easily be healed. But it is not, and the removal of the
                        obnoxious bible from the schools, which has been recommended by able and
                        influential Protestants would be a material concession thrown away. We have
                        no disposition to enter into a discussion of this question at this time, nor
                        to urge our objections against the proposition to shut the doors of our
                        school houses against the bible, for that will not satisfy the Catholic
                        Church, but to submit to the words of one of the most influential Catholic
                        journals the extent of their demand.</p>

                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Freeman Journal</emph>, in reply to Henry Ward
                        Beecher's liberal views on the subject, says:</p>

                    <p>"If the Catholic translation of the Books of Holy Writ, which is to be found
                        in the homes of all our better educated Catholics, were to be dissected by
                        the ablest Catholic theologian in the land, and merely <emph rend="italic"
                            >lessons</emph> to be taken from it--such as Catholic mothers read to
                        their children; and with all the notes and comments, in the popular edition,
                        and others added, with the highest Catholic <orig reg="endorsement"
                            >indorsement</orig>--and if these admirable Bible lessons were to be
                            <emph rend="italic">ruled</emph> as to be read in all the public
                        schools, this would not diminish, in any substantial degree, the objection
                        we Catholics have to letting Catholic children attend to the public
                        schools." It adds: "We will not subject our Catholic children to your <emph
                            rend="italic">teachers</emph>;" "we will not expose our Catholic
                        children to association with all the children who have a <emph rend="italic"
                            >right</emph> to attend the public schools!" And again: "The 'State' or
                        the 'City' has no more right to <emph rend="italic">tax me</emph> for <emph
                            rend="italic">schooling</emph> my neighbor's children, than for <emph
                            rend="italic">feeding</emph> them, or <emph rend="italic"
                        >clothing</emph> them, or <emph rend="italic">housing</emph> them. The
                        utmost that can be granted is, that, for <emph rend="italic"
                        >abandoned</emph> children, the State may provide schooling as it provides
                        food and clothes, for its paupers."</p>

                    <p>This objection goes to the very heart of the common school system. Its
                        demands do not stop short of its complete destruction. If there is anything
                        of which the old free States could justly boast, and which other nations
                        have pointed to as their special pride and honor, it is their free schools.
                        And the distinguishing feature of the system is that all children have a
                            <emph rend="italic">right</emph> to attend them. This <emph
                            rend="italic">right</emph>, which brings the opportunity of an education
                        to all, the children of poverty, as well as those of wealth, is assailed by
                        the Catholic Church. No system of education can be devised which will not
                        imperil it, except that system which puts the schools in charge of the
                        States themselves, and for which the States provide the means by taxation.
                        The common school system, with or without the bible, is equally obnoxious to
                        the Catholics, because they fear the influence of the daily association of
                        their children with Protestant youths and Protestant teachers, and they are
                        resolved to leave no measures untried to defeat it, even if its destruction
                        be necessary. We wish to call the subject to the attention of our readers,
                        for it is one which in the future is destined to agitate this country.
                        Secretly and insidiously has the Catholic Church labored to prepare for its
                        assault upon the Common Schools, and now that she is beginning to unmask her
                        guns, the people should be warned and prepared.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper denounces Catholic calls for the removal of bibles from the
                    public schools as a threat to the entire public school system.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.12.01.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Hon. Charles Sumner in Chambersburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>A large audience assembled in Repository Hall, Thursday evening, to listen to
                        the lecture on "Caste," by the distinguished Senator from Massachusetts, the
                        Hon. Charles Sumner.</p>

                    <p>At ten minutes before eight the distinguished lecturer entered the Hall
                        accompanied by his Honor Judge Rowe. His appearance was greeted with
                        applause. He was introduced to the audience by Judge Rowe, in a few
                        well-timed remarks.</p>

                    <p>Mr. Sumner began his lecture by saying that the question of Caste he opened a
                        great subject of immediate practical interest. Happily slavery no longer
                            <orig reg="">no</orig> exists to obstruct the peace of our Republic, but
                        it is not yet dead in other lands, while among us the impious pretension of
                        this great wrong still survives against the African because he is black, and
                        against the Chinese because he is yellow. This is a claim of hereditary
                        power from color--All of which is inconsistent with that sublime truth,
                        being a part of God's law for the government of the world, which is for the
                        unity of the human family and its final harmony on earth.</p>

                    <p>Government has for centuries been a device, an expedient--at most an art. It
                        must become a science subject to the laws as fixed as astronomy and
                        chemistry. This will be the science of justice on earth. To this end there
                        must be knowledge. The laws must be understood. Every human soul testifies
                        to the law of right; and under the safeguard of this law I now, said Mr.
                        Sumner, place the rights of all mankind--hoping to contribute something to
                        that judgement which blasts the effrontery of Caste as doubly offensive,
                        first to the idea of a Republic and secondly to human nature itself. He then
                        presented a picture of Caste in India, exhibiting the contrast between the
                        Brahmin, child of rank and privilege, and the Sudra, child of degradation
                        and disability. The sacred <orig reg="Hindu">Hindoo</orig> book says: "When
                        a Brahmin springs to the light he is born above the world." Passing from
                        ancient India to our Republic, the Caste claiming hereditary rank and
                        privilege is white, and the Caste doomed to hereditary degradation and
                        disability is black; and this pretention is vindicated by an alleged
                        difference of capacity, and it is said that all men do not proceed from a
                        common stock. Here Mr. Sumner quoted from Genesis the creation of man, and
                        also the words of St. Paul, that all are of "one blood." He then said that
                        the apologists for Caste hurry from these tests to science, and these he
                        followed.</p>

                    <p>He then sketched the varieties of the human family, as indicated by color,
                        skill and language, showing that people differ in color and skill and
                        language which philosophy traced to a common origin. Here he quoted the
                        testimony of Humboldt in his Cosmos to the unity of the human family and
                        against caste. The unquestionable unity appeared in the common organization,
                        common nature and common destiny, being at once physical, moral and
                        prophetic. By these tokens is he known everywhere to be man, and by these
                        tokens is he everywhere entitled to the rights of man. The dog is
                        cosmopolitan as man, and makes no discrimination of condition or complexion
                        in his fidelity. Every whole is unity. This is the law of creation, from the
                        sun in the heavens to the soul of man; not one law for one group of stars,
                        and one law for one group of men; but one law for all stars, and one law for
                        all men. Only when we consider the universality of the moral law do we
                        appreciate the goodness of this unity. Religion takes up the cross, and the
                        daily prayer "Our Father who art in heaven," is the daily witness of the
                        brotherhood of man. If not children of Adam, we are all children of God.</p>

                    <p>Mr. Sumner then considered the Common Destiny of Humanity, and the promise of
                        a common universal civilization. Why this common humanity, why this common
                        brotherhood, if the inheritance is for the Brahmins only? He was not
                        disturbed that this result had not been reached already. It would come under
                        the law of progress. Already our European civilization leads the way. But
                        there is no section of Europe which has not risen from well attested
                        degradation. Here he dwelt on England as described by Julius Caesar, whose
                        people were painted savages, and whose conjugal system was an incestuous
                        concubinage. These were our progenitors. The same report might be made of
                        France. Nothing worse is now said of Africa. But progress here prefigures
                        progress everywhere; nay, it is the first stage in the world--progress. To
                        the inquiry how is this destiny to be accomplished, he said simply by
                        recognizing the law of unity and acting accordingly. The law is plain; obey
                        it. Drive caste from this Republic and it would be like Cain, a vagabond.</p>

                    <p>Bountiful agencies of civilization are now at work. Time and space--ancient
                        tyrants--keeping the people apart--are now overcome. There is nothing of
                        aspiration for universal man which is not within reach of well directed
                        effort. By the printing press and steam engine civilization is extended and
                        secured. These two agencies are more than Greece and Rome contributed to
                        man. The question "How?" is followed by the question "When?" Not at once;
                        not in nay way which does not recognize nature as co-worker. To help in the
                        work it is not necessary to be emperor or king. <orig reg="Everybody">Every
                            body</orig> can do something. Not a thing done, not a thing said, which
                        does not help in part the beautiful consummation.</p>

                    <p>In conclusion Mr. Sumner said that he was impressed anew by the grandeur of
                        the question. Let caste prevail and civilization is threatened. Let caste be
                        trampled out and there will be a triumph which will make the Republic more
                        than ever an example. In the large interest beyond, said he, I have not lost
                        sight of the practical interest at home. This question must be settled; and
                        again I repeat nothing is settled which is not right. Here as always justice
                        is practical, politic--the best practice, the best policy. Hospitality of
                        citizenship is the law of our national life. If the Chinese come for labor,
                        we have the advantage of their wonderful and docile industry; if for
                        citizenship, then do they offer the pledged incorporation in our Republic.
                        Nor is there peril in the gifts they bring. As all rivers are lost in the
                        sea, so will all peoples be lost in our Republic.</p>

                    <p>He occupied the attention of his hearers about an hour and a half, during
                        which time he was listened to with marked attention. After its conclusion a
                        few of the audience remained to congratulate the Senator. Mr. Sumner left in
                        the 9 o'clock train for Lancaster, where he had an engagement to lecture on
                        Friday evening.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Account of Charles Sumner's appearance in Chambersburg at which he
                    delivered an address on "Caste," which the paper summarizes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Dowell</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahon</ln>
                        <fn>Thad</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strickler</ln>
                        <fn>Harry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cormany</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper bids farewell to William H. M'Dowell, Thad Mahon, and Harry
                    Strickler as the vacate their posts as prothonotary, clerk of the courts, and
                    register and recorder. The paper singles out Strickler for praise for his six
                    years of service. Democrats George W. Welsh, Mr. Snider, and Mr. Cormany will
                    replace the trio. The paper believes Welsh, who is a member of the Chambersburg
                    Bar, is well-qualified for his new duties.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brookins</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Diehl</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McPherson</ln>
                        <fn>J. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winters</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coder</ln>
                        <fn>N. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. H. Brookins was arrested in St. Thomas by Lewis Diehl on charges of
                    forgery. He was brought to Chambersburg jail with the assistance of J. N.
                    McPherson and Joseph R. Winters. The prisoner matches the description of a man
                    named N. B. Coder whose arrest carries a $1,000 reward. Coder is wanted for
                    purchasing 450,000 feet of lumber with $7,350 in forged bills.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Villainous Conduct</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sites</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Two "besotted, God forsaken wretches" named Frank Kurtz and Mr. Sites
                    stormed into the United Brethren Church in Quincy during Thanksgiving Day
                    services, insulted the minister and congragation, and then took a drink of
                    liquor. After leaving, they threw a stone through a window that struck a
                    sleeping child. Kurtz was arrested and lodged in Fort Fletcher. Sites is still
                    being pursued.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The "Boys in Blue" banner was taken down from the third story of Austin,
                    Elder, and Fletcher's Banking House on Monday. "It was the last visible relic of
                    the Grant's campaign, and of a noble organization that worked hard for the
                    success of the Republican party in this county."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Elwain</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. M'Elwain, Justice of the Peace, has resumed his duties of magistrate.
                    His offices are in the Repository building.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Daihl</ln>
                        <fn>Simon P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gaff</ln>
                        <fn>Sue M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gotwalt</ln>
                        <fn>L. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Simon P. Daihl and Miss Sue M. Gaff, both of Franklin, were married on
                    November 25th by the Rev. L. A. Gotwalt.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pensinger</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swarts</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John M. Stover and Miss Jennie R. Pensinger, both from near Greencastle,
                    were married at the Bentz House in Carlisle on November 18th by the Rev. J.
                    Swarts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heller</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Perkepile</ln>
                        <fn>Barbara Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fohl</ln>
                        <fn>John </fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Adam Heller from near Jackson Hall and Miss Barbara Ann Perkepile from near
                    Quincy were married in Chambersburg on November 25th at the residence of the
                    officiating minister, Rev. John Fohl.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Herst</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heagy</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roth</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John S. Herst of Antrim and Miss Rebecca J. Heagy of Green were married on
                    November 25th by the Rev. G. Roth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Irwin</ln>
                        <fn>Matthew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Matthew Irwin died suddenly near Mercersburg on November 22nd. He was 69
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.12.01.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
