
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1869/pa.fr.fr.1869.04.14">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/02/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1869-04-14">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day>14</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.04.14.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.04.14.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>"An Evil Spirit Troubleth"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The <emph rend="italics">Valley Spirit</emph> knows the taste of its patrons
                        better than we; yet we have too much respect for newspaper readers, to
                        believe that even the most unthinking and rabid of its subscribers can
                        derive any gratification from its editorials on the late fiendish outrage
                        that sickens the hearts of our community, and the atrocity of which is
                        without parallel in the annals of crime. The flippant and indelicate style
                        indulged in by the editors, gloating obscenely over the hellish iniquity,
                        shows too clearly that they do not deplore the crime, but regard it as a
                        windfall for the especial benefit of their party, whose mission seems to be
                        only the imbruting of the negroes and forcing them into a condition of
                        abasement that would forever make them a loathing and a dread in our midst.</p>

                    <p>"The teachings of the Radicals" that all men should be equal under the law,
                        and should have a free chance for development and culture - that no caste,
                        condition or color should be suffered in a democratic government to trample
                        the manhood out of their fellow mortals of other classes, is consonant with
                        the precepts of human wisdom and the obligations of the Divine Law.</p>

                    <p>Claiming with pride the superiority of the Caucasian over all other races of
                        men, in moral and intellectual capabilities, we are ashamed to acknowledge
                        that it had furnished examples of brutality and wickedness that blanch the
                        cheek with horror, and cause our statute books to groan under fearful
                        penalties.</p>

                    <p>And we believe that meagre as the Democratic party has, fortunately, become,
                        the vast body of criminals that stain our fame as a people, are burning and
                        shining lights in that horde of national offenders. The great cess-pools of
                        vice in our large cities fester with "Democratic" teachings and teachers.
                        New York, whose anti-Republican majorities are made up to order by all
                        manner of fraud and violence, is literally beneath the dominion of outlaws
                        and cut-throats, who intimidate the courts of justice, and bully the judges
                        on the bench, instigated by the teachings and sanctioned and sustained by
                        the Democratic party. By these teachings, too, such Congressmen as the Woods
                        and Morrissey, and such blaspheming, clergy-hating organs as Brick
                        Pomeroy's, are possible.</p>

                    <p>From the same teaching come the swarms of counterfeitors (the particular
                        friends of the late President after he relapsed into his first love and his
                        natural affinities,) who, accepting the <orig reg="cordwood"
                        >cord-wood</orig> valuation of greenbacks, think it no sin to imitate them,
                        and who lately filled our penitentaries until a sympathising Democratic
                        President turned them loose upon society.</p>

                    <p>The impunity with which this offence could be committed bore its fruits even
                        in this county, and our own prison now is ornamented by gentry of this ilk,
                        whose intense Democracy nevertheless does not prevent the social equality of
                        whiling away the time in playing "seven up" with nigger culprits in Fort
                        Fletcher.</p>

                    <p>The <emph rend="italics">Spirit's</emph> efforts to fasten the responsibility
                        of Cane Norris's diabolism upon the negroes as a people is cruel and wicked.
                        As well hold the Germans responsible for the fiendishness of Probst, the
                        Swiss of Wirz, the Philadelphians of Twitchell.</p>

                    <p>The black beast, fitly so called by the <emph rend="italics">Spirit</emph>,
                        would fare worse at the hands of such partisans as the <emph rend="italics"
                            >Spirit</emph> men, who seek to make his brutality a systematic purpose
                        of his race, and who welcome every crime committed by a "nigger" as so much
                        water on their party wheels, and to whom no sight is so odious as a
                        respectable, well-doing colored man. It is a shameless prostitution of the
                        press to attempt, for interested purposes, to pervert this horrid outrage of
                        a brute, that disgraces mankind whether white or black, to inflaming and
                        exciting the mind of the people against a class. But as there is joy in
                        Heaven over one sinner that repenteth, so there is jubilation and triumph
                        over every "nigger" that commits an atrocity, in the breasts of <emph
                            rend="italics">evil spirits</emph>.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article refutes the Valley <emph rend="italics">Spirit</emph>'s
                    editorials arguing that the recent rapes by a black man are indicative of blacks
                    in general under Republicanism. The <emph rend="italics">Repository</emph>
                    argues that only the single criminal is responsible and attacks the Democratic
                    party in general for its conduct over the past several years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.04.14.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Border Damages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>C. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>C. M. Duncan passed a resolution in the State Senate ordering the printing
                    of 10,000 copies of the report accompanying the act for the relief of the
                    citizens of the border counties who had property destroyed or damaged during the
                    war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The April term of Court commenced on Monday last. His Honor Judge King <orig
                            reg="presided">precided</orig>; Associates Ferguson and Armstrong were
                        also present. The following cases have been disposed of:</p>

                    <p>Com. vs. Bishop Meads - Assault and Battery. True Bill. Prosecutor, Brandy
                        Williams. Verdict guilty. Def't was sentenced to pay a fine of $1,00, costs
                        of prosecution and to undergo an imprisonment in the county jail.</p>

                    <p>Com. vs. James P. Wilson and James Parker, - Rape. Prosecutrix, Josephine
                        Franklin. True Bill. Verdict not guilty.</p>

                    <p>Com. vs. David Beckwith. - Rape. Prosecutrix, Mary Studebaker. Verdict not
                        guilty.</p>

                    <p>Com. vs. Josephine Franklin. - Larceny. Prosecutrix, Elizabeth Rell. Verdict
                        guilty.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meads</ln>
                        <fn>Bishop</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>Brandt</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>James P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parker</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Franklin</ln>
                        <fn>Josephine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beckwith</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Studebaker</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This weekly article lists court proceedings in the county, including the
                    defendants, plaintiffs, accusations and verdicts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Religious</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gotwald</ln>
                        <fn>L. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. L. A. Gotwald will preach in Chambersburg's Lutheran Church on
                    Sunday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Jerome Blitz on the Brain</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Jerome Blitz performed tricks of dexterity before a large audience at
                    Repository Hall.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Franklin County Horticultural Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>John P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryder</ln>
                        <fn>B. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper announces the next meeting of the society and explains that the
                    last meeting was poorly attended because of a miscomunication.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Woolen Mill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Arrangements are being made to keep the Chambersburg Woolen Mill in the
                    hands of the present stockholders in order to prevent sale of the company.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>One hundred shares of Cumberland Valley Railroad preferred stock were sold
                    at $57.25 per share on the Philadelphia Exchange. Common stock went at $55 per
                    share.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Metcalfe</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oaks</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas Metcalfe opened a grand sewing machine depot in Chambersburg in the
                    room formerly occupied by D. B. Oaks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>School Superintendent</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The school directors of Franklin County will hold a convention on May 4th
                    in order to elect a county superintendent of common schools.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>M. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>M. A. Keefer bought the warehouse of George A. Deitz near the Cumberland
                    Valley Depot. "Persons wishing to sell their grain at the highest market price,
                    or buy coal cheap, should give him a call."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Resigned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Sherry</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William M'Sherry, Revenue Assessor of the district including Franklin
                    resigned on March 23rd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Cumberland Valley Railroad carried 281,134 passengers last year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. William A. West of Path Valley received a call to Sinking Valley
                    Church, Presbytery of Huntingdon.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snoddy</ln>
                        <fn>R. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>R. F. Snoddy, formerly of Chambersburg, was appointed postmaster at
                    Shippensburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints a supplement to the road law act providing for the
                    nomination of three road and bridge viewers who will examine sights for new
                    roads and bridges. They will be responsible from securing damage waivers from
                    property-holders along the route. No building may begin, however, until they
                    report to the people who ordered the new construction.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>John P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                        <fn>Julia E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kunkleman</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John P. Culbertson and Miss Julia E. Wunderlich, both of Chambersburg, were
                    married on April 6th at the residence of the bride's parents by the Rev. J. A.
                    Kunkleman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witherow</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noonan</ln>
                        <fn>Laura</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kunkleman</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William H. Witherow and Miss Laura Noonan, both of Carrick, Franklin
                    County, were married on April 8th by the Rev. J. A. Kunkleman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brechbill</ln>
                        <fn>Fanny</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Fanny Brechbill died in Antrim on April 7th. She was 92 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foust</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Philip Foust died in St. Thomas on April 3rd. He was 50 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kaufman</ln>
                        <fn>Isac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Isac Kaufman died in Letterkenny on February 3rd. He was 54 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.04.14.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>


    </paperBody>
</hwp>
