
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1869/pa.fr.fr.1869.01.06">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/30/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1869-01-06">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>06</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.01.06.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.01.06.02" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.01.06.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Murder Near Shippensburg--Arrest and Confession of the Murder</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Titus</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hykes</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Constable</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maius</ln>
                        <fn>Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Adam Titus, a German, was arrested in Shippensburg by Constable Hykes for
                    the murder of Henry Stem, also of German descent. The two friends were last seen
                    together leaving the house of Mrs. Frey on the property of Marshall Maius. Titus
                    returned alone, and in the company of his wife, Mrs. Frey's daughter, purchased
                    a number of goods, including a shovel with which he planned to "bury a sheep."
                    Mrs. Frey became suspicious, followed tracks in the snow, and came upon a
                    shallow grave containing the body of Stem. When confronted with the body, Titus
                    confessed. He explained that he had struck Stem with an axe after an argument
                    that he blamed on "ale, whiskey, and bad women." He was arrested as he was
                    making plans to leave for Harrisburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="l">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Sunshine at the Parsonage</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>I. N. Hays, pastor of the Central Presbyterian Church, thanks his
                    congregation for a surprise visit on New Years Eve. They brought many gifts of
                    food and provisions for the parsonage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Mysterious</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Toms</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swank</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Senseny</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyle</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hyssong</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The body of Nancy Toms was exhumed and a post-mortem inquest held in the
                    town of Mercersburg. A girl named Swank, who took up with a man named William
                    Jones, now in jail under suspicion for the robbery of Fallen's Store, had been
                    living with Toms and her nephew. Toms' nephew, about 50 years old, died a few
                    years ago under suspicious circumstances, but no charges were made. Nancy Toms,
                    about 80 years old, died suddenly after writing a will that left her house,
                    money, and eight acres of land to William Jones on condition that he and Swank
                    care for her while she lived. The citizens of Mercersburg requested an
                    investigation. Dr. Senseny, Dr. Boyle, and Mr. Hyssong conducted the inquest.
                    They are said to have evidence they will be sending to the grand jury.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Readings from Gough's Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Corwin V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A large audience crowded the M. E. Church for Prof. Corwin V. Wilson's
                    reading of Gough's famous lecture on the evils of intemperance. Readings have
                    been popular lately, and Wilson did an admirable job of equalling Gaugh's
                    dramatic presentation. "We had no doubt of being interested in the argument of
                    the lecture, as enforcing the benefits resulting from total abstinence, as well
                    as in the terrible pictures drawn to show the evils resulting from drinking; but
                    we had no expectation that Prof. Wilson would be able to give the bold and
                    masterly delineations of those scenes with any thing approaching the dramatic
                    power and pathos of the author."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Murderous Attack</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Harry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Diarman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witherow</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A dangerous altercation occurred at the bridge near Spring Garden Mills
                    between Harry Wilson and Dr. Diarman. The two men had been feuding for some
                    time. Wilson stalked the Doctor while he shopped at the store of J. H. Witherow.
                    He then followed Diarman home and attacked him twice, the second time inflicting
                    three dangerous wounds with a butcher knife.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Arrested for Fishing with Stir-Nets</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yeager</ln>
                        <fn>Francis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yeager</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yeager</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Francis, Samuel, and George Yeager were arrested for fishing in the
                    Conococheague with stir-nets in violation of an act of the legislature. Francis
                    paid a $10 fine, while the others served 30 days in Fort Fletcher. The law was
                    intended to "protect the bass placed in the creek a few years since."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Important Change in the Revenue Districts of Pennsylvania</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that the state has eliminated the office of Assistant
                    Assessor in Pennsylvania distilleries. All distilleries will henceforth be taxed
                    on their full operational capacity. The act will save the state money on
                    salaries, and also decrease whiskey production and consumption as some
                    distillers go out of business and prices consequently rise.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Earnshaw</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. William Earnshaw, former pastor of the Methodist Church in
                    Shippensburg, is now serving as chaplain of the National Asylum for Disabled
                    Volunteer Soldiers. The paper recalls that Earnshaw "was among the first to
                    volunteer his services to his country at the commencement of the late war, and
                    served faithfully until its close."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Dedication Notice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creigh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Church of the United Brethren in Christ in Mercersburg will be
                    dedicated on the third Sunday in January. Bishop Glossbrenner of Baltimore and
                    Dr. Creigh of the Presbyterian Church will preach.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Rev. Dr. Schwartz of Carlisle will deliver a lecture before the Young
                    Men's Christian Association on January 11th. His topic is "No man owns deeper
                    than he plows."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Border Damages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The commissioners to assess war damage claims give notice that all claims
                    must be filed with the clerk in Harrisburg before January 31st.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donovan</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Frank Donovan, "one of the finest young men in town," died on Saturday
                    evening from a disease contracted while in the army. He was a member of the 77th
                    Reg. Penna. Vols. and had an excellent service record.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumaker</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prof. J. H. Shumaker, principal of the Chambersburg Academy, delivered a
                    lecture on "Manliness" in the Court House on Monday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Riley</ln>
                        <fn>Edward M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wengert</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaffer</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Edward M. Riley and Miss Margaret E. Wengert, both of Green, were married
                    near Fayetteville at the residence of the bride's parents on December 24th by
                    the Rev. J. Shaffer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michael</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Covert</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John M. Michael and Miss Mary Lizzie Covert, both of Lurgan, were married
                    on December 29th at the residence of the bride's father by the Rev. James M.
                    Bishop.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eshelman</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weber</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Christian Eshelman of Maryland and Martha Weber of Franklin County were
                    married on December 15th by the Rev. Dr. Schneck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn>Charles E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finafrock</ln>
                        <fn>Annie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles E. Evans and Annie E. Finafrock, both from Chambersburg, were
                    married on December 31st by the Rev. Dr. Schneck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richey</ln>
                        <fn>Amanda E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Byers and Miss Amanda E. Richey, both of Fayetteville, were married
                    at the Montgomery House on December 30th by the Rev. S. Barnes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mackey</ln>
                        <fn>W. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neff</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beltz</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anthony</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W. B. Mackey and Miss Sarah C. Neff, both of Franklin, were married near
                    Upper Strasburg at the residence of Mr. D. Beltz on December 24th by the Rev. J.
                    P. Anthony.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Sophia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anthony</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Reed and Miss Sophia Smith, both of Franklin, were married at Spring
                    Run on December 31st by the Rev. J. P. Anthony.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deckellmayer</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deckellmayer</ln>
                        <fn>F. X.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Margaret Deckellmayer, wife of F. X. Deckellmayer, died in
                    Chambersburg on December 23rd. She was 48 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donovan</ln>
                        <fn>Francis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Francis Donovan died in Chambersburg on January 2nd. He was 25 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spencer</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Martha Spencer died near Orrstown on November 27th. She was 54 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.01.06.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
