
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1869/pa.fr.fr.1869.04.07">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/02/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1869-04-07">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day>07</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.04.07.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.04.07.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Honest Officials</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>The people of both parties believe that the Government has been plundered and
                        bled remorselessly and without stint by a large part of the <orig
                            reg="officeholders">office holders</orig> during Mr. Johnson's
                        administration. Every stump speaker charged it on the stump in the late
                        campaign, and every political journal alleged it in its columns. The great
                        falling off in the revenues proved it, although the burdens of the taxpayers
                        were not lightened. There is no disputing that corruption and incompetency
                        in official positions have come to be regarded as the most alarming troubles
                        which threaten us, and honest taxpayers and the true friends of the
                        Government look to Congress for relief. The collection of revenue seems
                        especially to have something demoralizing in its nature, and taxpayer and
                        tax collector combine only too often to defraud the Government.</p>

                    <p>The two hundred millions of dollars annual stolen outright, are just so many
                        reasons why there should be a thorough overhauling of the civil service -
                        more especially the manner of selecting persons for appointments. Long
                        experience in other countries - to say nothing of our own - has demonstrated
                        the necessity for looking beneath the surface for the moral and intellectual
                        qualifications of applicants for office. It is not placing too low an
                        estimate on human nature to hold that the few and not the many will stand
                        the test. If no real test be applied, what proportion, under the most
                        favorable circumstances, will be likely to come up to the requirements of a
                        well devised civil service system? Were candidates for admission to the army
                        and navy subjected to no other scrutiny than is given to appointees in the
                        internal revenue service, to what state is it probable that army and navy
                        would be bought, and that, too, right speedily? The war has left the country
                        in a condition rendering thorough examination into the qualifications of
                        candidates for civil stations, as absolutely necessary as was such
                        examination into the qualifications of candidates for important military
                        service at any time during the war. We learned in the war slowly but dearly
                        the necessity for rigid scrutiny. We paid a heavy penalty for going ahead
                        pell mell, with no better guide than the recommendations of those whose
                        first object it was to pension favorites on the public treasury. Are we
                        doing better now in collecting the revenue? The startling fact that two
                        hundred million dollars are annually stolen, to say nothing of the failure
                        through dishonesty and incomptency to collect, affords a sufficient answer.
                        As during the war a certain amount of experience sufficed to cause the
                        application of the only remedy to save the nation from further consequences
                        of appointing to important service dishonest and incompetent men, so we may
                        conclude - and there is some comfort in contemplating the prospect - that
                        there will come a time, not far distant it is to be hoped, when a like
                        remedy will be applied to repress the evils incident to the civil service,
                        not in relation to the revenue alone, but every branch of it. As we have
                        said, the people on whom the consequences fall are even now right; it is
                        Congress that refuses. Whoever contemplates the present scramble for office
                        at the capital will not be at a loss for the reason. And in the reason
                        inhered that which forbids the hope of anything much better in the future
                        than in the past, only that we have an Executive and an administration which
                        will be prompt to detect and remove the incompetent, and if necessary punish
                        the unfaithful. This, in the absence of a proper Civil Service Law, is our
                        hope. With officers selected almost at random in the recommendation of
                        representatives, who, in too many instances, are intent chiefly on promoting
                        their own chances of <orig reg="reelection">re-election</orig>, or to reward
                        some past service which would scarcely stand the test of scrutiny, it will
                        necessarily follow that the appointing power will make serious mistakes and
                        have early and frequent occasions to make changes, and bring the civil
                        service up to something like a proper standard. It cannot be done in the
                        first or perhaps second attempt. The assurance of President Grant that he
                        will as readily remove his own appointee, if he be unfaithful or
                        incompetent, as that of his predecessor, is in the best spirit of a true
                        civil service law; and it is on this that the country will chiefly rely till
                        public opinion, making itself felt in the halls of Congress, will cause a
                        well digested civil service law to be placed among the national statutes.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial calls for a serious civil service examination system to
                    fight corruption and gross patronage, serious problems in the authors' opinion.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>A. J.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>Man in his brief life plays many parts, but to few men is it given to exhibit
                        to the world in so many and opposite characters as to Andrew Johnson. From a
                        real Moses to a harlequin the distance is doubtless infinitely great, but a
                        single step may separate a counterfeit Moses from a natural born knave and
                        fool. But six years - from 1863 to 1869 - do the business for A. J. He
                        returns to Knoxville, where he once had assumed the stately vestments and
                        the sublime demeanor of a prophet and a deliverer of the people, and
                        exhibits himself in his true character, arrayed in the tricks and trinkets
                        of a buffoon. He deceived the people of Tennessee into the belief that he
                        was a sublime patriot. He was lying. They can believe him now, he speaks for
                        truth. This last appearance is not in an assumed character, it is real. It
                        is Johnson as he is. These words came from the bottom of his heart. <emph
                            rend="italics">"I would to God that the Government had not had the
                            credit to borrow a dollar to carry on the war."</emph> Those other
                        words; "I will be your Moses to lead you out of bondage into a land of
                        freedom" were lies. He tells the colored people, now, that freedom is only
                        liberty to work, and backs it up with the declaration that he never deceived
                        them. If the latter be true they must have known him from the beginning.</p>

                    <p>His modesty, so characteristic of Johnson, doubtless restrained him from
                        speaking of much of the inestimable good he has done his suffering country,
                        but from what he does say he must have had a rough time "clinging to the
                        constitution." He modestly admits that he was badly bent, though not quite
                        broken, "by the storm which had nearly wrecked the Ship of State," and adds
                        "that he stood like a breakwater at the head of the American Government, and
                        arrested its progress for a time, at least until the people knew what was
                        going on." That last bit of truth shines like a gem amid the surrounding
                        falsehoods. He did arrest the progress of the Government for a time, until
                        the people knew what was going on, when they elected General Grant, removed
                        the obstruction, and allowed the Government to continue on in its progress.
                        Thank God he will never arrest its progress again.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This parting shot at Johnson, now that he is no longer in office, attacks
                    his (lack of) actions regarding the rights of black citizens and calls him an
                    obstructionist.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.04.07.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Assistant U. S. Treasurer at Phildelphia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. George Eyster of Chambersburg has been appointed assistant U.S.
                    Treasurer at Phildelphia. He is a well-known member of the Franklin County Bar.
                    He has served as District Attorney and war-time Provost Marshal for the 16th
                    Congressional District. He is an enthusiastic Republican and the paper applauds
                    the appointment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Rare Treat</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schwartz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. Dr. Schwartz of Carlisle will deliver a lecture in the Court House on
                    Saturday. His topic is "No man owns deeper than he plows." A collection will be
                    taken for the benefit of the Young Men's Christian Association.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Mercersburg Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The citizens of the southern part of Franklin County are working hard to
                    secure a railroad. They have raised more than $80,000 in Mercersburg, and men
                    have been appointed to raise more in Greencastle. Marion has not yet become
                    involved. "Every man knows the importance of this enterprise and the great
                    benefit it will be to our county."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that there has been a great demand for money in town, but
                    that currency is scarce.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Wilson Female College</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Edwards</ln>
                        <fn>Tryon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Small</ln>
                        <fn>Albert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>I. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wightman</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creigh</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Raffensperger</ln>
                        <fn>E. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Officers of the Board have been chosen for Wilson Female College.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Personal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ulrich</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. C. Ulrich and his family set out on a move from Fayetteville to Iowa.
                    Four families have already left Franklin for the West this spring. At least 25
                    young have also left.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>John P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryder</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Franklin County Horticultural Association met in the rooms of the Ryder
                    Nursery Association on March 30th. There was a large attendance. John P. Keefer
                    read an essay on "Pears."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eckenrode</ln>
                        <fn>S. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"A Citizen" of Amberson's Valley writes that Mr. S. J. Eckenrode and family
                    are setting out for a move to Illinois. Eckenrode plans to go into the
                    mercantile business. He is a "fine jovial fellow and a thorough business man"
                    who will be "greatly missed" in Amberson's Valley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Confirmation at the Episcopal Church</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Rt. Rev. William B. Stevens will visit the parish of Trinity Episcopal
                    Church in Chambersburg. He will lead services and conduct the rite of
                    confirmation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zook</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>B. F. Zook took charge of the Heidler Hotel in Greenvillage on April 1st.
                    "'Ben' will make a good landlord, and will leave nothing undone to accomodate
                    his patrons. He has refitted the establishment. His table will always be ladened
                    with good things, and his bar will contain the choicest liquors."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dine</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Dine, who "served faithfully" throughout the war in the battery
                    recruited by Col. Housum died on Thursday and ws burried in Cedar Grove Cemetery
                    with military honors. The Housum Zouaves presided. </summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The citizens of M'Connellsburg are pushing for a connection between the
                    Western Maryland Railroad and Pennsylvania Central at Mount Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Malone</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowers</ln>
                        <fn>S. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Malone and Miss Susan Lilley, both of Franklin, were married on March
                    30th by the Rev. S. A. Mowers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Wunderlich, formerly of Chambersburg, died in Shippensburg on March
                    29th. He was 63 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scott</ln>
                        <fn>Florence Ellen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scott</ln>
                        <fn>Timothy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scott</ln>
                        <fn>Ellen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Florence Ellen Scott, daughter of Timothy and Ellen Scott, died near
                    Chambersburg on April 2nd. She was 3 years, 11 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.04.07.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
