
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1869/pa.fr.fr.1869.05.12">

   <header>
      <title>Franklin Repository</title>

      <tagger>
         <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
         <tagDate>06/06/06</tagDate>
         <tagNote/>
      </tagger>

      <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Virginia</state>
</address>

      <date n="1869-05-12">
         <year>1869</year>
         <month norm="05">May</month>
         <day>12</day>
         <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
      </date>
   </header>

   <paperBody>

      <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.05.12.01" exists="no">

         <div type="a">
            <column>06</column>
            <head>Registry Law</head>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <trailer/>
            <names/>
            <summary>The paper prints the text of the new state voter registration law that provides
               for more rigorous upkeep of the voter roles, including periodic assessment and
               removal from the roles of deceased persons.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <pageNote/>
      </page>

      <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.05.12.02" exists="no">

         <div type="e">
            <column>01</column>
            <head>Organization</head>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <transcript>

               <p>The announcement of candidates for the various public offices, both district and
                  county, to be filled the coming fall reminds us that there is work to be done, and
                  an urgent necessity for an organization of the Republican forces throughout the
                  State. The political struggle will be fought on the part of the Democracy to wrest
                  control of the State, and to accomplish this end the party is already actively
                  moving and organizing its forces. It is but the part of ordinary wisdom to derive
                  practical lessons from our experience with our old foe, who is always active and
                  on the alert, and construct our lines and marshal our forces that we may be fully
                  prepared for the conflict when it does come.</p>

               <p>We must not shut our eyes to the fact, that though the Democracy have been
                  defeated in three successive Gubernatorial Elections the Republican majorities
                  have always been small when compared with the immense number of voters in the
                  State. It is this circumstance more than any other which has encouraged Democratic
                  leaders to gather up their shattered forces and renew the fight after each defeat.
                  Last fall the campaign was contested with unusual energy and vigor on both sides,
                  resulting in the triumph of the Republicans in the State by a majority of about
                  nine thousand. It is safe to assume that the vote was as fully brought out on this
                  occasion as it is possible to be, and though our majority was reduced some
                  thousands by fraudulent Democratic votes, as a legal investigation has
                  ascertained, it would have required but a few Republican voters out of every
                  hundred to have stayed away from the polls to give the Democracy a victory.</p>

               <p>It is fair to claim that we have a clear Republican majority in the State, and
                  that the Democracy can only hope to succeed by the lukewarmness and indifference
                  of our voters. It is this, if anything, which inspires them in the approaching
                  campaign. And it is this also, the only hope they have, which must be taken away
                  from them. In no respect does the party begin this campaign under adverse and
                  discouraging circumstances, as it did a year ago. Then the Democracy had carried
                  the State by a reasonable majority, and were rendered hopeful by their success.
                  The federal patronage, with scarcely an exception, was placed at their disposal by
                  a false and perfidious President, and was boldly used to buy and corrupt voters.
                  The loyal people were disheartened and disgusted by the treason of Johnson, and by
                  the perfidy of some of their Senators.</p>

               <p>Now all this is changed. The Democracy have no promises of patronage to make to
                  the weak, no political favors to barter to the corrupt. The Republican ranks are
                  unbroken and unwavering, and the country is sound to the core. The new
                  administration has already secured the confidence of all classes of the people.
                  The financial condition of the country is improving monthly, and the reports of
                  the Treasury show a steady reduction of the national debt. The industrial masses
                  are encouraged by this and by the independence, the honesty and the fearless
                  Republicanism of the new President manifested in every official act. There is
                  nothing - except the feeling pervading the large body of Republicans that in the
                  election of Gen. Grant to the Presidency, the country was rescued from the grasp
                  of its enemies, and that so long as he is at the helm of state no harm can befall
                  the Republic, and hence they can safely rest upon their oars, - to give the
                  Democracy hope in the approaching campaign. It is the duty of the Republican party
                  to remove this ground also, and it can best be done by organization. The enemy can
                  only be defeated in this contest as it has been in others, and heretofore it has
                  demanded sleepless vigilance and unity of action. An early interest in this
                  matter, so as to keep well constructed the nucleus of an organization, will assure
                  us at all times against surprise and demoralization. We earnestly urge upon the
                  active Republicans of every election district to devote some time and attention to
                  the cause of the party, so that when our candidates are selected no time need be
                  lost in effecting a systematic organization. If we postpone all this until the day
                  of battle comes we will be at the mercy of our foes, who are even now working
                  industriously. They are daily presenting false issues to the people, which must be
                  met and refuted. The truth must be so clearly and fully disseminated that error
                  cannot prevail against it. Let us not be idle.</p>

            </transcript>
            <trailer/>
            <names/>
            <summary>The paper urges Republican organization and energetic participation in
               Pennsylvania, noting that while Republicans are the majority in the state, voter
               apathy and a poor turnout could overcome the relatively small gap and result in a
               Democratic victory.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <div type="a">
            <column>01</column>
            <head>Grain and Fruit Prospects in the County</head>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <trailer/>
            <names/>
            <summary>The paper reports that this year's crops promise to yield an excellent harvest.
               Wheat, rye, fruit trees, and oats are all coming along well.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <div type="l">
            <column>03</column>
            <head>County Treasurer</head>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <trailer/>
            <names/>
            <summary>"Republican" writes to endorse Rueben Lewis as a candidate for county
               treasurer.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <pageNote/>
      </page>

      <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.05.12.03" exists="no">

         <div type="a">
            <column>01</column>
            <head>Treasurer of the Poor House</head>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <trailer/>
            <names>
               <name>
                  <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                  <fn>Charles</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Clayton</ln>
                  <fn/>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Smith</ln>
                  <fn/>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Martin</ln>
                  <fn>Alexander</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
            </names>
            <summary>The paper complains that the new Democratic majority on the board of directors
               of the poor house exceeded their authority by removing Republican Charles Gelwicks
               from the office of treasurer and replacing him with Alexander Martin.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <div type="a">
            <column>01</column>
            <head>Franklin County Horticultural Society</head>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <trailer/>
            <names/>
            <summary>The society held their usual meeting in the rooms of the Ryder Nursery
               Association. Minutes were read and addresses delivered on various aspect of
               cultivation.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <div type="a">
            <column>02</column>
            <head/>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <transcript>

               <p>The Chambersburg Woolen Mill, which has been lying idle, or nearly so, for several
                  months, was sold last week to an association of individuals, and will shortly be
                  put in active operation, with flattering prospects of success. We learn that the
                  price paid for the entire property, embracing the grist mill, &amp;c., was
                  about $70,000. The purchasers intend to increase this sum to $100,000, and will
                  thereby have a working capital, above their real estate, of $30,000. The lack of
                  capital, and the heavy burden of borrowed money at high rates of interest,
                  encumbered the stockholders of this property, and made futile all their efforts to
                  succeed. In the hands of its present owners, who have purchased at a low estimate,
                  and are unencumbered with debts, it cannot fail of success.</p>

               <p>We are glad to announce to the community that this important industrial enterprise
                  will not be allowed to linger and drag along without profit to itself or benefit
                  to the town. Labor is not abundant among us, and many persons anxious for
                  something to do, but unable to find employment, can now be supplied with steady
                  and remunerative work. Business of every kind will be benefitted by it, and,
                  indeed, the whole neighborhood will feel its good effects. We wish the new owners
                  much success, and hope it may not be long before the splendid opportunities for
                  manufacturing, for which our town offers, will be seized, and half a dozen mills
                  ply their busy spindles where now there is but one.</p>

               <p>At a meeting of the new Stockholders of the Chambersburg woolen mill, on the 10th
                  inst., an organization was effected by the election of Major James C. Austin
                  President, and Mr. Wm. Wallace Treasurer.</p>

            </transcript>
            <trailer/>
            <names>
               <name>
                  <ln>Austin</ln>
                  <fn>James C.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf>Maj.</pf>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Wallace</ln>
                  <fn>William</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
            </names>
            <summary>The paper reports on the sale of the Chambersburg Woolen Mill. The editors are
               pleased that it will remain in operation, and predict it will continue to enhance the
               economic life of Franklin.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <div type="a">
            <column>02</column>
            <head>Personal</head>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <trailer/>
            <names>
               <name>
                  <ln>Rebman</ln>
                  <fn>John J.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
            </names>
            <summary>John J. Rebman, formerly of Chambersburg, took charge of the Sunday School
               department of the American Lutheran Journal. "He is a zealous worker" and "eminently
               qualified" for the job. In other news, Gen. E. B. Tyler, former commander of the
               brigade to which the 126th Pa belonged, recently visited Chambersburg.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <div type="a">
            <column>03</column>
            <head>Election of County Superintendent</head>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <transcript>

               <p>The School Directors of Franklin county met in the Court House, on the 4th inst.,
                  for the purpose of electing a County Superintendent of Common Schools. The
                  Convention was organized by electing Jacob Henninger, of Chambersburg, President,
                  and Rev. A. M. Whetstone, of Mercersburg, and Joseph Douglas, Esq., of Waynesboro,
                  Secretaries. </p>

               <p>A motion was made by S. M. Shillito, that the salary of the County Superintendent
                  be fixed at $1,200, which was agreed to - yeas 34, nays 32.</p>

               <p>The following nominations we were then made for County Superintendent:</p>

               <p>William H. Hockenberry, of Chambersburg.<lb/> George E. Jones, of Metal
                  township.<lb/> I. Y. Atherton, of Mercersburg.<lb/> Samuel Gelwicks, of
                  Letterkenny township.<lb/> George H. Cook, of Quincy township.</p>

               <p>The balloting resulted as follows:</p>

               <table>
                  <row>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>1st</cell>
                     <cell>2d</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>1st</cell>
                     <cell>2d</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Hockenberry......</cell>
                     <cell>15</cell>
                     <cell>17</cell>
                     <cell>Gelwicks.........</cell>
                     <cell>31</cell>
                     <cell>42</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Jones............</cell>
                     <cell>2*</cell>
                     <cell>---</cell>
                     <cell>Cook.............</cell>
                     <cell>9*</cell>
                     <cell>---</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Atherton.........</cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell>13</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
               </table>

               <p>*Withdrawal</p>

               <p>On the second ballot Mr. Samuel Gelwicks having received a majority of all the
                  votes cast, was declared elected.</p>

            </transcript>
            <trailer/>
            <names>
               <name>
                  <ln>Henninger</ln>
                  <fn>Jacob</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Whetstone</ln>
                  <fn>A. M.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf>Rev.</pf>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Douglas</ln>
                  <fn>Joseph</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Shillito</ln>
                  <fn>S. M.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                  <fn>Samuel</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
            </names>
            <summary>This table includes voting results for the office of County Superintendent of
               Common Schools.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <div type="a">
            <column>03</column>
            <head>Meeting of the Republican County Committee</head>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <transcript>

               <p>The Republican County Committee met in the Court House on Tuesday, the 4th inst.
                  There were twelve members present and ten absent.</p>

               <p>A. F. Schafhirt, of Greencastle, and Wm. Gelwicks, of Chambersburg, were nominated
                  as delegates to the next State Convention. The vote for delegate was as follows:</p>

               <table>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Schafhirt..........9</cell>
                     <cell>Gelwicks...........3</cell>
                  </row>
               </table>

               <p>Mr. Schafhirt was declared elected.</p>

               <p>On motion it was resolved, that the delegate from Franklin County to the
                  Republican State Convention be instructed to support Maj. Gen. John W. Geary for
                  Governor. On motion it was resolved that the County Nominating Convention be held
                  on Tuesday, the 3d day of August next.</p>

               <p>On motion committee adjourned to meet at the call of the chairman.</p>

               <p>S. F. GREENAWALT, Chairman.</p>

               <p>WM. ADAMS, Secretary.</p>

            </transcript>
            <trailer/>
            <names>
               <name>
                  <ln>Schafhirt</ln>
                  <fn>A. F.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                  <fn>William</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Geary</ln>
                  <fn>John W.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf>Maj. Gen.</pf>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                  <fn>S. F.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Adams</ln>
                  <fn>William</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
            </names>
            <summary>This letter includes the results of the local Republican Committee meeting to
               decide who would be the county's delegate in the State Convention.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <div type="a">
            <column>03</column>
            <head>I.O.G.T.</head>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <trailer/>
            <names>
               <name>
                  <ln>Roney</ln>
                  <fn>William S.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Black</ln>
                  <fn>J. Harper</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Dyson</ln>
                  <fn>Laura</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf>Miss</pf>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Hull</ln>
                  <fn>Charles S.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Leisher</ln>
                  <fn>Barton</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Forrest</ln>
                  <fn>Hamilton</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf>Dr.</pf>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Sheets</ln>
                  <fn>Levi</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Eiker</ln>
                  <fn>John L.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Shuman</ln>
                  <fn>Mary</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf>Miss</pf>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Cook</ln>
                  <fn>Jennie</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf>Miss</pf>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Forbes</ln>
                  <fn>Beckie</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf>Miss</pf>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Ludwig</ln>
                  <fn>C. B.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Hull</ln>
                  <fn>George</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Tolbert</ln>
                  <fn>William E.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                  <fn>John M.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
            </names>
            <summary>Lodge Deputy W. S. Roney installed a number of officers at M'Murray Lodge, No.
               119, I. O. G. T.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <div type="a">
            <column>03</column>
            <head/>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <trailer/>
            <names>
               <name>
                  <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                  <fn>John</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Reed</ln>
                  <fn>W. G.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
            </names>
            <summary>The paper points to the case of "our much esteemed and greatly lamented friend"
               John Wunderlich who bought a life insurance policy from W. G. Reed as an example of
               the benefits of insurance. His policy was for $3000 and $390 in dividends accrued.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <div type="a">
            <column>03</column>
            <head>Skiff and Gaylord's Minstrels</head>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <trailer/>
            <names/>
            <summary>Joe Mack, Jr., business agent of Skiff and Gaylord's Minstrels, secured
               Repository Hall for a performance on May 13th. The company is well-known throughout
               the US, and has a program "far superior to that of any other company." It should
               provide the people of Chambersburg with a "rich and rare treat of music and fun."</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <div type="a">
            <column>03</column>
            <head>The Court House Cistern</head>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <trailer/>
            <names/>
            <summary>The County Commissioners broke ground on a new cistern located behind the Court
               House. It will be very helpful in protecting the town in the event of fire.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <div type="a">
            <column>03</column>
            <head/>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <trailer/>
            <names/>
            <summary>A convention will be held on June 1st to take into consideration the Border
               Damages and promote resolution of claims.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <div type="a">
            <column>04</column>
            <head/>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <trailer/>
            <names/>
            <summary>The Mercersburg Classes of the Reformed Church will hold its annual session in
               Zion's Reformed Church, Chambersburg, beginning tomorrow.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <div type="a">
            <column>04</column>
            <head/>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <trailer/>
            <names/>
            <summary>A large crowd was drawn from the county to see a recent circus in Chambersburg.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <div type="a">
            <column>04</column>
            <head/>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <trailer/>
            <names/>
            <summary>H. S. Gilbert and Co. have made a number of improvements to the machine shop
               purchased from the Chambersburg Manufacturing Association.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <div type="a">
            <column>04</column>
            <head>Mail Agents Appointed</head>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <trailer/>
            <names>
               <name>
                  <ln>Wallace</ln>
                  <fn>Henry</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Wood</ln>
                  <fn>Lafayette</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
            </names>
            <summary>The Postmaster General has appointed Henry Wallace of Greenvillage and
               Lafayette Wood of Hagerstown to positions as mail agents on the Cumberland Valley
               Railroad.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <div type="s">
            <column>04</column>
            <head>Married</head>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <trailer/>
            <names>
               <name>
                  <ln>Gehr</ln>
                  <fn>Charles</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Elder</ln>
                  <fn>Amelia Jane</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
               <name>
                  <ln>Hassler</ln>
                  <fn>J.</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf>Rev.</pf>
               </name>
            </names>
            <summary>Charles Gehr and Miss Amelia Jane Elder, both of Chambersburg, were married on
               May 6th by the Rev. J. Hassler.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <div type="o">
            <column>04</column>
            <head>Died</head>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <trailer/>
            <names>
               <name>
                  <ln>Miller</ln>
                  <fn>Lanah</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
            </names>
            <summary>Mrs. Lanah Miller died near Greenwood, Franklin County, on May 4th. She was 40
               years old.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <div type="o">
            <column>04</column>
            <head>Died</head>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <trailer/>
            <names>
               <name>
                  <ln>Alexander</ln>
                  <fn>Robert</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
            </names>
            <summary>Robert Alexander died near Spring Run on April 25th. He was 41 years old.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <div type="o">
            <column>04</column>
            <head>Died</head>
            <origin/>
            <commentary/>
            <trailer/>
            <names>
               <name>
                  <ln>Stewart</ln>
                  <fn>James</fn>
                  <sf/>
                  <pf/>
               </name>
            </names>
            <summary>James Stewart died near Spring Run on April 30th. He was 67 years old.</summary>
            <note/>
            <look/>
         </div>

         <pageNote/>
      </page>

      <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.05.12.04" exists="no">


         <pageNote/>
      </page>

   </paperBody>
</hwp>
