
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1869/pa.fr.fr.1869.03.10">

    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>

        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/01/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>

        <address>
<city>Chambersburg</city>
<county>Franklin</county>
<state>Pennsylvania</state>
</address>

        <date n="1869-03-10">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>10</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
    </header>

    <paperBody>

        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.03.10.01" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.03.10.02" exists="no">

            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The New Era</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>On Thursday last, the people of the United States changed their servant. The
                        event was long looked for and impatiently awaited. For three weary years,
                        the majority of Americans, though angered by the opposition made to their
                        will, by a man whom they had honored with the trust of their powers, had
                        fixed their eyes upon the point of time when the wrong-doer would
                        necessarily surrender his office and give up his trust. The endurance of
                        such evil as could not well be prevented and the repression of gross misuse
                        of power where possible were deemed preferable to a forcible ejection from
                        place and a resumption of the misplaced trusts. Perhaps in no other land
                        under the sun would forbearance by a nation - the fickle, inconsiderate,
                        hydra-headed mob of monarchists - be so continuously, steadily and wisely
                        exhibited. Though bitterly repentant of its own mistake, and hopeless of
                        amendment, on the part of the recreant office-holder, yet respect for law,
                        regard for order, caution as to precedent, and, above all, reliance on their
                        own ultimate victory with time and patience for helpers, the nation
                        sublimely bore and waited. The event has justified its action. The period of
                        suffering is over - the hour of relief has come. Without violence, the Ides
                        of March beheld a Consul, who had usurped the powers of the people,
                        overthrown; without the fear of a war of factions, another, who will take
                        care of the Republic, installed. The people rejoiced at the consummation -
                        not as when the herald proclaiming "the King is dead - long live the King!"
                        the bells are wrung and artillery thunders and obsequious crowds wave their
                        ready hats in the air to honor one they fear, but as men who see and know
                        that a great good which involved their own dearest interests, the welfare of
                        their country and of mankind, is accomplished. Such is our rejoicing at the
                        change which the ceremonies at Washington effected. Andrew Johnson has left
                        a place, which it is charity to say, he occupied chiefly to thwart the
                        popular will. To divert the energies of our national life into channels
                        which, circuitously, would bring us into the direction of old-time progress
                        was his avowed purpose. It availed nothing that the inclinations of the
                        people and the plain indications of events pointed him to new and <orig
                            reg="more direct">directer</orig> channels to the open waters of peace
                        and security. He preferred the old and set up a stubborn will against the
                        desires of them whom he had sworn to serve. A pilot so minded, with a crew
                        so averse, can neither reach his haven, not yet make theirs, but the vessel,
                        inconstant and veering, beats upon a limited expanse and touches on every
                        tock and shoal that borders its course. Nothing but an overseeing Providence
                        prevents the ultimate catastrophe, wherein the perverse helmsman and the
                        helpless crew are merged in the common flood. That such has been our risk
                        and such our hope of salvation, every thoughtful man knows and the fourth of
                        March, with its change of pilot and the substitution of one who will seek
                        those straighter broader channels without delay, brought no greater or <orig
                            reg="more just">juster</orig> ground of relief than this knowledge. With
                        Ulysses S. Grant the conflict ceases. Today the quiet of concord reigns
                        where so long were heard only the mutterings of discontent and angry
                        rebukes. But, to drop metaphor, with Johnson went out the last hope of the
                        reactionists; slavery, the hope of the reactionists; slavery, the
                        culmination of the devil's protest against God's making of humanity, lost
                        its last defender. The battle of human right, the beginning of which no eye
                        can see, was won when the plaudits of the people rose to the echo of the
                        Inaugural. Hereafter, in all of this broad land, no man can trample with
                        impunity on another's rights. As equals in the civil scheme as in the
                        divine, though differing in endowment, it is given to <emph rend="italics"
                            >all</emph> men to follow to the end, the life which Providence has
                        bestowed, laboring to receive fruit and enjoying when gathered. The
                        contemplation of this result, better as it is than the dreamer's picture in
                        Atlanta or Utopia, fuller than the end for which, for a race only, Marathon
                        and Salamis were fought; broader in its scope than Sidney's or Hampden's
                        aspirations; wide as the most liberal interpretation of the Divine love
                        which embraces every creature in the whole earth, must awaken the purest
                        thankfulness and content. The new era is the time of peace. The message
                        given in Judea, for eighteen hundred years has been working out its results.
                        To-day they are visible, fully rounded and complete; for, in perfect freedom
                        from all shackles of limb or conscience men may, for the first time,
                        securely look to Heaven alone for direction and to their own wills for
                        motives.</p>

                    <p>The problems of our daily life are henceforward, greatly simplified. Radical
                        abuses, affecting our existence even as beings, are stricken out of the list
                        of objects to live for and attack. The subjugation of the earth, the single
                        work given man when first put here, alone remains for occupation for our
                        hands. It is true that errors and blunders in our dealings with each other
                        as nations and as individuals will continue to abound and to require
                        correction, but it will never happen, we think, that abuses, fundamental
                        encroachments on primal rights, will arise. Free to develop all the
                        resources of our home, the earth, because we have, in fact and in truth, the
                        only peace that is lasting, the peace of recognized equality and
                        independence as men, what may we not expect from the unconstrained,
                        unperverted, intelligent, efforts of all men?</p>

                    <p>The outlook, <orig reg="today">to-day</orig>, in this material point of view,
                        is hopeful to the last degree. The language of oriental hyperbole is barely
                        equal to the depicting of our natural advantages. Every variety of climate
                        and kind of soil, illimitable space for expansion by land the omnipresent
                        waters for communication - a numerous people, healthy, hardy, intelligent
                        and pure - the materials of progress in profusion and the agents for its
                        attainment in abounding numbers, there seems nothing more to be looked for
                        or desired save that reverent trust in Him who made us and who, through
                        chastening, but in much love, has permitted us, perhaps in advance of the
                        other peoples of earth, to reach this point. Let us avail ourselves of our
                        past experience and the old, old, mistakes of all mankind, and forgetting to
                        subdue man that his unrequited toil may shift the curse of labor from his
                        master, be content, by subduing nature, to finally conquer our fate by
                        obedience to law.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The <emph rend="italics">Repository</emph> here celebrates the end of
                    Andrew Johnson's administration with great optimism and a harsh summary of
                    Johnson's actions in office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The St. Thomas School Board Again</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>It seems a little strange that the St. Thomas School Board should compel one
                        of its teachers to stultify himself as it did John Calvin Detrich, the
                        teacher of the school to which the colored children were sent. The Board has
                        a simple escape from the odium which attaches to such conduct as it was
                        charged with, if it was not true; and that was to deny it. Instead of this
                        its members force John Calvin Detrich, a son of one of the board, who
                        teaches the school, to publish two cards, in each of which he fully confirms
                        all that was alleged against them. This poor fellow, who evidently would
                        deal out even handed justice to his pupils if he were not a coward, admits
                        in the first card, that while parents and pupils complained that the little
                        colored girl was allowed the same privileges as themselves, the board
                        directed him to settle the matter to suit himself. In the second card, not
                        signed by himself it is true, but bearing his unmistakable earmarks, he goes
                        a step further and says he was directed "not to make any change if he could
                        possibly get along without it." It is perfectly safe for the friends of
                        justice to allow this statement to go before the public without a word of
                        comment. It shows outrageous bigotry on the part of the white parents and
                        pupils, total incapacity on the part of the teacher, who seeks "peace and
                        harmony" at the expense of right and justice, and a moral unfitness for the
                        important duties of school directors on the part of the board.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detrich</ln>
                        <fn>John Calvin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The <emph rend="italics">Repository</emph> attacks the school board for
                    ordering a teacher to continue treating black students in an inferior manner
                    because parents were complaining.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="l">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>The St. Thomas School Board</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>

                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italics">To the Editors of the Franklin Repository,</emph>
                    </p>

                    <p>By request of the honorable Board of School Directors of St. Thomas township,
                        I hereby make a statement of some facts concerning the difficulty that
                        occurred in my school, between the whites and the colored children of Joseph
                        Winters. I received them kindly, and have not the least aversion to teaching
                        them. I taught the little boy the alphabet, having no others in the class
                        with him. I procured the necessary books for Miss Lucy and placed her in
                        those classes that her attainments demanded. She was at least two years the
                        senior of any other in the classes, I allowed her to trap and persisted in
                        it until parents and pupils began to complain. I then brought the matter
                        before the Board. They took no action, but told me to manage the affair in
                        such a manner that I could have peace and harmony in the school. Some of the
                        members of the Board however, spoke to Mr. Winters in regard to the matter.
                        He said I could dispose of them as regards the trapping and classification
                        as I saw fit. He only desired me to give them the same attention that I gave
                        the others. Taking it for granted that Mr. Winters was perfectly satisfied
                        with the arrangement, I made the change. Miss Lucy being absent for a few
                        days returned. Her place of course was at the foot. I then kindly told her
                        that in order to remedy a disturbance that had been existing in the school
                        for some time, she should keep her place at the foot. After disposing of her
                        in this manner we got along very smoothly in school. The young ladies who
                        previously shunned her, now associated to a greater extent with her and we
                        had peace. Previous to this change, the whites would not drink out of the
                        same drinking vessel. I told them to bring a drinking vessel along. They did
                        so. I did all I possibly could to have peace and harmony reign. So far as I
                        understand, Mr. Winters cherishes the highest regard for me. I desired peace
                        and harmony to reign in my school, and in order to have it so, I found it
                        necessary to dispose of her as I did. It was a painful duty that devolved
                        upon me, and I dealt with it to the best of my judgment and ability. Hoping
                        these few isolated facts will suffice, I will close.</p>

                    <p>JOHN CALVIN DEATRICH.</p>

                    <p>ST. THOMAS, PA., MARCH 8, 1869.</p>

                    <p>We, the undersigned, teachers of St. Thomas township, were present at the
                        meeting of the Board of School Directors when the teacher brought the
                        difficulty that occurred at the Bratten school before them. The Board took
                        no action in the matter, but told the teacher he should do the best he could
                        to keep peace and harmony in the school, and not to make any change if he
                        could possibly get along without it.</p>

                    <p><lb/> JOHN F. REESE,<lb/> JOHN W. COBLE.</p>

                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winter</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn>Lucy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deatrich</ln>
                        <fn>John Calvin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reese</ln>
                        <fn>John F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coble</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This letter comes from a teacher at a local school who was ordered to
                    preserve "peace and harmony" at the school at all costs in the face of parental
                    agitation over a black student being placed in a position of higher standing. He
                    lays out his version of the case.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.03.10.03" exists="no">

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>New Road Law</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints the new Franklin County Road Law. It provides for the
                    election of road supervisors who will be responsible for assessing and
                    collecting a tax for construction and maintanence of roads. They will be paid $2
                    a day during their service, and must post a bond before taking up the post.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Franklin County Horticultural Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cooper</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jenkins</ln>
                        <fn>T. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The horticultural society held its semi-annual meeting at the Ryder Nursary
                    Association. John M. Cooper gave an address on manures. The librarian reported
                    on books purchased, and a number of fruits and vegetables were exhibited. The
                    editors assert that the association will be of great benefit to anyone who
                    engages in gardening and agriculture in Franklin County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Donation Visit</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolf</ln>
                        <fn>M. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The friends of Rev. John Hunter, pastor of the Church of God, paid him a
                    visit to bestow gifts and provisions upon him. He publishes a letter of thanks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Dramatic Entertainment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Housum Zouaves of Chambersburg will give their first dramatic
                    performance in Fayetteville on Saturday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Wilson Female College</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Raffensperger</ln>
                        <fn>E. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. E. B. Raffensperger has been appointed Financial Secretary of the
                    Board of Trustees of Wilson Female College. He will immediately begin completing
                    the endowment of $200,000. He will live in Chambersburg and will carry on his
                    work there and in surrounding counties.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garver</ln>
                        <fn>Luther M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ditzler</ln>
                        <fn>F. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ott</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Youst</ln>
                        <fn>John G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kilpatrick</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Embich</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lesher</ln>
                        <fn>John L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Glass</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. Amos</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bittinger</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The meeting of the Republicans of Scotland enjoyed a large turnout. Luther
                    M. Garver chaired the event, and Maj. F. D. Ditzler served as Secretary. The
                    following were nominated as candidates for office: Henry Wallace for judge;
                    Jeremiah Ott for inspector; John G. Youst for assessor; William Clark, Robert
                    Kilpatrick, and John Embich for school director; John L. Lesher, David
                    Greenawalt, Jr., for supervisors; Jacob Glass and John R. Thompson for auditors;
                    J. Amos Miller for township clerk; William Bittinger for constable.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Velocipede School</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lawton</ln>
                        <fn>George P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George P. Lawton announces he will offer lessons on riding the velocipede.
                    Five of the new vehicles have been ordered, which is creating a great excitement
                    in Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>I. O. O. F.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Columbus Lodge No. 75, I. O. O. F., of Chambersburg will participate in the
                    order's semi-centennial celebration in Philadelphia. </summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>Ezra</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cort</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Ezra Stouffer of Illinois and Miss Eliza Cort, formerly of Franklin, were
                    married in Illinois on February 23rd in Illinois.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guyer</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David Guyer, Jr., died in Horse Valley on February 22nd. He was 29 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunkle</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David Dunkle died near Spring Run on February 26th. He was 20 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehner</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Lehner died in Chambersburg on February 7th. He was 65 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sowers</ln>
                        <fn>Hiram</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Hiram Sowers died in Fayetteville on February 21st. He was 34 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Remley</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sarah E. Remley died on March 2nd. He was 13 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Sarah B. Wright died in Loudon on March 4th after a protracted
                    illness. She was 57 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>

            <pageNote/>
        </page>

        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1869.03.10.04" exists="no">


            <pageNote/>
        </page>

    </paperBody>
</hwp>
