<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1868/va.au.vv.1868.09.16">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/10/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-09-16">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="">16</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1868.09.16.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1868.09.16.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Shall we have Presidential Electors?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>This is a question that should be deliberately considered by the Democratic
                        Central Committee of Virginia. We have urged it to act and called upon the
                        people of the States to act out. The time for being politic, or whatever you
                        chose to call it, has passed.--Action is the word now, and the voice of old
                        Virginia should be heard. Hear what a brave Mississippi paper says to the
                        people of that gallant State. It applies with equal force to Virginia.</p>
                    <p>"We should have electors in the field even now. The State is democratic and
                        the Northern Democracy should know it is a certainty. After the election her
                        votes should be counted; and when it is ascertained that the State is
                        largely democratic--which she undoubtedly will be--her vote should be handed
                        in to the electoral college with the following address to the Democracy:
                        'Gentlemen, we have voted in accordance with our constitutional right. True
                        to our country and our principles, we have given a large Democratic
                        majority. In so doing we exercised a legal right--but, so far as we are
                        concerned, we have not the power to enforce this right.--You brother
                        Democrats of the North, have the power to see us righted--to have our vote
                        counted.</p>
                    <p>Can anyone doubt the result of such an application? We, for one, do not; and
                        are in favor of trying it, not only as a chance for the restoration of our
                        constitutional rights, but to test the sincerity and 'pluck' of our Northern
                        friends, many of whom have at the masthead of their leading newspapers "A
                        free vote or a free fight."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article concurs with the sentiment of a Mississippi publication
                    stating that a vote in accordance with constitutional rights will reveal a
                    Democratic majority throughout Virginia. The author notes that white southern
                    men have lost the power to exercise this right and calls on Democratic
                    "brothers" in the North to rectify this problem.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Destiny of the Negro</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> We extract the following from an able article in the Petersburg <emph
                            rend="italic">Index</emph> upon this subject, and suggest to employers
                        the duty of reading and explaining it to the Colored people. There is no
                        dodging this serious question, and though disagreeable, we must meet it and
                        do our duty to this unfortunate race.</p>
                    <p> The <emph rend="italic">Index</emph> well says: </p>
                    <p>"And now is the time, in this contest between the party of GRANT and that of
                        SEYMOUR, for the negro to determine what the attitude toward him of the
                        Democratic party shall be--whether the white people of the South are to
                        regard him as a citizen or a radical tool--a free voter, or a pack-mule
                        bearing the burdens of a domineering faction wherever bidden. And this the
                        whites should make the blacks understand.</p>
                    <p>The negroes' destiny will not be decided by the success of SEYMOUR or GRANT.
                        His status will be not secured by a republican triumph. No matter which
                        party wins the present field--a very few years of shifting issues and
                        conflicts between the interests of the whites in different sections of the
                        country, will leave the negro high and dry off the sea of national politics,
                        and his fate will remain in the hands of the people of his State. And the
                        impression which his use of power may make upon the minds of that people
                        now, is the real key to the future fate of the negro in the South."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article is in essence an admonition directed to the black people of
                    the South. The author suggests that regardless of the upcoming election results,
                    blacks' fate will ultimately be in the hands of the white people of the state in
                    which they reside. Their power will wane once competing political factions
                    hammer out all conflicts. Thus, how blacks wield their current power will be a
                    deciding factor in blacks' future positions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Augusta Academy of Medicine</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The old Medical Association has transformed itself into the Augusta Academy
                    of Medicine. The new organization, patterned on the American Medical
                    Association, will work to elevate "the standard of medical education," and
                    conserve "the public health." Different committees will work on key questions
                    confronting the medical community, ensuring a "wide field of inquiry."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1868.09.16.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>75 students of an expected 138 have arrived at the Deaf, Dumb and Blind
                    Institution for the upcoming term.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scheffer</ln>
                        <fn>Fred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ayers</ln>
                        <fn>R. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Fred Scheffer, "the Flying Dutchman," has secured the services of R. M.
                    Ayers as Superintendent of the Virginia Hotel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Insurance Paid</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>A. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Phillips and Garber, agents of the United States Marine Fire Insurance
                    Company, paid out $1000 to Col. A. W. Harman to replace his granary that was
                    recently burned by lightning.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Nuisance</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitcomb</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper urges Major Whitcomb to place a railing around the train depot
                    platform to keep away the crowds that gather every time a train arrives. The
                    paper asserts that most of these are "idle people who should be at work."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Warning to Boys</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The police arrested an African American boy for jumping on the railroad
                    cars. He was held for trespassing on the property of the C and O Railroad, in
                    the sum of $50. "Boys and men should remember that the grounds and cars belong
                    to the company, and that they are not warranted in going upon them, except upon
                    business connected with the R. R."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Religious</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Central Bible Society of Augusta calls upon ministers to aid them "in
                    supplying every destitute family in the county with a copy of the Bible."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Robbery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>G. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An unknown thief robbed the collection box of the Baptist Church. It
                    contained donations to make up three-month's salary for the Rev. G. B. Taylor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tillery</ln>
                        <fn>L. A. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowger</ln>
                        <fn>Louisa A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowger</ln>
                        <fn>Job</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neff</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>L. A. S. Tillery of Missouri and Miss Louisa A. Cowger, daughter of Job
                    Cowger, were married at the residence of Jacob Neff on September 10th by the
                    Rev. John Pinkerton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shiplet</ln>
                        <fn>Martin S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Catherine E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Martin S. Shiplet and Miss Catherine E. Wright, daughter of the late
                    William Wright, were married near Moscow on September 3rd by the Rev. Jacob
                    Thomas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert White died at his residence near Waynesboro on September 3rd. He was
                    72 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1868.09.16.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
