<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1868/va.au.vv.1868.10.07">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/10/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-10-07">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day norm="">7</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1868.10.07.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1868.10.07.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Situation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> The political contest <del/> which lately enshrouded the friends of Seymour
                        and Blair has been, in a measure, dispelled, and greater confidence now
                        animates the Democratic masses. General Reynolds has issued an order
                        forbidding an election in Texas; and the same policy may be anticipated in
                        Virginia and Mississippi.</p>
                    <p> The last political sensation is a controversy between Hon. B.H. Hill, of
                        Georgia, and Horace Greely. Mr. Hill's letters are having a good effect
                        North and have cleared up matters a little. Mr. Hill closes with the
                        following vigorous, truthful, and spirited paragraph: "Ten millions of white
                        people (Americans)--wearied with repeated offers of Union, exhausted with
                        protestations of good faith and sincerity, voiceless with vain pleadings for
                        peace, hopeless of the redemption of pledges, impoverished with insatiate
                        exactions, sick with fruitless concessions to malignity, distracted because
                        they will not consent to dishonor, despised because they will not be <del/>,
                        oppressed because they will not agree to be ruled by slaves, maligned as
                        rebels because they will not submit to pillage by negroes led on by
                        strangers, and driven by a terrible experience to the final conviction that
                            <emph rend="italic"> in themselves alone is their protection--such a
                            people, though deserted by all mankind, are not</emph> POWERLESS."</p>
                    <p>The election soon to come off will decide who is to be President. Till then
                        the best judges know nothing, and we can only say watch and wait!.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The author suggests that the political situation, although seemingly dire,
                    nevertheless offers a ray of hope for white southern people. A letter of the
                    Hon. B.H. Hill illustrates that despite maltreatment of white southerners, they
                    are not without power. Supposedly, this message is making an impact in northern
                    states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Mystery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> How the young <emph rend="italic">gentlemen</emph> of our town, who walk
                        about the street and lean against pumps and street corners from morning till
                        night manage to dress so nicely. We are quite sure that their parents are
                        not able to support them in their idleness, as the most of them are
                        compelled to work. These gentlemen, for the most part, look upon honorable
                        labor as something never intended for them, but loaf around stores and
                        offices for the purpose of sponging off of men who work hard in order to
                        keep out of debt, and to contribute something to the support of their aged
                        parents, whose lives have been devoted to their interests. The poor,
                        ignorant, lazy young "gentlemen" who turn up their nose at mechanics as they
                        pass them from a day of hard labor should be arrested and placed in a work
                        house or kicked out of a community which they disgrace by their damnable
                        presence. A Mechanic. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This vehement attack on "idle young gentlemen" shows the dismay expressed
                    by laborers against members of the upper class who, according to the author,
                    somehow feel above honest labor. The mechanic who wrote this short and direct
                    article suggests the lazy "gentlemen" should be severely punished.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Guard Your Civilization</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Peculiar dangers threaten the civilization which Virginia received at
                        Jamestown and our fathers have nourished through successive centuries. Our
                        enemies seek to impose new systems upon us, and obliterate the proud
                        landmarks which were our colonial glory.--The inequality of man has been
                        recognized through ages save in New England. We know nothing of man's
                        equality beyond what has been told us in a modern school. Let no one be
                        deceived by such popular clap trap.--God Himself has impressed a distinction
                        in race upon the whole human family. It is idle to assert the contrary.
                        Guard well your portals against the introduction of novelties which will
                        disturb our peace.--Virginians nourish a noble history--a noble blood--a
                        noble civilization! Cling to it with a tenacious grasp. Defend it against
                        intrusion. It was the richest legacy of our fathers--it will prove the most
                        precious inheritance we can transmit to our children.</p>
                    <p> Dr. Sears, General Agent of the Peabody Fund, in a recent speech at Boston,
                        gave those Athenian boosters his impressions of the South as obtained while
                        visiting our section on business connected with his agency. His address
                        taken as a whole, was honest and manly--a pretty fair reflex of Southern
                        sentiment. But he libeled the South when he declared that he discovered
                        amongst us "a desire, <emph rend="italic">which the people scarce dared to
                            whisper,</emph> to have introduced the elevating influences of Northern
                        civilization." Observe the words which we have italicized and tell us, dear
                        Mr. Sears, where did you obtain your information? When you were endowed with
                        that divine penetration which grasps an idea before it is uttered? You are
                        greatly mistaken, Mr. Sears. Virginians do not credit the "elevating
                        influences of Northern civilization," and we will have none of it. Powerful
                        as is the sword it can create a new civilization only when the old is in the
                        custody of a cringing, fawning race of cowards, demoralized by defeat and
                        stripped of manhood.--Virginia has not yet reached that point.--brave men
                        still are reckoned among her jewels. While these remain we shall cherish the
                        civilization of our fathers.--<emph rend="italic">Petersburg,
                    Express</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article defends the idea of a superior southern civilization. Although
                    speakers in the North, such as the Dr. Sears mentioned here, have suggested that
                    the South wishes to introduce "elevating influences" of northern civilization,
                    the author denies this emphatically. Virginia, he claims, will only adopt
                    northern ways once its citizens become a "fawning race of cowards." This has not
                    happened and, implies the author, never will.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1868.10.07.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Augusta produced a surplus of 100,000 barrels of flour in 1867. It will be
                    one-half more in 1868.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Cattle</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Cattle men from the Southwest are moving stock through Staunton. The price
                    for good stock cattle is going for 4 to 6 cents "on the hoof." Several thousand
                    have passed through town.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>A Mistake</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper retracts its statement regarding a diphtheria outbreak in
                    Staunton. So far, only one case has been reported.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Thieving</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lara</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Timberlake</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper complains about the frequent reports of robbery or attempted
                    robbery in town. Most recently, Lara and Timberlake's tobacco factory was
                    entered, but the attempt was halted by the arrival of Mr. Timberlake.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Terry vs The Central Bank of Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>Nicholas K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tams</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn>Henry H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>F. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guthrie</ln>
                        <fn>H. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>J. Wayt</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Harvey Terry, a citizen of Pennsylvania, is suing the board of directors of
                    the Central Bank of Virginia for $8,800 owed him.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>County Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The COunty Court met on the 28th ult., J. Marshall McCue, Presiding Justice.
                        Wm. Chapman and Geo. W. McCutcheon renewed their bonds as Notaries Public.
                        E. L. Houff and Jno. M. Kinney were appointed Surveyors of roads. Ordered
                        that James Bumgardner be instructed to examine and report whose duty it is
                        to keep in repair the road between the Railroad bridge and the U. S.
                        National Cemetery. License was granted to John Stoner to keep private
                        entertainment at Buffalo Gap, and also to Elias Pirkey, at the Cave of the
                        Fountains. Petition of J. D. Craig and others to change the road near
                        Weyer's Cave was granted. According to report of Commissioners and
                        Surveyors, the road running through the lands of Judge John Kenney and Mrs.
                        Margaret D. Lyman was ordered to be made of lawful width. About 47 cases
                        were disposed of on the motion docket.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J. Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chapman</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCutchen</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houff</ln>
                        <fn>E. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pirkey</ln>
                        <fn>Elias</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kenney</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lyman</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Proceedings of the Augusta County Court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Matrimonial</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that "matrimonial fever" is raging in the mountains. 10
                    couples got married last week alone. "There seems to be a general desire on the
                    part of the young people to renounce a life of single blessedness and plunge
                    into the mysteries of housekeeping." The paper jokes that Dr. Bagby should be
                    consulted for a cure for the epidemic.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>City Council--October Session</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>For the first time in two months, the Council met last Saturday night, Mayor
                        Trout presiding--all the members present except Messrs. Maupin, Baird and
                        Benedict. A petition was presented from Geo. M. Cochran, Jr., and other
                        tax-payers asking that steps be taken to improve New street. Referred to
                        Street Commissioners. A petition from E. W. Bayley and others for making a
                        pavement from Dr. Stribling's to Coulter street, was refused as
                        impracticable, at present. The Street Commissioners were ordered to examine
                        and report at what places in the city additional lamp posts are required.
                        The petition of Rev. J. I. Miller was referred to Commissioners of Streets.
                        A. H. H. Stuart, Jno. B. Baldwin, M. G. Harman, B. R. Donaghe, R. G. Bickle,
                        Jno. B. Evans, Bolivar Christian, J. C. Covell, R. Mauzy, E. M. Taylor, Jno.
                        Echols, H. M. Bell, W. H. Tams, J. H. Skinner, N. K. Trout, Wm. Frazier, E.
                        W. Bayley, M. H. Effenger, and Wm. B. Kayser, were appointed a committee to
                        represent the city at the approaching Commercial Convention in the town of
                        Norfolk. The Water Works Ordinance was amended so as to punish interference
                        by unauthorized parties with the same. The petition of M. G. Harman to
                        reconsider the tax of $100 levied on Express Companies was referred to the
                        Finance Committee; also petition of W. H. Tams for reduction of tax upon
                        Insurance Companies. The water tax upon one of B. T. Bagby's brickyards was
                        remitted. Thos. E. Coleman's Hotel liscense for present year, was reduced to
                        one eighth of the amount assessed against him. The public hydrant at Jno.
                        Gregory's corner was ordered to be discontinued. The tax imposed upon the
                        Staunton Building Association was referred to the Finance Committee. The
                        Mayor reported that the city officers had done their duty. The Law Library
                        Association was allowed the usual $30 per annum for use of Library. One
                        hundred and twenty dollars was appropriated to repair the road leading from
                        Dr. Stribling's to the Fair grounds. Council adjourned to meet the first
                        Saturday in November.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mayor</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maupin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baird</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Benedict</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>George M.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bayley</ln>
                        <fn>E. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stribling</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donaghe</ln>
                        <fn>B. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>R. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Covell</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mauzy</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>E. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tams</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frazier</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Effenger</ln>
                        <fn>M. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>William B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gregory</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Proceedings of the October Session of the City Council.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bolton</ln>
                        <fn>A. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trusler</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stringer</ln>
                        <fn>W. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. G. Bolton and Miss Sarah C. Trusler were married near Stuart's Draft on
                    September 24th by the Rev. W. R. Stringer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitesell</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stringer</ln>
                        <fn>W. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel P. Whitesell and Mrs. Mary E. Davis were married near Staunton on
                    October 1st by the Rev. W. R. Stringer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>Houston</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moseley</ln>
                        <fn>Emmie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moseley</ln>
                        <fn>William P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Col. Houston Hall of Augusta and Miss Emmie E. Moseley, daughter of the
                    late Dr. William P. Moseley of Buckingham County, were married at Wheatland, the
                    residence of the bride's mother on September 22nd by the Rev. Thomas N. Johnson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lightner</ln>
                        <fn>William T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lightner</ln>
                        <fn>Dora M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lightner</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Canter</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William T. Lightner of Augusta and Miss Dora M. Lightner, daughter of
                    William Lightner of Highland, were married at the residence of the bride's
                    father on September 17th by the Rev. J. W. Canter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keesey</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Philip Keesey, formerly of Staunton, died suddenly in Middlebrook on
                    September 24th. He was 69 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hollingsworth</ln>
                        <fn>Catherine R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finks</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Catherine R. Hollingsworth died at the Waynesboro residence of her
                    son-in-law, Capt. J. B. Finks, on September 23rd. She was 72 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1868.10.07.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
