<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1868/va.au.vv.1868.10.14">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/10/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-10-14">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day norm="">14</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1868.10.14.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1868.10.14.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Valley Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> The Fincastle <emph rend="italic">Herald</emph> says:--Our former
                        legislation on the subject of railroads was unwise. It sought to build up a
                        few interior cities, not by the sure means of developing the more fertile
                        and populous agricultural districts of the State, but by establishing
                        numerous little lines of railway from one pet city to another, and at the
                        same time refusing to open up the better portions of the State, for fear
                        trade might possibly find its way to Baltimore instead of to Lynchburg and
                        Richmond.</p>
                    <p>What has been the result?</p>
                    <p>Baltimore, anxious to secure for herself, not only the trade of the great
                        Valley, but a link in the Southern Pacific thoroughfare, has through the
                        Baltimore and Ohio R.R. Company, taken advantage of the short sighted policy
                        of Eastern Virginia, and now holds out to our people the only tangible hope
                        they have ever had of a railroad.</p>
                    <p>Had some of the cast sums of money, squandered so lavishly by the State, in
                        former years, upon Eastern railroads, commencing at nowhere and terminating
                        at the next station, been appropriated to the construction of a line running
                        from Salem to Staunton;--the trade of the Valley would to day be pouring
                        into Richmond and Norfolk, and the Alexandria and Orange R.R. on one side,
                        and the Virginia and Tennessee R.R. on the other, be ultimately the link in
                        the Pacific thoroughfare.</p>
                    <p>As it is, the B. &amp; O. R.R. Company will build the Valley road and
                        make it one of the connecting links in the Southern Pacific.</p>
                    <p> We would rather our own State to build the road. But this is now out of the
                        question,--and a railroad we <emph rend="italic">must</emph> have, build it
                        who may. The enterprise of the Valley has languished long enough for want of
                        an outlet to the world. Her coal and iron cannot be allowed to slumber
                        longer up yonder in the mountains. Her people are not satisfied to dream
                        while others are awake and doing.--They yearn to hear the whistle of the
                        engine.</p>
                    <p>But why does the work lag? The expectations of our people have been somewhat
                        disappointed by the tardiness of the B. &amp; O. R.R. Company.</p>
                    <p>We are glad to see the matter being again agitated by the Valley press.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article, reproduced from the Fincastle Herald, criticizes the railroad
                    legislation voted through by Eastern Virginians. The result: Virginia rail
                    companies did not build the road that served as a vital link in the Southern
                    Pacific, but rather a Baltimore company. Nevertheless, although money is not
                    "pouring into Richmond and Norfolk," the people of Virginia "yearn to hear the
                    whistle blow" so that enterprise formerly languishing can thrive in a prosperous
                    future.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Colored Men and Women</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> You are allowing your children to grow up in idleness. You permit them to
                        break engagements at will. You let them be as insolent as they please to
                        yourselves and rather like it when they are disrespectful to their
                        employers.--how is this going to end? If you, with habits of industry, find
                        it uphill work to make a living, what is to become of your children? White
                        children, raised in idleness, always turn out badly. Will your children turn
                        out any better? When you are no longer able to support them--and that day is
                        coming much sooner than you suppose--they must--we repeat it, they <emph
                            rend="italic">must</emph> become thieves and vagabonds. These are
                        serious questions and every day you put it off answering them, makes matters
                        worse. Worse and worse.--An evil day is coming, perhaps to all of us. If you
                        love your children and want them to do well in this world, make them civil
                        and make them stick to their work. A few years hence, it will be too late,
                        too late. Mark <del/><emph rend="italic">Native Virginian</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The author warns hard working black parents that their children are
                    suffering from idleness. The problem is that the future will be bleak for those
                    blacks who turn to their children for support. If black children are not pushed
                    into honest work by their parents, their children will not only turn out badly,
                    but their futures will be in jeopardy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Washington Express</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article reports an increase in "unspeakable outrages upon women and
                    children" throughout the country and especially in the South. The author
                    denounces Governor Wells of Virginia for pardoning some accused perpetrators.
                    "If rape and murder are thus to be encouraged, it is not difficult to foresee
                    the terrible consequences. There will be a deplorable increase in the belief in
                    the justice of Lynch law."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1868.10.14.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Temperance</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The State Council of the Friends of Temperance will meet in Staunton next
                    Tuesday. A large attendance is expected. "It affords us great pleasure to state
                    that the Order is in a most flourishing condition here and large numbers joining
                    weekly."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Happy Event</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Cornelia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>T. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latin</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Cornelia Peyton, "one of the most beautiful and accomplished of Staunton's
                    daughters," and Dr. T. E. Brown of Abingdon were married in Trinity Church,
                    Episcopal, Staunton. The Rev. J. A. Latin presided before a "happy gathering of
                    friends."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Switzer</ln>
                        <fn>S. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snapp</ln>
                        <fn>Mary M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn>J. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>S. C. Switzer of Mt. Crawford and Miss Mary M. Snapp of Augusta were
                    married on September 17th by the Rev. J. T. Carson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carroll</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cross</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wasson</ln>
                        <fn>S. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John B. Carroll of Lexington and Miss Elizabeth C. Cross of Augusta were
                    married on October 8th by the Rev. S. C. Wasson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vint</ln>
                        <fn>Esau</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kershner</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neel</ln>
                        <fn>A. A. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Esau Vint of Highland and Miss Elizabeth F. Kershner of Augusta were
                    married on October 1st by the Rev. A. A. P. Neel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Mary H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>See</ln>
                        <fn>C. S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. P. Hamilton and Mary H. Wilson, both of Augusta, were married on October
                    8th by the Rev. C. S. M. See.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>James B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wise</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hensell</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James B. Young and Miss Sarah C. Wise, both of Augusta, were married on
                    October 1st by the Rev. J. C. Hensell.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bolton</ln>
                        <fn>A. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trusler</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stringer</ln>
                        <fn>William R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. G. Bolton and Miss Sarah C. Trusler, both of Augusta, were married on
                    September 24th by the Rev. William R. Stringer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitesell</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stringer</ln>
                        <fn>W. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel P. Whitesell and Mrs. Mary E. Davis were married near Staunton on
                    October 1st by the Rev. W. R. Stringer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keesey</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Philip Keesey, formerly of Staunton, died suddenly in Middlebrook on
                    September 24th. He was 69 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1868.10.14.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
