<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1868/va.au.vv.1868.09.02">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/09/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-09-02">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="">2</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="va.au.vv.1868.09.02.01" image="" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1868.09.02.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Political Situation--General Rosecrans' Mission of Peace</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Gen. Rosecrans' visit to the White Sulphur, his conference with General Lee
                        and other leading Confederates has caused quite a stir, not only in the
                        political world but among the people. It is but another cheering sign;
                        another star of hope for an oppressed people, when the great soldiers of the
                        late war meet together, to devise means to restore the General Government to
                        its original character and plant it once more firmly on the Constitution.
                        This, together with the enthusiastic earnestness of the Democratic masses
                        North, ensures the success of Seymour and Blair in November, which will
                        guarantee to aid the priceless privilege handed down by the Fathers of the
                        Republic.</p>
                    <p> We are pleased to learn, from a distinguished Confederate who participated
                        in the conference, that the following telegraphic synopsis in the New York
                            <emph rend="italic">Herald</emph> of the 27th ult, is in the main
                        correct. It says: "During his stay General Rosecrans has had the fullest and
                        freest interchange with leading and most influential men from every Southern
                        State. On yesterday he addressed a letter to general Lee, in which he
                        expressed his views of the present condition of affairs in this country, and
                        the necessity for a speedy restoration of good feeling between the men of
                        the North and the South, and asking him to give a written expression of his
                        views as to the best way by which this era of good feeling between the
                        sections could be restored. General Lee responded with his accustomed
                        frankness and directness, expressing his reverence for the Constitution of
                        the United States, and his ardent desire for a complete union of the States
                        as of old, and also his unqualified belief that his reverence and desire
                        were shared by a large majority of the reflecting people of the South; that
                        they longed more ardently for that greatest boon of American freemen--the
                        right of self government; that the people of the States would treat kindly
                        and humanely the colored people among them if left to themselves; that they
                        would be impelled to this by the dictates of their own hearts, as well as by
                        a feeling of self interest. General Lee, however, was as especially emphatic
                        in deploring the attempt to commit the political destinies of the States to
                        these colored people at this time, before they are prepared for such a
                        mighty responsibility in an attempt which, he remarked, is fraught with
                        incalculable misfortune and calamities to the whole country, North and
                        South, and with distinction to these colored people themselves. General Lee
                        was joined in this communication by such distinguished men as Beauregard,
                        Stuart of Virginia, Stephens of Georgia, Conrad of Louisiana, and other men
                        of note, both military and civil, whose names are well known to the
                        country."</p>
                    <p>From the South we have the most cheering news; the negroes are joining
                        Democratic clubs by the thousands and our friends confidently expect to
                        carry even South Carolina. The bitter apple of negro suffrage, which the
                        Radicals presented to our lips, will turn to ashes upon their own and the
                        very means intended for our destruction, prove their ruin, politically.</p>
                    <p>Democratic fires burn brightly all over the great North West and the Middle
                        and New England States send forth "glad tidings of great joy" to the sorely
                        tried people of the United States. The States on the Pacific Coast are a
                        unit for the Democracy, and even the most sanguine Radicals begin to
                        despair--let us not cast down, but devote our whole thoughts to developing
                        our immense material resources, and all will yet be well.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article shows a bridge developing between former opponents against the
                    Radicals. Notable soldiers from both North and South have come together in
                    agreement over a number of things, most significantly constitutional government.
                    The "restoration of good feelings" is the imperative in a country currently
                    plagued by Radicals. Even black voters, the author notes, have joined Democratic
                    political clubs against Radical rule. The author suggests that this could very
                    well be at least one instrument of their ruin. Furthermore, not only have clear
                    minds in the North lined up against the Radicals, but in the West as well.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The End of the Central and the Rise of the Great Chesapeake and Ohio R. R.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>ALL HAIL! On the 29th, at White Sulpher Springs, a mighty stride was made in
                        the progressive development of our dear old Virginia. The Central Company
                        closed the contract with the Commissioner of both States, to build the
                        Chesapeake &amp; Ohio R.R. in three years--the Central ceases to exist,
                        but the Chesapeake &amp; Ohio looms grandly up in its stead!</p>
                    <p>ALL HONOR! to Anderson &amp; Co, Tredegar works, Richmond, who subscribed
                        the 300,000 Augusta failed to vote. Honor to C.R. Mason, who subscribed
                        20,000--honor to all who voted and worked for the road--honor, the highest,
                        to brave Col. Fountaine and his energetic staff! This generation will enjoy
                        the fruits of their labor, and posterity will bless them and theirs. As
                        Pendleton said of the Union, in the event of a Democratic triumph, "The
                        opening bud of Virginia's greatness, will be as nothing to the blooming rose
                        of her prosperity and grandeur," when this giant enterprise is completed, as
                        it will in three years.</p>
                    <p>ALL SHAME! on proud old Augusta, the richest and most prosperous county in
                        the State, for listening to the croaking words of timid leaders, and
                        allowing selfish prejudices to place her in the position of a "shirker," in
                        the proud battle of practical reconstruction and progress. Let her wipe it
                        out, by voting $500,000 or $1,000,000 to the Great Valley R.R., or forever
                        after hold her peace.</p>
                    <p>ALL HAIL! again to the progressive party of this State; to the young life and
                        energy that is now hampered by the obsolete ideas and old fogyism of past
                        ages. We bid them be of good cheer; a better day is coming; the great
                        Northwest is waking up to the necessity of completing our great water line;
                        and we see the triumph of progress, written on the records of a near future,
                        so plainly that the way faring man, though a fool, may read.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This articles praises all those Virginians with enough progressive
                    foresight to monetarily support the construction of the Chesapeake and Ohio
                    Railroad. By the same token, the author condemns those of Augusta County who
                    failed to vote the subscription. "Old Fogyism," he suggests, is detrimental to a
                    progressing state. The promise of the future, in this case, relies on a
                    dismissal of ways of the past. Progress is the key to Virginia's future.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Valley R. R.--A Proposition</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Those people who said they would vote $500,000 for the Valley Railroad, but
                        voted against the subscription to the Chesapeake &amp; Ohio, will have a
                        chance to prove their sincerity now. A proposition will be made to the
                        County Court to submit this question of an early day. Come down to the work,
                        gentlemen, come down! and vote for the Valley R.R. A well informed
                        Rockbridge gentleman informs us that if Augusta votes $500,000 Rockbridge
                        will increase her subscription to that amount. Drop politics, brethren of
                        the Valley press and stir this important matter up.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This brief article suggests that those who did not vote the Chesapeake and
                    Ohio Railroad subscription have another chance. A vote for the Valley Railroad
                    will rectify matters. Furthermore, the author proposes that support from Augusta
                    will stimulate an increase in money from elsewhere in the valley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1868.09.02.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parrent</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper asserts that the streets and back yards of Staunton need
                    cleaning, and urges Sgt. Parrent to see to it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sears</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A ditch is being dug across Garber's Hill to Dr. Sear's residence to carry
                    water from the public pipes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The new cemetery has been graded and curbed and now only needs brick
                    pavement and a row of trees.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper argues that an Intelligence Office for supplying house servants
                    and laborers is needed in Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The circus of McGinley and Carrol, rumored to be the best around, will
                    perform in Staunton on the 15th. The agent, Mr. A. W. Morgan, is now in town.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that "new improvements constantly meet the eye in our
                    growing city, emigrants continue to arrive, new business houses are opened,
                    produce shipments are heavy, all our Mechanics are kept busy and a general air
                    of prosperity prevails. Staunton is the liveliest city in the State and in five
                    years will have about 15,000 inhabitants."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Census</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A private census of Staunton will be conducted soon. It is estimated that
                    the current population is now 7,000, an increase of 3,500 since the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1868.09.02.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
