<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1868/va.au.vv.1868.04.08">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/04/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-04-08">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day norm="">8</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1868.04.08.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1868.04.08.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Prison Life at Johnson's Island, Prison Poetry, etc.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>R.M.C. C.S.A.</p>
                    <p>"Little Gate," cried the soldier on the top of the wall, and the sergeant in
                        charge opened the door seven feet by two, and one hundred Confederate
                        officers filed into the "pen" of Johnson's Island, just as the sun was going
                        down one Sabbath evening, August 2nd 1863. "Fresh fish" was the cry that
                        greeted us on the inside, and we were instantly surrounded by eager
                        enquirers to know where we were from what was the news &amp;c. many of
                        us found comrades who took us into their "messes," others found bunks where
                        they could. Some of us who were wounded were conducted to a building which
                        by way of distinction from the rest was called a "hospital," but which was
                        provided with neither medicine doctors nor diet.</p>
                    <p>There are perhaps few of our readers, who, if they can transmit to their
                        children the honor of having served their country in her time of peril, that
                        had not at some time during the contest, the misfortune to become prisoners
                        of war. While the cartels of exchange were on operation this did not amount
                        to more than a short absence from your command, but when Stanton, the
                        heartless wretch persisted in his advice to Lincoln that it was "cheaper to
                        feed the Confederates than to fight them," all cartels were broken, they
                        stopped fighting us, and <del/> for our rations were cut down <del/> would
                        sustain life, the sutlers were taken out of the prison yard and the <del/>
                        exercised over them <del/> into the "pen," lest they should be bribed to
                        smuggle in something to us.</p>
                    <p>Johnson's Island is about one mile long and half a mile wide, is situated in
                        the mouth of Sandusky Bay as it enters Lake Erie, and three miles out from
                        the city of Sandusky - On the Eastern end of the Island was a lot of about
                        ten acres enclosed by a wall fifteen feet high, which we styled the "pen."
                        Inside were thirteen buildings arranged in two rows about eighty yards
                        apart, these were the prisoners quarters, and on the wall a line of our
                        "guardians" kept eternal peace, and every half hour during the night they
                        cried the time with "all's well."</p>
                    <p>This prison was set apart for the confinement of officers, and usually its
                        population numbered about three thousand. Once inside all that was left was
                        to kill time, and to do this all kind of enjoyment was resorted to, such as
                        the making of trinkets from gutta percha and shell, with which the yankees
                        could be bribed to supply us, reading, card playing, debating, playing at
                        various games that gave us exercise &amp;c. In winter we had snow
                        battles with a thousand fighting on each side all day long. Gen Tremble on
                        his crutches, Jeff Thompson and old gray headed veterans joined in the
                        contest with the same spirit as if they were school boys. And at night we
                        all in turn watched beside our sick comrades. How hard it was to see a
                        strong man yield up his spirit in so desolate a spot, so far from home and
                        loved ones, with no soft hand to smoothe his dying spirit, no one shed a
                        tear of regret over the soul that was gone to God who gave it.</p>
                    <p>We were allowed to bury our own dead and we marked each grave with the name,
                        rank, command, age, and date of death, and some were the most beautifully
                        and tastefully executed - The principle events of the day were the calling
                        of the rolls in the morning, the issuing of our scanty rations and the
                        bringing in of our mail, and what joy it carried in our hearts when the cry
                        of "Dixie man" was raised, well do I remember how I forgot all my hunger,
                        all my nakedness, and all the troubles which surrounded me, when I held in
                        my hand and a letter from a loved one away off in my native land. And at
                        night we gathers <del/> quarters and discussed the news of <del/> the
                        armies, as the yankee paper <del/> the prospects of exchange, and we
                            <unclear>talked</unclear> over our old battles, and marches, and
                        triumphs.</p>
                    <p>I will not tell you now of our suffering from hunger, from cold, and from the
                        wanton cruelty of our <del/> that is all past and the memory of our pleasant
                        intercourse with the fellow prisoners and fellow sufferers who are scattered
                        over the country rises uppermost as the mind <del/> back to prison life.
                        Friends there whose association prevented prison from being a Hell must
                        always hold a warm place in the heart.</p>
                    <p>No one can imagine, except by experience, the joy with which on the 14th of
                        March 1865, I again heard the sentinel cry "Little Gate," and two hundred of
                        us marched forth and once again breathed the free open air and how proud and
                        almost bursting with gladness was the heart when eight days afterwards we
                        once more stood on Dixie soil, and once more under our noble old leader Gen.
                        Lee confronted defiantly the yankees who had for so many long, weary months
                        kept a cruel and tyrannous watch over us.</p>
                    <p>Here are some verses written by a fellow prisoner: Lieut Howard C. Wright, of
                        the 30th Va. Regt, from New Orleans, he was a gallant soldier and fell in
                        the last fighting of the war.</p>
                    <p>"ALL IS WELL"</p>
                    <p> Silence, deep, profound, mysterious,<lb/> Gains her sway with subtle
                        power<lb/> O'er the mind She holds imperious <lb/> Court within this solemn
                        hour, <lb/> And the sable sky is teeming <lb/> With her starry courtiers,
                        gleaming, <lb/> And the vestal moon is beaming <lb/> There as well.</p>
                    <p>Silence over Erie's waters, <lb/> Restling in the ambient air: <lb/> Silence
                        over prison quarters - <lb/> Melancholy silence there. <lb/> Hark! The spell
                        at last is broken! <lb/> Shrill the cry by sentry spoken; <lb/> What may not
                        those words betoken? - <lb/> "All is well." </p>
                    <p>In Half past ten o'clock! and calling <lb/> "All is well!" Ah, whence that
                        sigh? <lb/> 'Twas like grief in cadence falling <lb/> from some o'ercharged
                        heart close by; <lb/> Like a weary zephyr dying <lb/> Yet the sentries are
                        replying <lb/> "All is well!" </p>
                    <p> From you light house comes a glistening <lb/> Like a ray of hope it seems
                        <lb/> Eager hearts to false hopes listening - <lb/> Hope that only comes in
                        dreams. <lb/> Oh that hope of home returning! <lb/> Hoping on and with a
                        burning, <lb/> Feverish fire of ceaseless yearning. <lb/> "All is well." </p>
                    <p> See - a bridge of silver glossing <lb/> Spans the lake from shore to shore;
                        <lb/> Eager fancy o'er it crossing <lb/> Seeks to wander evermore - <lb/>
                        Seeks to stroll 'midst childhood's flowers, <lb/> 'Midst affection's
                        changeless bowers, <lb/> Or with love in moonlight hours, <lb/> "All is
                        well." </p>
                    <p>But the present still intruding, <lb/> With its harsh, repulsive truth, <lb/>
                        Comes unbidden here, excluding <lb/> Sweetest dreams of buoyant youth; <lb/>
                        Sweetest dreams forever fleeting, <lb/> Fancy's self forever cheating, <lb/>
                        And the sentry still repeating <lb/> "All is well." </p>
                    <p> "All is well!" The prisoner sleeping <lb/> In his bunk so rude and bare
                        <lb/> See an aged mother weeping, <lb/> Hear a young wife's whispered
                        prayer. <lb/> "All is well!" While hopes forsaking <lb/> Leaves behind it
                        only aching; <lb/> "All is well?" - While hearts are breaking, <lb/> "All is
                        well?" </p>
                    <p> "All is well!" A spirit tiring <lb/> Of its chains will soon be free; <lb/>
                        Yes, a captive now expiring <lb/> Soon shall find his liberty! <lb/> "All is
                        well ! - A soul is fleeting - <lb/> Angels hover round with greeting; <lb/>
                        And the sentinel's repeating, <lb/> "All is well!" </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A Confederate veteran submits his memories of prison life at Johnson's
                    Island.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1868.04.08.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ettinger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A musical entertainment directed by Prof. Ettinger will be given at the
                    Baptist Church on April 18th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that the Ku Klux Klan appeared in Lexington and "created
                    a great excitement among the people of the area--especially among the colored
                    population. They appeared in the apparel of the dead--looked very Ghostly. The
                    Head centre is a frightful looking monster."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hobbs</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hobbs</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eidson</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs Mary Hobbs, wife of James Hobbs and daughter of Henry Eidson died at
                    West View on March 21st.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel Wilson died on March 12th. He was 65 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zones</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Zones died near Buffalo Gap in Augusta County on March 13th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1868.04.08.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
