<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1868/va.au.vv.1868.07.22">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/09/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-07-22">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="">22</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1868.07.22.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1868.07.22.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>"Vox Populi, Vox Dei!"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The representatives of the PEOPLE have spoken in tones too loud and clear to
                        be misunderstood. They have given to the nation a ticket that will just as
                        surely be elected as that water runs or grass grows. They have given to
                        Americans a Platform of Principles such as cannot fail to send a thrill of
                        patriotic pride to the heart of every true lover of his country. They have
                        arrayed Right against Wrong; Justice against Injustice; and the divine
                        precept of "Do unto others as you would have others do unto you," marked all
                        their actions. Surely, if ever "the voice of the people" was the "voice of
                        God," it was in the words of those who composed the National Democratic
                        Convention.</p>
                    <p>In strange contrast with this is the position of the present mis-rulers of
                        our country. For party purposes they shrink at no sacrifice of money, blood,
                        or treasure--honor they never possessed. The old Jewish law of "an eye for
                        an eye and a tooth for a tooth," has been and is their motto; and to save
                        their tottering fortunes they would willingly sell to an empty, drunken,
                        imbecile "Reticent" the future control of America. To this end--military
                        despotism--are we approaching, and nothing but "the voice of the people,"
                        which "is the voice of God," can save us.</p>
                    <p> But hark! What do we hear? Ah! they are glad sounds! The day of deliverance
                        is at hand! For <lb/> "The storm which had seemingly banish'd the dawn <lb/>
                        Only hastens the advent of day!" </p>
                    <p>The good tidings have gone forth over the length and breadth of the land, and
                        from the pine clad hills of Maine to the golden sands of California--from
                        the cold black shore of the Northern Lakes to the bright, sunny banks of the
                        Gulf, cheer after cheer rolls up for Seymour and Blair! the choice of a
                        reunited people, and "the voice of the people is the voice of God!"</p>
                    <p> The "good men and true" of other States send us greeting. Do your duty,
                        Virginians, and the day is not far distant when the proud old "Mother of
                        States" will again resume her position in the Federal family, rid of the
                        vile incubus which now grinds her to the earth! Let not hope forsake us now
                        in the eleventh hour, and all will yet be well. By our own acts shall we be
                        judged, and let it not be said that Virginia was ever found wanting. Let us
                        arouse to the dangers of the hour!--hurl the accursed "constitution" in the
                        teeth of its framers!--join hands with the Democracy in the North, and in
                        the coming contest aid them in once more proclaiming that <emph
                            rend="italic"> "the voice of the people is the voice of God!"
                    </emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>As the Democratic National Convention rapidly approaches, the author of
                    this article remains confident that the majority of the people throughout the
                    entire country will side with the conservative ticket of Seymour and Blair. all
                    those who love their country in both North and South will naturally see the
                    evils of the radicals. For the author, this is a forgone conclusion. He equates
                    the voice of the people with Divine intervention. Since God favors
                    conservatives, the voice of the people and the voice of God are one in the same.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>There Can be Nothing Worse</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> Unless we adopt this "constitution," says the timid croaker, "Congress will
                        impose a still worse government upon us." And suppose, says the Petersburg
                            <emph rend="italic">Express,</emph> Congress does? Let them do their
                        worst!--let them do all that venom and malignancy can suggest!--give them a
                            <emph rend="italic">carte blanche</emph> to rival, in the cruelty of
                        their measure, the ferocity of demons!--but amid it all let them understand
                        that Virginia is still brave undaunted and unflinching--neither to be
                        bought, nor cheated, nor frightened from her devotion to principle. For near
                        seven years our people have "been tried, as if with fire"--persecuted,
                        beggared, slandered, oppressed--death has become our familiar friend, and
                        danger has been disarmed of its terror by frequent intercourse--and after it
                        all, shall Virginians be forced into a base betrayal of their State and a
                        surrender of their honor by a cowardly apprehension of some future physical
                        inflictions? Such is not the material from which spring "the true and brave"
                        of earth. Such men lack principle--with them personal and national honor is
                        at a heavy discount. Unlike the great master of the German reformation, they
                        fail to grow as strong as dangers increase, and their timid imaginations
                        discover in every tree and shrub a "masked battery" for their destruction.
                        Like the frightened soldier on the field of battle, palsied with fear,
                        without sufficient courage either to advance or retreat, tightly closing his
                        eyes in the vain attempt to become oblivious to danger, these men fall to
                        the ground, awaiting the advance of the foe, in order that their precious
                        carcasses may be made secure from grape and canister in the enemy's
                        prison.--heaven pity such men! Heaven pardon their weakness, and help them
                        yet to be true, strong and brave.</p>
                    <p>And what can Radicalism do that is worse? A tax, amounting as we <del/> some
                        time since, to <unclear>3</unclear> percent is levied by the constitution,
                        thus virtually confiscating every acre of land in the State. Southern
                        children forced to companionship with negro brats in public
                        schools--Southern gentlemen sitting on negro juries, or drilled by negro
                        soldiers, or asking justice from negro officials, or harassed by negro tax
                        gatherers--can radicalism do much worse? Negro supremacy fills the cup. We
                        have no rights left which can be wrenched from us--no property to be
                        stolen--no security to life of which can be disappointed. Virginia has
                        nothing left but her honor. Honor is her only treasure. Let the Virginian be
                        forever accursed who dare yield it, save with his life. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asking what could possibly be worse than current conditions forced by
                    radical rule, the author points out the near certainty of future taxes, land
                    confiscation, and integrated schools. He illustrates how those who would force
                    such measures are the very lowest of men. However, despite what the radicals may
                    do, Virginians will never be forced to surrender their honor. Having no rights
                    left to be taken, Virginians have only their honor left; the author condemns
                    those "who dare yield it."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper urges citizens to cast aside old party affiliations and
                    prejudices and stand "shoulder to shoulder in the last great battle for our
                    rights."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper asserts that radicalism is now "playing its farewell engagement"
                    before its disappearance from American politics.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Shall Virginians Vote in the Presidential Election?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>To the question we answer aye! Vote as our fathers did; vote as free citizens
                        of a republic whose Constitution guarantees this right to each and every
                        state!</p>
                    <p>"How will you do it?" is asked by some croaker or timid time-server. "Suppose
                        Congress prohibits an election and allows us no voice, as it now seems
                        disposed to do, in regard to a vote on the infamous Constitution, framed by
                        its orders?"</p>
                    <p> The question is easily answered. Let the Democratic State Central Committee,
                        which represents the white people of the State, call upon the county
                        Superintendents to see who will volunteer to act as judges and clerks of
                        election at each precinct. Let each and every legal vote, under the
                        constitution of Virginia, walk boldly to the polls and ring out the old
                            <emph rend="italic">viva voce</emph> of Virginia, in favor of Seymour
                        and Blair--against oppression and wrong--Sic Semper Tyrannis, forever!</p>
                    <p>This can and should be done, and the voice of the people sent to Washington.
                        It will cost nothing, and the fact should be recorded in History. Let the
                        central committee set promptly and the press proclaim the will of the
                        people. "He who dallies is a dastard and he who doubts is damned.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This brief passage answers yes to the question of voting in the upcoming
                    presidential election. Even if Radicals in Congress attempt to prevent it, the
                    Democratic State Central Committee will see to it that every eligible voter will
                    be able to go to the polls.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The 21st</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> Yesterday, seven years ago, the first battle of Manassas was fought. The
                        individual gallantry of the South triumphed over the disciplined masses of
                        the United States and the <sic>incompetency</sic> of our generals!
                        Yesterday, the Staunton Artillery, under General J.D. Imboden, (then
                        Captain) gained its first laurels! Yesterday the "Stonewall" and Bee's
                        Brigades gained their immortal names! Yesterday Wm. E. Woodward and Joab
                        Seally, the first martyrs from Staunton, gave up their lives for the
                        Right--Woodward shouting "Give me liberty or give me death!"</p>
                    <p>Oh, the hot and weary day! How it breaks upon our memory! How it fires every
                        fibre of our heart! How it tingles each pulsation, and casts a halo of glory
                        around and about the cloud of darkness that now enshrouds us!</p>
                    <p> Let it forever be sacred! Treasure it up in your hearts, and sadly cherish
                        the memories of the boys who we lost--those gallant boys who represented all
                        that was good, brave and noble in humanity! And the "Old Stonewall," the
                        "West Augusta Guards," the "5th"--all--Baylor, Harman, Harper, and a host of
                        others, the peerless and free! all gone! God help us! we cannot pursue the
                        subject. They are gone<lb/> "Out of a life ever lornful. <lb/> Out of a land
                        very Mournful, <lb/> Where in bleak exile we roam; <lb/>Into a joyland above
                        us, <lb/> Where there's a Father to love us--<lb/>Into "our Home--sweet
                        Home."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>On the anniversary of first Manassas, this brief note honors those who
                    fought and triumphed over the "disciplined masses" of the United States. While
                    darkness now enshrouds the South, the memory of the battle and of the "boys
                    lost" is "forever sacred."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1868.07.22.03" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper complains that "idle negroes still hang around waiting for the
                    'forty acres and a mule.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>General Stoneman has ordered the Auditor of Public Accounts to advance
                    $5,000 to Staunton's Deaf, Dumb and Blind Institution for the next term.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Base Ball</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Little Tom" is leading the boys of Staunton in forming a baseball club.
                    The paper suggests the name "West Augusta Base Ball Club."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Misner</ln>
                        <fn>Robert F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Misner</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert F. Misner and Mrs. Sarah Misner, both of Augusta, were married in
                    Staunton at the County Clerk's Office on July 16th by the Rev. William A.
                    Harris.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1868.07.22.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
