<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1868/va.au.vv.1868.05.06">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/04/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-05-06">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day norm="">6</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1868.05.06.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1868.05.06.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following well put sentences of the Mobile <emph rend="italic"
                        >Register</emph> so well express our sentiments in reference to the suicidal
                        dissensions which are springing up in the ranks of the Northern Democracy,
                        that we adopt them as our own. We can tell the <emph rend="italic">New York
                            World</emph> and the "War" Democracy on the one hand, and "Brick"
                        Pomeroy and the "Peace" Democracy on the other, that neither need appeal to
                        the Southern people in this unhappy controversy which, if persisted in, will
                        prove so fatal to all our hopes and constitutional freedom on this
                        continent. The <emph rend="italic">first</emph> wish of the Southern people
                        is to enter the canvass next fall <emph rend="italic">to win,</emph> and it
                        makes but very little difference to them who bears the standard, provided he
                        stands on a platform of principle which will relieve us from negro suffrage,
                        military domination, &amp;c., and restore us to our equal rights in the
                        Union.</p>
                    <p>"In the section where the La Crosse Democrat is published, the people may
                        perhaps afford to sacrifice success to preference. They are not yet under
                        the pressure of an unmitigated despotism; they are not in danger of negro
                        domination; they are not walking on the edge of a social volcano; they can
                        afford to indulge themselves in the luxury of making their own choices.</p>
                    <p>But the case is far different with us of the South. The interests dependent
                        upon the success of the right in the next Presidential election are too
                        momentous to permit us to regard the promptings of fancy or sentiment. <emph
                            rend="italic">Ultimate</emph> success is necessary to the salvation of
                        the North, but it is indispensable to us that it should be <emph
                            rend="italic">immediate</emph> success: the alternative is ruin. The man
                        who sneers at the idea of <emph rend="italic">availability</emph> under
                        these circumstances is a fool or a fanatic.</p>
                    <p>We fully admit the claims upon our admiration, respect, and support of these
                        Northern men "who kept political faith and integrity" under all the trials
                        and temptations of the late war. Our right hands would forget their cunning,
                        and the pen would fall powerless form our fingers before we could forget or
                        forsake them. But there is another class of men, whom people that talk like
                        the assailants of Mr. Forsyth appear to forget, and to whom our obligations
                        are still higher. This class includes Jefferson Davis, Robert E. Lee, Joseph
                        E. Johnston, and a few others of the same sort. If we are to discard all our
                        considerations of policy or availability, why not go to the fountainhead of
                        principle, or sentiment, and nominate one of those at once? Follow your
                        principles, gentlemen, even if they take you out of the window."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The author of this article is concerned primarily with the upcoming
                    presidential election. Like many others, he favors northern Democrats who
                    support constitutional liberties of white men. As usual, the idea of Negro
                    suffrage is regarded with contempt. Still, the author reminds his readers that
                    they are obligated to a higher class of men, such as R.E. Lee. If one were to
                    "discard considerations of policy or availability," then "principle" should
                    trump all else and lead to the nomination of a member of the higher class.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper quotes the Richmond Examiner who argue that African Americans
                    "are being led like sheep by the white carpet-baggers." Black men will supply
                    the votes and white men will receive all the spoils.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>What if the Senate becomes an Obstruction?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper argues that Johnson was impeached and faces Senate trial because
                    he was deemed an "obstruction" to the Republican agenda. The editors ask what
                    should be done with the Senate when it proves an obstruction to the Democratic
                    administration expected after the next election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1868.05.06.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper asks "white people who wish to see the State made a hell on
                    earth" to stay home on election day.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that 35 new members joined Staunton's Presbyterian
                    Church, 33 by profession and 2 by certificate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Lyceum</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pierce</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Y. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Staunton Lyceum decided that liberty of the press ought to be
                    restricted in a Republican Government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Staunton Thespians</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Thespians will repeat their performance of "The Bride of Death."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Quiet City</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper boasts that Staunton is one of the "most orderly places in the
                    State" because everyone works and there "are no drones, of either color." Fires,
                    robberies, and fighting are all largely absent.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Firemen's Parade</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donovan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Toole</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Staunton Fire Company and the Fire Company of the Deaf, Dumb, and Blind
                    Institution paraded through Staunton joined by the Institution's band and a
                    chariot drawn by four bays from the stable of Donovan and O'Toole.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1868.05.06.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
