<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1868/va.au.vv.1868.08.12">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/09/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-08-12">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="">12</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1868.08.12.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1868.08.12.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Chesapeake and Ohio R. R.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that the Central Company is calling for contractors to
                    complete the road to White Sulphur Springs. "This shows energy and determination
                    to go through with this great work. Everything now rests upon Augusta's vote.
                    Vote for the subscription, and we have the grand through connection to the Ohio
                    and Pacific; our country will be filled with white emigrants, and no matter who
                    is elected or what party triumphs at the November election, we can control the
                    State!"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Educational Advantages of Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In one of our late papers we unintentionally drew an invidious distinction
                        between the school presided over by Mr. Harris and some others. We
                        cheerfully make the correction:</p>
                    <p>The Wesleyan Female Institute may be justly classed as one of the first
                        schools in Virginia or the South. It has just closed its 18th session with
                        unprecedented success. It is under the auspices of the Methodist Episcopal
                        Church, South. The Rev. Wm A. Harris, so widely celebrated throughout the
                        South as one of our most talented Educators, is President--assisted by a
                        full and able Faculty.</p>
                    <p>In the institution the course of study is high; the system of teaching being
                        largely by lecture, and like that pursued in our Virginia University.
                        Mathematics and Moral Philosophy are taught by Professor Harris; Physical
                        Sciences and Languages by a gentleman who has been educated in two of the
                        oldest colleges in Virginia. French is in the hands of a native of France
                        and a master of the language. Music is taught by Professor Hewitt, one of
                        the oldest and ablest composers and teachers of Music in the South. He is
                        assisted by a superior and accomplished vocalist. Other departments are
                        equally well filled by competent Professors and Teachers. Besides these
                        advantages, this school is a refined and happy home, in which the health,
                        comfort, morals and manners of pupils receive special attention. Its well
                        deserved popularity is indicated by the fact that the applications for
                        admission of pupils last session exceeded its accommodations. It was filled
                        with pupils from Virginia and various Southern States. It has a high class
                        of patrons, and a more refined and dignified class of young ladies we have
                        ever seen in any Institute.</p>
                    <p>Situated in a most delightful locality, the whole appearance of the buildings
                        denoting a beautiful summer retreat rather than a school; with a President
                        and a Faculty so justly celebrated, the future success--as has been the
                        past--of the Wesleyan Female Institute is an assured fact. We learn that
                        applications are already coming in, promising another full and promising
                        session.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article offers a corrective to a previous article that made
                    distinctions regarding the Wesleyan Female Institute and other local academies.
                    The Institute's administrators presumably considered these distinctions unfair.
                    Thus, the author heaps accolades upon Wesleyan that had been given to the
                    various other schools. Included is an enumeration of the several professors and
                    their specialties, a brief description of the school grounds, and the prediction
                    of the school's undoubted future success.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1868.08.12.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>City Council</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The City Council met and passed an ordinance forbidding cows to wear bells
                    from sun-down to sun-up. A pavement was ordered from the Baptist church to the
                    top of Gospil on Main Street.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Gas Works</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The late flood damaged the Gas Works by breaking pipes and filling them
                    with water.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Our Streets</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parrent</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eichelberger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hilb</ln>
                        <fn>S. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sergeant Parrent has ordered everyone to clean their gutters and remove
                    grass from the sidewalks. Dr. Eichelberger and S. H. Hilb are the only citizens
                    who have complied so far.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Night Police</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parrent</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Virginian agrees with the Vindicator in calling for night police, and
                    urges the council to give Sgt. Parrent two more assistants. "If we are a
                    city--let's be a city."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Corporation Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Diggs</ln>
                        <fn>Worthy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>A. A. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>James F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Several cases were tried in Staunton's Corporation Court. Three persons
                    indicted for keeping houses of ill fame were found not guilty. Worthy Diggs was
                    sentenced to three years in the penitentiary for grand larceny. The paper
                    praises A. A. W. Cochran, Attorney for the Corporation, for the many cases he
                    has won, and congratulates James F. Patterson, clerk of the court, for the work
                    he has done in his position for 20 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1868.08.12.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
