<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1868/va.au.vv.1868.05.13">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/08/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-05-13">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day norm="">13</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1868.05.13.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1868.05.13.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Canvass</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>S. Travis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Y. Howe</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that the campaign is heating up, and conservatives are
                    getting "good mad." "We respectfully notify all scalawags, deluded darkeys,
                    etc., that they can no longer run rough-shod over this State. They will be met
                    by men and we intend to beat them." Col. J. B. Baldwin, Col. B. Christian, S.
                    Travis Phillips, and Y. Howe Peyton are all addressing the people of Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Conservative Ticket</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It is with no common emotions that we place this ticket at our masthead. In
                        this crisis empty compliments and old worn out political clap-trap is
                        useless. The issues at stake are of too solemn and awful import--the ship is
                        too near running upon the breakers <emph rend="italic">for us,</emph> as a
                        people, to trifle with each other.</p>
                    <p>It was our good fortune, for it is a <emph rend="italic">fortune</emph> to
                        shake hands with honest men, to be present at the Conservative Convention.
                        In that body we did not see one who thought of self or had, what was once
                        known as "an axe to grind." To look at the mongrel crew assembled to
                        nominate Gen. Wells; to see what was done there--to become so disgusted that
                        any gentleman would inevitably get sick; and then to look at the Convention
                        of Virginia gentlemen assembled, in the Old Exchange--well, language fails
                        to express the feelings of a Southern man.</p>
                    <p>Col. Jno. B. Baldwin, the representative man of Old Augusta, was complimented
                        as we never saw a man or people complimented. He nobly declined the position
                        and Col. R.E. Withers was made our standard bearer.--Col. Withers did not
                        seek this position--it was forced upon him. He is a gentleman, an editor,
                        and a soldier. It would be idle to tell his people about him--ask the
                        soldier and he will tell you.</p>
                    <p>Gen. James Walker--"Stonewall Jim," we used to call him, is the candidate for
                        Lt. Governor. He is a man all over--the only Confederate Genl. Who inherited
                        the name of the immortal and God-inspired, T.J. Jackson. Mr. Mayre is the
                        man of his section. Col. Marmaduke Johnson will probably be up on our
                        section and speak for himself. He is "Candidate for the State at large to
                        Congress" and his heart is as large as the State.</p>
                    <p>In conclusion, if we have any influence with our people, we would urge upon
                        them, in all the sincerity of a heart that had never known a thought that
                        was not love for them and the South, to vote the ticket and <emph
                            rend="italic">vote down the Constitution.</emph> After that work is done
                        we can look into the next move the enemy makes against us. <emph
                            rend="italic">We repeat, vote the ticket and vote down the
                        Constitution.</emph>--That is the sum and substance of what is left for us
                        to do now and every man must stand up to the work, or we are irretrievably
                        and forever lost.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This is a typical plea to the Augusta County constituency to vote for
                    conservative candidates and to vote down the radical constitution. Most
                    important, caution is expressed. First, the author suggests, conservative men
                    who had served the South faithfully during the war must be put in office. At
                    this point, plans can be made on how to best counter the "enemy" radicals.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Few Good Hits at the Mongrels</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Lexington, Va.<lb/> May 7th, 1868</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">Dear Virginian</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>The State treasury being exhausted the Convention has adjourned. No longer
                        held together by the "cohesive power of public plunder," the body naturally
                        falls to pieces, and disintegration into its original obscure and repulsive
                        elements. The season for "carpet bags" is over! A glut in the market has
                        already ensued; and the Richmond merchants are now prepared to sell out the
                        entire stock at a heavy discount on prime cost. In the meantime the former
                        "pensioners on State bounty" yelped "carpet baggers" find, like Othello,
                        their occupation gone. It is to be hoped that they will go too, and
                        patriotically "leave Virginia for Virginia's good," which would probably be
                        the only act of patriotism any of them are capable of performing.--Butler
                        (the beast) compares himself to a dog--well, every dog has his day--but we
                        have too much respect for the canine race to admit the justice of his
                        comparison. His well known "hankering after spoons," and his visual and
                        moral obliquities would easily acquit him of any natural affinities with
                        dogs, except perhaps with those who have "rebelphobia," as Bill Arp would
                        express it. It must be admitted, however, that he does belong to the
                        carnivorous class of animals, but fortunately of a species "Sui Generis."</p>
                    <p>I you design publishing that issue of outrage politely denominated the
                        "Constitution of Virginia," it is respectfully suggested to have a few
                        copies carefully "bottled up" as specimens for our future State Museum, and
                        which, some years hence might be appropriately added to an American edition
                        of Disrael's "Curiosities of Literature." The verbatim diatribes of the
                        congo representatives would constitute another valuable contribution and
                        splendidly serve to illustrate the beauties of miscegenation as applied to
                        the English language. These last might be gotten up in the elegant modern
                        style of embellishment, and we have no doubt each of the ebony orators and
                        miscegenating "carpet baggers" would cheerfully furnish their photographs
                        (including that of the "Senogoper") for this purpose. The classic features
                        of the gentlemen from Africa, and the pure diction of their "eloquent"
                        harangues would show a "unity of design" little dreamed of by our benighted
                        forefathers; for now it is perfectly demonstrated that <lb/> "All partial
                        evil's universal good, <lb/> All discord, harmony not understood."</p>
                    <p>We dislike to hear these unique exponents of American civilization--these
                        ideal types of reconstructed union citizens so continually compared to apes
                        and baboons! In the name of the four handed fraternity we protest against so
                        grievous a wrong: for we are very sure that no anthropoid apes, or well
                        raised gorillas would have voluntarily assumed responsibilities so far
                        transcending their capacities; or, having assumed them, would have behaved
                        with such egregious folly, and it illustrates the truth: <lb/> "That fools
                        rush in where <emph rend="italic">monkeys</emph> fear to tread.<lb/> But
                        this is the age of humbug. "Viva la bagatelle."<lb/> Anon</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This particularly vicious article lambastes the Virginia Constitution.
                    Along with a harsh attack on General Benjamin Butler, the anonymous author
                    condemns the language of miscegenation, sarcastically referred to as "diatribes
                    of the congo representatives." In addition, the author compares blacks to apes
                    and baboons and claims they could never have consciously advocated for their own
                    rights as they are incapable of that level of thought.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper argues that only those who like "paying taxes" to "support negro
                    schools and office holders" will vote for the constitution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1868.05.13.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scheffer</ln>
                        <fn>Fred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Fred Scheffer has opened the Virginia Hotel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Supper</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The ladies of Staunton's Methodist Church will hold a supper in the town
                    hall on May 26th. The ladies of the Presbyterian Church will hold a fair there
                    on June 1st.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Personal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Confederate General D. H. Hill lectured before the Staunton Lyceum on
                    Monday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>P. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper touts the healing powers of the warm springs and announces that
                    Maj. P. H. Woodward will manage them.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tipping</ln>
                        <fn>Minnie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beall</ln>
                        <fn>D. Ed.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Minnie A. Tipping of Staunton and Dr. D. Ed Beall of Hampshire County,
                    West Virginia, were married on May 6th by the Rev. Mr. Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>William N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Poague</ln>
                        <fn>Mary V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William N. Wilson and Miss Mary V. Poague, both of Augusta, were married on
                    May 7th by the Rev. Frank Bowman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn>Claude Eugene</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn>Kate M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Claude Eugene Turner, son of Prof. A. J. and Kate M. Turner died on May
                    11th. He was 9 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ide</ln>
                        <fn>Ella Franklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ide</ln>
                        <fn>Annie Baldwin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ide</ln>
                        <fn>Louis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Ella Franklin Ide and Annie Baldwin Ide, daughters of Louis Ide, died on
                    May 4th. Ella was 8 and Annie 9 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ide</ln>
                        <fn>Estelle Sophie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ide</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Estelle Sophie Ide, daughter of Prof. L. Ide died on May 12th. She was 3
                    years old. "May the 'Lord temper the wind to the shorn Lambs.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1868.05.13.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
