<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1868/va.au.vv.1868.02.05">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/03/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-02-05">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day norm="">5</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1868.02.05.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Address of Dr. C. R. Harris, Delivered Before the Staunton Lyceum, January 24,
                    1868</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mr. President, gentlemen of the Staunton Lyceum, and respective auditory. The
                        subject which we propose to discuss is NATIONAL ADVERSITY; or an inquiry
                        into the effects, which will probably result from the present state of the
                        country. No one will evidently deny, that it is one of adversity.</p>
                    <p>The evidences meet us on every hand, and reiterate in our ears painful
                        truths, with which we are already too well acquainted, and which we would
                        fain drive from our minds. Reflecting men, too, seem to have settled down
                        under a melancholy consciousness that the sun of our prosperity has been
                        obscured, by clouds whose murkiness and gloom hang heavily around and about
                        us. It is not our purpose to swell the catalogue of evils: they are written
                        in the consciousness of every heart and meet the gaze of every eye. To
                        inquire into the details of the various causes, both proximate and remote,
                        is not our purpose now. Leaving, then, the causes of our present unfortunate
                        condition to shift for themselves, the interesting and important inquiry is:
                        What is to come next, and what are the probable results.</p>
                    <p>Are there still deeper depths into which we are to be plunged? And are our
                        days of mourning and despondency, long to continue? Watchman what of the
                        night!</p>
                    <p>Guided, we think, by the quality and comparison of our calm reflective hours,
                        but perhaps allured by the deceptive whispering of Hope, we have arrived at
                        the conclusion: "The morning cometh"; and that although there may be darker
                        scenes still to pass through, yet, the nature of the effects which are to
                        follow our present adverse circumstances may ultimately be beneficial.</p>
                    <p>I trust, my friends, you will not startle at the seeming Paradox. We are all
                        well aware that the coming attendants of the times, do not well accord with
                        the figure which we shall picture to ourselves, perhaps, of our future
                        national well being. But, let us remember that he who contents himself with
                        reading the first pages in the book of adversity, will find nothing written
                        there but tales of sorrow and distress; of baffled projects, blighted hopes,
                        ruined fortunes and broken hearts. - But let us pass on to other leaves and
                        pages, and we will find, perhaps, pleasant, cheerful stories, growing more
                        cheerful and pleasant, as we advanced, which will make us forgetful of the
                        woeful past, and teach us, though we "have sown in tears" may we yet reap in
                        joy!</p>
                    <p>However much we may regret the difficulties which environ us, as a nation,
                        and however much we may wish they had never been, yet since they are here,
                        if we will look hopefully into the future, we may ere long come to the
                        belief that the declaration of Holy writ "blessed are they that mourn for
                        they shall be comforted," is true in more respects than one, and is, as well
                        the sentiment of Philosophy and Christianity.</p>
                    <p>Strong is the belief of this sentiment, we proceed to specify some of the
                        benefits which result form National Adversity in general, the particulars
                        whereof to our own country and times, will naturally occur to our minds,
                        and, consequently, need not be specially noted. The first beneficial result
                        which we shall notice, is the expulsion of some of the evils engendered by
                        long prosperity. What are those evils?</p>
                    <p>A little thought will show us, that of the people that compose a nation, some
                        catch the spirit like unto that of the man in the scriptures, who "said,
                        "soul thou hast goods laid up for many years, take thine ease and be merry,"
                        others who continuing in the walks" of business become inflated with vanity
                        and pride, indulging in showy pomp, and ridiculous extravagance. Others
                        become profligate, licentious and corrupt. Others make a trade of filling
                        their pockets from those of the vain and luxurious, and become narrow
                        minded, avaricious and miserly. Indeed where the series of prosperous years
                        are long continued (as was, for instance, in one period of ancient Rome)
                        society becomes divided into scarcely more than two classes: the luxurious
                        and corrupt on the one hand, and the narrow-hearted and avaricious on the
                        other.</p>
                    <p>Under such a state of things selfishness assumes almost universal sway.
                        Philanthropy and Patriotism are banished, (a condition more to be dreaded
                        than any we can well imagine,) and one, too, in which free institutions must
                        perish. Now if such a period arrives, and a nation becomes impoverished by
                        adversity, or rather if her superfluities are thus retrenched, the evils we
                        have enumerated will be, in a measure, greatly removed and their baneful
                        consequences prevented. Nor does the benefit stop here. The people learn to
                        practice their humbler virtues they before despised - Parents educate their
                        children more for usefulness than for show - there is a return to habits of
                        industry, frugality and economy, living within ones means - constant
                        activity - cheerful labor and untiring perseverance. The result is, things
                        begin to brighten - every day adds to the little store of comforts and
                        consolations, and, as years shall roll on, those who were, in a measure,
                        overshadowed by the darkness of night, are cheered by the brightness of
                        morning, and ultimately in the full sunlight of peace and plenty, they will
                        arrive at the sensible conclusion that, by the aid of a good and kind
                        Providence, which He will extend unto all, there may be many a Job, "more
                        blessed in his latter end, than in the beginning."</p>
                    <p>It will easily be perceived that, where the individuals of a State or a
                        Nation, (under the influence of what are called the humbler, yet nobler
                        virtues) must advance steadily on until they obtain a comfortable and
                        substantial - though not a showing and gorgeous wealth. In the same ratio,
                        too, must the nation itself advance to a high rank amongst the Empires of
                        the earth.</p>
                    <p>With these recollections still on our minds, let us glance, by way of a
                        pleasant and proud retrospect, at the courage, endurance, industry,
                        frugality, and other virtues of those noble men whose posterity we are; and
                        of whom we are so proud, and we will cease to be surprised at the high rank
                        which we had once attained as a nation. We too plainly see now that if the
                        virtues of a noble ancestry, could have been entailed upon their children,
                        without the possibility of sectional alienation, there would have been no
                        limit prescribed to our national strength and greatness. But we need not
                        stop with our own country, if we wish to discover how the humble, but
                        sterling virtues have accompanied the rise and growth of all nations, and
                        the showy but degrading vices, their decline and fall. History teems with
                        illustrative examples, all serving to establish the truth of the opinion set
                        forth, that the strength of a nation consists not so much in its possessions
                        and pecuniary resources, as in its spirit, truth, and virtue of its members.
                        If <emph rend="italic">these</emph>, from the natural tendency of man's
                        nature to be lulled to sleep, or to become corrupted by the existence of
                        great prosperity have been banished, <emph rend="italic">that influence is
                            partially</emph> beneficial in an eminent degree, which recalls them
                        from their exile and gives them a place in the hearts of the people.</p>
                    <p>To illustrate the inefficiency of mere forms of government without virtue or
                        morality, we must look for a moment at the history of the first French
                        Revolution. Henry the IV, declared publicly that he held himself amenable to
                        tow sovereigns, "God and the Laws," but the French people began their
                        reforms by renouncing allegiance to both. Their spirit of resistance, was
                        tempered with no spirit of either religion or morality. They scorned the
                        natural and devout reliance, common even among more barbarous nations - upon
                        the God of battles. Clubs were formed in every part of the Empire, for the
                        propagation and enforcement of atheism. Twenty thousand men were employed of
                        great literary distinction, in exterminating all sense of moral obligation,
                        and every sentiment of private and public virtue. They proceeded throughout,
                        upon the principle that Christianity and Republicanism could not subsist
                        together.--The whole Government renounced the allegiance to Heaven, and
                        established impiety by law. They had their theory of national rights and
                        more absurd than all, a national oath, (very common in this, our day,) to be
                        renewed every 4th year, differing, however, from a portion of this, our
                        nation, in the fact that we are required to take 4 and 20 oaths every year.
                        They adopted a new calendar, also to be renewed every 4th year, and the
                        motto, "live free or die," instead of the precious liberty awarded to us in
                        this, our day, that is, "to eat if we have it, pay taxes and die."</p>
                    <p>The world stood aghast at such a bold and shameless desecration of everything
                        pure, venerable and holy. Those who managed the vessel of State, threw chart
                        and compass over board, and madly put out on the sea of revolution. They had
                        hailed the rising sun of liberty with joy; but when the ocean swelled and
                        the air darkened, with what terror did they behold his blood red disc, climb
                        a sky black with tempest, and sounding with loud thunders from side to side.
                        And thus the French Republic, drunk with blood, vomited forth crime, and
                        staggered on under a load of misery and sin towards the gulf of a military
                        despotism. Anarchy, always impatient for a tyrant, there was a brief and
                        fearful pause, when lo! girt about with darkness and clad in complete steel,
                        a stern and solitary figure, the offspring and very image of the times, rose
                        on the highest wave of Revolution, with the Imperial Eagle in his hand. The
                        Tribune hailed him as the very head of the nation. The Senate entreated him
                        to accept the people, the army followed and laud the glory of a thousand
                        victories at his feet, whilst the people shouted, <emph rend="italic">Vive
                            la Emperor Napoleon!"</emph></p>
                    <p>Another advantage arising from our national adversity is that our people may
                        learn political wisdom. In the halcyon of fair weather days of prosperity,
                        everything moves on with so much harmony (and with so much monotony too),
                        the events of the day differing from those of yesterday; only in being of
                        brighter hue, that from day to day we read from the same lesson, from the
                        Book of experience; and consequently remain comparatively ignorant of the
                        things which make for a nation's peace and prosperity. Political theories
                        are formed beautiful as dreams and of equally as light fantastic stuff, and
                        when applied to the operations of Government seem to work well, because
                        other influences continue prosperity, in spite of such make-weights and
                        draw-backs. But when the storm of severity comes; political opinions and
                        theories are put to the test, and according as they have proved true or
                        false, the people will reject them.</p>
                    <p>But not only do we learn in adversity to distinguish between true and false
                        theories, we also become expert in the use and application of true political
                        science, and are thus prepared to meet future difficulties as they arise, or
                        foresee, and avoid them. How would the mariner be skillful in navigation if
                        he had never been in a storm? or the pilot know how to avoid the shoals and
                        sandbanks, and rocks, which may beset his way, if he has never been among
                        them; and knew not what they were. Another benefit from national adversity
                        is that Demagogues, the scurges of all Republics, are unasked. Who has not
                        seen in prosperous times and (as we do now,) a class of men who flatter,
                        cajole and excite the people both black and white; merely for the purpose of
                        self aggrandizement, who try to worm themselves into the community and
                        thence into office and high places, where they may feed upon the public
                        crib, and bask on the sunshine popular and Executive favor.</p>
                    <p>Now in the times of adversity the people, awakened by the peril and dangers
                        which surround them, discover, though ever so much disguised by midnight
                        conclaves, or Union Leagues with their sable brethren, the artifices of
                        those demagogues, to humiliate and degrade their own anglo saxon race, to
                        elevate the poor African, and for whom they now express so much love and
                        sympathy, and the result is these gentlemen, some of them to the manor born,
                        will be known to the future and have permission to retire to a well deserved
                        solitude. On the other hand when adversity threatens a country with serious
                        danger, either from without or within, great characters are thrown into
                        relief, as the edifices which are concealed by the darkness and gloom of
                        night, are illuminated by the glare of a conflagration. In dangerous times
                        genius no longer refrains from presenting itself in the arena and the people
                        alarmed by the perils of their situation bury all jealousies, party spirit
                        and envious passions, and great and good men, are, then drawn from the "urn
                        of election."</p>
                    <p>And what a blessing, too, adversity is in weakening the force of local
                        interests, conflicting party spirit and opinions, and discordant passions?
                        Prosperity engenders, my friends, many bad feelings in the hearts of men.
                        They become proud, self-reliant, envious, jealous, and consequently soon
                        learn to contend about mere trifles, and quarrel upon the slightest
                        provocation. It is not difficult, either, to see how the same feelings may
                        exist in different portions of a State or country, as well as among
                        individuals. But when adversity comes, all trifles, selfish considerations,
                        and local interests are forgotten in the <del/> of a common woe, and a
                        common enemy. </p>
                    <p> Bones of contention are then thrown aside, and the very sections of country
                        between which there existed so much division, discord, hatred and jealousy,
                        influenced by a sense of common danger or by sympathies excited by mutuality
                        of sufferings, become linked together in strong fraternal bonds. There is
                        another benefit resulting from <emph rend="italic">National</emph> adversity
                        which some may think more imaginary than real, but which we deem of more
                        importance than say we have enumerated; we mean its tendency to recall the
                        wandering mind of man and to fix his attention and affections, upon <emph
                            rend="italic">the Supreme Ruler of the Universe,</emph> and this on the
                        well reorganized principle that, though "no chastisement for the present" is
                        joyous, but grievous, yet if the subject is properly exercised thereby, it
                        yieldeth the peaceable fruits of righteousness, and he is therefore
                        naturally led to the resolution, "I will arise and go to my Father."</p>
                    <p>Nations, as well as individuals, during great prosperity, become vain and
                        ungrateful, and wrap themselves in robes of fancied security, and a kind of
                        independent <emph rend="italic">self importance.</emph> Leaning confidently
                        upon the comparatively frail support of fleets and armies, and other
                        contingencies of national defense; they forget the Power on High whose word
                        the strength of serried hosts are shivered, and the "skeletons of thousands
                        left" to rot on the battle field, and by whose <emph rend="italic">command
                            the storms of Ocean,</emph> gather, and the dwellers upon the Sea are
                        wrecked and left to sleep beneath the waves. National calamity, by
                        humiliating their pride and self sufficiency and convincing them of their
                        wants, and comparative nothingness, destroys this, and thereby secures the
                        favor and smiles of Heaven. The causes which from danger produce safety, and
                        from trouble rest, are then put in motion--the storm passes over--the clouds
                        vanish, and then all hearts are filled with gratitude and love.
                        <lb/>Convinced That Heaven but tries their virtue by affliction <lb/>That
                        oft, the clouds which wrapt the present hour <lb/> Seem but to brighten, all
                        their future days.</p>
                    <p>In our national adversity we have learned, too, that political power whether
                        obtained usurpation (and we might say suffrage), accompanied with a total
                        subversion of the principles of a Constitutional government, never willingly
                        surrenders any portion of its vested rights. If it ever, innovate on
                        precedent, or wanders from the beaten path of constitutional liberty, it is
                        to gather to itself, not to scatter abroad, among the people, and to
                        construct new defenses against popular inroads. All its concessions to human
                        rights, will be reluctantly yielded by its fears, or forcibly wrung from its
                        grasp by the Red hand of Revolution.</p>
                    <p>We see, in its God of Ethics, a diplomacy, inculcated and refined, into a
                        system, it exonerates itself by a species of mental casuistry, from the
                        eternal principles <emph rend="italic">in</emph> justice and morality which
                        implies that the moral sense should not be consulted, in the administration
                        of the affairs of the Nation, and that "all is fair in politics," and "that
                        the end justifies the means." Hence we have the dissemination; perfidy,
                        fraud, and circumvention, infractions of constitutional law, resumptions in
                        the hour of strength, of conceded rights made with conquered party in the
                        hour of its weakness and violation of faith, plighted to its own citizens.
                        It assumes therefore that its members are amenable to the moral code, in
                        their individual but not their collective capacity, which involves an
                        absurdity as great as that would be--were we to assert of gravitation, that
                        it is true of atoms, but its principles are not applicable to worlds. It is
                        a work of supererogation to dwell, my friends, upon a doctrine as
                        demoralizing in its tendency as it is defective and illogical in theory. It
                        is in part to the application of this obnoxious principle that we are
                        indebted to the prevalence of injustice and oppression, and the attendant
                        evils which we are now afflicted, as a people. Under its pernicious
                        influences, earth has been converted into one great slaughterhouse and man
                        debased at once into Tyrant, Executioner and Victim!</p>
                    <p>Our national calamity, therefore, must and will learn us to appreciate the
                        intricate and eternal beauty of virtue and <emph rend="italic">moral
                            rectitude in governments</emph> as well as individuals, its laws possess
                            <emph rend="italic">the</emph> same coherence, and consistency which
                        exists in those that regulate the material universe. And yet, while discord
                        is a prime agent in the affairs of human government, the starry worlds still
                        revolve harmoniously in their orbits, chiming the praises, and vindicating
                        the wisdom of their Almighty architect. It is true these glorious orbs are
                        inanimate, free agency the precious attribute, and chief distinction of man
                        is withheld from them, and that they, from necessity, conform to the
                        original laws of their creator. But let us suppose for example that they are
                        suddenly endowed with consciousness, and with volition, that availing
                        themselves of their novel privilege they shout madly from their spheres, and
                        range at will through the illimitable space of other--what confusion would
                        presently ensue; what jostling of planet against planet; what infringing of
                        sun against sun; what running of system into system; what war of elements,
                        what wreck of matter, and what a crash of worlds! <emph rend="italic"
                        >Chaos</emph> indeed would have come again, and the plastic hand of the
                        Almighty would be required to remould them into form--to place them in their
                        original and appropriate position, to re attune the broken harmony, and to
                        strike again, the best music of the spheres. Such is the order which exists
                        among the Heavenly bodies, and such the ruin which would be produced by a
                        departure from the essential condition of their existence. Striking
                        examples, but alas! Too true of the actual condition and relations which now
                        exists, between the centripetal and centrifugal forces, which once
                        controlled a glorious and grand confederacy of co equal and independent
                        Sovereign States. In recounting some of the important results of national
                        adversity, which may seem marvelous at the first blush, yet there is nothing
                        to them particular or strange! They are governed by the same laws, bearing a
                        direct analogy on many others. Pursuing a train of thought suggested by our
                        subject, we may add that our own country, perhaps, which had reached the
                        very highest grade of prosperity, is now under the operation of <emph
                            rend="italic">Divine Providence,</emph> suffering the amputation of its
                        morbid excrescences, for the salvation of its health, and its national
                        existence. For the waters of the swollen stream are turbid; but if
                        diminished, they become pure and pellucid. The excision of redundant limbs
                        and branches, may, for a time, <emph rend="italic">mar the beauty</emph> of
                        the tree, yet it will give strength, vigor, and beauty to the remaining
                        boughs, and so of other exhibitions--profusely scattered throughout the
                        kingdom of nature, and known and read by all men. It is true our country has
                        lost millions of its wealth and much of its alluring splendor, but we trust
                        it will save and preserve its dignity, its <emph rend="italic">morals and
                            its virtue.</emph> Many who made haste to be rich over the blood and
                        suffering of their country during our late struggle may become poor,
                        property may be reduced to a fair estimate, and many things which we may
                        think of vast importance, may be swept away, but let them all go,--so
                        integrity, virtue and industry prevail, and all that is inestimable in our
                        favored and lovely country, survive the wreck; we shall emerge like silver
                        and gold when tried in the fiery furnace; or like rocks embedded in our
                        native hills and mountains, purified by <emph rend="italic">fire and
                            solidified</emph> by pressure. It is encouraging to know that there are
                        many things, even amid our adversity as a people, which are operating with
                        great power on the social and individual happiness of man. We live in the
                        midst of an age which may be emphatically styled one of <emph rend="italic"
                            >Free inquiry, and which</emph> is pre-eminently progressive. Under its
                        guidance the brilliant achievement in Demonstrative Science, in inductive
                        philosophy, and in the fine arts, are daily adding to our comforts, and
                        working important changes in every condition of society. And no where is
                            <emph rend="italic">it more conspicuously displayed</emph> than in the
                        varied branches of Medical Science. In Surgery, in Physiology, (true basis
                        of rational medicine) in Hygiene, which in the treatment of disease has
                        become one of the great medical facts of the day) besides its beneficial
                        effects on true philosophy of food and the laws for the preservation of
                        health.</p>
                    <p>In Botany and Zoology, by which plants and animals, both aquatic and terrene,
                        are named and classified, their structure delineated, their habits
                        described, and their properties and uses made known. In chemistry, which is
                        daily conducing as much to the health and comfort of man, decomposing the
                        forms, and disembodying the essence of things, recombining them in different
                        proportions; thereby producing results the most brilliant and useful. In the
                        fine arts, too, do we see it moving steadily onward, and its plastic powers
                        are no where more conspicuously displayed, than in the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Science of Music,</emph> which draws forth and appropriates the harmony
                        of nature; fixing and characterizing them in their varied, new and exquisite
                        combinations, which takes the "prisoned soul and laps it in elysium."</p>
                    <p>We see it moulding with increasing perfection, the lifeless inexpressible
                        marble, with its solidity and ragged excrescences and polished lifelike into
                        almost breathing forms. We see it guiding the pencil of the painter in
                        producing the grandest and noblest specimens of the pictorial art; and in
                        the science of Photography transmitting to posterity the likeness of eminent
                        Statesmen. Christians and Warriors, who have illustrated and adorned the age
                        in which they lived, and portraying to the gate of bereaved survivors,
                        faithful likenesses of the living, the loved and the lost.</p>
                    <p>We see it as penetrating the bowels of the earth and extracting its mineral
                        and metallic wealth, examining its varied stratifications; reading the
                        hieroglyphic characters thereon inscribed, and learning its true history.
                        The knowledge of Geology is enlightening the farmer, too, by tending to
                        lighten his labors, instructing him to the nature and property of soils,
                        (and trenching somewhat on a kindred science) teaches him the process by
                        which fertility may be reclaimed from exhaustion.</p>
                    <p>Recent, as is the science of Geology, (comparatively speaking,) its
                        discoveries have already rendered and are daily affording incalculable
                        results to the agriculturalist, and with a brighter and still larger field
                        before it, it will go adding to the physical comforts, the social
                        advancement, and the regeneration of man.</p>
                    <p>From a political stand point, too, we see this <emph rend="italic">spirit of
                            free inquiry,</emph> with argus eyes, arising, from the low and bending
                        posture in which it formerly crouched under military rule. Springing to its
                        natural and upright attitude and without embarrassment, aye, with a proud
                        confidence, it will ere long confront tyranny on its throne, and under the
                        guidance and prestige of the great Conservative Constitutional Union party
                        of the country, the turrets and towers of absolutism and monarchy will
                        topple to destruction, when the giant man shall arise from his slumbers, and
                        hurl to the dust those vulgar great, yet pigmy tyrants, who now claim to
                        rule us--ten States of the Union by sort of divine right. Yes, the great
                        Conservative party from the ice bound shores of Maine to the golden villas
                        and snow capped mountains of <emph rend="italic">California,</emph> is
                        swelling with the amplitude, and deepening with the <sic>profoundity</sic>
                        of its vast conceptions, emulating the blast of the trumpet, startling its
                        thousands and millions from repose, on the eve of a worlds winning battle.</p>
                    <p>Let us trust that it is the pioneer of a more enlightened civilization, than
                        has yet been seen in the dreams of mere <sic>phylosophy.</sic> That it is
                        destined by Providence, to be the harbinger of a state of things, as yet
                        unprecedented upon the earth. The morning star burning with
                        <unclear>pencil</unclear> beauty, or the brow of a glorious political
                            <sic>millenium;</sic> that in the fullness of time it will usher in the
                        commencement of that era, when the war announcing trumpet shall be heard no
                        more, when peace shall gather the entire family of man under the shadow of
                        her wing; when as individuals and as a nation, rectitude in thought and
                        deed, shall be an aim and attainment, and not only an abstract reality, but
                        an universal presence. Let us then remember even amidst the dark desolations
                        of the hour that <lb/>"The gloomiest day hath gleams of light, <lb/>The
                        darkest wave, hath bright foam near it; <lb/> And twinkles through the
                        cloudiest night, <lb/> One <emph rend="italic">solitary star to cheer
                        it."</emph></p>
                    <p>Amid our national adversity, my friends, a love of liberty and of country is
                        an indigenous principle with our people, as the evergreen is to our native
                        hills and mountains. It is here where the stars of Heaven first shone upon
                        us; where the lightening first declared His omnipotence, and the storm winds
                        shook our souls with awe. Here are all our affections. Here is our country.
                        The bones of our beloved ancestors sleep here, and those of the dear ones
                        that fell in our "Lost Cause." It is here where the first human eye bent
                        lovingly over cradle; where our mother first bore us joyfully on her bosom;
                        where our fathers engraved words of wisdom on our young hearts. Here are all
                        our affections then. Here is our country. <lb/> And though it were a
                        desert--yet <lb/> Dear, to our hearts this spot shall prove <lb/> Our home;
                        we never can'st forget <lb/> Our country never cease to love. <lb/> And
                        wheresoever our steps may roam,<lb/> As restive wanderers o'er the earth;
                        <lb/> With love, our bosoms still shall burn,<lb/> For this dear land that
                        gave us birth; <lb/> For wherever else, our steps may roam, <lb/> This is
                        our country--this is our home. </p>
                    <p>But when we unroll, my friends, the scroll of time, and open the pages of
                        Virginia's history, the heart almost sinks with sadness, at the
                        reflection:--What Virginia was, and what she now is. Upon every page of the
                        annals which record the greatness and power of America, she stands
                        preeminent above all her sister States. Her fame is eternal. The eternal
                        sunshine of her greatness outdazzle the splendor of the gorgeous mausoleum.
                        As the mother of States and Statesmen, she stands solitary in the grandeur
                        of her achievements, in war, in peace, in the science of government, and in
                        fundamental law. It would be vain to attempt to take from her, one atom of
                        her greatness. It has passed into history, and is interwoven with the rise,
                        progress and decline of constitutional liberty.</p>
                    <p>But look upon that picture, and now upon this. With the ascendancy of
                        Radicalism, by military rule, her constitution is to be ignored, passion
                        substituted for reason, guaranteed rights immunities (as old and
                        cotemporaneous with out forms of government,) are to be swept away before
                        the progressive tide of isms. Outrage has succeeded outrage, in rapid
                        succession, until now, Virginia is a territorial dependency, her territory
                        dismembered, a mere military satrapy, (according to Radical logic and
                        legislation,) and in the same Hall, where in 1829-'30, James Monroe,
                        President of the Convention, James Madison, the author of the Federal
                        Constitution, John Marshall, its great expounder, Lyttleton Tazewell, John
                        Randolph, Briscoe G. Baldwin, Robt. Stanard, John Tyler, Phillip Doddridge,
                        John S. Barbour, Phillip Barbour, and others, no less distinguished, who
                        have rolled down their brilliant pathway to the tomb, and lent their aid and
                        experiences in the cause of good government, is now occupied by ignorant
                        blacks, and blackhearted whites, to undo the great work of these great men,
                        and make for Virginia an organic law!! Whilst the heart sickens in
                        contemplating the contrast, and the brain reels and staggers at the awful
                        spectacle, we are yet cheered with the pleasing reflection, that "there is
                        life in the old land yet."</p>
                    <p>The recent Conservative Convention, of over 1000 Virginia gentlemen, which
                        met in Richmond, representing the intellect, and Virtue of the State, with
                        the dignity, decorum, and practical statesmanship of their deliberations,
                        remind us, that our soil is still the abode of greatness; and the time is
                        not far distant, when their counsels and sentiments must prevail, and the
                        country restored to the influence of the spirit which animated a noble
                        ancestry. For their is a salient, plastic, living principle in our people
                        yet, and <lb/> Our land, the first garden of Liberty's tree,<lb/>It has
                        been, and it shall be, the land of the free. </p>
                    <p>And, what, though misfortune for a time, my friends, has cast clouds of
                        sorrow over our pathway; what though the merry laugh of joy and prosperity
                        may now and then find its echo in the mournful cry of sadness, and although
                        this tide of misfortune like the mighty Ocean's waves, has risen and swept
                        <del/> over us, we are not conquered yet; our spirits are still free. This
                        beautiful world still moves on, which requires no tongue to give
                        intelligibility to its meaning. For there is a language in the stars. There
                        is a voice in the night wind, and in the trumpet blowing cataract, and in
                        the mighty silence of limitless space.</p>
                    <p>Let us then take courage and dash the blighting spray aside and like a goodly
                        gallant bark, without a started <unclear>seam</unclear> or a riven sail,
                        we'll breast the novel tempest of time and chance.</p>
                    <p>For there is a beacon star which still shines with undiminished lustre,
                        whispering in our ears a charm so full of joy, that life seems so new--that
                        danger is forgotten, while sorrow flies before its inspiration--for there is
                        an Heavenly spirit which still beacons us onward. And Lo! high over the
                        ramparts of the wished for <emph rend="italic">goal,</emph> our flaunting
                        flag, is given to the <sic>breese,</sic> when we behold the talismanic words
                        in living characters of fire upon it--<emph rend="italic">Hope and
                            Persevere.</emph> If I were called upon to name the emotion of the human
                        mind, which is most sufficient in its influence upon mankind--which suggests
                        the grandest enterprises, and which supports us under the most trying
                        reverses, I am certain that I should only be anticipating the judgment of my
                        intelligent auditory in pronouncing <emph rend="italic">Hope,</emph> to be
                            <emph rend="italic">that feeling.</emph> The earliest visions of
                        childhood are tinged with its golden hues, and the reveries of the boy and
                        the man are filled with gorgeous palaces, and regions of delight, which it
                        can build. It animates the school boy and girl at their tasks; it emboldens
                        the soldier on the battlefield; it nerves the sailor against the perils of
                        the sea; it gives light and strength to the patriot in his struggles for his
                        country's good. It achieved the splendid results in the discovery of
                        America, by Columbus and his little band, and though the mountain billows of
                        the Atlantic rose up before them; and amid the laughs and scoffs of the
                        witty, and the lamentations of the loving, it led them on--they were guided
                        by it until they rested from their labors, doubts and fears upon the borders
                        of a new and noble continent. Though in results less splendid than these, we
                        find it in the every day affairs of life, supporting the weak, encouraging
                        the strong, and beckoning on the prosperous to more varied fields of
                        usefulness and renown. We see it sitting beside the mother in cradle
                        infancy, while she winds the laurel wreath around the brow of her loved
                        infant, teaching her to love not only that which is, but will be--when
                        weakness puts on strength and walks; when knowledge has brought its
                        treasures, and, when wealth fame and honor shall attend its steps. It stands
                        by the man of business in his daily toils; it mounts with the statesman up
                        the steps of office. It lies down, with the poor and rich on the bed of
                        anguish, and accompanies the Physician in the sick chamber; it walks with
                        the strong upon the path of vigor, and there are none so poor as to live
                        without its companionship, and none so high as to not need its help.</p>
                    <p>Finally, my friends, if tears shall water our course, may old Time, as he
                        flies along, with a single flap of his broad wing, dry them all up. And may
                        the bright visions of the future cause us all to doff the garb of sorrow,
                        whilst the troubles of to-day may melt if like noxious vapors, 'neath the
                        genial sun of Fortune, and disclose the sweetest imageries of life; whilst
                        the dim vista of coming years, shall cause each heart to leap for joy.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Harris's long-winded and often-ponderous speech brings adversity to the
                    forefront and asks: what will happen next? Rhetorically suggesting that
                    adversity could possibly plunge Virginia into even deeper despair, he
                    nevertheless optimistically looks to the future. Among detailed declarations of
                    noble virtues indicative of the southern "anglo saxon," Harris enumerates the
                    evils and wrongdoings of the tyrannical Radical party, "Negro rule," etc. Only
                    with the expulsion of this element, he argues, can Virginia once again take its
                    place among states and resume the path to prosperity.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1868.02.05.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper agrees with the Philadelphia News's assertion that if Congress
                    would end its "crusade" against the South, the section would be open for
                    profitable northern investments. "The people of Virginia, and, indeed, of all
                    the Southern States, are extremely anxious for Northern men to settle among
                    them."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"A Farmer" writes in support of the proposed $300,000 county subscription
                    to the stock of the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad. He argues that only $2 a farm
                    would raise the money, and the increase in the price of farm goods following
                    introduction of the railroad would make up for it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Political Status</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following is an extract from a private letter, from the pen of one of our
                        gifted townsmen, to a friend in the Great West. He says:</p>
                    <p>The radicals in Congress have so shaped legislation as to destroy all hope of
                        an amicable adjustment of the vexed question of reconstruction, and
                        consequently everything is in an unsettled condition. There is no capital in
                        the South to invest in enterprises calculated to increase the prosperity and
                        develop the vast resources of the country, and Northern capital is afraid to
                        come here,-- in consequence, every material interest languishes, and the
                        people are compelled to plod along the best way they can.</p>
                    <p>By the simple edict of a single man, (Gen. Schofield), the legislature of our
                        State has been prevented from assembling, and of course the best interests
                        of the State must suffer.--Instead of the representatives of the people
                        occupying the legislative halls at Richmond, legislating for the
                        encouragement of immigration and the development of our untold resources, we
                        have a set of mongrels and political quacks, working like beavers for the
                        promotion of their own selfish ends and the advancement of party purposes.
                        They have voted themselves eight dollars a day, and, vampire like, are
                        sucking the life blood of the State. Of course they have no idea of
                        adjourning as long as there remains a dollar in the treasury. Not the first
                        practical step has as yet been taken towards the formation of a
                        constitution, and the radicals themselves are becoming very restive at the
                        impracticability of this body. The fact is, the convention is destitute of
                        brains, and without brains nothing good can be accomplished. There is
                        something radically wrong when slaves are suddenly transformed from serfdom
                        into legislators, and from being the hewers of wood and drawers of water,
                        into rulers and representatives of a free and enlightened people. Such a
                        State of affairs cannot last long. A change for the better or worse must
                        inevitably take place, and that too before many more years are added to the
                        cycle of time. Never before in the world's history has such a monstrosity
                        been perpetrated or attempted, and it cannot succeed. The people will rise
                        up and put down the party that now attempts to rule the country at the
                        sacrifice of its dearest interests, and when the storm of opposition is once
                        fairly started, woe be unto those who may attempt to oppose its onward
                        march. It will sweep the country from one end to the other, and those who
                        may have been instrumental in raising the storm will be hurled into
                        oblivion.</p>
                    <p>It is hoped that a returning sense of reason on the part of the people of the
                        North, will see this injustice and wrongs that have been visited on the ten
                        "unreconstructed" States, and the danger they are in of losing their own
                        liberties, if a check is not speedily put to the career of those destroyers
                        of the people's liberty, and at once rally to our support and
                    encouragement.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article succinctly articulates many of the issues at hand concerning
                    the opposition to radical reconstruction. Along with the problem of the lack of
                    capital and lack of northern investors, the author vehemently attacks "mongrels
                    and political quacks" currently framing the new constitution. Most
                    significantly, this article rejects any notion that former slaves are in any way
                    capable of effectively legislating. The author gets right to the point by
                    stating simply that the Radicals are "destroyers of people's liberties."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1868.02.05.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Lutheran Visitor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper praises the Lutheran Visitor, a monthly magazine edited by the
                    Rev. J. I. Miller of Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Staunton Lyceum</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fauntleroy</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Y. Howe</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powers</ln>
                        <fn>Pike</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pierce</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Staunton Lyceum discussed whether the goodness of God can be revealed
                    without the aid of Revelation. Dr. A. M. Fauntleroy will lecture at the Lyceum
                    next Friday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Virginia Express Company</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Virginia Express Company has extended lines throughout the Valley and
                    can ship goods anywhere between Salem and Harper's Ferry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The White Sulphur</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>George L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George L. Peyton will open the White Sulphur Springs in the early spring.
                    Repairs are now in progress. The paper declares that it was always good luck
                    when the Democratic Party caucused there, and hopes they will do so again.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dogget</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Bishop</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>Lucy J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>John L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Bishop Dogget of the Episcopal Methodist Church preached in Staunton's
                    Methodist Church, including the funeral sermon of Mrs. Lucy J. Clarke, wife of
                    the Rev. pastor John L. Clarke. His text was, "If a man die, shall he live
                    again?" He also expounded on the Christian virtues of Mrs. Clarke. In the
                    evening he preached on Paul's imprisonment and appearance before Felix.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Sibert's Iron and Steel Patent</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Perkins</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nelson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibert</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The foundry of Perkins, Nelson and Company cast two eight to ten pound
                    railroad tires according to Sibert's new steel process. Once they are turned in
                    a lathe and dressed, they will be sent on to Richmond for testing on the
                    Virginia Central Railroad. "The success of the new process of making steel from
                    an ordinary blast furnace, will soon be felt throughout the length and breadth
                    of our land. So important a discovery cannot long be confined to one or two
                    localities. The spirit if the age and the necessities of man require that it
                    should be brought to light, and applied to every department of industry." The
                    new process is faster than Bessemer's. "Parties from the North who have been on
                    to examine the merit of this invention have expressed themselves as satisfied
                    and delighted. We learn that Messrs. Sibert and Peyton have had several large
                    offers for the right of manufacture in several of the States, but for the
                    present have declined."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Andrew</ln>
                        <fn>Nelson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Earhart</ln>
                        <fn>Christiana S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Earhart</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Nelson Andrew and Miss Christiana S. Earhart, daughter of John Earhart,
                    were married at the house of the bride's father near Sangersville by the Rev.
                    John Pinkerton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cupp</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Staubus</ln>
                        <fn>Ellen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Staubus</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Frederick Cupp and Miss Ellen Staubus, daughter of Jacob Staubus, were
                    married on January 30th at the residence of the bride's father by the Rev. John
                    Pinkerton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>Harriet E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John H. Jones and Miss Harriet E. Price, both of Augusta, were married near
                    Staunton on January 30th by the Rev. J. I. Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cross</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burns</ln>
                        <fn>Winnie Matilda</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neel</ln>
                        <fn>A. A. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas H. Cross and Miss Winnie Matilda Burns, both of Augusta, were
                    married on January 30th near Lebanon by the Rev. A. A. P. Neel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Laney</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. Charles Laney died at Cedar Hill on Naked Creek at age 94. "He was
                    too young to take part in the Revolution of 1776, but he bore himself gallantly
                    in the War of 1812. Those in the Valley born previous to the war of 1776 now
                    number but few indeed. The present status of the country caused him much pain in
                    the ebbing out of the last of the sands in the glass of his life."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1868.02.05.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
