<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1868/va.au.vv.1868.03.18">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/04/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-03-18">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="">18</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1868.03.18.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1868.03.18.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Impeachment Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It becomes more evident every day that the Radicals in Congress, are maturing
                        or have matured a deliberate plan to overthrow the Executive and Judicial
                        Departments of the Government, and having drawn all the powers of the three
                        co-ordinated branches to themselves, establish themselves permanently in
                        power, in defiance of the voice of the Northern people, expressed so
                        recently at the polls, against their destructive policy. - Those sanguine
                        persons who so fondly relied upon the decency and conservatism of Senators,
                        sworn as jurors to try the Impeachment of the President, must have been
                        sadly disappointed by the proceedings of that body on Friday last. On that
                        day the President was summoned to appear before the bar of the Senate, to
                        answer the charges against him by the House of representatives. In obedience
                        to this command, the President, by his counsel, Messrs. Stanbery, Curtis and
                        Nelson, entered his appearance and demanded the very reasonable time of
                        forty days to prepare his answer and defense, to the numerous charges
                        brought against him. This demand was of course resisted by the blood hounds,
                        who are termed the "managers of Impeachment, on the part of the House of
                        Representatives," and the "high court of Impeachment," after retiring for
                        consultation, (a thing so far as we are informed, unheard of in any court
                        here or in England,) entered the following laconic order:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">"Ordered,</emph> That the respondent answer to the
                        articles of Impeachment, on or before Monday, the 23rd day of March,
                        instant." - So that the President is required in the greatest State trial
                        the world has ever seen, to prepare his defense, which will most probably
                        require the attendance of numerous witnesses from all parts of the country,
                        in <emph rend="italic">ten days,</emph> just half the time the Legislature
                        of Virginia thought it necessary to give the debtor, on a notice to collect
                        the interest on a debt of $100, barred by the stay law.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Accusing the Radical Congress of trying to dominate all three branches of
                    government, this article provides a brief update of the current impeachment
                    proceedings on Washington. The president was summoned to appear before the bar
                    of the Senate, at which time he demanded forty days to prepare his defense. His
                    demands were naturally resisted by Radical "bloodhounds."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Murder</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>Christopher</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCreary</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Three men with crape over their faces entered the house of Christopher
                    Stover on the road between Waynesboro and Greenville. They ordered a number of
                    ladies and gentleman gathered at the Stover's for a social to keep still and
                    proceeded to ransack the house. Mr. Stover, between 60 and 70 years of age,
                    followed them out of the room and was fatally shot after striking one of the
                    intruders with an axe. A guest named McCreary was also shot when he rushed to
                    the scene.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>A Few Words to the Colored People</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Last year we honestly advised the colored people not to vote; to hold aloof
                        from all participation in the political struggles then going on. Again we
                        repeat the advice. It was a white man's war and a white man's political
                        fight now. You incidently [sic] made your freedom by it, and, if that's
                        anything made, you are the only winner in the game. So let well enough alone
                        - work hard - make yourself so useful that the country can't do without you,
                        but avoid voting and politics. You can not effect the issue, in the long
                        run, as you are only 3,000,000, with no increase by immigration, to
                        40,000,000 white men on this Continent. You can and will only be used as
                        tools to promote the designs of "mean white men," and be made an
                        "obstruction" to the prosperity of the whole country. If you vote for the
                        Radicals you cannot expect us to employ you any longer than we can get other
                        labor; and you enlist yourselves in a vile crusade against the dearest
                        rights of your best friends - the Southern people. If you vote Conservative
                        the Radical Yankee idea of exterminating your race, and filling your places
                        with free white labor, will soon be carried out. You are between two fires;
                        you are in the most helpless condition of any body of people on earth,
                        unless you pursue the safe road - taking neither the right nor the left,
                        neither Radical nor Conservative, but holding to what you have with content.
                        In all kindness; as a friend of the negro race, in this place, we throw out
                        these suggestions. They are as true as that there is a God above us and
                        honestly told, not caring whom they may offend. You must "learn to labor and
                        to wait," or you must perish. Choose ye!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urging black people not to vote, the author suggests that since freedom was
                    won in a white man's fight, blacks, the "only winners in the game," should
                    remain out of politics. Rather, blacks should apply themselves to their labor
                    and understand that a vote for the Radical party will ultimately exterminate the
                    race. Radicals are interested only in filling blacks places with free white
                    labor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1868.03.18.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Crops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that the wheat looks "healthy and vigorous."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Capt. Stewart Symington of the 5th Maryland Regiment, and well known in
                    Staunton and the Valley, has, in the paper's estimation, the best drilled
                    militia company in Baltimore.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Religious</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>John L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. John L. Clark, pastor of Staunton's Episcopal Church, sent a
                    report on the condition of his congregation to the Baltimore Episcopal
                    Methodist. He says membership is up, the church has been carpeted, all financial
                    demands are met and the school is flourishing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>R. R. Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mayor</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mauzy</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A meeting was held at the Court House to discuss the proposal that Staunton
                    contribute $50,000 to the proposed $300,000 county subscription to the stock of
                    the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad. Mayor Trout presided and several prominent
                    citizens spoke in favor of the plan.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Officers of the Augusta County Bible Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latane</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>George P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>J. Addison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>English</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheat</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Drake</ln>
                        <fn>D. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strasburg</ln>
                        <fn>David E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baird</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Augusta County Bible Society chose officers, including Judge H. W.
                    Sheffey, president. The pastors of Staunton were made lifetime members at $15
                    each. $308 were raised in cash and contributions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Staunton and Her Business Prospects</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Moorefiled Advertiser comments on Staunton's enterprise, industry and
                    improvement. William A. Burke is singled out for putting up a building and
                    filling it with state of the art machinery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coyner</ln>
                        <fn>William P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitesell</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William P. Coyner and Miss Sarah Whitesell, both of Augusta, were married
                    on February 25th by the Rev. Martin Garber.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Humphreys</ln>
                        <fn>Oliver M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bradburn</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Oliver M. Humphreys and Miss Martha Bradburn, both of Augusta, were married
                    on March 5th by the Rev. Martin Garber.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>J. Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Denny</ln>
                        <fn>Francis L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. Alex Grove of Newtown and Miss Francis L. Denny were married at the
                    residence of the bride's father on February 25th by the Rev. George A. Long.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1868.03.18.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
