<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1861/va.au.rv.1861.02.01">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Colleen Doody</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/7/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1861-02-01">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day norm="01">1</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1861.02.01.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Epauletts</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator rejects the Spectator's assertion that Capt. Imboden and
                    Gen. Harman should not be elected to the State Convention because they are
                    military men. The Vindicator believes that Augusta voters will recognize this
                    ruse, and will reject it when they go to the polls.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Duty of the People</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Any man who, in this canvass, votes for another merely upon personal
                    grounds, regardless of his defined position upon the issues involved, is
                    unworthy to exercise the privileges of a freeman. He is a servile slave, better
                    fitted to be driven before an overseer's lash than to exercise the right of
                    suffrage, only vouchsafed by our fundamental law to free white citizens."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that, just because a man signs a petition calling on someone to run
                    for office, it does not mean that he must vote for that candidate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Gov. Letcher</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Although Gov. Letcher's policies have not been adopted exactly by the
                    Legislature, his general line of policy has been endorsed. However, the
                    secessionists have been making "incessant war" on the Governor. The Vindicator
                    warns this faction that Letcher is supported by the people of Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The N.Y. Herald denies the claim that a special tax has been laid on slaves
                    in South Carolina. The contributions made of both slave labor and money have
                    been voluntary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>For the Vindicator.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Editor:--A few thoughts have presented themselves to my mind, of a local
                        character, whilst enjoying the luxury of a blazing fire and a rich Havana,
                        during the inclement weather, which has so sorely afflicted us for the last
                        week; and for the benefit of our community, as well as to gratify myself, I
                        have determined to ask your permission to print them.</p>
                    <p>Cemetery Fund</p>
                    <p>About a year ago, I believe, a Fair was held by the ladies of Staunton, for
                        the purpose of raising funds to improve the Cemetery. It is understood that
                        the means thus raised through the energy of our <emph rend="italic"
                        >fair</emph> ladies, have never been applied to the object originally
                        designed, on account of some legal disability, or other sufficient cause. If
                        this be true, and the fund is still lying idle, I respectfully suggest that
                        it be loaned to the two military companies of Staunton, for the purpose of
                        aiding them in purchasing the necessary equipments, such as tents,
                        knapsacks, &amp;c, for active service in the field. The unsettled state
                        of our national affairs may render a call for the services of our volunteer
                        companies by the State necessary at any moment, and in order to enable them
                        to be prepared for marching, this suggestion is made. If complied with, a
                        praiseworthy object will have been materially advanced, and the Cemetery
                        fund be made interest-bearing.</p>
                    <p>Home Guard</p>
                    <p>Our two military companies have offered their services in case of war, and in
                        the event of need, will doubtless be called away--that would leave our
                        property and wives and children without organized protective force. This
                        should not be, as in the <emph rend="italic">kind</emph> of warfare which
                        will prevail, if there should be war, every place is liable to attack or
                        disturbance. I suggest, therefore, the formation of a Company, to be called
                        the Staunton Home Guard, who are to act merely on the defensive, and not to
                        act except in the absence of the two companies now existing. Men past
                        military age, ministers and others, might join this company. It need have no
                        uniform, but a simple badge, and need drill but little. Having organized
                        selected arms and badge, they might agree that a certain alarm-signal should
                        at any time summon them to an appointed place.</p>
                    <p>Lewis Street</p>
                    <p>All our streets are bad enough, in all conscience, but Lewis street, from
                        Frederick street out, is my far too bad. It is all mud, with a ditch for
                        sidewalks. On said street live many poor persons, who can't afford boots and
                        shoes, and they get to church and their daily work (when they <emph
                            rend="italic">can</emph> get there) at the expense of health; and at the
                        risk of their lives. I doubt not that some girls have, from wading along
                        this street, gotten the seeds of death in their constitutions. Every
                        Corporation owes it to its citizens to abolish nuisances, and Lewis street
                        is certainly a nuisance. It has been said, "a Corporation can't sin;" but I
                        say this Corporation is a grievous sinner, if it don't [sic] do something
                        for Lewis street.</p>
                    <p>TOWNSMAN</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Townsman</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Townsman" makes a number of recommendations to improve and protect
                    Staunton. He argues that the town should donate money from the cemetery fund to
                    the militia, should raise a Home Guard to protect the area in case of war, and
                    should improve Lewis Street.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvfeb61.html#2.1a</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>When a certain Southern gentleman was asked if he would need ice during the
                    coming summer, he replied in the negative and claimed that "the men of the South
                    would drink boiling hot water on the 4th of July before they would receive or
                    use any of the free soil ice of the States of the North."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Excerpts from speeches given by the Senators from Alabama, Florida, and
                Mississippi on the occasion of their states' withdrawal from the Union, column
            6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1861.02.01.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Correspondence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>Geo. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>Jas. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eskridge</ln>
                        <fn>W.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>R.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berkley</ln>
                        <fn>T.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Opie</ln>
                        <fn>H.I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Kenton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn>H.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilkeson</ln>
                        <fn>W.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>J.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuffin</ln>
                        <fn>D.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Jas. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watts</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jordan</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Edwin M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tams</ln>
                        <fn>W.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>P.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The men listed above asked that Thomas J. Michie make his views on the
                    "important questions" known. Michie replied that he would be glad to meet with
                    them on the evening of February 2nd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Public Speaking</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Alex. M. Cochran will address the people of Staunton on Saturday night in
                    the Court House. The ladies of Staunton are invited to attend.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Mr. Sheffey Retires</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>H.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A.H.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Vindicator prints elsewhere in this issue an announcement that H.W.
                    Sheffey has decided to withdraw his name from contention in the delegate race.
                    The Vindicator regrets his decision, especially since it makes it more likely
                    that Mr. Stuart might win. The paper argues that Stuart should not be elected
                    because he has refused to resign from the Legislature.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Combination Ticket</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A.H.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A ticket with the names of Baldwin, Baylor, and Stuart has been circulating
                    in Staunton. The Vindicator claims that this is an "attempted fraud upon the
                    people" and urges them not to vote for any combination ticket. The paper also
                    cannot believe that Baldwin and Baylor support this effort.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Speech of Mr. Skinner</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator editor was unable to attend Skinner's speech last Monday
                    night. While the paper does not endorse all of Mr. Skinner's views, it praises
                    him for always making his arguments with "a great deal of candor and frankness."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Revolution</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that revolutions always move forward: "Progress is the law--the
                    shibboleth of civilization." The current revolution will also move forward
                    unless the "irritating cause is removed. The Southern States will not recede
                    from their position unless the basis of reconstruction embraces a clear and
                    distinct enunciation and guarantee of equal rights and privileges."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Last Monday</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A.H.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The candidates spoke at the Court House on Monday. The people present paid
                    close attention to the candidates, which they must since "the destiny of the
                    country may depend upon the course of Virginia, in this momentous crisis."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Fortress Monroe</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The people of Eastern Virginia have taken a great interest in the
                    improvements that are being made at Fortress Monroe. This work indicates that
                    the President is prepared to use coercive force against Virginia if it should
                    secede, since the guns in the fort are now pointed in toward the State.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Senators Mason and Hunter and three members of Congress from Virginia have
                    issued a statement from Washington saying that there is no hope that the present
                    difficulties can be solved. The Vindicator didn't publish the statement because
                    it believes that these men want an excuse to secede. The paper claims that it
                    supports neither secession or submission.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator objects to the article printed in the Spectator on January
                    29th that encouraged mothers to influence their husbands to vote for Union men
                    in the upcoming election. The papers asks if the Spectator meant to insult the
                    women of West Augusta "by an appeal to their fear, when the question of
                    patriotism is involved?"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Blames Mr. Staurt's recent resolutions in the Senate for creating a climate
                    of fear, which lead to the reinforcement of Fortress Monroe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rejects the assertion of Stuart and Baldwin that certain Augusta candidates
                    for the Convention support immediate secession. None of them have taken this
                    position.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mason</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mason</ln>
                        <fn>C.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumate</ln>
                        <fn>T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoge</ln>
                        <fn>Byron</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Mason and Miss Brown were thrown from the sleigh of C.R. Mason when
                    the horses bolted. Neither one was badly hurt.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"Old Uncle Frederick Hill . . ."</p>
                    <p>Old Uncle Frederick Hill, for a number of years a servant at the Hospital at
                        this place, died one day last week. Uncle Frederick was as regular in his
                        visits to the Vindicator office, every Saturday, as clock work, until the
                        past month, during which time he was too feeble. His funeral was largely
                        attended by colored and white persons and as much respect paid his memory as
                        if he had been one of our most respected citizens. Frederick was truly a
                        pious man, and one of the most faithful servants we have ever known.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Old Uncle Frederick Hill, a servant at the Hospital in Staunton, died last
                    week. He was a faithful servant, and his funeral was "largely attended by
                    colored and white persons and as much respect paid his memory as if he had been
                    one of our most respected citizens."</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvfeb61.html#2.1b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>President-elect Lincoln will have a military escort when he travels to
                    Washington for his inauguration. This is the first time military protection has
                    been necessary for a high civil official passing from one part of the country to
                    another. The Vindicator thinks that Lincoln is "investing idle rumors with too
                    much importance."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"We have frequently . . ."</p>
                    <p>We have frequently called the attention of the Council and Street
                        Commissioners to the condition of the side-walks on our principal
                        thoroughfares. As yet there has been no regard paid to these timely and
                        appropriate notices. We once again remind these public functionaries, that
                        the <emph rend="italic">people</emph>--the <emph rend="italic">tax
                        payers</emph>--DEMAND some improvement in the condition of the streets. Next
                        May is not far distance, and we shall take especial pleasure in ventilating
                        the present Council before the sovereigns, if they do not do something
                        towards making our side-walks tolerable. A word to the wise is
                    sufficient.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Complains that neither the Staunton Council nor the Street Commissioners
                    have paid attention to the paper's complaints about the deplorable condition of
                    the sidewalks on the town's main thoroughfares.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvfeb61.html#2.1c</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator publishes the resolutions adopted by the South Carolina
                    Legislature in response to Virginia's sending a commissioner to the Southern
                    states. The paper believes that the "spirit of these resolutions is anything but
                    encouraging."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the Republicans have been sending out conflicting reports about
                    the nature of the incoming administration. The Vindicator recommends that
                    Southerners should "Mistrust a suspected traitor until his character is proven."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Hay Scales</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>&gt;Hay Scales</p>
                    <p>Ever since the destructive freshet of last Summer, by which the foundation of
                        the Hay Scales was washed away, that useful town improvement has been <emph
                            rend="italic">non est inventus.</emph> We call the attention of the Town
                        Council to this fact, and urge upon them the imperative necessity of at once
                        putting the Hay Scales in order. It is a convenience the benefits of which
                        almost every citizen feels, and we trust they will at once be rebuilt. We
                        deem it only necessary to remind the Council of the omission, believing that
                        they will promptly order them to be placed in weighing order.</p>
                    <p>If the town authorities will not go to the expense of fixing up the Scales,
                        if they will give the authority, there are a number of public spirited
                        citizens who will, provided they can have the revenue from them for their
                        trouble and outlay.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Staunton hay scales were damaged in last summer's flood. The Vindicator
                    hopes that the Town Council will act to fix these scales, which benefit the
                    whole community.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvfeb61.html#2.1d</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Beware the Roorbacks!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Denies the rumor that Gen. Harman and Capt. Imboden are disunion candidates
                    who favor immediate secession.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Louisiana Out</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Louisiana has seceded from the Union, the sixth state to do so.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Virginia</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Defines disunionists and submissionists. The former are actually "boldly
                    and firmly demanding all their rights under the Constitution, and [are]
                    determined to take nothing less." The latter are "influenced by a hereditary
                    love of the Union as our fathers made it" and are "willing to yield much to
                    preserve it." The writer believes that only the former course will allow the
                    South to secure its rights.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Fair Play</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>One of the People</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Objects to Mr. Stuart's candidacy for delegate while he is still a member
                    of the State Legislature.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>To the People of Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Hugh Sheffey announces his withdrawal from the delegate race.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Miscellaneous news from Washington, column 7</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1861.02.01.03">
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFarland</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Andrew Stuart and Sarah McClure, daughter of John McClure, were married on
                    January 17 near Greenville, Augusta County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Resolutions from the South Carolina legislature, column 1; Message from
                President Buchanan on the resolutions adopted by the Virginia Legislature, column
            1</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1861.02.01.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
