<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1861/va.au.rv.1861.05.03">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Colleen Doody</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/7/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1861-05-03">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day norm="03">3</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1861.05.03.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Half Sheet</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Half Sheet.</p>
                    <p>We are able only to give our readers a half sheet this week. It will be seen
                        however, that we furnish almost as much reading matter as usual, as we have
                        thrown out all the Yankee advertisements except one or two that have paid in
                        advance. We devote our space almost entirely to the publication of news
                        relating to the present crisis.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator will only be two pages long this week.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmay61.html#5.3a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Capital of the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Capital of the South.</p>
                    <p>It is now believed that Richmond will become the Capital of the South. The
                        resolution of invitation, published elsewhere by the Virginia Convention,
                        will go far to bring about a result so desirable. Everything combines to
                        make Richmond the very place for the Southern Capital.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses the belief that Staunton might become the capital of Virginia now
                    that Richmond is the Capital of the Confederacy.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmay61.html#5.3b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>No Pressing</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>No Pressing.</p>
                    <p>The impression has become almost general with our country friends that their
                        horses, cattle, sheep, cows, &amp;c., would be <emph rend="italic"
                            >"pressed"</emph> into the service, and for the use of the army of the
                        State. We are glad to have it in our power to relieve them. The Governor has
                        issued an order expressly forbidding any and every thing of the kind.--We
                        hope therefore that our farmers and other who may have been apprehensive on
                        this point, will be contented with the assurance that there will be no
                        "pressing." Our most excellent, wise and able Governor has taken every
                        precaution to protect the people from unnecessary and unjust annoyance.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Assures farmers that the overnor has issued an order forbidding the state
                    from impressing their livestock into service.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmay61.html#5.3e</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Object of the War</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Object of the War.</p>
                    <p>To prevent any misapprehension on the part of our readers relative to an
                        expression in our paper last week, "that the war would be carried into
                        Africa," we make this explanation. Gen. Scott has extended the Military
                        Department of Washington as to include Pennsylvania and Delaware.--Should a
                        battle occur and we take Washington, then it will in all probability be the
                        policy of President Davis to drive the enemy from his position on Southern
                        soil. The base line of the operations of General Scott will have to be
                        broken up. This accomplished, the South will not advance one foot further.
                        We simply want our own soil relieved from the oppression of the North. We
                        want and mean to have our rights and our liberty, or else honourable graves.
                        We are acting on the defensive exclusively. We are repelling aggression. We
                        are defending our firesides and homes. "Lives there a man with soul so
                        dead," that he is not willing to spring eagerly to the trigger for such a
                        purpose?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>States that the South only wants to be "relieved from the oppression of the
                    North." The Confederacy is defending its homes, not attacking the Union.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmay61.html#5.3c</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"The pretentious editor . . ."</p>
                    <p>The pretentious editor of the Winchester Republican, in noticing the Tenth
                        Legion troops, says that they used the "chaste and dignified language, <emph
                            rend="italic">'hoggled'</emph> sure," when alluding to the result of
                        their contest with "old Abe." Now, we do not believe any such expression
                        fell from a single member of either company that went from any county in the
                        District. Those who compose the "Tenth Legion" companies are equally as
                        chaste and dignified as the editor of the Republican, and would certainly
                        not be guilty of a contemptible attempt to make sport when there was no
                        occasion for it. The idea having gotten out that the people of Rockingham
                        and Shenandoah were crude and uncultivated--nothing more false--it seems to
                        be the pride of pedantic and superficial scribblers to make them the text
                        for disguising and abortive witticisms.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes the editor of the Winchester Republican for implying that the
                    men from the Tenth Legion are "crude and uncultivated."</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmay61.html#5.3d</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column/>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"Mr. Phillips desires to correct . . . "</p>
                    <p>Mr. Phillips desires to correct a statement in the last issue of the
                        Vindicator, calculated to detract from the merits of the many noble citizens
                        in Staunton, who are daily working to equip our solders for field service.
                        B. Crawford, Esq., at the head, was followed by all the merchants in town,
                        in selling their goods at cost, besides donating a part for tents, camp
                        jackets, &amp;c. The ladies, all over town, offered their services to
                        sew, and prepare bandages, &amp;c. and the difficulty has been to get
                        the work ready for them. The pupils and teachers at the Virginia Female,
                        Wesleyan, and Augusta Institutes have done nobly. The large band of ladies
                        at work in the basement of the Lutheran Church, and ladies at the Italian
                        Villa on Gospel Hill, the teachers and pupils at the Deaf and Dumb
                        Institute, in short, all the ladies of the town are ready to go on with
                        their efforts to equip the gallant old State to defend her rights. When all
                        have done so nobly, and are willing to do any thing in their power,
                        distinctions are improper, and, of course, were innocently made. A letter
                        from the Governor of the State promises us a plenty of work, and it is hoped
                        the ladies will organize themselves and be ready for action when the
                        materials are received. There is work enough for all to do, and every one
                        can assist in thus achieving our Independence.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Praises all the citizens of Staunton who are helping to equip the volunteer
                    companies with supplies.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmay61.html#5.3f</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Important Ordinances</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints of the text of a number of ordinances from the State Convention,
                    including an ordinance to authorize banks to issue small notes and an ordinance
                    to equalize taxation between all parts of the Commonwealth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>By the Governor of Virginia: A Proclamation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Text of the Ordinance to repeal the Ratification of the Constitution of the
                    United States by the State of Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1861.05.03.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Message of President Davis</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on a message read to the Confederate Congress from President Davis.
                    In it, Davis stated that all the Confederate states have ratified the permanent
                    Constitution. He pointed out that the declaration of war by the Lincoln
                    administration forced the Confederacy to convene Congress. He also congratulated
                    the people of the Confederacy for their patriotism and stated that the new
                    nation sought "no conquest--no aggrandizement--no concessions from the free
                    States. All we ask is to be let alone, and that none shall attempt our
                    subjugation by force of arms."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Negroes Volunteering</head>
                <origin>Richmond Dispatch</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Negroes Volunteering.</p>
                    <p>About fifty free negroes in Amelia county have offered themselves to the
                        Government for any service.</p>
                    <p>In our neighboring city of Petersburg, two hundred free negroes offered for
                        any work that might be assigned to them, either to fight under white
                        officers, dig ditches, or any thing that could show their desire to serve
                        Old Virginia. In the same city, a negro hackman came to his master, and with
                        tears in his eyes, insisted that he should accept all his savings, $100, to
                        help equip the volunteers. The free negroes of Chesterfield have made a
                        similar proposition. Such is the spirit among bond and free, throughout the
                        whole of the State. Those who calculate on a different state of things, will
                        soon discover their mistake.</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">Rich. Dispatch.</emph>
                    </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Claims that more than 250 free blacks in Virginia have offered their
                    services to the Confederacy.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmay61.html#5.3g</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Murder and Pillage</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"Such is the war cry of that worst of men, Horace Greeley, in the
                    following article:"</commentary>
                <excerpt>"The worn-out race of emasculated First Families must give place to a
                    sturdier people, whose pioneers are now on their way to Washington at this
                    moment in regiments. . . . Free States, inspired with Northern vigor, may start
                    new in the race for prosperity and power. The property of the true Union men in
                    both these States will not be disturbed; but the traitors must be punished."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator reprints an article by Horace Greeley, in which he argues
                    that traitors in Virginia should have their lands and homes taken away and given
                    to loyal Union men.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>Phebe W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>Ellen S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Phebe Patterson, only surviving daughter of Ellen Patterson, died near
                    Greenville on April 19.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>A Battalion to Be Formed of the Sons of "West Augusta"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn>R.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>R.D. Lilley proposes to form a battalion called the Augusta Lee Rifles in
                    honor of Maj. Gen. R.E. Lee. "Young men of intelligence of every portion of the
                    county, are most respectfully and cordially invited to join the Battalion."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
