<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1861/va.au.rv.1861.01.11">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Colleen Doody</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/7/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1861-01-11">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>11</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1861.01.11.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Meeting in Highland</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The people of Highland county have declared in favor of submitting the
                    question of whether or not to hold a State Convention to a popular vote. The
                    Vindicator disagrees with this position because the State needs to take action
                    before the 4th of March.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Free Negroes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Free Negroes</p>
                    <p>There are a number of free negroes about town, who are not registered, and
                        consequently have no business here. It is the duty of the proper authorities
                        to forthwith commence the correction of the serious evil by notifying them
                        to leave, or suffer the penalty imposed by law of remaining.</p>
                    <p>Another source of great annoyance to our town is the policy of permitting
                        slaves to hire their own time, or get persons to stand as their masters. The
                        habit induces idleness among slaves, and is the cause of all kinds of
                        trafficing [sic] among them, which is more or less connected with petty
                        thefts. These evils should be radically corrected without delay. The quicker
                        the better.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>There are a number of free blacks living in Staunton who are unregistered
                    and have no business in town. The Vindicator urges the authorities to notify the
                    free blacks to leave or suffer the legal consequences.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjan61.html#1.11a</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Wood Measurer</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator believes that Staunton needs a wood measurer, and urges the
                    town council to pass an ordinance creating such an office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Fast day was generally observed in Staunton. A Union prayer meeting was
                    held in the Lutheran Church, and a large audience attended.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The New York Herald called on the President to call out 60,000 troops to
                    protect Washington from an invasion on March 4, the day of Lincoln's
                    inauguration. The Vindicator sees this call as another example that "the North
                    is becoming united on the policy of coercion."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The South Carolina government has laid a tax on slaves in order to raise
                    money. If the wealthy men of the state do not make a $400,000 loan for military
                    purposes, coercion will be used. The Vindicator likens this threat of coercion
                    to the reign of terror of the Jacobin Clubs of France.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Article about diphtheria, column 5; minutes of the Highland county meeting,
                column 6; miscellaneous news about South Carolina and the federal
            government.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1861.01.11.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Gov. Letcher's Message</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gov. Letcher gave a lengthy message touching on many questions of
                    importance, including Virginia's relations with South Carolina and Southern
                    attempts at convincing Northern states to abolish personal liberty laws. The
                    Governor does not favor calling a State Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>"Is Western Virginia All Right?"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator believes that the editors of many eastern Virginia
                    newspapers have whipped themselves into a fury over a question that "no sensible
                    man in Western Virginia scarcely ever dreamed of--the division of the State."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> "He is in favor of a Convention but we have no doubt he will, in accordance
                        with the sentiments of his constituents, vote against it."--<emph
                            rend="italic">Spectator</emph></p>
                    <p>The above sentence we find in a paragraph in the last Spectator, referring to
                        Col. J.M. McCue, one of the delegates in the Legislature from this county.
                        Upon what authority the editor of the Spectator bases the conclusion that
                        the people of Augusta are opposed to a State Convention we are at a loss to
                        conjecture. We venture the assertion that ten out of every twelve voters in
                        the county are decidedly in favor of a Convention. Our acquaintance extends
                        to every portion of the county, and to members of all parties, and we have
                        not conversed with half a dozen men, within the past month, who are not for
                        Virginia taking her position through the action of a Convention. Certainly
                        two out of the three representatives in the House of Delegates from this
                        county will vote for the call of a Convention. We have not heard the views
                        of Mr. Massie expressed. Mr. Stuart, our Senator, we understand, is, as now
                        advised, opposed to such a step. But we are very sure, if the gentlemen who
                        represent us wish to do it properly, they will all, without hesitation,
                        favor a Convention and speedy and prompt action.</p>
                    <p>We should like to learn the Spectator's authority for making the broad charge
                        that the people of Augusta are opposed to a Convention. Col. McC. has not
                        been in this State for several months, and consequently, does not know
                        precisely where his constituents stand; but we can inform him that,
                        according to our understanding, he could not more fully represent the
                        sentiments of his constituents, than by voting in accordance with his own
                        convictions in favor of a Convention.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator disagrees with the Spectator's assertion that the majority
                    of Augusta voters oppose the plan to hold a State Convention.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjan61.html#1.11b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Coercion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the federal government cannot maintain the Union with coercive
                    means.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Desperate Negro Woman</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Desperate Negro Woman</p>
                    <p>A fine looking negro woman aged about 28 years, belonging to Mr. Joseph
                        Cline, living about four miles from Staunton, becoming unruly, he determined
                        to bring her to town and sell her. While she was going to get her clothes,
                        she picked up an axe which she had concealed, and deliberately cut three of
                        her fingers off, taking two licks at them. She was brought to town, placed
                        in jail, and her hand was dressed by Dr. Baldwin. She did the act for the
                        double purpose of preventing her sale and taking revenge upon her
                    master.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cline</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A slave woman who belonged to Joseph Cline, who lives four miles from
                    Staunton, chopped off three of her fingers to prevent her master from selling
                    her.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjan61.html#1.11c</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Vallandingham of Ohio</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises Vallandingham, who voted with the South and against the resolution
                    of approbation offered on behalf of Major Anderson's actions at Fort Sumpter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A General "Stay Law"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Advocates the passage of a law that would protect the property of debtors
                    during this period of economic chaos.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Commencement of Hostilities--The Cause and the Blunder</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes South Carolina for making a gross blunder and relying on the
                    "promises of the treacherous Buchanan."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Abdication of Buchanan--Gen. Scott Acting President</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Claims that Buchanan turned against the South after his defeat of Douglas
                    and has essentially turned over power to General Scott.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Richmond Correspondence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Augusta</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Correspondent claims that popular opinion in Richmond holds that "danger of
                    civil war is imminent, certainly on the 4th of March, if not sooner." The halls
                    of the Legislature are crowded with anxious spectators.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Disagrees with the Spectator's assertion that the call for a Convention is
                    a disunion movement.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Delay is Dangerous</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that, unless the North backs down, the State Convention should
                    "adopt measures preservative of the honor, integrity, and sovereignty of
                    Virginia."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>During the past year, many men have spoken of their devotion to Virginia
                    and to the South. The Vindicator hopes that these men will come forward and
                    fight in the militia, should such action become necessary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1861.01.11.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Message of Governor Letcher</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summarizes the Governor's message given on January 7. He seeks to hold the
                    Union together, and so opposes a State Convention. He argues that slave property
                    must be protected in the District of Columbia and in the territories. He also
                    calls for the abolishment of personal liberty laws.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gamewell</ln>
                        <fn>W.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coiner</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on January 3. Miss Beard is from Columbia, South Carolina.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>B.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>Jas. M.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>Maria L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on December 25.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>B.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shepherd</ln>
                        <fn>Nathaniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huff</ln>
                        <fn>Caroline</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on December 25.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gamble</ln>
                        <fn>Emily E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gamble</ln>
                        <fn>Philander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Emily Gamble died on January 4 at age 24.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hobbs</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hobbs</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hobbs</ln>
                        <fn>James O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Hobbs, son of Elizabeth and the late James Hobbs, died on December 14
                    at age 3.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Loudermilk</ln>
                        <fn>W.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Loudermilk</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Loudermilk</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W.H. Loudermilk died on December 26 at age 2. His windpipe was blocked by a
                    grain of corn.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wonderlick</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wonderlick</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Wonderlick died on December 26 at age 53.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Letter from ex-Gov. Wise, column 1, Speech of Judge Douglas, column 2,
                proceedings of Virginia Legislature, column 3.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1861.01.11.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
