<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1861/va.au.rv.1861.01.04">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Colleen Doody</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/7/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1861-01-04">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day norm="04">4</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1861.01.04.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deep Snow</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>Not withstanding the clear, beautiful sky and genial sun which blessed us
                    last week, Saturday brought us a gloomy heaven and the commencement of the
                    heaviest snow we have had for several years. The snow fell constantly until
                    Sunday night, and Monday morning it was about two feet in depth. Bright and
                    early the merry sleigh bells made music on our streets, and frolicksome [sic]
                    men and boys amused themselves by tossing snow balls. A real, genuine wintry
                    snow rejuvenates age and makes us all feel like boys again.</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Deep Snow.</p>
                    <p>Not withstanding the clear, beautiful sky and genial sun which blessed us
                        last week, Saturday brought us a gloomy heaven and the commencement of the
                        heaviest snow we have had for several years. The snow fell constantly until
                        Sunday night, and Monday morning it was about two feet in depth. Bright and
                        early the merry sleigh bells made music on our streets, and frolicksome
                        [sic] men and boys amused themselves by tossing snow balls. A real, genuine
                        wintry snow rejuvenates age and makes us all feel like boys again.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Saturday brought "the heaviest snow we have had for several years" to
                    Augusta.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjan61.html#1.4a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Sudden Death</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brownlee</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Brownlee, a member of the firm of Robertson &amp; Brownlee, live
                    stock dealers, died suddenly on December 30.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1861.01.04.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"A few negro women were hired publicly in this place on New Year's day, by
                    Col. R. Turk. One of them brought $86.50 and another $84, large increase [sic]
                    over last year's prices. Women servants are in great demand, while men are less
                    sought after."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A few negro women were hired publicly in this place on New Year's day, by
                        Col. R. Turk. One of them brought $86.50 and another $84, large increase
                        [sic] over last year's prices. Women servants are in great demand, while men
                        are less sought after.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary/>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjan61.html#1.4b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armentrout</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn>H.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marshall</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Armentrout, the long-time jailor for Augusta county, vacated the jail
                    on January 1st. Capt. Peck, Sheriff of the county, will now occupy the jail,
                    while Judge Marshall will act in the capacity of jailor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Seventeenth Volume</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>This number commences the Seventeenth Volume of the Vindicator. Coming into
                    existence at a time when the Democratic party of the county numbered not more
                    than six hundred, it has sustained ardently under most unpropitious
                    circumstances and amid the varying fortunes of a doubtful enterprise, the cause
                    of the Democratic party, until the numerical strength of the organization has
                    been more than doubled and the paper established upon a firm foundation.</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Seventeenth Volume</p>
                    <p>This number commences the Seventeenth Volume of the Vindicator. Coming into
                        existence at a time when the Democratic party of the county numbered not
                        more than six hundred, it has sustained ardently under most unpropitious
                        circumstances and amid the varying fortunes of a doubtful enterprise, the
                        cause of the Democratic party, until the numerical strength of the
                        organization has been more than doubled and the paper established upon a
                        firm foundation.</p>
                    <p>Seventeen years have witnessed the steady growth of the Democracy and its
                        triumphs over the elements of opposition, under whatever name presented,
                        with almost unvarying success, until the year 1860, when through its own
                        dissensions and disintegration, it yielded to the more firmly united and
                        better disciplined forces of the enemy.</p>
                    <p>It is no difficult task to trace the recent result of the Presidential
                        election to the human agencies that brought it about. But <emph
                            rend="italic">why</emph> it should have entered into the hearts of men
                        to plot the destruction of the most perfect system of government the world
                        has ever seen, is past finite comprehension, and is one of those
                        unfathomable mysteries which the more confound us as we approach their
                        investigation. There can be no rational motive given as an excuse for the
                        action of men, that is pregnant with such untold disaster and misery, not
                        only to the present generation of our country, but to the generations yet
                        unborn, and to the cause of human freedom, religious and political
                        throughout the world. Were we alone to realize the blighting and destructive
                        influences of the dissolution of the Union of these States--a Union hallowed
                        by so many glorious associations, cemented by such sacred ties, and baptized
                        in the blood of our fathers--then we might with some palliating excuse
                        assume the responsibility of so tremendous an undertaking. But this is not
                        the case. We are acting for posterity. Many of us believing that the
                        government has failed to accomplish that good designed and contemplated by
                        its founders, are unwilling that a living libel upon their wisdom,
                        patriotism and philanthropy, shall longer exist. A recurrence to the
                        fundamental idea of our political system convinces many that in the
                        practical operation of our governmental machinery, the end there proposed is
                        not being carried out. Instead of the equality of all, the tyranny of
                        numbers is substituted. Instead of sovereign State independence and State
                        responsibility, the people of other States assume to say what we shall do,
                        and regulate our system of morals as well as our domestic institutions.
                        Solemn and serious warning does not bring them to a sense of the injustice
                        they would perpetrate. Expostulation they "will none of." But determined
                        upon the point that <emph rend="italic">they</emph> are right and every body
                        else is wrong, they are daily seeking by all the devices of the hypocrite,
                        the bully and the incendiary to force their views upon an unwilling people,
                        regardless of consequences.</p>
                    <p>These causes have brought the Southern people to the investigation of the
                        fact, whether or not the legacy bequeathed by our revolutionary fathers is
                        being faithfully administered--whether its designs are being studied and its
                        ends encompassed--that posterity may receive it from us as we received it
                        from them.</p>
                    <p>The consideration of such momentous questions and the contemplation of the
                        probable result, will necessarily absorb all mere party issues and erase
                        party distinctions. Henceforth, it is a contest of <emph rend="italic"
                            >Sections</emph>. Things are rapidly drifting to a focus. The reasonable
                        demands of the South that the North should retrace their hostile steps, give
                        assurance of future fidelity to the national compact, and cease their
                        aggressions, have been met with insulting sneer and taunting defiance. They
                        dream little of the volcano over which they are sporting. If the North by
                        such means expect to intimidate the South then they are fearfully deluded.
                        What heretofore has been deemed conservatism in Virginia, is being aroused
                        to stern and relentless indignation. If the North expect co-operation, then
                        they are mistaken. The South will be as one man in defense of her honor, her
                        rights, her sovereignty and her equality.</p>
                    <p>Heretofore, we have remarked, the Vindicator has been enlisted in the
                        interests of the Democratic party, with the firm conviction that the
                        faithful administration of its doctrines is the most efficient agency by
                        which to perpetuate the Union. The defeat of that organization, has sounded
                        the deathknell of the confederacy. While we shall cherish the tenants of the
                        Democracy as those most assimilative to the true idea of our government,
                        their advocacy and elimination have become unnecessary for the present, and
                        henceforth we shall unite our efforts with all good men in the vindication
                        of the honor of Virginia and the South, and the maintenance of the
                        principles of constitutional liberty as understood by our fathers.</p>
                    <p>We commence the seventeenth volume of the Vindicator and the year 1861, with
                        a dark and portentous cloud lowering over our political horizon, but
                        whatever may betide, through civil war may rage and the country be drenched
                        in blood, with Virginia and the South our destiny is cast, and with the same
                        zeal and energy we have in the past endeavored to uphold the flag of the
                        National Democratic party, will we rally to the support of Virginia and the
                        South. Where Virginia leads there will we follow to victory or to death.
                        With her glorious motto, <emph rend="italic">"sic semper tyrannis,"</emph>
                        streaming in the breeze, we will join in resisting an oppression more odious
                        than that of George the Third, and crushing out a despotic fanaticism as
                        repulsive as the Spanish Inquisition.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator commences its seventeenth year in existence with this issue.
                    It has always been loyal to the Democratic party, but it is very disturbed by
                    the party's defeat in the 1860 election. Elections have become contests between
                    the sections, not the parties, and the North refuses to listen to the South's
                    concerns. As a result, the Vindicator's primary loyalty can no longer to the
                    party, but must be to Virginia and the South. The paper pledges to "unite our
                    efforts with all good men in the vindication of the honor of Virginia and the
                    South, and the maintenance of the principles of constitutional liberty as
                    understood by our fathers."</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjan61.html#1.4c</note>
                <look>X</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>A Note of Warning</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator states that it has always discouraged extreme sectional
                    rhetoric in its attempt to hold the Union together. However, it now appears that
                    the paper was mistaken in its belief that the North "would correct the fanatical
                    dogmas of some of their leading traitors." The South now has little choice but
                    to adopt a policy of self-protection.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>State Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Papers from the eastern part of Virginia are indignant at the idea that the
                    subject of taxation should be dealt with at a State Convention. However, people
                    from western Virginia argue that "If the East believes, as does the West, that
                    slaves are property, and desires to do 'justice' . . . to the West, then an
                    amendatory clause to the Constitution could be reported in a very short time,
                    and the matter settled at once, without the necessity and expense of calling
                    another convention in a few years."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Resignation of Secretary Floyd</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>John Floyd, the Secretary of War in the Buchanan administration, resigned
                    his position in protest of the actions taken by Major Anderson in Fort Sumpter.
                    The administration had pledged to maintain the status quo in the Charleston
                    forts as long as negotiations were pending between South Carolina and the
                    federal government. However, Major Anderson evacuated Fort Moultrie and occupied
                    Fort Sumpter, which put the military in a much stronger position. The Vindicator
                    condemns Major Anderson's actions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Meeting of the Legislature</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>The Legislature of Virginia meets in extra session on Monday next, the 7th
                    inst. In no period of the history of the country has a deliberative body been
                    called upon to consider graver, or more important and stirring events than those
                    that will be presented to the General Assembly of Virginia during its present
                    session. Among its first duties will be to call a State Convention, and take
                    efficient steps towards thoroughly arming the State.</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Meeting of the Legislature</p>
                    <p>The Legislature of Virginia meets in extra session on Monday next, the 7th
                        inst. In no period of the history of the country has a deliberative body
                        been called upon to consider graver, or more important and stirring events
                        than those that will be presented to the General Assembly of Virginia during
                        its present session. Among its first duties will be to call a State
                        Convention, and take efficient steps towards thoroughly arming the State.
                        While there are objections that might be urged to the Convention at this
                        time, we think the considerations which call for it are paramount, and that
                        it should be instantly authorized, and the day of the election of delegates
                        fixed as early as possible, to the end that the Convention may meet before
                        the fourth of March. We are utterly opposed to the suggestion of our
                        esteemed contemporary of the Whig, that several months should transpire
                        before the assembling of the Convention, and that its action be submitted to
                        the people. In ordinary times, we should favor the policy of "making haste
                        slowly," but now, it seems to us urgently important that Virginia should act
                        at once, decidedly and promptly. Her position should be clearly and
                        distinctly taken before the 1st of March. Events of great import are
                        pressing upon us. We should meet them, and be prepared for any emergency.
                        The rule of Black Republican treason and fanaticism should never be
                        permitted to be inaugurated at Washington city. Virginia should be prepared
                        to play her part in resisting the act which would place the purse and the
                        sword of the government in the hands of a power that will use them for her
                        destruction and that of the South. We do not wish to act rashly. But it
                        would be madness--inexcusable suicide--for us to sit quietly down with arms
                        folded in supine indifference to our own identity, while our avowed enemy is
                        forging the chains that are to manacle us, and whetting the sword that is to
                        prove our executioner. Let the Legislature consider these matters, and act
                        as becomes brave men and patriots who have the nerve to stare death in the
                        face when honor and right are at stake.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Virginia Legislature will meet in an extra session on January 7th. Its
                    first duties will be to call a State Convention and take steps to arm the state.
                    The Vindicator disagrees with the Whigs, who want to wait several months before
                    calling a Convention and want the people to vote on the question of whether a
                    Convention should be held. Instead, the Vindicator wants the state to take
                    action before March 1st, when the "Black Republicans" will gain power in
                    Washington.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjan61.html#1.4d</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Festive Season</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Despite the current political crisis, the people of Staunton and Augusta
                    were "unusually gay and happy during the holydays [sic]."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Fasting and Prayer</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It is appropriate in James Buchanan to call for the aid of the prayer of
                    the pious men of the nation for the extrication of the country from its present
                    difficulties, for he of all men has been the chief in the terrible work of
                    precipitating upon us the ruin that seems inevitable."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>President Buchanan has called for January 4th to be a day of fasting and
                    prayer to save the country from destruction.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Four Free Negroes Drowned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Four free black men drowned on December 26th in Rockingham county. They
                    were attempting to cross the Shenandoah river near Port Republic.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The Conspiracy</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Richmond Whig quotes a number of prominent South Carolinians to prove
                    that they have long been conspiring to leave the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Page includes a number of articles discussing Major Anderson's actions in
                Charleston.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1861.01.04.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Proclamation of the Governor of South Carolina</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Proclamation of South Carolina's dissolution of the union between the State
                    and the other states of the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The bishops of the Methodist Episcopal Church have decided that the act on
                    the subject of slavery is not binding on the membership of the church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheeler</ln>
                        <fn>J.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bagby</ln>
                        <fn>Chapman</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Humphreys</ln>
                        <fn>Theresa</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on December 21.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>W.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelso</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Glendy</ln>
                        <fn>Mary M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on December 25. Miss Glendy is from Rockbridge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>W.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bailey</ln>
                        <fn>Charles E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bashaw</ln>
                        <fn>Fannie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on December 25. Mr. Bailey is from Charlottesville.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyle</ln>
                        <fn>James Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>S.K.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyle</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Kyle, son of William Kyle, died on December 22 at age 21.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cease</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cease</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elizabeth Cease died on December 17 at age 71.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Butterly</ln>
                        <fn>Annie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Butterly</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Annie Butterly died on December 31 at age 25.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Alex. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Margaret Bell, daughter of Alex. Bell, died on December 15.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Altafer</ln>
                        <fn>G.H.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on December 7 of dropsey at age 6.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witts</ln>
                        <fn>George R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died of diphtheria at age 6.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Congressional news, column 1; letters at the post office, column 3</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1861.01.04.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
