<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1861/va.au.rv.1861.05.31">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Colleen Doody</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/7/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1861-05-31">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>31</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1861.05.31.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Proclamation to the People of the Confederate States</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>President Jefferson Davis calls for a day of fasting and prayer for the
                    people of the Confederate States on June 13th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Duty of Good Citizens</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Loyalty to Virginia and to the government of the Confederate States
                    imperatively demands that a spirit of trust and confidence should be cultivated
                    on the part of the people towards those in authority."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator calls on all Virginians to stop grumbling and complaining
                    about the military decisions of the Confederate authorities. The paper likens
                    such complaining to giving "aid and comfort to the enemy."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Election: Official Vote of Augusta County</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Table of voting of Augusta County for the Senate, House of Delegates,
                    Ordinance of Secession, and the Board of Public Works. The voters overwhelmingly
                    supported the Ordinance of Secession--3130 people supported it while only 10
                    voted against.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The vote for the Ordinance of Secession "exhibits a unanimity unparalleled
                    in popular elections," according to the Vindicator. This was the largest vote
                    ever cast in Augusta county.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>West and Northwest</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The counties in the extreme Western and Northwestern parts of Virginia cast
                    a larger vote against the Ordinance of Secession than anticipated. The paper
                    blames this on the large number of federal troops stationed by the Ohio river,
                    who intimidated many voters into opposing secession.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Roughly 160,000 voters in Virginia supported the Ordinance of Secession
                    while 25,000 opposed it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Destructive Fire</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumate</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>A.F.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>H.J.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barkman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>B.F.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn>R.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A large fire threatened much of the lower part of Staunton, although it was
                    contained before it spread. It did destroy Thomas Shumate's stable and badly
                    damaged Mrs. Barkman's house. The fire companies worked hard to control the
                    flames and were aided by the Greenbrier Cavalry and the Augusta Lee Rifles.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Telegrams Suppressed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Telegrams Suppressed.</p>
                    <p>It appears that Gov. Letcher has given direction that the telegrams relating
                        to the operations of the army which come to the Richmond office, shall be
                        withheld from the newspapers of that city. We think this entirely right. The
                        people are kept in constant excitement and suspense by the various
                        announcements and contradictions which of late have been sent over the
                        wires. The imposition has been cruel. It is better to be without information
                        at all, than to be receiving so many false statements. We think the Governor
                        has acted wisely and prudently in ordering the telegrams to be withheld.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gov. Letcher has given the order that telegrams relating to military
                    operations should not be provided to the Richmond newspapers. The Vindicator
                    supports this action.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmay61.html#5.31b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Serious Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gooch</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>D.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonaghe</ln>
                        <fn>B.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Gooch, of Churchville, was hurt last Wednesday when the horses
                    attached to her carriage bolted during the dress parade at the military camp.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>State Capital</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>State Capital.</p>
                    <p>Now that the Capital of the Confederate States is to be removed to Richmond,
                        the opinion seems to be almost universal that Staunton will be selected as
                        the Capital of the State. We are sure no more desirable place could be found
                        within the limits of the Commonwealth. Liberal inducements would be offered
                        by our citizens.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator believes that Staunton may become the capital of Virginia
                    now that Richmond has become the capital of the Confederacy.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmay61.html#5.31a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>President Davis</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>President Davis arrived in Richmond on May 29th. This city will now be the
                    capital of the Confederacy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Lincoln, as Described by an Eyewitness</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A.H.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Stuart described Lincoln to a crowd at the Court House last Monday.
                    According to Stuart, Lincoln is a large and awkward man whose manners and
                    appearance "clearly indicated that he was not accustomed to good society, but
                    that he was a coarse, rude, and uncultivated man, with none of the
                    qualifications essential to grace the position he holds." Stuart also criticized
                    Lincoln's inaugural address as "insincere and double-faced." The Vindicator
                    reminds its readers that when the paper similarly denounced Lincoln's speech
                    shortly after the inauguration, it was "censured freely for our rashness and
                    want of charity." The paper believes that history has proven it correct.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Adj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Praises Maj. Harman, the Quartermaster and Commander at Staunton
                    Encampment, for his "extraordinary exertions in behalf of the State and the
                    Southern Confederacy."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The recent drought has injured the wheat crop.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Confederate Guards</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>J.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. Skinner is in the process of raising a volunteer company that will be
                    called the Confederate Guards.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The Indian Nation</head>
                <origin>New Orleans Picayune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A letter from the Indian Nation assures the Picayune that the Choctaws,
                    Cherokees, Seminoles, and Creeks will give a kind reception to the Commissioners
                    who have been appointed by the Louisiana State Convention to visit them. These
                    tribes are slaveholders, so they support secession and the Confederacy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1861.05.31.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>An Attack on Richmond</head>
                <origin>New York Tribune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Tribune states that 30,000 federal troops are ready to march from
                    Washington and capture Richmond. The paper believes that the first battle will
                    be at Culpeper.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>News dispatches from Alexandria and Manassas Junction, columns 1-2; new
                Confederate postal law, column 3; Richmond markets, column 4, Staunton Markets,
                column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
