<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1861/va.au.rv.1861.02.08">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Colleen Doody</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/7/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1861-02-08">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day norm="08">8</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1861.02.08.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Democracy of Ohio and the Doctrine of Coercion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Endorses a resolution of the Democratic State Convention of Ohio that
                    states that the North should fulfill its duties to the Constitution before
                    considering a policy of coercion. The Vindicator argues that, as it now stands,
                    the North is the aggressor and is entirely in the wrong.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Preparations for Coercion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"The following dispatch fully explains itself. The voters of Virginia
                    cannot now fail to perform their duty."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Dispatch from South Carolina stating that the federal government has
                    ordered reinforcements to Fort Sumpter. The dispatch asks if Virginia will not
                    interpose to prevent coercion before it is too late.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Senator Douglas' Speech--its Effect on the Senate--Graphic Description</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Douglas gave a much-anticipated speech on the present political crisis. It
                    was a "truly noble" speech that proved that Douglas is "the foremost statesman
                    in the country."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>"The Day of Compromise is Gone and the Day of Fighting Come"</head>
                <origin>Cincinnati Enquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We will tell what it was all for. It was because a set of demagogues, to
                    subserve their own ambitious purposes, made the people of the free States
                    believe that African slavery, in the Southern States, was a great moral, social,
                    and political evil, and should not be allowed to extend into new Territories."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asks why "the day of compromise is gone and the day of fighting come" and
                    argues that it was because of the actions and ambitions of demagogues.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Loyalty of a Slave</head>
                <origin>Cahaba (Ala.) Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A slave offered to aid a militia company in Alabama and stated that,
                    although he couldn't go himself (since he was a slave) he gladly made his money,
                    hogs, cows, and corn available.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1861.02.08.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Vote of Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Table of voting for the election of delegates to the State Convention.
                    Baldwin, Stuart, and Baylor won.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Why it Was So</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Why it Was So.</p>
                    <p>The election last Monday shews clearly that there was a wide spread panic in
                        this county--that the people were under the impression, to a considerable
                        extent, that they were voting upon a question of peace or war. Harman and
                        Imboden, the States Rights candidates, are as good Union men as Baldwin,
                        Stuart and Baylor, but because they advocated the policy of prompt and
                        decisive action on the part of Virginia, as the course best calculated to
                        bring about a satisfactory adjustment of our National troubles, they were
                        regarded as dangerous men to the peace of the country, and were voted
                        against by hundreds who believed their election would be equivalent to a
                        declaration of war, and might cause pestilence and famine? On the other
                        hand, hundreds of people thought that those who could denounce the seceding
                        States as the immediate authors of all our ills, and sing the praises of
                        Northern patriotism the loudest, could preserve the peace of the country and
                        save the Union. Well, we shall soon see who was right and who was wrong.</p>
                    <p>Another thing that contributed to the general alarm and excitement, was the
                            <emph rend="italic">statesmanlike</emph> and <emph rend="italic"
                            >accurate</emph> sensation epistle of Senator Stuart to his
                        constituents, in which he stated and intended it to be believed, as it was,
                        by the credulous, that negroes were already taxed $16 per head in South
                        Carolina, by way of a beginning, and that similar burdens would presently
                        fall upon land and other property! And in his speech on Court day followed
                        up the same idea to the conclusion, that in a short time we should exclaim
                        here in Virginia, "blessed is he that has nothing to be taxed." Mr. Stuart
                        has a financial turn of mind, and considers questions of political,
                        individual and States Rights, affecting the present and future honor and
                        equality of the people of half this Union, in the same light that he would a
                        project to make a turnpike from Christian's Creek to South River. <emph
                            rend="italic">Verb. sap.</emph> and more, anon.</p>
                    <p>We believe that in the march of events the people of Augusta will discover in
                        less than sixty days that the best way to preserve the peace of this
                        country, and the only way to bring back the States that have gone, is go
                            <emph rend="italic">demand</emph> a recognition of our rights in the
                        Union, and let the North know that we will take nothing less. If Virginia
                        takes this position our difficulties may be adjusted, perhaps. If she shews
                        a want a firmness now, all hope of a settlement is gone, and separation is
                        then sooner or later inevitable, and with separation in all probability will
                        come civil war. We are in the midst of fearful dangers, and there is no use
                        in trying to escape by taking counsel from the timid and the vacillating.
                        Dangers often recede before the bold and fearless. Let us all go to work and
                        be prepared to face whatever the future has in store for us in the spirit of
                        men of '76.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the election shows that "there was a wide spread panic in this
                    county-- that the people were under the impression . . . that they were voting
                    upon a question of peace or war."</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvfeb61.html#2.8a</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Contest Over</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The election is over, and the Vindicator fears that the vote of Augusta
                    indicates that "the death-knell of the Union has been tolled."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Sheriffalty</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn>H.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Towberman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Batis</ln>
                        <fn>J.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowrey</ln>
                        <fn>W.L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn>A.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lightner</ln>
                        <fn>A.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>List of deputies to Sheriff Peck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>What Can Virginia Do?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>What Can Virginia Do?</p>
                    <p>The return so far received from the election on Monday last, show that a
                        majority of "Union" candidates have been chosen over their "Secession"
                        opponents. The complete returns from the State will not be received in time
                        for publication in our issue of this week. We are glad to perceive that our
                        brethren of the press, in announcing the success of the "Union" men, are
                        very carefully guarding against a misapprehension on the part of the
                        Republican party at the North, of the position of the "Union" men elected.
                        The term "Union men" has a very different meaning in Virginia from that
                        generally applied to it at present in the North, and if the idea is taken up
                        out of the State that the election of a majority of "Union" men is
                        equivalent to the election of a majority in favor of quietly submitting to
                        the rule of Lincoln and a Black Republican administration, they will find
                        themselves most egregiously mistaken. We should be deeply grieved to think
                        that Virginia had fallen so low as quietly to submit to that rule without a
                        sufficient guarantee that every right of the South will be fully protected
                        in the future. We do not believe that there will be even a "corporal's
                        guard" of actual submissionists in the Convention. Messrs. Botts and Clemens
                        are considered "Union" men North of us--in Virginia, except by a few <emph
                            rend="italic">like themselves</emph>, they are looked upon as nearly as
                        dangerous men as Seward himself. Of <emph rend="italic">immediate</emph>
                        secessionists there will probably be about 25. In the classification of a
                        contemporary we see Gov. Wise put down as a Union man. Our Northern friends
                        will hardly count upon much from him. If, as is very generally believed, the
                        Convention now in session at Washington adjourns without accomplishing
                        anything more to the purpose than the famous "Committee of 33" of the House
                        of Representatives, there will be scarcely anything left for a Convention to
                        do, but to draw up an act of secession, and submit it immediately to the
                        people, so that their action may be known, one way or the other, before the
                        4th of March. That anything will be done at Washington, we have little hope.
                        Barely a majority of the Northern States are represented, and even these, by
                        legislative authority, have so instructed their delegates as to prevent any
                        conclusion being arrived at that will prove acceptable to the South.
                        War--war--war--and nothing else but war, not only of <emph rend="italic"
                            >words</emph> but <emph rend="italic">deeds</emph>, against the South
                        and its institutions, will satisfy the fanatical leaders of the Abolition
                        party. The fate of the Crittenden Resolutions in the Senate ought to satisfy
                        any reasonable man of the slightness of a hope of a satisfactory settlement
                        of affairs before the inauguration of the new President. Nothing short of
                        that basis will satisfy Virginia, and we do not believe that even that will
                        bring back the seceded States.</p>
                    <p>Let the result be what it may, we fully and firmly believe that Virginia will
                        stand by the rights of her sisters of the South, and if at last all efforts
                        at reconciliation are fruitless, we as Virginians will have the satisfaction
                        to know that we have left no means untried to bring about an adjustment. She
                        has twice, lately, given assurances of her deep and heartfelt attachment to
                        the Union as formed by our forefathers. She proposed the Convention of
                        States at Washington; and last of all, the election of a majority of Union
                        delegates, in spite of the bullying of Wade, Hale, Sumner, Wilson &amp;
                        Co., ought to be sufficient proof that, fully as she desires to stand by the
                        Federal Constitution, she will as fully vindicate her rights, when satisfied
                        that all hope of a peaceful adjustment of these difficulties is lost.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It appears that a majority of "Union" candidates have been elected over
                    their "Secession" opponents in the delegate races. Article points out that
                    "Union man" has a very different meaning in Virginia than it does in the North.
                    Virginia Union men will not quietly submit to the rule of the Black Republicans.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvfeb61.html#2.8b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Virginians view the turning of Washington, D.C. into an armed camp as a
                    "result of the silly fears of an old dotard [Gen. Scott]." They deny that there
                    is any secret organization in the State that is planning on seizing Federal
                    property in D.C.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"We call the attention . . ."</p>
                    <p>We call the attention of the editor of the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Spectator</emph> to the communication signed "Augusta," in to-day's paper.
                        We leave him with our correspondent, with the simple assertion, that the
                        friends of Judge Douglas can never be seduced into the embrace of any
                        Delilah in the shape of the Whig party. And one word further, that the <emph
                            rend="italic">Spectator</emph> man must first acquaint himself with the
                        reason and facts of history, before he attempts to read lectures to those
                        whose sense of honor aspires higher than probably the philosophy of certain
                        persons ever drempt of.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator calls the attention of the editor of the Spectator to a
                    letter signed "Augusta" in today's paper. The paper argues that "the friends of
                    Judge Douglas can never be seduced into the embrace of any Delilah in the shape
                    of the Whig party."</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvfeb61.html#2.8c</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Our State Defenses</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>If war does come, Virginia has sufficient men and excellent commanders.
                    However, it lacks arms and munitions. The men should be trained to shoot rifles
                    and minnie muskets, and should be taught simple tactics.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Our Streets</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our Streets</p>
                    <p>Who, under the order and control of our sublime Corporate authorities, has
                        charge of the higher streets, lanes and alleys of this ancient, and once
                        renowned, but now, alas! dilapidated borough?</p>
                    <p>Never, we believe since the era of chaos, when, as the geologists tell us,
                        this solid ball which men call earth, was one dismal flat of unmitigated mud
                        and ooze and slime, has there existed as muddy a place as this same town of
                        Staunton. Though the ground is still frozen beneath the sea of slush now
                        covering the main thoroughfares, still it (the mud) is deep enough to swim
                        pigs, and would, if the weather was warm enough, form a perfect paradise for
                        snapping turtles and alligators. But when the freeze breaks up, and the
                        streets are thawed to the bottom, then we say, let the short-legged public
                        beware how they tempt the dangers of August, Beverly and Lewis streets, or
                        Court-house alley. High top boots, come they up ever so high, will afford
                        them no protection. Could not there be limestone enough [word illegible]
                        within a couple of miles of town, sufficient to McAdamize slightly our
                        side-walks, if not the whole bed of the street. We would respectfully submit
                        to our town authorities, that limestone broken up in small pieces, and
                        spread evenly over the surface of the ground, makes in time a very good
                        road. We suggest to them, in all respectfulness, the propriety of trying the
                        experiment.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator questions who is in charge of the streets of Staunton, which
                    have become hopelessly muddy.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvfeb61.html#2.8d</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>List of men elected as delegates to the State Convention from every county
                    in Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Cheap Patriotism</head>
                <origin>New Hampshire Patriot</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes the cheap patriotism of Massachusetts, which offered the
                    President men and money to use against the South, but which refused to provide
                    soldiers for the War of 1812 and the Mexican War.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>"Some of the Supporters of Judge Douglas"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>For the Vindicator: "Some of the Supporters of Judge Douglas."</p>
                    <p>The Spectator heads an article thus, and says he has witnessed with
                        astonishment and mortification the course of the Douglas supporters who have
                        wheeled around and are now acting with the secession men. I don't know that
                        I am responsible to the Spectator man for my actions; but as he is as much
                        responsible to me as I am to him, I can tell him that I, too, have witnessed
                        with pain and mortification <emph rend="italic">his</emph> course. When a
                        man at this time deserts the South, and goes over, as the editor of the
                        Spectator has done, bag and baggage, to the enemies of this section, the
                        Union and their God, it does not become such a man to say aught to the
                        supporters of anybody. I think the times have changed since the Presidential
                        contest. If they have not, I for one have--Before I'll bend my knee to
                        Lincoln and Seward, and their Virginia cohorts, I will see this land run in
                        rivers of blood; and as the gallant supporters of Judge Douglas in the
                        Illinois Legislature have said to the Republican members, "If you attempt to
                        coerce the South, before you cross the Ohio river, you will have to pass
                        over the dead bodies of the men of Egypt,"--I tell the editor of the
                        Spectator, and all men of his kidney, that before they leave this good old
                        county on such a mission, their own firesides will be visited with civil
                        war. You know, Mr. Editor, that Judge Douglas had few warmer supporters in
                        this State than myself; but if it was to do over again, knowing that I was
                        in a minority, I would never play into the hands of the enemies of my faith
                        and section--I would not again divide my party or assist in anyway to do
                        it--I would sacrifice my private opinions and feelings, and go for the good
                        of the old Democratic party, through good and evil report.</p>
                    <p>AUGUSTA</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Augusta</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Denies the Spectator's assertion that Douglas supporters have allied with
                    the secession men and accuses the Spectator of deserting the South.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvfeb61.html#2.8e</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>For the Vindicator</p>
                    <p>The article under the signature of "Townsman," which appeared in the last
                        week's issue of your paper, meets our most cordial approval in the
                        suggestions it contains in reference to the disposition of a certain
                        unexpended sum of money, raised about a year ago, by means of a Fair held by
                        the ladies of the town, for the purpose of adorning and improving the
                        Cemetery grounds. The amount thus obtained, we have been informed, was
                        between six and seven hundred dollars, and we do more respectfully ask, that
                        the ladies in whose hands this fund was placed for safekeeping, will advise
                        the citizens of the precise amount, and whether it will be loaned for the
                        purpose indicated in the communication referred to. However, be this as it
                        may, we make the following proposition to Mr. "Townsman," and through him to
                        the gentlemen of Staunton, namely: That the ladies will raise five hundred
                        dollars, provided the gentlemen will make up the deficit necessary to <emph
                            rend="italic">thoroughly equip</emph> our two volunteer companies with
                        not only tents and knapsacks, but also with the most improved and effective
                        guns to be had, for we, the ladies of West Augusta, their mothers and wives
                        and daughters and sisters and sweethearts, are determined that they shall,
                        if necessary, do a little fighting as well as sleeping and eating. We know
                        nothing about it, but have been told that the guns now in possession of the
                        two companies are scarcely superior to bows and arrows compared with those
                        with which the enemy would be furnished, were such a calamity to befall us
                        as civil war. Therefore, we insist that those who profess to love us so
                        dearly, should be properly prepared to defend us against danger, should
                        occasion require it.</p>
                    <p>And now, Mr. "Townsman" and gentlemen of Staunton, let us assure you that we
                        mean what we say, and intend to accomplish it, if you will respond like men
                        and patriots to our PROPOSITION.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Proposition</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter agreeing with the proposition made by "Townsman" in last week's
                    paper. The ladies of Staunton will not only donate the money previously raised
                    for improving the Cemetery grounds, but will also raise $500 more to pay for
                    guns for the West Augusta Guard.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvfeb61.html#2.8f</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Report of Ex-President Tyler to Gov. Letcher, columns 5-7</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1861.02.08.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Convention</head>
                <origin>Richmond Dispatch</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that, although many so-called "Union" men were elected to the State
                    Convention, Northerners should not misunderstand this term and think that these
                    men will submit to the will of the federal government. The Virginia Convention
                    "will insist on a settlement of our present difficulties at this time in a
                    proper manner; and the only question of difference among its members will be as
                    to the length of time to be employed in efforts at the restoration of the
                    Union."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Earman</ln>
                        <fn>Jos. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hague</ln>
                        <fn>Harriet</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on February 6.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cummins</ln>
                        <fn>J.P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>H.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noel</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on December 25th in Ohio. Dr. Beard is formerly from Augusta while
                    Miss Noel is from Scioto county, Ohio.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>News from Fort Moultrie and Washington, column 1; brief discussion of the
                Seceded States Convention, column 2</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1861.02.08.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
