<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1863/pa.fr.fr.1863.09.16">
 <header>
  <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
  <tagger>
   <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass; Susanna Michele Lee, 2nd pass, 12/26/98</taggerName>
   <tagDate/>
   <tagNote/>
  </tagger>
  <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
  <date n="1863-09-16">
   <year>1863</year>
   <month norm="09">September</month>
   <day>16</day>
   <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
  </date>
  <frequency>weekly</frequency>
  <extent>08</extent>
  <editionNote/>
 </header>
 <paperBody>
  <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1863.09.16.01">
   <div type="l">
    <column>1</column>
    <head>WASHINGTON. Murders in Washington--Death of Lieut. Brannin--The Drafted Men--Military
     Orders--Gov. Curtin--Military Orders--Military Dignitaries Displaced--Distinguished Visitors in
     Washington.</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer>"Norval"</trailer>
    <names/>
    <summary>Details events in Washington including the examination of the drafted men. The
     correspondent suggests that Gov. Curtin appoint an agent to look after the wants and needs of
     every soldier in Washington.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>2</column>
    <head>Hon. Daniel Agnew</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Provides a biography of the Union party of Pennsylvania candidate for Judge of Supreme
     Court.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="l">
    <column>4</column>
    <head>Letter From President Lincoln</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary>"The following dispassionate and patriotic letter was written by President Lincoln
     to a meeting of the Union men at Springfield, Ill. It effectually silences all the copperhead
     clamor for peace on the ground that the rebels are ready to negotiate, and is followed by the
     assurance to the people, given with characteristic sincerity and frankness, that 'if any such
     proposition shall hereafter come it shall not be rejected and kept secret from you.' We subjoin
     the letter."</commentary>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer>"A. Lincoln"</trailer>
    <names/>
    <summary>Prints a letter written by Abraham Lincoln to a meeting of Union men. In his response
     to complaints about the war and fighting for the freedom of blacks, Lincoln states that those
     unwilling to fight for the freedom of should fight for the Union.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <pageNote/>
  </page>
  <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1863.09.16.02">
   <pageNote>The page includes the proclamation of election and advertisements.</pageNote>
  </page>
  <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1863.09.16.03">
   <div type="a">
    <column>1</column>
    <head>Address Of The Union State Central Committee</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer>Wayne McVeagh</trailer>
    <names/>
    <summary>Praises the President, his policies and support of the war, and the platform of the
     Union party.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>4</column>
    <head>Sword Presentation To Gen. Meade</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Reports the presentation by the Pennsylvania Reserve Corps of a sword to Maj. Gen. Geo.
     G. Meade, initially the Brigadier for that corps, and now the commander of the Army of the
     Potomac. The present Brigadier (of the Pa. Res. Corps) Gen. S. W. Crawford and Gov. Curtin gave
     speeches praising Meade's leadership, and he, in turn, spoke of the outstanding efforts of the
     Corps.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <pageNote/>
  </page>
  <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1863.09.16.04">
   <div type="a">
    <column>1</column>
    <head>The Situation</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Reports that Rosecrans and Burnside possession of Tennessee for the Union and reports
     Lee's movement to Richmond or to the Shenandoah Valley.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>2</column>
    <head>What Of The State?</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Estimates the Democrats' political power and predicts the voting in the various
     counties. The Repository predicts that Curtin will be victorious.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>4</column>
    <head>Rebel Aid To The Democrat</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt>"Gen. Lee must turn politician as well as warrior, and we believe he will prove the
     most successful politician the Confederacy ever produced. He may so move and direct his army as
     to produce political results, which, in their bearing upon this war, will prove more
     effectually than the bloodiest victories."</excerpt>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Links Confederate military campaigns and Northern Democrats. The author argues that a
     rebel victory encourages wavering Democrat supporters.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>5</column>
    <head/>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>McPherson</ln>
      <fn>E.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Hon.</pf>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>Thanks McPherson for the Report of the Committee on the Conduct of the War.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>5</column>
    <head>How to Prevent Raids</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt>"Copperheads are ever ready to whisper in the ears of our people that the government is
     neglecting us; that without troops we are at the mercy of rebel plunderers, and loyal men are
     appealed to in every way to desert the government and throw themselves into the arms of
     traitors."</excerpt>
    <transcript>
     <p>It is not to be disguised that the people of Franklin county have been much exercised during
      the last few weeks, because of the general apprehension that cavalry raids may be made upon
      us, plundering our people of horses, cattle and provender. We consider the apprehension well
      grounded, and unless the people themselves shall take prompt and effective steps to guard
      against such incursions, there can be no doubt about the result. We have had frequent
      complaints from different sections of the county against the government because it has not
      placed a large force upon our border. Such complaints are unreasonable and unjust. What force
      Gen. Couch has about him and at his disposal, it would not be best to state; but if he had
      50,000 men he could not protect the border of the States from rebel raids. It must be
      remembered that there are hundreds of miles of border exposed, all opening into rich valleys,
      and it is an utter impossibility to guard the entire line against well drilled and mounted men
      with daring and skil[l]ful leaders. They might be caught as was Morgan in Ohio and Streight in
      Mississippi; but they have every advantage in such an enterprise, and usually pay no respect
      to armies. Thus Stuart spent three days in Pennsylvania, plundering indiscriminately, during
      which he ran the arc of the circle around a Union army of 100,000 men; and although he was
      never over twenty miles from it, he escaped with his booty. So Stoneman made his grand raid
      around Lee, with rebel soldiers on every side; penetrated into the fortifications of Richmond,
      and returned in safety with his command. So Carter did in Tennessee, Grierson in Alabama, and
      Averill in Western Virginia, and so it will be until the end of the war.</p>
     <p>It is time our people understood that armies are no serious obstacle to cavalry raids. They
      may protect certain points, and by chance capture the raiders, but as a rule, when it is
      important to make a raid, the existence of an army is not deemed an insuperable obstacle. If
      the country be clear of armed citizens, raids can be made almost anywhere, and in spite of
      almost any numbers or the most skil[l]ful generalship. This has been the safety of our cavalry
      when penetrating into the enemy's country. The able bodied men are all in the rebel army, and
      if they only avoid the rebel armies, they have no resistance. So in the North, although
      abounding with able bodied men, they have been unorganized and unarmed, and could offer no
      obstacles.</p>
     <p><emph rend="italic">There is but one way to prevent raids, and in that one way they can be
       most effectually prevented.</emph> Cavalry detachments cannot penetrate a densely populated
      country like ours if the citizens are organized and armed. If we had 2,500 men organized in
      Franklin county, with experienced leaders such as we have in abundance in every district, and
      with their muskets and well filled cartridge-boxes at home, ready to fill up their company
      ranks as soon as a rebel should cross the Potomac, and to offer resistance in every locality
      where marauding parties should appear, there would be no raids attempted upon us. No raid
      could be made with such organizations assailing it at every step, for the contest would be too
      unequal and deadly. Every thicket, every hollow, every pass, would be fruitful of death, and
      the assailants could protect themselves almost entirely in such warfare. No rebel cavalry
      officer would dare to enter Franklin county if he knew that in every district there were
      experienced officers with well armed bands ready to cut him off and assail him from every
      shelter; but if Gen. Couch had 50,000 men in his Department, and the citizens unorganized and
      unarmed, Gen. Stuart would not hesitate an hour to traverse portions of our county, and he
      would have every advantage in the way of escape.</p>
     <p>Copperheads are ever ready to whisper in the ears of our people that the government is
      neglecting us; that without troops we are at the mercy of rebel plunderers; and loyal men are
      appealed to in every way to desert the government and throw themselves into the arms of
      traitors. We ask our people to look at the history of this war, and a little reflection will
      satisfy any honest, unprejudiced mind, that unless troops should be encamped immediately about
      him, they can afford no protection against raids. If we would not be plundered this fall, we
      must put every able-bodied man in a military company under tried soldiers--have them well
      armed and supplied with ammunition, and ready to fly to arms the moment a foe enters the
      county. If this be done promptly no rebel raids will be attempted--if it be not done, the
      whole Army of the Potomac could not cover our entire border nor protect all our people from
      rebel plunderers. Our militia laws furnish ample means to meet this emergency. Every company
      duly organized can have regularly commissioned officers, and be well armed at once and kept
      well supplied with ammunition; and we appeal to our people to show that they mean to do their
      whole duty in the matter of their own protection. It need cost no money, and very little time;
      and let it but be known that in every district of Franklin county there will be well armed
      companies to repel raids, and there can be no doubt but that raiders will give us a wide
      berth. When malignant copperheads complain of the government, propose to join them in taking a
      musket for home defence, remind them that it is our first duty to show our willingness to join
      in the defence of our homes and property, and they may be shamed into doing one good at in
      spite of themselves.</p>
     <p>We earnestly urge the immediate and thorough organization of companies in every district for
      this purpose. Chambersburg should have not less than five companies--let us not be behind in
      the work. Certainly 2,500 can be thus enrolled and armed, and if so, we may rest easy about
      raids. If we neglect it, the rebels must become duller than usual if they don't divide our
      stock and crops with us this fall, in spite of any army we could possibly have here. This is a
      clear duty; let it not be delayed. What district will be foremost in the good work?</p>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Suggests the formation of local military companies to prevent raids on Franklin County.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>6</column>
    <head>An Invasion</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Notes the caterpillar infestations in the trees of the area and a request to burn the
     nests.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <pageNote>The page includes articles urging Union voters to support their ticket.</pageNote>
  </page>
  <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1863.09.16.05">
   <div type="a">
    <column>1</column>
    <head>Important Order</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Reports Gen. Couch's order to settle accounts between locals and the army.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>1</column>
    <head>A Scare</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Describes the mistake of an escaped "lunatic" for a rebel prisoner.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>1</column>
    <head>Farmers' Association</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Walker</ln>
      <fn>W. W.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Rinehart</ln>
      <fn>Samuel B.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>Reports that Washington Township farmers organized an association to protect against
     horse thieves, with W. W. Walker as President and Samuel B. Rinehart as Secretary.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>1</column>
    <head>Telegraphic</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Mentions the completion of a new telegraphic line that connects Chambersburg with
     Philadelphia, Baltimore, and Pittsburgh.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>1</column>
    <head>Franklin Railroad</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Reports that the Franklin railroad was re-laid to Greencastle last week and that the
     trains run regularly to Hagerstown.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>1</column>
    <head>PHILADELPHIA. No Copperhead Triumph in 1863--Democrats Deserting the Party--The City
     Nominations--Gen. Butler to Canvass Pennsylvania--Postal Affairs--Judge Cadwallader Decides the
     Draft Constitutional--Union Meetings</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Reports the upcoming speech of Gen. Butler in Chambersburg to canvass for the election.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>2</column>
    <head>Victories for the Old Flag! Cheering From Charleston! Forts Wagner and Gregg Occupied by
     Union Troops! Morris Island Evacuated by the Rebels! The Siege Progressing Gloriously! East
     Tennessee Redeemed! Chattanooga And Knoxville Captured! Cumberland Gap Captured with its
     Garrison of 2,000 Rebels!. A Victory In Arkansas! The Capitol Captured! Fort Smith Occupied!</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Reports military news from Charleston.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="s">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>Married</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Barnhart</ln>
      <fn>Thos.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Rev.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Haynes</ln>
      <fn>Geo. W.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Lieut.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Holman</ln>
      <fn>Anna Cordelia</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Miss</pf>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>On Sept. 8th, at the M. E. Parsonage, in Chambersburg, the Rev. Thos. Barnhart married
     Lieut. Geo. W. Haynes, of Philadelphia to Anna Cordelia Holman, of St. Thomas.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="s">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>Married</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Breidenbaugh</ln>
      <fn>E.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Rev.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Byers</ln>
      <fn>J. Boggs</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Mr.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Balsley</ln>
      <fn>Sarah A.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Miss</pf>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>On Aug. 25th, Rev. E. Breidenbaugh married J. Boggs Byers, of Greencastle, to Sarah A.
     Balsley, of Shady Grove.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="s">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>Married</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Kennedy</ln>
      <fn>John</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Mr.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Apple</ln>
      <fn>T. G</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Rev.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Snively</ln>
      <fn>Melchi</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Mr.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Boyd</ln>
      <fn>Catharine</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Mrs.</pf>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>On June 9th, at the house of John Kennedy, Rev. T. G. Apple married Melchi Snively, of
     Shady Grove, to Catharine Boyd.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="s">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>Married</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Apple</ln>
      <fn>T. G.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Rev.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Stoner</ln>
      <fn>Joseph</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Mr.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Bush</ln>
      <fn>Sydney M.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Miss</pf>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>On June 10th, Rev. Apple married Joseph Stoner to Miss Sydney M. Bush.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="s">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>Married</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Apple</ln>
      <fn>T. G.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Rev.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Strine</ln>
      <fn>John W.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Mr.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Tabler</ln>
      <fn>Dorotha W.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Miss</pf>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>On June 12th, Rev. Apple married John W. Strine to Doratha W. Tabler, both of
     Martinsburg, Virginia.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="o">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>Died</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Witherspoon</ln>
      <fn>Mary Ann</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Mrs.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Witherspoon</ln>
      <fn>Wm. N.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Mr.</pf>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>On Sept. 5th, in Guilford Township, Mary Ann, wife of Wm. N. Witherspoon, died at the
     age of 46 years, 7 months, and 5 days.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="o">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>Died</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Carl</ln>
      <fn>Anna Emilie</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Carl</ln>
      <fn>Henry</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Mr.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Carl</ln>
      <fn>Catharine</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Mrs.</pf>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>On Aug. 25th, Anna Emilie Carl died at 16 days old, daughter of Henry and Catharine
     Carl.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="o">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>Died</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Glans</ln>
      <fn>Catharine</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>On Sept 8th, Catharine Glans died at the age of14 years, 8 months and 21 days.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="o">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>Died</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Schmidt</ln>
      <fn>John</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Mr.</pf>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>On Sept. 8th, John Schmidt died at the age of 32 years, 7 months and 27 days.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="o">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>Died</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Baker</ln>
      <fn>Ella May</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Baker</ln>
      <fn>Peter</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Baker</ln>
      <fn>Matilda</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>On Aug. 28th, in Stoufferstown, Ella May, infant daughter of Peter and Matilda Baker,
     died at the age of 1 year and 6 days.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="o">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>Died</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Reynolds</ln>
      <fn>Thomas</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Mr.</pf>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>On Sept. 5th, in Mercersburg, Thomas Reynolds died at age 79.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="o">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>Died</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Ring</ln>
      <fn>Nancy</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Mrs.</pf>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>On Sept. 5th, in Mercersburg, Nancy Ring died at 89 years.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="o">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>Died</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Wilkins</ln>
      <fn>Marshall</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>On Sept. 7th, in Mercersburg, Marshall Wilkins died at age 69.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="o">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>Died</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>King</ln>
      <fn>Samuel</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>King</ln>
      <fn>Lemuel</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>On Sept. 9th, in Chambersburg, Samuel, infant son of Lemuel King, died at 7 months and
     4 days.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="o">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>Died</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Renfrew</ln>
      <fn>John</fn>
      <sf>Sr.</sf>
      <pf>Mr.</pf>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>On Sept. 6th, John Renfrew, Sr., died in his 73rd year.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="o">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>Died</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Welsh</ln>
      <fn>Delila</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Welsh</ln>
      <fn>Jacob</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>On Aug. 31st, near Greencastle, Delila, daughter of Jacob Welsh, died at the age of 3
     years and 10 months.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="o">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>Died</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Garner</ln>
      <fn>Susan</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Garner</ln>
      <fn>Samuel</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>On Sept. 2nd, near Greencastle, Susan, daughter of Samuel Garner, died at the age of 5
     years, 7 months, and 16 days.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="o">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>Died</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Carbaugh</ln>
      <fn>Abraham</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>On Aug. 25th, near Greencastle, Abraham Carbaugh died in his 73rd year.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="o">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>Died</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Smith</ln>
      <fn>Mary E.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Miss</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Smith</ln>
      <fn>Samuel</fn>
      <sf>Jr.</sf>
      <pf/>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>On Sept. 2nd, near Greencastle, Mary E. Smith, daughter of the late Samuel Smith, Jr.,
     died at age 17 years and 4 months.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="o">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>Died</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Foster</ln>
      <fn>Henry</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>On Sept. 8th, near Greencastle, Henry Foster died at the age of 63 years, 1 month and 4
     days.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>4</column>
    <head>Latest News! From the Army of the Potomac---A Recconnaisances in Force--Heavy Skirmishing
     as Culpepper--General Pleasanton Captures Guns and Prisoners</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Describes skirmishes in Virginia.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>4</column>
    <head>General Burnside's Resignation</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Notes that the President received but refuses to accept Burnside's resignation.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <pageNote>The page includes advertisements and market reports.</pageNote>
  </page>
  <page n="06" image="pa.fr.fr.1863.09.16.06">
   <pageNote>The page includes advertisements.</pageNote>
  </page>
  <page n="07" image="pa.fr.fr.1863.09.16.07">
   <pageNote>The page includes advertisements and train schedules.</pageNote>
  </page>
  <page n="08" image="pa.fr.fr.1863.09.16.08">
   <pageNote>The page includes advertisements, political items from around the state, and legal
    notices.</pageNote>
  </page>
 </paperBody>
</hwp>
