<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1861/va.au.ss.1861.10.22">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/08/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>Colleen Doody second pass, 6/7/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1861-10-22">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day>22</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1861.10.22.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>News from Western Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>News regarding troop movements in northwestern Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Prevention Better than Cure</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the bridge over Christian's Creek on the Staunton-Waynesboro
                    road is in need of repair. If an accident occurs, those responsible for the
                    bridge's upkeep will be held accountable.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Approaching Elections</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The election for President, members of Congress, are close at hand. They take
                        place on the first Wednesday in next month. With regard to the Presidential
                        election we have nothing to say, except that it is important for every man
                        who has a vote to give it. The Yankees, with Lincoln at their head, have
                        been contending all along that the secession of the Southern States is a
                        mere partizan movement on a small scale, gotten up by discontented
                        politicians, and that the great body of the people not only do not
                        sympathize with it, but are at heart bitterly opposed to it. This is or was
                        one of the pretexts alleged for invading the State of Virginia. It was
                        contended that a reign of terror existed here, and that the people voted
                        under its influence. It was confidently stated that if freedom of choice
                        were allowed, the large majority would be found opposed to secession, and
                        the federal army was designed to set opinion at liberty, and enable the
                        friends of the Union to express their preference without the fear of bodily
                        harm. Even now the Yankee papers, in sketching their programmes for a winter
                        campaign in the South, reckon largely upon the sympathy of vast bodies whom
                        they suppose to be attached to the old system. There never was a falser
                        assumption, it is true. But it has not been without its effect at the North,
                        where men, if they could be convinced that the whole Southern army was
                        arrayed in heart and soul against the restoration of the Union, would be apt
                        to see the folly of waging a long and expensive war for so unattainable an
                        object. It is proper that these men--That Europe--that the whole
                        world--should be taught the true state of the case, and they can only be
                        taught by the voters of the Southern States. Let the vote be thin, and the
                        people careless and willing to suffer the election to go by default, and
                        they will still have ground for maintaining their present position. Let the
                        turn-out be general, the movement enthusiastic, the vote large, and no
                        ground will be left them to stand upon. We therefore hope that there will be
                        no remissness in this respect. Let every man who can get to the polls
                        deposit his vote. Let none think because there is no opposition, there is no
                        danger, and therefore no occasion for exertion. A large vote, we tell all
                        persons disposed to indulge any chimerical notion to the contrary, is more
                        important now than it ever was before. We must show the world, who are
                        watching us with the deepest interest--we must show our friends abroad, who
                        are watching us with the deepest anxiety--we must show the Yankees and their
                        government, who are watching us with the deepest malignity--that we are a
                        great, united people. That the opposition among us is so small as scarcely
                        to make up that sort of exception which is said to prove a general rule.
                        That the whole Southern people are united in opposition to the old
                        Government, and in favor of the new. That the crisis, in the midst of which
                        we exist, is a mighty revolution, which it is wanton wickedness, in a
                        supreme degree, to attempt to suppress by means of an armed force. That it
                        is the strongly expressed desire of a vast country to change its system of
                        government, as every community under the sun has an undoubted right to
                    do.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges the citizens to turn out and vote to show that the South is united in
                    the cause of the Confederacy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Gen. Buckner and Judge Underwood</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item reports a correspondence between Gen. Buckner, leader of Confederate
                    forces in Kentucky at Bowling Green, and Judge Underwood, a Unionist of the
                    Kentucky legislature and a citizen of Bowling Green. Underwood asks Buckner if
                    he will be permitted to return to Bowling Green to his family. Buckner replies
                    in the affirmative and vows to protect his personal liberty.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Memphis Appeal and New York Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The man who fights simply because he is compelled to do so, will be very
                    likely to forget his devotion to his country when bullets are whistling around
                    him and prove his devotion to himself by running away."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Memphis Appeal asserts that drafting has been discontinued in the
                    North. The New York Times alleges that draftees will not fight.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Clarkesville (Tenn.) Chronicle</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asserts that any Northern hope for a reconstruction of the Union had best
                    be abandoned for such hope does not exist.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Accuses Lincoln of hypocrisy for opposing Fremont's proclamation to free
                    the slaves in Missouri while allowing the Army of the Potomac to carry out such
                    a program in Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item reports that Henry A. Barron has been imprisoned at Wheeling on a
                    charge of treason.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Confederate States' Elections</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item reminds voters that the election will take place the first Wednesday
                    in November.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hodge</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>E.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Youel</ln>
                        <fn>F.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kunkle</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kunkle</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kunkle</ln>
                        <fn>M.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Mollie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>W.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Item lists additional donations received by Rev. Campbell.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>What it Costs Them</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Outlines the monetary costs of the Northern war effort.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A Full Vote</head>
                <origin>New Orleans Bee and Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Southern papers encourage a full vote to disprove the Yankee assertion that
                    many in the South do not favor Southern independence.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>EDITOR SPECTATOR: <emph rend="italic">Dear Sir</emph>, It is my duty to
                        respond to the call made upon me by "Manassas," contained in your paper of
                        the 8th instant, asking my consent to become a candidate for a seat in
                        Congress from this District. The call is flattering beyond my merit, and I
                        am not insensible to the high honor it proposes for me. </p>
                    <p>The sentiment of the lamented Lowndes is more often quoted and applauded by
                        aspiring politicians than followed by them. That sentiment was, that "office
                        is neither to be sought after nor shunned by any good citizen, but should be
                        the free gift of the people."</p>
                    <p>Now, if no other obstacle stood in the way, the fact that I do not, and
                        cannot, suppose myself looked to by the people of the district to serve them
                        in this present great emergency, would of itself suffice to determine my
                        position. Excepting only this public call from "Manassas," and the
                        solicitations of a few friends, personally, and by letter from Rockbridge
                        and Augusta counties, since that publication, and endorsing the same, I have
                        no evidence that I have been thought of in that connection. Moreover, so
                        long have I been withdrawn from the public service, and from all
                        participation in public affairs--except to cast my vote at the polls--that I
                        must be personally, and even by name, unknown to a large majority of the
                        voters. Add to this the just claims of my business upon my time and
                        attention, and I am sure I shall stand excused and justified, even by my
                        most partial friend, for preferring to occupy a private post, and in that
                        post doing whatever I can to maintain and further the sacred cause.</p>
                    <p>Here I might stop; but I have some things to say, which, if you have room and
                        disposition to print them, I will offer as <emph rend="italic">my</emph>
                        contribution to the public expression of popular sentiment about this war
                        and the manner of conducting it. </p>
                    <p>That, on <emph rend="italic">our</emph> part, it is a war waged in defence of
                        our liberties, our homes, our altars, our very existence as a people, all of
                        us must admit and the impartial world will attest. That, on the part of our
                        foes, so lately our fellow-citizens and brethren, it is now become a war of
                        sujugation [sic], even to extermination, all their leading organs of opinion
                        unblushingly avow and all their acts unmistakably show. That in seeking our
                        overthrow and utter destruction they are animated by a spirit the most
                        fiendish, and are daily committing within our borders crimes the most
                        atrocious, impartial History, the arbiter of nations, must forever record to
                        their eternal infamy. </p>
                    <p>This being "the situation," what is our duty to our selves and our children?
                        What does common sense dictate? Let "Manassas" answer in one brief, pithy,
                        pregnant sentence: "<emph rend="italic">If it takes every man and every
                            dollar in the whole South to maintain our cause the sacrifice must be
                            made</emph>." </p>
                    <p>Have we and the whole South yet begun to come up to that high standard? This
                        beloved old Commonwealth <emph rend="italic">did</emph> in May and June last
                        offer herself in the full measure of that spirit of self-sacrifice. She who
                        had so magnanimously played out to its last act, the <emph rend="italic"
                            >role</emph> of peace and the part of peace-maker, now as nobly took
                        upon herself the <emph rend="italic">role</emph> of war and rushed to the
                        van of the conflict. She offered fifty thousand more volunteers than she had
                        already put in the field, and they were refused; were told their services
                        were not wanted. The spirit of the people was repressed by official
                        proclamation. Assuredly, <emph rend="italic">at that time</emph>, the State
                        authorities had not risen to the "mark of their high calling." Have they and
                        the Confederate authorities since? It is the most earnest, anxious,
                        unanimous wish of the people to believe that they have, and to be warranted
                        in the belief by the energy of their acts. But what have we done? Our armies
                        win battles, and we lose territory! Which is all one to say, the valor of
                        our troops vanquishes the foe, but the supineness of our administration
                        reaps no fruit of victory. </p>
                    <p>On the part of the South this is a defensive war. But does that imply or
                        require that we shall stand forever within our own limits and await the
                        attack? Being begun in defence of our every right, is it any the less a war
                        of defence if we strike the enemy in whatever vital part we can reach? Shall
                        we stand within our lines and make proclamation to him by our acts? "Come
                        over to us; leave all your homes unguarded, all your property unprotected.
                        Spare none of your force in their defence, for we shall not assail or molest
                        them where they are, nor even aim to injure your persons except you be found
                        within our territory!" And this to a people who are ravaging us by sea and
                        land! Was ever a proposition more preposterous? Could any war be more
                        sentimentally insane than one conducted on such a theory?</p>
                    <p>Of course we must not assume the offensive till we are prepared. But we <emph
                            rend="italic">can</emph> be fully prepared by the opening of the
                        campaign of 1862, if we will--if Congress wills it and decrees it. Let camps
                        of instruction be established in every State of the Confederacy. Let the
                        quota of each State be fixed by Law, and if the requisition be not
                        forthcoming by volunteers offering their services, let a pro rate draft of
                        the militia be made forthwith, say, if you please, 10 per cent, or 15 per
                        cent. It will be found in every State I doubt not, as I know to be the case
                        in Virginia, that some companies and regiments have already contributed
                        their full, and much more than their full quota, whilst others have done far
                        less than their just proportion. Let these new levies go into camp early in
                        1862; and a single month's rigid, vigorous training will turn them out
                        soldiers of the very best stamp. They are already such in every element,
                        with only the want of a little practice in the manual of arms and skill to
                        move in company and battallion [sic]. </p>
                    <p>I am no military man, and have no skill to plan a campaign, but one thing
                        seems obvious to me as the noon-day sun, and that is, we shall never conquer
                        a peace except we are strong enough and energetic enough to dictate it
                        either in old Independence Hall, Philadelphia, or in New York City, or on
                        Boston Common, at the base of Webster's statue, according as the backbone of
                        the Washington despotism is more or less strong.</p>
                    <p>Whilst I am glancing at the duties of our first Confederate Congress under
                        the Constitution, I take the liberty to say they will be criminally direlict
                        [sic] if they fail to probe to the bottom abuses in the Commissariat and in
                        the Medical Staff and the Hospital; possibly, also, in the Quartermaster's
                        Department, though I know less of that.</p>
                    <p>If it be found that nepotism or favoritism in dispensing Government "<emph
                            rend="italic">patronage</emph>" (I think the very word is loathsome) has
                        already crept into the Executive offices, and should high officials be found
                        more concerned about the fleshpots than about the public liberty and safety
                        in this great crisis, then, wherein are we better off than under the old and
                        broken down government? I will not assume that such is now the fact; but,
                        like causes produce like effects. We are living under the same Constitution
                        (with a few slight amendments) than nominally obtains at Washington. A
                        system of government more beautiful in theory and more beneficent in
                        practice, wit and wisdom and patriotism of man never before devised and
                        never will again. And so long as it was administered in the wisdom and
                        purity of patriotism of its founders, it vindicated their highest claims to
                        immortality. But that enormous "patronage" of the Federal head presently
                        grew too strong for State sovereignty, or even for popular liberty; and
                        behold the result in the truncated remnant of the United States! Thank God
                        we are cut loose from them, and I trust forever. </p>
                    <p>But, hastening to the conclusion of the whole matter, for I have already
                        trespassed too long upon your patience, if we would preserve our liberties
                        after securing them, we must cut off this fruitful source of corruption by
                        limiting within far narrower bounds than at present the powers and functions
                        of the Confederate Congress and the Executive head. We must reduce and
                        simplify its governmental machinery by reducing the scope and object of its
                        jurisdiction--we must reserve to the States, severally, and to the people a
                        far larger residuum of power, delegating to the Confederate agent a few
                        important specific duties. In fine, we must not aim at a grand Union of
                        States presently to be merged into one nationality, but strive for a simple
                        league of independent, co-equal sovereignties, each jealous of its own
                        rights and honor.</p>
                    <p>Submitting these views for your consideration as a public journalist, and for
                        the consideration of the people who have, in common with you and myself, a
                        deep and abiding interest in the whole subject, I subscribe myself,</p>
                    <p>Very respectfully, <lb/>WM. FRAZIER. <lb/>Rockbridge Alum Springs, Oct. 16,
                        '61. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>William Frazier</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>William Frazier of Rockbridge declines the nomination to run for Congress.
                    In his letter, he urges those who do run to stand on a platform of military
                    offense and urges that preparations be made to attack the North.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Asst. Surg. Isaac White</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asst. Surgeon Isaac White of the 31st Regiment wishes to thank the ladies
                    of Staunton for goods donated to his Regiment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Augusta</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut. Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut. Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Writer nominates William Baylor to stand for election to Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>To the Friends of the West Augusta Guard</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>James H. Waters, Capt. West Augusta Guard</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCuflin</ln>
                        <fn>D.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bledsoe</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waters</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter from a soldier appeals to the citizens of Augusta to donate blankets
                    and warm clothing to the West Augusta Guard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>A Dreadful Result of our Victory at Manassas</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>MR. EDITOR: Unmistakable signs of the times point to what may prove a fatal
                        result of our victory at Manassas--<emph rend="italic">an over confident and
                            boastful spirit</emph>--and its necessary consequences--inactivity. In
                        the beginning of the war, whilst we knew our cause was just, we also felt
                        our comparative weakness and hence betook ourselves, by a day of
                        humiliation, fasting and prayer, to our only sure refuge--the great God of
                        battles. We adopted our motto: "God and our rights." The result was seen in
                        the battles which ensued, but nowhere more remarkably than at Manassas in
                        the mysterious panic of the enemy and their utter overthrow, just at the
                        moment of their apparent victory. We have since indulged in a boastful
                        spirit, and said it was the strength of <emph rend="italic">our</emph> bow
                        and the might of our arm which got us this victory, and have forgotten the
                        mighty God who brought about this result. We have dropped into a fatal
                        indifference, and a vain, confident spirit that, we hear, may require a
                        terrible defeat to dispel. Many have ceased to <emph rend="italic"
                        >toil</emph>, and we fear to <emph rend="italic">pray</emph>, for our
                        success. Levity is taking the place of the gravity becoming the calamities
                        we are suffering. Amusements have supplanted the little "lint and bandage
                        circles," and the little "what-can-we-do-for-our-army circles" which once
                        showed the interest we felt in our soldiers and cause. </p>
                    <p>Is it a time to grow lukewarm, to forsake God, to court amusements and to
                        indulge in levity? We have thousands of sick to be restored; we have three
                        hundred thousand brave and valuable men in the field, and to keep them <emph
                            rend="italic">efficient</emph> requires not only all that the Department
                        at Richmond can do, but the earnest, private efforts of every true Southern
                        man and woman who longs for our independence. </p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">We are upon the eve of another great battle</emph>. Let
                        us awake to the nature of its untold results. Let us show our patriotism not
                        only by what we can <emph rend="italic">say</emph> but by what we can <emph
                            rend="italic">do</emph>. Not in finding <emph rend="italic"
                        >fault</emph>, but striving to <emph rend="italic">remedy</emph> the evils
                        we see; not in provoking God by levity, profanity, and a wicked neglect of
                        Him and His truth, but by a solemn regard to his precepts and earnest prayer
                        in public and private. Let a dignified gravity pervade the public mind. Let
                        our temples be filled with His worshippers, and, by taking Him for their
                        "defence and shield," secure His mighty aid, which will give us the victory
                        and a speedy and peaceful enjoyment of our rights. </p>
                    <p>AN OFFICER IN THE CONFEDERATE SERVICE.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>An Officer in the Confederate Service</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Writer asserts that, since the victory at Manassas, the troops have become
                    boastful and have forgotten that it was God that gave them the victory, not
                    their own might.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>A Tribute of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn>R.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swink</ln>
                        <fn>William Weade</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Resolutions adopted by the Augusta Lee Rifles regarding the death of
                    Private Swain.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Gen. Buckner</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item contains a brief biography of Gen. Buckner, who commands the Kentucky
                    States' Rights troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>To the Voters of the 11th Congressional District</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coffman</ln>
                        <fn>S.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Coffman announces his candidacy for Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Announcements</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Kenton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coffman</ln>
                        <fn>S.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces Baldwin, Harper, and Coffman as candidates for Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Bowman died of typhoid fever on September 24.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alexander Craig died of typhoid fever near Manassas Junction on September
                    26 at age 34. He was a member of the Southern Guard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Various reports of skirmishes. Page not clearly legible in various
            sections.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1861.10.22.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>East Tennessee</head>
                <origin>Memphis Appeal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that an attempt to raise a Confederate regiment in East Tennessee
                    may not be challenged by the so-called Unionists of the area.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Good for Thirsty Soldiers</head>
                <origin>Nashville Patriot</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Nashville Patriot</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Recommends using old coffee grounds as a preventative for thirst.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Patriot's Charge to his Sons</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Transcript from the will of Col. George Mason, who wrote the first
                    Constitution of Virginia. In it he charges his sons to defend their country
                    without regard to party preferences.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>New York Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asserts that political infighting is raging in the North and that
                    volunteering is at a standstill.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
