<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1861/va.au.ss.1861.11.05">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/08/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>Colleen Doody second pass, 6/7/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1861-11-05">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day norm="05">5</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1861.11.05.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Situation</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The Confederate States, on the other hand, promised nothing, threatened
                    nothing, but simply asked to be 'let alone.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Yankee States having commenced the war against the South, having avowed
                        the policy of coercion, and pledged themselves to punish "the rebels" and
                        restore the Union, have taken upon themselves the onus of aggression. It is
                        theirs to wage war, ours to resist; theirs to assail, ours to defend. We do
                        not mean to say that we think it our true policy to remain on the defensive;
                        we are not about to discuss that question but simply to remind the reader
                        that the role of aggressive and invasive war is that which the Yankees have
                        chosen for themselves, and that which they must continue, and succeed in, or
                        stand before the world defeated. Having undertaken to overrun and subjugate
                        the South, every day of inaction, every measure merely defensive, every
                        retrograde movement, is something equivalent to defeat---is a confession
                        that they have undertaken what they are not capable off accomplishing. Never
                        did a people swagger more in the outset, or thunder more in the preparation,
                        of hostilities than did they. Amid insolence and bombast and bravado, such
                        as the world never saw, they raised, equipped and organized the "Grand Army"
                        that was to quarter in the Capital of the Rebels by the 4th of July, at
                        farthest. Another Grand Army was to descend the valley of the Mississippi
                        and sweep everything before it. Huge fleets were to flock along the coast
                        and open all the cotton ports to the world. Yankeedom, in fine, was to
                        ravage unresisted and roar without reply. Such was the promise they held out
                        to the astonished world, such the menace they fulmined over our devoted
                        heads. Before this time, we were to have been severely chastised, and humbly
                        suing for peace. The Confederate States, on the other hand, promised
                        nothing, threatened nothing but simply asked to be "let alone." In their new
                        relation, they disclaimed all hostile feeling or purpose, and tendered
                        political amity and reciprocal commerce. When these were rejected and war
                        denounced, they mustered for defence. They accepted the war as something not
                        to be avoided, and to be resisted as long as it might be waged. This was
                            <emph rend="italic">their</emph> role. For them, merely to escape
                        subjugation was victory. To hold the enemy at arm's length was triumph.
                        These were the respective attitudes of the parties to the war at the
                        beginning, and so they remain. Thus far the Yankee undertaking has been
                        unmitigated and ignominious failure--while the undertaking of the
                        Confederate States has been a glorious success. They have failed in
                        everything of consequence they have attempted. We have succeeded in
                        everything of consequence we have attempted. They undertook, first, to
                        frighten us by bullyism, and failed. They undertook next, in the Sumter
                        business, to over-reach us by fraud and trickery, and failed. Then they
                        undertook to raise an army before whose ponderous battalions we would quail
                        and succumb, and they failed. They undertook to surround us with the
                        Anaconda folds of their vast army and compress us into submission, and they
                        failed. They undertook by a blockade to deprive us of the necessaries of
                        life and starve us into subjection, and they failed. They undertook to push
                        their way into our dominions by the irresistible momentum of serried ranks
                        and countless hosts, and failed. They undertook to win victories, and
                        failed. They undertook to cut off all communication between us and foreign
                        countries, and failed. They solicited sympathy and co-operation from
                        European governments, and failed to obtain them. They sought to obtain the
                        services of military leaders of note from abroad, and failed. They have
                        failed in all these and other undertakings, and each of their failures has
                        been our triumph. They have succeeded in putting chains upon helpless
                        Maryland, but only for a time. Those fetters will be burst, and the star of
                        the brave little Commonwealth will yet shine resplendent in the Southern
                        heavens. They have succeeded in buying, at more than they were worth, a
                        number of traitors in Northwestern Virginia, in Kentucky and Missouri. They
                        have succeeded in throwing into their dungeons some true and good men, and a
                        few undefended women. Beyond these things, they have succeeded in alienating
                        forever the land which was the nursing mother of all their prosperity; in
                        forfeiting the respect of other nations; in destroying their constitution
                        and all the defences of liberty; in converting a free government into a
                        despotism; in demonstrating that they are unworthy of freedom, because
                        incapable of maintaining it; and in convincing the people by whom they
                        desired most of all to be thought heroic and martial, that the "military is
                        not their line." These are the results of the war, so far; and this is what
                        we conceive to be "the situation." --<emph rend="italic">Rich. Whig</emph>.
                    </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article ridicules the ineffectiveness of the Yankee war effort.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Rockingham Teams--Patriotic Conduct</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that several citizens of Rockingham have voluntarily sent their
                    wagons and teams to Staunton to haul for the government free of charge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Buildings Burned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>J.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that the buildings formerly used as the freight depot for the
                    Virginia Central Railroad in Staunton burned down.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the judge released Union prisoners held in the Staunton jail.
                    These men voluntarily took the oath of allegiance to the Confederacy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports a collision between a mail train and a stationary freight train.
                    The engineer was slightly injured.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>By the President, A Proclamation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>President Davis released a proclamation declaring the 15th of November to
                    be a day of prayer and fasting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>To the People of Augusta County</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>John B. Baldwin</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announcement of Col. Baldwin's resignation from the State Convention
                    because of his duties as a military officer. Because of a delay in the mail, the
                    announcement was received and printed a week late.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A Citizen</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Writer complains that a street between the Virginia Hotel and the R.R.
                    bridge is badly in need of repair.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Gratifying</head>
                <origin>Petersburg Express</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises the thrift of the citizens who are wearing old clothing in order to
                    conserve for the war effort.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Meeting of the Augusta Lee Rifles</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn>R.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Augusta Lee Rifles thank the Ladies of Staunton for their donations to
                    the Army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>A John Brown Company</head>
                <origin>New York Tribune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item reports a company commanded by John Brown Jr. is preparing to take the
                    field for the Yankees.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lambert</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Capt. Samuel Lambert has died.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newton</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooks</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tinsley</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moffett</ln>
                        <fn>B.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howell</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howell</ln>
                        <fn>L.V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moffett</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaffer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stribling</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Table shows additional donations made to the Army and the ladies who
                    supplied them.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Blankets Scarce</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item reports a scarcity of blankets in the Union army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Announcements</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Kenton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists those running for the Confederate Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Another Strange Fact</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Encourages citizens to procure hog bristles from their own hogs rather than
                    buying them at the market.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>By the Governor of Virginia, A Proclamation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Governor's proclamation announces the vacancy in the Convention left by
                    Baldwin's resignation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCaden</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Hall and Miss McCaden, half sisters, died of typhoid on October 4 near
                    Greenville.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhyan</ln>
                        <fn>Latitia A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhyan</ln>
                        <fn>Nicholas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Latitia Rhyan died on September 21 at age 16. She had been a member of the
                    United Brethren in Christ for two years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Wayt</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sarah Bell, wife of Wayt Bell, died on November 22 at age 31. She was a
                    member of the Presbyterian Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Various items reporting military maneuvers. Detailed accounts of battles and
                skirmishes, including Leesburg. Also items reporting new military appointments.
                Column 7 contains a list of letters remaining at the Staunton Post
            Office.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1861.11.05.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Happy Reply</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An anecdote from a prisoner exchange ceremony where a toast was made by a
                    federal officer to "The name of George Washington" and a Confederate officer
                    added "the first rebel" to the toast.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Two items regarding military maneuvers. Majority of page ads. Page largely
                illegible.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
