<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1861/va.au.ss.1861.09.24">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/08/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>Colleen Doody second pass, 6/7/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1861-09-24">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day>24</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1861.09.24.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Poor Kentucky</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"This noble...state...is now degraded and debased by affiliation with the
                    despotic Lincoln Government which has trampled ruthlessly upon every principle
                    of freedom."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item ridicules Kentucky for its decision to remain in the Union and to
                    remain neutral.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Beware--Treasury Notes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Confederate treasurer reports that a load of ten dollar notes was
                    stolen. The thieves have been arrested, but the treasurer wishes to remove the
                    notes from circulation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>To the Patriotic Ladies of the Valley of Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article encourages the ladies of the Valley to donate blankets and clothing
                    to the war effort.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Address on the War</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Regester</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announcement of an address by Rev. Regester to the citizens of Staunton on
                    the war at 7pm on the 24th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Loyalty of Slaves</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that slaves belonging to Mr. Terrill and Mr. Mays of Bath County
                    who were hired out in Kanawah County fled back to their masters as the Yankees
                    approached.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Good Cigars</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>J.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Item reports that Mr. Johnson has opened a tobacco store in Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Prisoners</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item reports that sixty prisoners of war held in Staunton were moved to
                    Richmond.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Skirmishing on the Potomac</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports continued skirmishing around the Potomac River.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Plot to Escape Discovered</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An escape plot among Yankee prisoners held in Richmond at Liggon's tobacco
                    factory was discovered.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Candidates for Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that the election for the Confederate Congress will be held on
                    the 6th of November. No Augusta candidates had yet announced at press time.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Difference of Opinion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the brothers-in-law of Abe Lincoln and John Fremont are
                    fighting on Virginia soil for the Confederacy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The system of unconstitutional, unlawful and despotic arrests and
                        imprisonments now carried on by the Lincoln Government, is an evidence of
                        conscious weakness, and would never be resorted to by a government which had
                        the slightest confidence in its own strength. That nothing of the kind
                        occurs under the Administration of President Davis, is a clear demonstration
                        that the Southern Government is embedded in the popular affections, and that
                        thrice armed in that panoply, it feels secure, both of the justice and the
                        might of its case.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asserts that the suspension of liberties in the North is a sign of the
                    weakness of the Government and notes that no similar suspensions of liberties
                    has occurred in the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Amicus</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Writer encourages the citizenry to send blankets and warm clothes to the
                    men in the military.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>A Response to Fremont</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>M. Jeff Thompson</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>A transcript of a letter from a Missouri State Guardsman critical of Maj.
                    Gen. Fremont's pro-Union position. The writer threatens to hang a Yankee soldier
                    for every Confederate hanged under Fremont's decree.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Maryland</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A gentleman who was recently in Maryland, gives us a very interesting account
                        of the state of feeling among the people and of the horrible despotism of
                        the Yankee mercenaries. Arrests are nightly made of the most respectable
                        citizens; and in large districts of country, men never sleep at home. They
                        seek safety in the woods. Rougeries and outrages of all kinds are constantly
                        perpetrated. The negroes, almost without an exception, are true to their
                        masters, and have an intenser hate of the Yankees than even their mistresses
                        have. Very often, through their vigilance, their masters have been enabled
                        to escape the myrmidons of Lincoln. The wish, the prayer of the whole
                        population, white and black, men, women and children, is for the early
                        coming of Jeff. Davis' Army of DELIVERANCE. When that day does arrive, it
                        will witness such an uprising-- such an exterminating fury as the world has
                        never seen. The New York <emph rend="italic">Herald</emph> states that the
                        Maryland population is so intense Rebellious that a Confederate army could
                        march from the Potomac to Baltimore without the fact being made known to the
                        Federal authorities by any of the inhabitants. Surely, such a people,
                        outraged and panting for liberty, have a right to all our sympathies and to
                        all the aid our arms can give them. <emph rend="italic">Rich.
                    Whig</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Rich. Whig</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Details the suspension of liberties in Maryland and asserts that the people
                    there view the Confederate army as a liberating force.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Examination on a Charge of Treason</head>
                <origin>Charleston Free Press</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Charleston Free Press</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>A citizen in Berkeley County has been brought to court to answer a charge
                    of "entertaining treasonable sentiments towards the Southern Confederacy."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nelson</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Wayt</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guthrie</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guthrie</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Francisco</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter reports the donations received at the Staunton Military Hospital
                    since August 17.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Report of Deaths in the General Hospital at Staunton from its Establishment to
                    September 17, 1861</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Details the deaths that have occurred at the military hospital in Staunton
                    since September 17.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>John J. Fry</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A tribute to John J. Fry of Wheeling who remained loyal to the Confederacy
                    and died in battle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Women of the South</head>
                <origin>Vicksburg Sun</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"If anything could inspire courage in the hearts of cowards, or could
                    infuse the dauntless spirit of patriot heroes in our people, it would be the
                    glorious valor and enthusiastic devotion displayed universally, by our
                    unequalled women."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Laudatory article about the women of the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheeler</ln>
                        <fn>J.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roote</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkett</ln>
                        <fn>Evaline F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on September 19.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died in Staunton on August 22 at age 25. He was a member of the Greenbrier
                    Rifles.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baer</ln>
                        <fn>David H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on September 15 at Hightown, Highland County. He was a member of the
                    Churchville Cavalry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Various reports of battles and skirmishes. Column 7 lists markets and
                advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1861.09.24.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Patriotic</head>
                <origin>Memphis Appeal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lauds the efforts of the ladies in providing clothing and other goods for
                    the soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Unhappy Maryland</head>
                <origin>Richmond Dispatch</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Rich. Dispatch</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Bemoans the fact that civil liberties have been suspended in Maryland.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Column 1 partially illegible. Remainder of page 2 ads.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
