<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1861/va.au.ss.1861.04.16">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1861-04-16">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day>16</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1861.04.16.01">
            <pageNote>Ads, poetry, fiction, and anecdotes</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1861.04.16.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>War Commenced</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Lincoln attempted to resupply Fort Sumter, thus commencing
                    hostilities against the South. Lincoln also called for the raising of seventy
                    thousand Militia, declaring that their first service would be to retake the
                    forts. Pennsylvania, Ohio, and New York have committed troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A northeast storm bore down on Virginia over the weekend, bringing rain,
                    snow, and flooding that have disrupted the mails and washed away train lines.
                    Trains have been unable to deliver the mail from Richmond and the Spectator is
                    anxious of news of Lincoln's fleet, the Convention, and Fort Sumter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watts</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that John Watts's brother has been appointed Captain of Infantry in
                    the Confederate Army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At a meeting of the Commissioned Officers of the several Volunteer Companies
                        of Augusta County, held at the Clerk's Office of the Hustings Court of the
                        Town of Staunton, on the 18th of April, 1861, Col. Wm. D. Anderson, Colonel
                        of 160th Regiment, being in the Chair, the following resolution was offered
                        and adopted by a vote by companies:</p>
                    <p>RESOLVED, That we, Commissioned Officers in the following Volunteer Companies
                        in the county of Augusta; to wit: <lb/></p>
                    <p>The West Augusta Guard, <lb/>The Union Greys, <lb/>The Augusta Greys,
                        <lb/>The Southern Guard, <lb/>The Augusta Rifles, <lb/>The Valley Rangers,
                        <lb/>The Staunton Artillery, <lb/>comprising an aggregate of 422 men, rank
                        and file, uniformed and armed, do hereby agree to the formation of a
                        Regiment of Volunteers to be numbered the 5th, pursuant to the provisions of
                        the 26th Chapter of the Code of 1860, and that we proceed to organize the
                        same by the election of a Colonel, Lieut. Colonel and two Majors under an
                        order from General Head Quarters, dated the 27th of March, 1861, and
                        addressed to Col. Wm. D. Anderson, Col. of the 160th Regiment. </p>
                    <p>On motion, James Bumbgardner, jr., was appointed Secretary.</p>
                    <p>The meeting then proceeded to the election of Field Officers, which resulted
                        as follows: For Colonel, Capt. Wm. S. H. Baylor; for Lieut. Colonel, Capt.
                        Absolom Coiner; for 1st. Major, Capt. F. f. Sterrett; for 2d Major, Col.
                        Rudloph Turk.</p>
                    <p>The following resolutions were then offered and adopted:</p>
                    <p>RESOLVED, That the County Court of this county, at its next (April) term, be
                        earnestly requested to make such appriation to this Regiment, and the
                        Companies that may hereafter unite with it as may seem to it proper and
                        liberal.</p>
                    <p>RESOLVED, That Thos. J. Michie, Col. John B. Baldwin, Hugh W. Sheffey and
                        Gen. Wm. H. Harman be requested to present the claims of the Regiment to the
                        said Court and urge upon it the necessity of such an appropriation.</p>
                    <p>RESOLVED, That the Volunteer Companies of this county not here represented be
                        respectfully solicited to unite with this Regiment.</p>
                    <p>RESOLVED, That a Committee, be appointed, consisting of the Field Officers
                        and the Commandants of the companies comprising this Regiment and the
                        companies intending to join it, whose duty it shall be to prepare By-Laws
                        for the government of this Regiment; said Committee to be called together by
                        the Colonel.</p>
                    <p>RESOLVED, That the proceedings of this meeting be published in the Staunton
                        papers.</p>
                    <p>On motion the meeting adjourned.</p>
                    <p>J. BUMGARDNER, Jr., Sec'y.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumbgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col..</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the organization of several local militia units into one regiment
                    of volunteers, numbered the fifth.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssapr61.html#4.16a</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Mustering of the District Militia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the calling out of the Volunteer Militia of Washington to be
                    mustered into Federal service.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Massie</ln>
                        <fn>N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Writer enquires as to whether Mr. Massie is standing for re-election in the
                    upcoming Legislative election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Alexandria Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>States that the Administration should hold no delusions that the
                    reinforcement of Sumter and other Forts in the seceded states will cause Union
                    feeling in the Cotton States as well as the Border States to decline
                    dramatically.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Voter</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Writer proposes Baldwin, Bolivar, and Tate as candidates for the
                    Legislature.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Augusta</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Writer wishes to second the motion to send Baldwin and Baylor to the next
                    House of Delegates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Civil War Inaugurated! Bombardment of Fort Sumter! Fort Sumter Surrendered!
                    Maj. Anderson Goes to New York! Four Men Mortally Wounded in Firing a Salute!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces the beginning of hostilities at Fort Sumter. Also included is a
                    transcript of the communication between Gen Beauregard and the Confederate War
                    Department preceding the attack on Maj. Anderson. Maj. Anderson's surrender is
                    also reported.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>To the Voters of Augusta County</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Many Voters</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Writer nominates Samuel B. Finely to stand for election to the Legislature.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports a rumor that a recruiting office for the Southern Confederacy in
                    Cincinnati has been closed by police.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Union if the Olden Time</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Writer ridicules the secessionist papers for failing to give arguments on
                    both sides of the secession issue.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn>R.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A resolution from students at University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill
                    drilling under Maj. Lilley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Northern Men Expelled From the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Spectator dismisses charges that Northern men are being imprisoned,
                    mistreated and expelled from the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Column 7 ads.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1861.04.16.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Negro Exodus from Chicago</head>
                <origin>Chicago Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article reports an exodus of escaped blacks from Chicago to Canada in light
                    of recent fugitive slave arrests.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1861.04.16.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
