<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1861/va.au.ss.1861.10.01">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/08/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>Colleen Doody second pass, 6/7/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1861-10-01">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day norm="01">1</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1861.10.01.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Candidate for Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>As the individual whom we would prefer to see the Representative of this
                        District in the Congress of the Confederate States was in command of a
                        regiment, prepared to spill his life's blood in defence of the rights, honor
                        and independence of the South, we did not think that his services in the
                        halls of Legislation could be obtained, and had prepared a notice in
                        commendation of a distinguished Democrat whom we expected to support for
                        Congress; for the fact of his being a Democrat was no objection to us now,
                        for we could not respect ourself if, in these times, we could be influenced
                        by past party prejudices. We pity the contracted and bigoted soul who is not
                        willing now to merge the partisan into the patriot--to sacrifice party
                        prejudices upon the sacred altar of patriotism--to support heartily and
                        cordially the best man without any reference whatever to his past political
                        status, and party associations. The ink had scarcely dried upon the paper
                        with which our remarks commending the distinguished Democrat referred to had
                        been written when we received the Rockingham Register containing a letter
                        from the individual, whom of all others, we preferred to represent us,
                        stating that he would consent to be a candidate, and that he hoped his
                        present office would not prevent him from being able to serve, but, if it
                        should, he would give an opportunity to have another elected in his place.
                        We were rejoiced that the people of this District had the opportunity thus
                        offered them to elect a man in every respect qualified in the highest degree
                        to represent them in the Congress of the Confederate States. We call the
                        attention of our readers to the letter of Col. Baldwin in reply to a
                        gentleman of Harrisonburg, published in this issue. The possession by Col.
                        Baldwin of integrity, patriotism, ability, courage, honor, and all the moral
                        virtues and intellectual qualifications which adorn private and public
                        character, is so well known in this District that it would be an act of
                        supererrogation [sic] to say anything in commendation of him. He is one of
                        the first men of the country, and the people should be sufficiently alive to
                        their <emph rend="italic">own interests</emph> to secure his services as
                        their Representative in the Halls of Legislation. As we are about to put a
                        new Government in operation, we need the services of our purest and ablest
                        men. We are satisfied that the patriotic citizens of this county without
                        distinction of party, (for fortunately there are no party divisions in this
                        county--all being united in patriotic defence of the South,) will take
                        pleasure in voting for Col. Baldwin. We expect this county to cast its vote
                        almost <emph rend="italic">unanimously</emph> for her own distinguished
                        son--JOHN B. BALDWIN. Let the people of this county with one voice proclaim
                        Col. Baldwin their choice. </p>
                    <p>P.S.--Since the above has been put in type, another citizen of Augusta has
                        announced himself a candidate for Congress. We allude to Col. Kenton Harper,
                        whose card will be found in another column.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Kenton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Spectator announces that Col. Baldwin will be a candidate for Congress
                    despite his present command, which he will resign if elected. The Spectator
                    lends its entire support to the candidacy of Col. Baldwin. The item also
                    announces the candidacy of Col. Kenton Harper.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Sent to Richmond</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that a woman dressed as a Confederate soldier was arrested in
                    Lynchburg. She says she wanted to fight in the army but she is suspected of
                    being a spy. She was then sent to Richmond for a further hearing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Our Ticket</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Spectator endorses Davis and Stephens for President and Vice President
                    and John B. Baldwin for Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item declares that the Confederate forces in the North West need
                    reinforcements as well as flannel and wool garments.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item reports that trade in the North is at a stand still, voluntary
                    enlistments have ceased, and the peace party is gaining ground.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Foolish Criticism</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Where did they acquire such a vast experience in the science of war that
                    they should know so much better than Generals Johnston and Beauregard when,
                    where, and how to advance?"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There is nothing to which persons generally are more prone than to criticise
                        and complain, and so great is this propensity, and so great the temptation
                        to indulge this disposition, that it often influences persons to expose
                        their ignorance and make themselves subjects of ridicule by criticising the
                        conduct of adepts in sciences, about which they are as ignorant as the mole
                        is of topics, or the adder of acoustics. We frequently hear persons
                        criticising the conduct of our Generals, and, with great gusto, expatiating
                        upon the merits of a campaign which <emph rend="italic">they</emph> would
                        have adopted, if the authorities had had the perception to discover their
                        remarkable genius for military science and had made a demand upon their
                        services. And that there may be no doubt of their possession of more than
                        Napoleonic genius, they acknowledge that the world does not contain abler or
                        more accomplished Generals than those in the service of the Confederate
                        States, and yet those distinguished Generals have not the capacity to plan
                        campaigns which would meet with their approbation, as they could, without
                        the routine of military education, by the force alone of their native and
                        heaven-endowed genius, plan much better ones. The press is not free from
                        this kind of vanity and self-conceit, and a considerable number indulge
                        daily in their ridiculous criticisms of the conduct of our Generals, and
                        urge them to do what the sound judgment and discretion of our Generals
                        forbid them to undertake. We concur with the sentiments contained in a
                        communication in the Richmond Whig which says: On the Potomac we have at the
                        head of one of the most splendid armies upon which the sun ever shone two of
                        the ablest Generals of the age. They graduated at West Point with
                        distinguished honor long years ago. They are to-day rich in all the wealth
                        and lore of experience. The army reposes the most implicit and unbounded
                        confidence in their military attainments and abilities, and the people join
                        the army in the most enthusiastic admiration of their courage and
                        patriotism. Now, under such circumstances, allow me to inquire what the
                        people have to do with the operations of our army on the Potomac? Greeley
                        raised the hue and cry of "On to Richmond." The Northern people caught it up
                        and Northern hills and valleys were made to resound with the shout of "On to
                        Richmond." As long as it was only Greeley's cry, no notice was taken of it,
                        but when the old scoundrel succeeded in making the people echo it he
                        triumphed, and the order "Forward" was given before the army was ready to
                        move. The result is history. Is the lesson it teaches to be lost on our
                        people? In the same pragmatic, impertinent, and fool-hardy spirit will they
                        persist in the cry of "On to Washington?" What do they know about the
                        condition of our readiness to advance? What do they know about the
                        preparation the enemy has made for our reception? What do they know about
                        the condition of the Potomac, our means to cross it, the number of our
                        troops and that of the enemy? When and where did they receive a military
                        education? Where did they acquire such a vast experience in the science of
                        war that they should know so much better than Generals Johnston and
                        Beauregard when, where, and how to advance? If it be true that our people
                        are becoming diseased with a ricketty [sic] restlessness upon this subject,
                        it is high time that they be informed that it is a matter with which they
                        have nothing to do, and about which it is prudent policy that they have
                        nothing to say. The manifestation of public discontent now may do some harm,
                        but can, in no probable event, do any good. The only possible result that
                        can accrue from it will be to weaken public confidence in those to whom the
                        public should cleave, in an hour like this, with an unfaltering trust.
                        Suppose you were on board of a ship, far away at sea, and a terrible storm
                        were howling around you, would you have the captain and sailors directed by
                            <emph rend="italic">the people</emph> that might happen to be passengers
                        on board? It would be equally as wise to do so as to allow the people to
                        have anything whatever to do with our army on the Potomac! </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Ridicules those who criticize the strategy of the Confederate generals. The
                    article specifically criticizes those parties who want to attack Washington,
                    even though the army is not yet ready for such an enterprise.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>More Arrests in Baltimore</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the arrest of more members of the Maryland legislature and their
                    imprisonment at Fort McHenry. Article notes that, throughout the Revolution,
                    martial law was never declared despite the abundance of tories.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Fremont has freed 23 slaves in Missouri. Item suggests that
                    seized Northern assets will be used to reimburse the owners for their loss.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>'Tis Strange, Passing Strange</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that a number of members of the Southern branch of the Methodist
                    Episcopal Church in North Western Virginia are acting with Lincoln against the
                    South. The same is said to be true in Kentucky.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kundig</ln>
                        <fn>H.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thanks Mr. Kundig for some excellent Rambeau apples.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Many Augusta Voters</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter writer wishes to draft Samuel A. Coffman of Rockingham as a
                    candidate for Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Letter from Col. John B. Baldwin</head>
                <origin>Rockingham Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>John B. Baldwin</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Baldwin announces that he will stand for office and will serve if elected,
                    assuming his services as an officer are no longer required.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>To the Voters of the Eleventh Congressional District</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Kenton Harper</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Kenton Harper accepts the nomination to stand for election to Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Difference</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Northern papers seem to be surprised because our papers speak of the
                        sickness prevailing in some regiments of the Confederate armies. The
                        surprise is simulated. The Southern papers, and Southern letter writers, and
                        Southern officials, tell the whole truth about the condition of their army
                        and their country, whether good or bad, favorable or unfavorable, and thus
                        the people of the South are at all times informed of the real condition of
                        affairs. On the other hand, the Northern papers, Northern correspondents,
                        and Northern officials, studiously and systematically conceal from the
                        people the real condition of their armies and the sufferings of their poor
                        soldiers; and when, by accident, the truth is told, by them, as in the first
                        reports of their rout at Manassas, they at once set to work to convince the
                        people that their own accounts were all false, and themselves liars, or
                        cowards and fools. Northern papers, for telling the truth, are gutted and
                        destroyed by Northern mobs, or suppressed by Northern officials, and their
                        editors arrested or imprisoned without the privilege of a hearing or the
                        hope of redress. A correct report of the sickness, and suffering, and
                        disaffection, and mutiny prevailing among Northern troops, would surprise
                        the public; but it is not so in the South.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item responds to the amazement of Northern papers regarding the prevalence
                    of disease in some Confederate regiments by asserting that Southern papers are
                    truthful about the condition of the army. However, Northern paper that tell the
                    truth are closed, confiscated, or burned by mobs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>What Lincoln is doing in North Western Virginia</head>
                <origin>Richmond Dispatch</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It seems to be clear that the Lincoln Government has organized a new United
                        States District Court in Northwestern Virginia, appointing some traitor in
                        place of Judge Brockenbrough, and that this Court has instructed its grand
                        jury to indict, and they have accordingly indicted several hundred worthy
                        citizens of that region for treason. Among those thus branded as traitors by
                        the abominable Lincoln dynasty, we may mention the venerable Gen. T. S.
                        Haymond, of Marion county, who is now in this city, and a number of other
                        refugees from that section. Col. J. Willey is also under the ban. So, also,
                        are many worthy and loyal Virginians whose circumstances would not allow
                        them to leave home. These call with a loud voice upon the Confederate
                        Government to do all in their power to extend its authority over that
                        portion of our State. Let Rosencrantz, Reynolds, and their followers,
                        aiders, and abettors, be expelled by a powerful army, and the true men be
                        enabled to feel the protecting arm of a nation which is a "power in the
                        earth." We feel certain that the Confederate authorities experience a lively
                        interest in the welfare of the people of Northwestern Virginia who are true
                        to the South.--<emph rend="italic">Rich. Dispatch</emph>. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Richmond Dispatch</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Lincoln has set up a pro-Union government and a U.S. District
                    Court in Northwestern Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>An Honest and Independent Man</head>
                <origin>Lexington Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Lexington Gazette</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Applauds Baldwin's independence of thought in his opposition to the
                    expulsion of certain members of the Convention for their pro-Union views.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Tribute of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuffin</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hope</ln>
                        <fn>R.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Resolutions adopted by the Staunton Masonic Lodge regarding the death of
                    Thomas L. Harman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Tribute of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>J.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Resolutions adopted by the Staunton Artillery regarding the death of Thomas
                    L. Harman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Tribute of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bean</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>J.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Resolutions adopted by the Staunton Artillery regarding the death of Jacob
                    Bean.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinckle</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nelden</ln>
                        <fn>Cassie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Edmund Kirby</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on September 24 at St. Paul's Church. Miss Nelden is from
                    Lynchburg, and Gen. Smith is from the Confederate Army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harlan</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on September 18 at age 20.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pierce</ln>
                        <fn>M.L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on August 4 at age 23 of wounds sustained at Rich Mountain.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Eleanor</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Kenton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Eleanor Harper, wife of Col. Kenton Harper, died on September 4 at age 59.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Various articles reporting battles and skirmishes. List of letters at Post
                Office in column 7.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1861.10.01.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Resources of the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"[T]he most casual view of its numerous advantages must satisfy any mind
                    that it was furnished and destined by the Creator of all things to be the seat
                    of a mighty and flourishing nation. All its features indicate that it was
                    intended to have a national existence and career of its own, and to be tributary
                    to none."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There is no country as rich in resources as the South. It is God's favored
                        region, on which his hand has lavished boundless wealth. A single glance at
                        the map, and the most casual view of its numerous advantage must satisfy any
                        mind that it was furnished and destined by the Creator of all things to be
                        the seat of a mighty and flourishing nation. All its features indicate that
                        it was intended to have a national existence and career of its own, and to
                        be tributary to none.</p>
                    <p>No other portion of the earth possesses such a combination of natural
                        productions and resource. The three great kingdoms of nature, the animal,
                        the vegetable and the mineral, contribute their richest treasures to its
                        aggrandizement.</p>
                    <p>All the domestic animals which contribute to the sustenance and convenience
                        of man can be reared in this favored region. Horses, mules and cattle find
                        here a congenial clime, in which they reach their highest perfection. Its
                        boundless corn fields can fatten innumerable hogs. The true latitude of the
                        sheep, which furnishes both food and clothing for our race, is in the South.
                        It was Mark Cockerell, of Tennessee, who, at the World's Fair, in London,
                        took the gold medal, in competition with the wool-growers of the world, with
                        wool of Tennessee growth. The mountains of Tennessee and North Carolina
                        surpass even those of Spain as sheep pastures.</p>
                    <p>In the variety and value of her vegetable productions the South is without a
                        rival. She excels the North in the growth of cereals, while to these she
                        adds cotton, sugar, rice, tobacco and indigo, the elements of an immense
                        commerce, to whose expansion there are no limits. Their magnitude and value
                        are shown by the fact that they furnished four-fifths of the exports of the
                        old Union, and that any interruption in their supply would derange the
                        commerce of the world.</p>
                    <p>In mineral resources, also, the South possesses exhaustless wealth. She has
                        coal and iron enough to supply the world, and is rich in lead, zinc and
                        copper, and also in manganese, saltpetre, sulphur, salt, and other minerals.
                        The South has, also, a territory greater in extent than that of the leading
                        empires of Europe, watered by innumerable streams, affording limitless water
                        power, with an extended sea-coast, dotted with harbors, accessible to ships
                        of the largest class, and with a climate temperate and delightful and
                        peculiarly favorable to the highest development of the human species.</p>
                    <p>Added to all these vast and varied resources, the South has a population
                        combining more elements of strength than other of equal numbers on the
                        globe. In her slave population of four and a half million, she has a body of
                        laborers, hardy, industrious, reliable, and adapted to her industrial
                        pursuits, equal, according to late acknowledgments of Northern writers, to
                        double the number of white inhabitants at the North, in productive capacity,
                        and the value of their labor. In her white inhabitants she has a population
                        of freemen who, in point of intelligence, energy and courage, are unequalled
                        [sic]. Animated by an intense love of freedom, an unbending pride, an
                        indomitable personal courage, and a lofty chivalry of character, they can
                        neither be awed by fear nor subdued by force.</p>
                    <p>Without presumption, we may well rely on the ability of a country with such
                        resources to maintain her independence against the assaults of an enemy
                        twice as powerful as the North. It is well for the people of the South to
                        look at their own resources, to know and feel their own real strength, that
                        they may entertain the confidence which they are entitled to feel in their
                        ability to maintain successfully their present struggle against an insolent
                        foe bent on their subjugation.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article asserts that the South has a tremendous wealth of natural
                    resources.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Spain</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item asserts that Spain's recognition of the Confederate Republic is a
                    harbinger that the recognition of France and England is forthcoming.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Three Runaways in Jail</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>John Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lewis</ln>
                        <fn>Fielding</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Three runaway slaves from Richmond have been committed to the jail of
                    Augusta County. Their owners are requested to come forward and prove property.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
