<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1861/va.au.ss.1861.05.07">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1861-05-07">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day norm="07">7</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1861.05.07.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Virginia, God Bless Her</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> We are prouder than ever of the land of our birth. Virginia gives this day
                        satisfactory assurance to the world that she has not "lost the breed of
                        noble blood." Her long patience and forbearance under wrongs and injuries
                        will not henceforth be construed into timidity or a time serving policy, by
                        the world, or by any portion thereof. She has defined her position in
                        characters of living light. At the first open declaration of hostilities on
                        the part of the Northern aggressor, she defiantly displays in his presence
                        her time-honored flag, with its motto so suggestive to all <emph
                            rend="italic">Tyrants.</emph></p>
                    <p> Her sons, from the sea-shore to the mountains, come forth with unexampled
                        enthusiasm to uphold "that standard sheet" at the risk of life, fortune and
                        sacred honor. The moment Virginia calls upon her sons to come to her rescue,
                        the voice of party and of faction is hushed, to be heard no more till her
                        battle shall be fought and her victory won. The call of Lincoln for 2,300
                        troops from this State, to assist him in reducing our sisters of the South
                        to subjugation, will be responded to by forty times that number, if need be,
                        to assist in teaching him and his councilors a lesson of humility which they
                        will never forget. The spirit of patriotism which animated our forefathers
                        in the days of '76, still burns in the hearts of their sons! God bless the
                        old Commonwealth!--<emph rend="italic">Enquirer of April 23rd.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises Virginia's commitment to fight the tyranny of Lincoln.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssmay61.html#5.7a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Another Proclamation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lincoln announces a blockade of the ports of Virginia and North Carolina
                    because of their seizure of Federal Property and arrest of Federal officers in
                    the exercise of their duty. These blockades are in addition to the blockades
                    already effective on the ports of the other seceded states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Extract From Gov. Hicks' message</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Excerpt relates Gov. Hicks desire to have Maryland remain neutral, having
                    not instigated the conflict on either side. He wishes that Maryland not be a
                    theater of war and that his people not be asked to kill brothers on either side.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Address to the People of Maryland</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A message from the Senate and House of Delegates of Maryland assuring the
                    people that they do not intend to precipitate secession unless a popular vote is
                    consulted to gauge the desire for such.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Commander Lloyd B. Newell of the U.S. Navy committed suicide
                    at the Merchant's Hotel in Philadelphia by shooting himself in the heart with a
                    Colt's revolver. He was a native of Georgia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Column 1 ads. Columns 2 and 3 fiction. Various items enjoining Virginians to
                resist Lincoln's "mercenaries." Various military orders. List of naval
            resignations.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1861.05.07.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Affairs at Harper's Ferry</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gives details of the Virginia raid on Harper's Ferry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Gen. Harney's Arrest</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Outlines the role Augusta Guard volunteers played in the actions at
                    Harper's Ferry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Ladies' Soldier Relief Associations</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article notes that the ladies of Augusta are hard at work sewing military
                    apparel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Augusta Lee Rifles</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces the formation of another volunteer company in Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Place of Rendezvous</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that volunteer companies from Augusta, as well as other counties,
                    should rendezvous at Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Stand United</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>This is not time for crimination and recrimination. All discord is as, as it
                        should be, avoided, and the whole band performs in perfect harmony. Men
                        stand shoulder to shoulder in one common cause. No question need be made as
                        to what road individuals took to arrive at the point where all stand, it is
                        enough to know that we are a unit. None have stood firmer for the Union than
                        we, while we believed there was the least shadow of hope of a reconstruction
                        and preservation; but, alas, the day of hope is past, the die is cast and
                        our once happy Union is broken beyond the possibility of repair.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges Virginians to remain united against Lincoln in spite of the
                    disagreements of policy up until this point.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssmay61.html#5.7b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Baltimore Sun, the article reports, has abandoned its support of
                    secession because, should Maryland secede, it would "instantly become the
                    blasting theater of war and carnage."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Command at Harper's Ferry</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Kenton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>W.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Brig. Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tarna</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donaghe</ln>
                        <fn>B.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article lists the command at Harper's Ferry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Governor announces that he is relieving Gen. Harper of his duty for the
                    present. Control of the troops at Harper's Ferry will pass to Col. T.J. Jackson.
                    Item also includes several letters enumerating changes in the command chain at
                    Harper's Ferry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The State Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article announces that the Convention has gone into recess until the 12th
                    of June. Included is a congratulatory letter from the Richmond Whig.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Military Appointments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Kenton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces military appointments confirmed by the Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Letter from Bolivar Christian, Esq.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mr. Christian says that, while he is not declaring himself a candidate, he
                    would be honored to serve if called by the people of Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>To the Voters of Old Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>One of many voters</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Massie</ln>
                        <fn>N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reminds the voters not to forget about the election coming up in the face
                    of the crisis that is now at hand and wishes to nominate Stuart, Christian,
                    McCue, and Massie to be Augusta's delegation to the State Legislature.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>John T. Harris</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>John T. Harris, under the circumstances, withdraws his intention to run for
                    the U.S. Congress. Since there is yet no provision for the election of members
                    for the Southern Confederacy, he is waiting to announce on that subject.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Many Voters</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Writer wishes that Bolivar Christian announce himself as a candidate to the
                    Senate of Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Many Voters</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Massie</ln>
                        <fn>N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>D.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>T.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter writer wishes to draft Massie, Young, and Wilson to stand for
                    election to the State Legislature.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Constitution Subverted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Accuses Lincoln of ignoring Constitutional necessities in his call for
                    troops and acts of war against the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Various articles urging unity. Various reports of troop movements in other
                states. Column 7 ads.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1861.05.07.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Meeting of Congress--Message of Davis</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises the valor of the people of the Confederacy and notes that the
                    establishment of a Confederate infrastructure is progressing well.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Old Augusta</head>
                <origin>Farmville Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowan</ln>
                        <fn>A.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editor of the Farmville Journal, A.M. Cowan, praises the patriotism of
                    Augusta in the defense of the State.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Boston Courier</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Boston Courier advocates an amiable separation, noting that military
                    coercion cannot produce allegiance in the seceded states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements and Staunton and Richmond Market listings</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1861.05.07.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
