<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1861/va.au.ss.1861.12.03">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/08/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>Colleen Doody second pass, 6/7/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1861-12-03">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day norm="03">3</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1861.12.03.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Mr. John B. Snider Killed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Wednesday night last, at ten o'clock, Mr. Jno. B. Snider of this place was
                        killed by Henry J. Webster, of Murray county, Tennessee, a soldier belonging
                        to the 1st Tennessee Regiment, Colonel Manning commandant. Mr. Snider was
                        employed in Mr. Jno. Beck's restaurant, where he was attending to his duties
                        when Webster entered with his pistol in his hand and asked for oysters. He
                        was informed by Mr. Snider that he could not furnish them as his supply was
                        exhausted. Webster, in a very peremptory manner, demanded that he should get
                        him some. Mr. Snider told him that he did not know where any could be
                        obtained at that time. Webster swore that he should get them, aimed his
                        pistol and shot Mr. Snider in the head. The ball entered above the left eye
                        and penetrated the brain. He lived from 10 to 3 o'clock. He was a very
                        deserving young man, possessed a good character, and had a social, kind and
                        accommodating disposition. He leaves a young wife and child to mourn his sad
                        and untimely death. The jury of Inquest held over the body of the deceased
                        rendered a verdict of willful and malicious murder. The prisoner had his
                        examining trial on Thursday and was committed to the county jail. There was
                        very great excitement on the morning after the commission of the dreadful
                        deed among the friends of the victim, and a very strong disposition
                        prevailed to take the prisoner from the hands of the authorities and execute
                        him by the summary process of Lynch law.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Item reports the murder of John Snider by Henry J. Webster, a soldier
                    belonging to the 1st Tennessee Regiment, while Snider worked in Mr. Beck's
                    restaurant.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Obituaries</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spectator encourages those who send in obituaries to include the names,
                    ages, and residences of those who are deceased. Also requested is a ten-line
                    limit on obituaries.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Collection of the War Tax</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Suggests that Virginia take advantage of the discount offered to any state
                    that takes the collection and payment of the war tax into its own hands, thus
                    dispensing with the Confederate bureaucracy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Getting Their Eyes Open</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asserts that the Lincoln Administration has become aware that a much larger
                    force will be needed to subdue the rebellion than previously thought.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Shoes with Wooden Soles</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Advocates the use of wooden-soled shoes to save leather.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Reorganization of the Militia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains the details of the new militia reorganization law.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Staunton Artillery</head>
                <origin>Richmond Dispatch</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"Bohemian," the regular correspondent of the Richmond Dispatch, writing from
                        Occoquan makes the following notice of the location and services of the
                        "Staunton Artillery," commanded by Capt. John D. Imboden:</p>
                    <p>"Close by the town, lying under 'Rose Hill,' and almost in the shadow of the
                        haunted house, is the camp of Capt. Imboden, whose battery did such good
                        service in the battle of Manassas Plains. The gallant soldier is now very
                        busy with Gen. Wigfall in examining the country around him, and in selecting
                        locations where his guns could be used should the enemy advance. I have
                        already spoken of an erroneous map of the battle field, upon which Gen.
                        Ewell has a false position. It was even worse with Capt. Imboden, for in
                        places where he fought like a tiger, and where his battery did the best
                        service, the credit is given to another corps of artillery. Frequently on
                        the 21st I saw his battery working as well as the best General could wish,
                        but until late did not know whose guns they were, or who the gallant officer
                        was who aimed them. Capt. Imboden is now under Gen. Wigfall, and will have a
                        prominent place in the fight by the Occoquan, should one occur.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notice of the location and services of the Staunton Artillery by a Richmond
                    Dispatch correspondent.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report from England that the Gladiator is sailing from Nassau with arms for
                    the Rebels. The item also asserts that the capitalists and aristocracy of
                    England sympathize with the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Snow</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It snowed two inches in Staunton on December 2nd. Had the ground been
                    colder the accumulation would have been around 5 inches.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>A Singular Incident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A story about a Southern gentleman's pre-war visit to friends in Vermont
                    and the subsequent outbreak of war, in which he killed his friend's brother.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Where is the Cumberland Gap</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides geographical information about the Cumberland Gap and explains its
                    importance.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Item reports that Hugh Sheffey will be in Staunton the day after Christmas
                    and at the January Court to pay off the property certified for the support of
                    the families of absent volunteers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Arrests of Messrs. Slidell and Mason.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item reports the arrest of the Confederate ambassadors in England.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Expression of the English Press</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Excerpts from various English papers in defense of the Southern cause.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Interesting Letter from Col. Cogswell</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Transcript of a letter from Col. Cogswell to his brother. Col. Cogswell is
                    a Northern prisoner who was drawn by lot to act as a hostage pending the outcome
                    of the execution order for captured Southern privateers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Soldier Shot--Court Martial</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article reports the execution of James Miller for shooting John Henderson,
                    the captain of his company.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Proclamation of the President of the Confederate States of America</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Davis's proclamation recognizes the secessionist government of Missouri and
                    grants it admission to the CSA.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Provisional Government in Kentucky</head>
                <origin>Richmond Examiner</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the imminent arrival of the Commissioners of the Kentucky secession
                    government in Richmond.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Hon. Daniel C. Dickinson on the War</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Excerpts of a speech by Daniel Dickinson, once considered a friend of the
                    South, but now a supporter of the Northern war effort.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>R. M. Phillips</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>Walter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>E.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morehead</ln>
                        <fn>Carrie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Lydia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ball</ln>
                        <fn>H.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheat</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gait</ln>
                        <fn>Lucy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheat</ln>
                        <fn>J.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Writer wishes to thank those who have donated items to the Baltimore
                    company stationed in Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Contributions from Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>W. G. Campbell</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>John</ln>
                        <fn>A. Patterson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilkeson</ln>
                        <fn>D.V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>F.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoots</ln>
                        <fn>Elisa</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCutchen</ln>
                        <fn>S.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patrick</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists contributions to Augusta soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Bread and Whiskey</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A Southern contemporary denounces in terms of just but strong reprobation the
                        extensive distillation of the staff of life into one of the most prolific
                        fountains of misery and death that ever was let loose upon an unhappy race.
                        In the present condition of the South, when it is absolutely necessary that
                        all the grain we raise should be converted to its legitimate purposes, the
                        distillation into whiskey should be restricted to such limits as are
                        required for medicinal purposes, and the moderate supply which is necessary
                        for the army. Anything beyond this is a wanton, criminal, and treasonable
                        waste of articles essential to the support of our soldiers and the comfort
                        of our population.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Denounces the conversion of bread to whiskey when the maintenance of a food
                    supply is so critical.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frenger</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Frenger died on November 14 at age 52 near Greenville. He died of
                    typhoid, which he appears to have contracted from his son in the army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>Willie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>M.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>S.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Willie White died on November 10 at age 4.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Various battlefield reports. Column 4 includes miscellaneous telegraphic
                dispatches from various states in the CSA and USA.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1861.12.03.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Furious Fighting Parson</head>
                <origin>Montgomery Advertiser</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Anecdote about a soldier in Tennessee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>To Tax-Payers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grills</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Instructions to tax payers regarding payment of taxes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
