<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1867/va.au.vv.1867.04.10">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/10/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-04-10">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day norm="">10</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1867.04.10.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1867.04.10.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Truth of History</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors object to Dabney's life of Stonewall Jackson being regarded as
                    "the only authentic history of Stonewall Jackson," and point out some of its
                    errors.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>"No Time For Swapping Horses."</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial celebrates the victory of the conservative party in
                    Connecticut as a harbinger of things to come. There should be no resting an
                    laurels, however; northern conservatives must "push the good work ahead," and
                    Virginians must complete "reconstructing" their state in order to "turn the
                    tide" in the North.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Candidates for the Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In the rural districts, truly says the Richmond Times, we learn that
                        gentlemen of intelligence and character have announced, in a few instances,
                        and are preparing, in very many cases, to announce themselves candidates for
                        the inevitable Convention. Many gentlemen whose services will be greatly
                        needed are deterred, we learn, from becoming candidates, by a false sense of
                        delicacy and propriety. They say that it is not proper for any Virginian to
                        make himself a voluntary party to the monstrous violation of the
                        Constitution which the Sherman act and the supplement thereto involves.</p>
                    <p>In common with men whose opinions are entitled to a weight which ours do not,
                        of course, possess, we hold this to be a most dangerous and suicidal error
                        of judgement. It is a part and parcel of that dangerous apathy and inertness
                        which menaces us with the most alarming consequences. The acceptance of the
                        situation, to the extent of candidacy and the exercise of the right of
                        suffrage, we hold to be a duty as sacred and important as a defence of
                        family and fireside. Every leading and distinguished politician at the South
                        should labor to dispel the clouds of error which obscure the judgement of
                        our people. But as our people have, for six years, thought little and cared
                        less for their old party leaders, let them respect the sound judgement and
                        intelligence of those great soldiers whose fame misfortune has not disarmed.
                        Let them accept the examples of LEE, JOHNSTON, BEAUREGARD, HAMPTON and
                        LONGSTREET, as worthy of imitation, and exercise with harmony and energy and
                        earnestness every right which the conquerors have left us. Unless we do this
                        we shall be speedily reduced to the condition of serfs and Helots, not of
                        Spartans, but of the vilest and most demoralized renegades and enemies of
                        their own race and lineage. Away with all doubts and hesitancy about voting
                        and becoming candidates. The safety, not only of the State, but of our wives
                        and children, should make every voter follow the example and advice of
                        ROBERT E. LEE.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article denounces the apathy and misguided principle that induces many
                    talented men to refuse to become candidates for the Constitutional Convention
                    because they fear cooperation may imply acceptance of radical policy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>"Want of Respect for Gen. Lee."</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper defends its use of General Lee's name as a supporter of a
                    Convention. Though he dislikes public notice, he is happy to use his influence
                    in such an emergency, the editors assert. They are willing to be tried and
                    condemned by fellow soldiers should anyone think them wrong.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Crime in the North</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This item publishes a list of the crimes reported in one issue of a New
                    York newspaper. They include assault, lynching, "divorces, seductions, rapes,
                    murders, forgeries." "Just imagine what a howl would be raised if a tenth of it
                    had occurred South!"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1867.04.10.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that "last year 165 colored persons were assessed for
                    taxes in Staunton."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lumber and building materials are arriving in Staunton by railroad and
                    wagon, and many improvement projects are planned.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>To Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Valley Virginian office is supplying, free of charge, forms for
                    applying to the state for artificial limbs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Good reports of farm operations and growing wheat are arriving from around
                    the Valley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Gas Co.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>H. H. Peck gave up his lease on the Gas Works, and the Company will run it
                    in the future. "We understand the price is to be lowered and many improvements
                    made when the rosin arrives to make gas."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Personal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tukey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. Tukey was exonerated through investigation of the charges made
                    against him, according to General Brown, Superintendent of Freedmen. The
                    General, in his letter, compliments Tukey "on the faithful discharge of his
                    duties. A fact our people can testify to."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Registration</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tukey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. Tukey, Superintendent of the Freedmen's Bureau in Augusta, has
                    provided General Schofield with a list of magistrates and the number and
                    boundary of magisterial districts in preparation for early registration of
                    voters. "Let every man, who can, do his duty and register."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Population And Voters of Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports the number and race of voters in Staunton. The 1860
                    census recorded a population of 3,875, of which 900 were black. Recent estimates
                    place the population at 4,500, of which 750 are black. There are 470 white
                    voters. "Taking one-third of the negroes, as voters, 250, making in all 720,
                    which gives the whites a majority of 220--but there will be little division
                    among the voters."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Statistics of Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper lists statistics for Augusta County as provided in the 1860
                    census. An 1866 assessment shows growth in all categories: number of farms,
                    1,569; dwellings, 3,829; families, 3,786; manufactures, 189; value of real and
                    personal estate, $12,343,324; number of schools, 90; teachers, 93; pupils,
                    3,237; paupers, 35; average wage of mechanics without board, $1.25 per day; day
                    laborer, $1; price of board, $2 per week; number of churches, 53.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Augusta Fire Company</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waters</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>P. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donovan</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>John P.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stafford</ln>
                        <fn>Charley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Toole</ln>
                        <fn>Patrick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardy</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The annual meeting of the Augusta Fire Company was held. The company passed
                    a vote of thanks for the ladies of Augusta for raising $400 on behalf of the
                    company. The following officers were elected: J. H. Waters, Captain; J. A.
                    Bickle, 1st Lieut.; P. H. Trout, Secretary; John Donovan, Treasurer; John P.
                    Scherer, Jr., 1st Engineer; Charley Stafford, 2nd Engineer; Jacob Scherer, 3rd
                    Engineer; Patrick O'Toole, 4th Engineer; John M. Hardy, 1st Hose Director; James
                    Smith, 2nd Hose Director; William S. Grove, Engine Keeper.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerr</ln>
                        <fn>Upsher</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Ferrall</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Philomethesian Society met on Saturday night and debated the question:
                    "Were the young men of the South justifiable in emigrating?" Upsher Kerr argued
                    in the affirmative, and J. P. O'Ferrall in the negative. The debate was decided
                    in the negative by a vote of 10 to 8.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Hon. N. K. Trout</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>State Senator N. K. Trout was profiled in the Whig: "Mr. Trout, of Augusta,
                    is chairman of the Judiciary Committee, and is an able man and a hard worker. He
                    contents himself with explaining the bills reported by the important committee
                    of which he is the head, instead of indulging in long speeches. He is never
                    absent when an important vote is taken."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Market or No Market</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper asks for a decision on whether or not Staunton will have a market
                    "and get rid of the middle men," or not. As the matter stands, the Market
                    Ordinance is not enforced and the Market-House is empty. The paper suggests a
                    referendum on the subject, and calls for the sale of the Market-House if it
                    fails.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Population of Augusta and Voters</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The census of 1860 gives the whole population of Augusta at 27,764. Whites,
                        22,212; negroes, 5,552. Taking one-fifth of the number of whites as voters,
                        this gives 4,442 white voters, from which deduct about 100 for
                        disfranchised. Averaging the negro vote at the same it gives 1,110 negro
                        votes--making a total of 5,452 voters, or say 5,000, which gives the whites
                        3,000 clear majority; allowing that the negroes will vote against us in a
                        solid body, which we do not expect. Since the census, another has been taken
                        by the Freedmen's Bureau, which gives the negro population of the County at
                        4,700, a decrease of 852. These facts should impress upon the colored people
                        the utter folly of going against their best friends--the majority of our
                        people--and being led astray by designing white men. While it is sacredly
                        our duty to protect them in all their rights, it is none the less theirs to
                        co-operate with us in our efforts to save the State from ruin. Proper
                        efforts on the part of our intelligent white and colored people, will make
                        everything work towards one great end--the welfare and prosperity of all
                        classes.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article gives a statistical breakdown of Augusta County voters based
                    on race, and concludes that the whites have an overwhelming majority. This
                    should convince blacks of the "folly" of voting against their white "friends."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Soldiers' Cemetery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Munsey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The ladies have invited the Rev. Mr. Munsey to speak on May 10th. The work
                    on the cemetery is progressing, but "40 loads of rich earth are needed to plant
                    trees. Can't our farmers bring them in?"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Number of Slaves Between 18 and 45 in Augusta, Jan. 1st 1863.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>Robert G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sterrett</ln>
                        <fn>W. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>When Gov. Smith asked Augusta to supply 250 slaves to work upon
                    fortification during the war, a Committee appointed by the County Court and
                    consisting of Robert G. Bickle, William A. Bell, W. G. Sterrett, Samuel B.
                    Brown, and B. F. Points, estimated the county had 762 male slaves between the
                    ages of 18 and 45. 50 free blacks were not included, "but it gives a good idea
                    of the negro vote now, and makes it less than the calculation we make from the
                    census." The paper recommends that every effort be made to estimate the
                    potential African American vote in the entire state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1867.04.10.04" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Good Advice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Rev. J. L. M. Curry, of Alabama, better known as a member of the
                        Confederate Congress, lectured before the Young Men's Christian Association,
                        of Richmond, last week. We ask a careful perusal of the following synopsis
                        of his remarks, which we find in the Examiner, by all of our readers,
                        especially the young.</p>
                    <p>He spoke for about an hour in an eloquent, interesting and instructive vein,
                        giving the rising generation some wholesome advice, and showing great
                        research, extensive reading and careful thought. We do not propose to follow
                        him in his lecture, but merely to touch a few of its salient points. He
                        wished, above all, that the young men of the South should be gentlemen, and
                        in order to be such they must be good Christians; and he counseled them to
                        go to work energetically and labor unceasingly in order to build up the
                        commercial and material interests of the South. The country was not ruined.
                        It still contained all the elements of wealth; and by properly directed
                        industry, its immense resources could soon be developed. It was neither
                        slavery--the basis of a proud aristocracy--nor a rich soil, nor much
                        learning, nor a splendid government, that made a country great; but the
                        industry and energy of its people. There was nothing in this opposed to
                        aristocracy, for it was noble to work. He also cautioned them against
                        fostering a feeling of alienation towards any portion of the people of the
                        country, and told them not to flout the old flag, for it was our fathers'
                        flag and our's.</p>
                    <p>He was earnest in his appeals to the youth of the South to be steadfast to
                        their glorious traditions--to preserve the memory of their forefathers, and
                        to emulate their noble actions and greatness of character; but above all
                        they must labor diligently to build up the country, in order to insure its
                        future wealth, prosperity and happiness. As Christians, they would be
                        gentlemen, and enoble their manhood.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article reports on a speech by the Rev. J. L. M. Curry to the Young
                    Men's Christian Association of Richmond. Curry encouraged his audience to live
                    upright lives, and to labor diligently at building the industry and prosperity
                    of the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
