<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1867/va.au.vv.1867.03.06">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/05/1867</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-03-06">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="">6</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1867.03.06.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Our Ralroad</head>
                <origin>Rockingham Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We think we may congratulate the people of the Valley of the Shenandoah, upon
                        the early dawning of a better day in their pecuniary fortunes. We believe we
                        are to have our long-wished for Railroad completed at an early period to
                        Harrisonburg. The legislation at the present session of the General Assembly
                        upon this subject accomplishes this result.</p>
                    <p>The act for the transfer of the Manassas Gap railroad, with its franchises
                        and interests to the Orange and Alexandria Railroad Company, was a great
                        thing for this magnificent Valley, with its teeming and rapidly augmenting
                        population, and its almost boundless stores of undeveloped wealth. It is
                        impossible to conceive what a deep interest this great Valley, a giant in
                        physical strength and resources, will now arise in its might, and show what
                        it is capable of doing. We shall no longer, if we will exert ourselves,
                        suffer beneath the grinding heel of poverty. Our lands, amongst the richest
                        and the best in the world, will now be put up to their highest productive
                        capacity, for we are to have the means of transporting to market what we can
                        raise. No man can correctly calculate or estimate what our people can
                        produce upon their farms. Even now, without facilities for getting to
                        market, we are getting along just about as well, as the balance of the
                        world, paying enormous State and Federal taxes, and asking no favors of
                        either, but to be let quietly alone to work out our pecuniary salvation.</p>
                    <p>We advise our people to turn their anxious gaze from the darkened and
                        darkening skies of their political future, to the prospect now distinctly
                        looming up in the no longer dim distance of the coming of the "iron horse."
                        If we can speedily repair our shattered pecuniary fortunes, as we will do
                        through the agency of our railroad, we can well afford to stand still in the
                        storm and see the infernal Radicals dashed down into the abyss of the
                        popular indignation and scorn, to which they inevitably hasten. Let them
                        establish "territorial governments" over us; let them do their worst. We
                        have survived "the wreck of matter" caused by their war upon us, and we can
                        yet stand the terrible inflictions of the territorializing acts of an
                        illegal, unconstitutional and despotic Congress. Our only hope of
                        resurrection to material life and prosperity, is in the fulfilment of our
                        wishes with respect to our railroad.--<emph rend="italic">Rockingham
                            Register</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article from the Rockingham Register celebrates the recent bill passed
                    in the legislature clearing the way for a railroad to Harrisonburg. The coming
                    of the "iron horse" to the Valley will open a future of unlimited prosperity.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1867.03.06.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper agrees with the Richmond Examiner that the Radicals' next move
                    will be to forbid the meeting of southern militia companies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Situation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>As we said in our last issue the President has vetoed the Military bill and
                        Congress has promptly passed it over his veto. A telegraphic synopsis, which
                        we get from the Lynchburg News, gives the main points of the veto message,
                        but what does its able arguments on the Constitution, the <emph
                            rend="italic">right</emph> and the Law, avail us? Nothing, <emph
                            rend="italic">absolutely nothing</emph>, in the presence of the radical
                        mob, which now tyrannizes over a people, once free. The President is
                        powerless and will enforce that odious bill, as mildly and gently as
                        possible, we know, but he will enforce it. Knowing this, knowing the men we
                        have to deal with, how reckless and unscrupulous they have been and will
                        continue to be, what are we to do?</p>
                    <p>It is a hard question to answer and on that demands, in the interest of all
                        we hold dear, the serious consideration and study of our people. The
                        Richmond Examiner, of Monday, has the ablest article, we have seen upon the
                        subject, which we regret our inability to publish in full. It briefly sums
                        up the Situation in a paragraph: "In this emergency, two courses remain open
                        to you. They may be described each in a word--action and inaction." The
                        natural resentment of a brave people, at the cruelty and devilish malignity
                        of the proposal of our enemies, makes many resolve to meet with simple
                        defiance and "inaction," the despotism they can not resist. But common sense
                        and sober judgement says: "Your government is at once declared provisional.
                        On the 4th Thursday in May next, if the terms of the act of Congress have
                        not meanwhile been fully complied with, and your State restored--a result
                        physically impossible--an election will be held in Virginia for Governor,
                        Lieutenant Governor, Attorney General and for members of the Legislature. At
                        that election all may vote (and none others) who are qualified by this act
                        to vote. All will be eligible (and none others) who are by the act made
                        eligible."</p>
                    <p>And this election will be held by the vilest and lowest, if the good and true
                        men do not vote. Remember, this is the result of "inaction," and answer the
                        question, what is the best for us to do?</p>
                    <p>To our mind, as Southern men and Virginians, there appears but one course to
                        pursue, with honor. It is, for the Legislature to at once submit to the
                        people of Virginia the question; whether they will hold a Convention or not?
                        Let the question be fully and freely discussed and a Convention, elected by
                        the people, can decide what we are to do--but when we act, let us act as one
                        man and know what we are about. In the meantime, let us be hopeful; be kind
                        to one another, <emph rend="italic">work</emph> and recollect that it is "a
                        long lane that has no turning."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial on the political situation argues that despite President
                    Johnson's veto of the Military Reconstruction Bill, the radical Congress
                    tyrannizes over southern whites. The only answer, say the editors, is to hold a
                    convention as soon as possible and be sure every white man votes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>What Shall We Do?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>An able article in the Charlottesville Chronicle, on this important question,
                        concludes as follows: "What shall we do? This question is to be answered
                        coolly, and in a spirit corresponding to the gravity of the situation. It
                        should be answered calmly and wisely. The avalanche is already descending
                        the sides of the mountain.</p>
                    <p>What shall we do? There are two courses open: one is to take our chances with
                        the Supreme Court. That requires time, and the negroes are voting in the
                        meanwhile. This is to be considered. Then we are to consider, will Congress
                        (supposing the Court to decide favorably) be balked by the Supreme Court?
                        Then we must consider that there is a probability that two of the judges on
                        that court will not live twelve months. And Gov. Pierpont stated in his
                        address Saturday evening, that the Supreme Court have just adopted a rule
                        not to meddle with political questions for the present. The other course is
                        to call a Convention at once, accept the terms, and fight the battle in
                        Congress. We go there with about sixty members. In framing a State
                        Constitution there might be a provision that no <emph rend="italic">one
                            shall be eligible to office who does not possess the elements of an
                            English education, and does not own $---- worth of property</emph>.
                        Congress would have to pass on this Constitution: would they admit such a
                        clause? If they rejected it, would not our position be a strong one? In that
                        constitution we might also take the election of judges, magistrates,
                        sheriffs, &amp;c., &amp;c., from the people, and we might extend the
                        terms of office for all others so as to have fewer elections.</p>
                    <p>Under the provisional government we have the military and negro suffrage; if
                        admitted into the Union, we have negro suffrage and get rid of the military.
                        Pending the provisional government the men proscribed by the third clause of
                        the amendment cannot vote; they can vote when the state is admitted. Then
                        this is to be considered: the quicker we get into the Union the better:
                        there we are a State, and we can control our own affairs--<emph
                            rend="italic">changing our State constitution</emph> is necessary. There
                        we are out of the jaws of the beast that is ready to devour us.</p>
                    <p>Again: the quicker this State constitution is formed, the greater will be the
                        influence of the whites in shaping it. Postpone, and the Radicals will
                        organize the negroes against us. And lastly, if the Legislature does not
                        call a Convention, Botts and the negroes will by primary meetings."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Charlottesville Chronicle offers an assessment of how white southerners
                    should respond to military reconstruction. Dismissing the Supreme Court as too
                    uncertain, the article advocates holding a constitutional convention and
                    re-entering the Union as fast as possible, even if it means accepting the terms
                    of the radicals. Then arrangements can be made to disenfranchise blacks with
                    measures such as education and property requirements.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Hon. John B. Baldwin on the "Situation."</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Last Saturday the Legislature adjourned. Speaker Baldwin delivered the
                        following admirable address, which will be read with interest by our people.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Baldwin replied at length, thanking the House for the sentiment of the
                        resolution, and assuring the members of a reciprocation on his part of all
                        the kindly feelings expressed. In conclusion, he said as he was about to
                        part with them, he would take occasion to allude to the fact that he was
                        about to part also with public life. He had never been a politician, and
                        entered public life as a member of the State Convention six years ago, when,
                        as he believed, there was a crisis in our history. When he thought on the
                        condition of the country then, and what was its situation now, and of the
                        many scenes he had witnessed, he had no satisfaction in what he had
                        attempted, no consolation for all our hopes that had been destroyed, except
                        that of having been at all times an honest man and a Virginia gentleman. It
                        was not for one like him, a disfranchised man, to speak of public affairs.
                        He would return to those who six years ago had sent him into public life,
                        and had unvaryingly supported him since, through all trials and
                        difficulties. It was a striking commentary on the events of the hour, that
                        one whom the House thought worthy of this resolution of thanks and
                        approbation, and who had the approbation of the constituents at home, should
                        be stricken and disfranchised. It was not for him to say that the public
                        would lose by the loss of him, but he could not help saying that a policy
                        that prevented a body like this, or a constituency like his, from expressing
                        its preferences, was a mistaken one, and that it would be so discovered to
                        be sooner or later.</p>
                    <p>As a conservative citizen it was his duty to urge upon members, as leading
                        citizens, to counsel their constituents to maintain and obey the laws. We
                        cannot make further resistance; let us see that we give no pretext for
                        trampling upon us. Let us go on like good citizens, and if oppression is
                        committed, let God and man see that the fault is with the oppressors, and
                        not with the oppressed. If, as I think, the crisis is upon us, let us meet
                        it calmly, as becomes men and patriots. Let us exhibit to mankind the
                        spectacle of a people who, though it is no longer becoming in them to
                        continue the strife at the cannon's mouth, yet have the civic courage to do
                        justice, to suffer and not to loose their self-respect.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>John B. Baldwin, as a man disfranchised under Congressional Reconstruction,
                    takes leave of the Virginia legislature. He asserts that a policy which takes
                    away citizens' rights to choose their representatives is a mistaken one, but
                    urges Virginians to obey the laws and give no further pretext for radical
                    measures even while they resist as best they can.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1867.03.06.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Cholera</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper denounces the Town Council for doing nothing "practical and of
                    immediate benefit to the horrible condition of our Streets." The editors avocate
                    a special meeting of the Council to remedy the problem. "If our streets, alleys,
                    backyards, &amp;c., are not thoroughly cleaned, and lime used freely, by the
                    1st of May, look out!"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Staunton has a Thespian Society; a Lyceum; a Phylomethesian Society; a
                        Building Association; three Newspapers; a Musical Association; seven
                        Churches; an Institution for the Deaf, Dumb, and Blind; a Lunatic Asylum;
                        four female Schools, of a high order; three male schools, ditto--for
                        whites--free School and Schools for Freedmen; two Foundries; two first-class
                        Hotels; fine Water Works and Gas Works in operation, when the "rain" comes
                        regularly. It has about 6,000 inhabitants; business is brisk and money
                        scarce, with times "tighter" than ever before known. The latter on account
                        of the Radical policy of keeping away labor and capital.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper publishes a list of Staunton's cosmopolitan attractions and the
                    important industries in town.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Town Council--March session</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bunch</ln>
                        <fn>George C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>R. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Edmonson</ln>
                        <fn>E. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>W. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piper</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardy</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>F. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Town Council met for March, James W. Crawford presiding. All were
                    present except Trout, Kayser and Points. George C. Bunch, Overseer of the Poor,
                    had received since November 1, 1866, $400 and expended $251,52 leaving a balance
                    of $148,48 which will be used for the present year. The Commissioner of streets
                    received for the period March 3, 1866, to November 1867, $1,516.20, and spent
                    $1,373.70, leaving a balance of $142.50, which was turned over to the Chief of
                    Police. The Superintendent of Water Works did $124.57 in work for individuals.
                    Superintendent David Taylor was complimented by the Committee for "efficiency
                    and promptness." The Treasurer kept the books with distinction. The Attorney of
                    the Corporation settled with R. H. Fisher, ex-overseer of the poor, who was
                    indebted $42.54. He paid the sum promptly to A. B. Cochran who handed it over to
                    the Chief of Police. Benjamin Crawford, E. L. Edmonson and A. M. Garber, Jr.,
                    were exempted from paying erroneous taxes. A resolution was passed calling for
                    all streets to be paved and curbed at town expense; it was referred to Evans,
                    Bickle and Peck. W. B. Kayser, J. A. Piper, J. M. Hardy, A. M. Bruce, and F. M.
                    Young were appointed commissioners to superintend the election. William Craig
                    was appointed officer to conduct the election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Gassy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Staunton correspondent of the Richmond Enquirer writes the following
                    about the Staunton Gas Works: "The gas concern here is still conducted on the
                    monopoly and extortion plan. Seven dollars in gold per thousand cubic feet! This
                    is what I call 'Sheridan-izing,' or burning a man out of house and home."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>Tiflin W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>Mary B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>J. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Tiflin W. Allen, of Shenandoah County, and Mrs. Mary B. Patterson, of
                    Augusta, were married on February 21st by the Rev. J. E. Armstrong.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cease</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>Helen T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Helmick</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>N. K. Cease, of Staunton, and Miss Helen T. Johnson, recently of
                    Mississippi, were married on January 8th in Harrison County, West Virginia, by
                    Rev. Mr. Helmick.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ballew</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lotts</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Helmick</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. D. Ballew and Miss Catharine Lotts, both of Augusta, were married on
                    February 28th by the Rev. Mr. Helmick.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1867.03.06.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
