<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1867/va.au.vv.1867.08.14">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/14/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-08-14">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="">14</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1867.08.14.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1867.08.14.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Situation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have space for but few words. The situation grows interesting, and the
                        organ of the President says "more is coming." Andrew Johnson has, at last,
                        "shown his teeth." He publishes a confession of "Sanford Conover," or
                        "Charles A. Dunham," a "convicted perjurer," which implicates Holt, Butler
                        and Ashley, in a conspiracy to impeach the President, <emph rend="italic">by
                            suborning witnesses</emph>. The letters of these men, Holt, Butler and
                        Ashley, are on file, and the whole confession bears internal evidence of its
                        truth. It has fallen like a bomb-shell in the Radical camp, and is the most
                        glaring record of double-distilled villainy ever published. We regret our
                        inability to publish it in full this week, and can only say that Andrew
                        Johnson has made a "ten strike."</p>
                    <p>This astounding development of corruption in high places; this expose of the
                        utter want of principle on the part of prominent Radical leaders must have a
                        wonderful effect North and hurl that party from power. In the meantime, it
                        becomes our people, more than ever, <emph rend="italic">to work, to watch
                            and to wait</emph>. "When rogues fall out honest men get their
                    dues."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports on corrupt behavior from the Radicals in their effort to
                    impeach President Johnson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Fourth in Dekato Territory</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This letter from an ex-soldier in the West Augusta Guards sends a
                    description of an improvised Fourth of July celebration on the Western plains.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Dan Castello's Great Circus--Barnum's Museum Collection and Van Amburgh's
                    Menagerie</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Dan Castello's Great Circus, Barnum's Museum Collection, and Van Ambaugh's
                    Menagerie will be visiting Staunton on August 21st. The editors have "no doubt"
                    that it "will be liberally patronized, as the attractions it offers are of a
                    first-class character. There is a large Menagerie, containing many rare and
                    curious beasts, birds and reptiles, and a very large and talented Circus
                    Company, comprising the very best talent in the country. Also a den of
                    performing Lions, exhibited by Prof. Hall, who goes into their cage and feeds
                    them with raw meat from his naked hand. The Great Street Pageant is spoken of by
                    the press as being really magnificent. There will be a cavalcade of Knights in
                    armor, accompanied by 'lady's farie'; a troop of huzzas; besides Band Chariots
                    and Tableau Cars, upon one of which, a large living Lion will be carried,
                    uncaged and loose, through the open streets. A herd of diminutive Ponies,
                    Elephants, Camels, Drumedaries, etc. etc. All the members of the Company will
                    also appear in the procession, and mounted followed by a huge array of Dens,
                    Cages, avidues, all properly decorated with banners, pennons and all sorts of
                    brilliant insignia."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Model Wife</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Rev. Dr. Willets has been lecturing on this subject, and gives off some
                        sensible [unclear] especially on the [unclear] to be maintained by a model
                        "domestic wife" and her duties, which we commend to our lady readers. We
                        think we know one or two.</p>
                    <p>The modesty of woman's nature causes us to overlook her influences on
                        mankind, because they are silent, like the moisture which nourishes the
                        flower and the tree. And how the world fails to see this. Mankind only looks
                        at that which makes a noise and fuss in the world; and too few recognize the
                        worth of a good woman. That sweet spirit presiding over the home, is an
                        object of reverence. It is a significant fact that the most complete picture
                        of the Bible is the portraiture of a model wife which is beautifully
                        portrayed in the Book of Proverbs. In that picture, there is no mention of
                        idleness; she is industrious; she not only attends to her duties, but she
                        sets the example of industry. A foolish and pernicious idea has crept into
                        society that work should be done only by the common people. Now a-days young
                        ladies try to look like the lily; and like the lily, "they toil not, neither
                        do they spin, yet Solomon in all his glory was not arrayed like one of
                        these."</p>
                    <p>* * * * * *</p>
                    <p>There is such a thing as industry without good management. There are those
                        who are busy from morning to night, and yet fail in the essential elements
                        of a well regulated household. A learned Judge comprehended the idea of
                        proper management in the kitchen, when he had inscribed on his wife's
                        tombstone, "She was an excellent woman and a <emph rend="italic">good
                        cook</emph>." And the old deacon who attended a religious convention, caught
                        the spirit of the same idea, for on being questioned as to what kind of time
                        he had, said, "Very good; and <emph rend="italic">such</emph> puddings." I
                        like to hear a man brag about the manner in which his wife can get up things
                        for the table. It shows that she has the faculty of <emph rend="italic"
                            >gumption</emph>, by which she can accomplish wonders. A woman may have
                        all the <emph rend="italic">ologies</emph>, and music, and French, and if
                        she have not gumption, she don't amount to much. A good wife sees that her
                        household are producers; and her husband does not have to do a dishonorable
                        thing to meet the expenses which accrue from her carelessness. A despondent
                        man finds, in her cheerful co-operations, just the sympathy which he needs,
                        and he is not wise who does not counsel with her in matters of importance.
                        If he is threatened with reverses, why should he not confide in her who can
                        more fully understand him than any one else? She is but his other half.
                        Women have an instinct judgement. God has given them an intuitive
                        perception. Yet some men say, "what do women know about business? Let them
                        attend to the babies!"</p>
                    <p>A good wife stretches out her hand to the afflicted poor. This diamond of
                        mercy is the central jewel in the coronet of goodness. The most unnatural
                        thing in the world is a woman who, having the means, does not relieve the
                        poor. In this sphere of charity she can compare with man. It was not woman
                        who slept in the garden of Gethsemane; it was not woman who refused to
                        follow Christ to the cross; but it was woman who poured out her tears and
                        washed his feet with the hair of her head.</p>
                    <p>It is important to take care of the tongue and temper. We should see twice as
                        much as we say. Some wives' tongues, however, are like race horses, the
                        lighter the load the faster they run. And by this continual fretting, they
                        make men's lives burdens to them; and when death puts the seal of silence
                        upon them, husbands can say with the bereaved clergyman who preached his
                        better half's funeral sermon; pointing to the coffin, said he: "<emph
                            rend="italic">There</emph> the wicked cease from troubling;" and then
                        placing his hand on his heart, "<emph rend="italic">here</emph> the weary
                        are at rest." Others may not be veritable scolds, and yet they make homes
                        uncomfortable by fretting. Nothing is more repulsive than an unruly tongue.
                        Nature is changed by sunshine; so a kind word from a woman has a wonderful
                        charm. Her sphere is home, and there is the real throne of her power. In the
                        retired realms of the domestic life, character is formed, and heaven has
                        given to her the mission of taking the whole world, in its infancy, and
                        shaping it. God has created her to the highest sphere in the world; and
                        infinite goodness pillows the infant's head upon its mother's breast. The
                        fruit of this is the honor of the household; and from high places come back
                        praises to her.</p>
                    <p>There are some who think that they should leave home and take the stump. But,
                        oh, what a mistake. All great and good men have had domestic mothers, whose
                        presence has been the controlling power of their after lives. When John
                        Adams was minister to Hague, he took his son, John Quincy Adams, then a lad
                        of great promise, with him. At a dinner party, some one of the dignitaries
                        arose and toasted John Quincy for his wonderful talents. The father arose to
                        his feet, and, in response, with eyes filled with tears, replied, "Gentlemen
                        I thank you for the respect shown my son; John Quincy has a mother! he has a
                        mother!" And that mother in a letter to her boy, actually shaped and
                        developed his great life; and no man knew that so well as he.</p>
                    <p>The last words of Henry Clay, as death was stealing over him, were,
                        "Mother--mother--mother," She had died fifty years before; but her name was
                        the first on his lips in childhood, and the last in death. And so woman is
                        the morning and evening star of life.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints advice on how to be a model wife.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1867.08.14.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Tournament at Belle Fonte</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Asher</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eidson</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>R. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Major John A. Harman held a medieval tournament on his farm. Augusta county
                    youth rode, jousted, and competed as knights. The events were followed by a
                    dance at the American Hotel at which a Queen and Maids of Honor were crowned.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanna</ln>
                        <fn>John N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn>Angeline</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lt. John N. Hanna and Miss Angeline Carson, both of Augusta, were married
                    on August 1st by the Rev. J. Pinkerton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lambert</ln>
                        <fn>T. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Austin</ln>
                        <fn>Martha C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stringer</ln>
                        <fn>W. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>T. H. Lambert and Miss Martha C. Austin, both of Augusta, were married on
                    July 20th by the Rev. W. R. Stringer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>Christian S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>Fannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Christian S. Baker and Miss Fannie Baylor, daughter of Col. George Baylor,
                    were married in Staunton on August 14th by the Rev. J. I. Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Hare</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John O'Hare, aged 60 years, died in Staunton on August 8th. "He leaves a
                    wife and many friends who mourn his loss."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1867.08.14.04" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>What Time I Wore the Rebel Grey.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>I sit in melancholy mood<lb/> And strain my eyes across the bay,<lb/> Tow'rd
                        where she dwells whom once I woo'd<lb/> What time I wore the rebel grey.</p>
                    <p>I know I'm somewhat better clad,<lb/> My dress is perfect, I may say,<lb/>
                        But ah! my heart was not so sad<lb/> What time I wore the rebel grey.</p>
                    <p>Her robe was linsey-woolsey when<lb/> I saw her first; 'tis silk to-day,<lb/>
                        But she's no fairer now than then,<lb/> What time I wore the rebel grey.</p>
                    <p>Nay, she was fairer then than now,<lb/> One charm has faded quite away,<lb/>
                        For truth shone cloudless on her brow,<lb/> What time I wore the rebel grey.</p>
                    <p>She has forgotten: who has not?<lb/> What men do calmly every day,<lb/> It
                        had been treason to have thought<lb/> What time I wore the rebel grey.</p>
                    <p>They say, "our bitterness and pride<lb/> Are quite absurd." I hate that
                        "they."<lb/> I <emph rend="italic">am</emph> absurd; I should have died<lb/>
                        What time I wore the rebel grey.</p>
                    <p>But I must rise and take my crutch,<lb/> The wind blows chill across the
                        bay;<lb/> Wounds, somehow, did not hurt so much,<lb/> What time I wore the
                        rebel grey.<lb/> Unipes.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This poem expresses a soldier's nostalgia for a woman wooed during his days
                    in uniform.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that in Virginia there are 182 white and 90 black
                    teachers currently teaching in African American schools.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
