<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1867/va.au.vv.1867.11.20">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/10/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-11-20">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day norm="">20</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1867.11.20.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1867.11.20.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Let Us Counsel Together</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A mighty responsibility now rests upon the people of Virginia. The
                        accumulated honors; the glorious records of a past, unsullied by ignoble
                        acts, and the hopes of a posterity born of such a race, rests upon our
                        shoulders. It is a fearful responsibility, surrounded, as we are, by perils
                        such as a people, once free, were never called upon to meet and overcome. It
                        is useless to particularize as to our troubles. They are patent to every
                        thinking white man, and he must see that our only hope is in concert of
                        action, and the thorough organization of our people.</p>
                    <p>While we believe the white people of this State can control it, we feel that
                        we are utterly powerless without organization. The late election has taught
                        us that, and we cannot too earnestly urge upon our people the necessity of
                        turning out on Monday next, (Court Day,) the day selected for the
                        Conservative Mass Meeting to nominate delegates to the Convention, to be
                        held in Richmond, Dec. 11th. The best talent, and the influence of
                        Conservative Old Augusta will be needed in that Convention, and our people,
                        the working masses, should let nothing keep them from attending. "Let us
                        counsel together," and organize thoroughly for the coming contest with
                        Radicalism--that accursed combination of "mean whites" and negroes--which
                        threatens to overrun our once proud Old Dominion.</p>
                    <p>The line has been clearly drawn between white men and negroes, after all our
                        efforts to promote harmony and peace. There is no middle course left; it is,
                        are you "white or black?" Therefore, we appeal to the people of Augusta to
                        rally, as one man, and organize "He who dallies is a dastard--he who doubts
                        is damned."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editor urges the white men of Augusta County to gather on Court Day
                    for a Conservative mass meeting aimed at selecting delegates for the convention.
                    The recent elections have shown that a "line has been clearly drawn" between
                    whites and blacks, and only white unity will defeat rule by "mean whites and
                    negroes."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Object of the Radical Party</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial argues that the Radical Republicans never intended to
                    smoothly reunite the country. Instead they seek to hold on to power by receiving
                    a majority of southern votes engineered through legislation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Whole Question</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper declares that those who were for acceptance of the Military Bill
                    are now against it, since it has become clear that the Republicans never
                    intended to give southern whites a fair shot at returning to the Union and
                    regaining power within their own states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The New York Tribune warns Virginia's black voters that unless "a greater
                    division of all the white vote can be effected," the new state constitution is
                    likely to be rejected. There are 116,982 registered white voters in Virginia, of
                    whom 76,684 voted, while there are 104,772 black voters, of whom 92,155 voted.
                    Of the white voters, 61,249 voted against the convention, and only 14,885 voted
                    for it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1867.11.20.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>70 houses have been built in Staunton over the last year, and the demand
                    has not slackened.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>John F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grabbin</ln>
                        <fn>Emma T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burrows</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John F. Beard, of Staunton, and Miss Emma T. Grabbin, of Richmond, were
                    married in Richmond on November 14th by the Rev. Mr. Burrows.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1867.11.20.04" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Stuart</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following Ballad was published sometime during the year 1862 in one of
                        the first numbers of the Richmond Illustrated News, then a paper of small
                        circulation. We reproduce it now with the belief that the piece will be
                        perfectly original to the great majority of our readers.</p>
                    <p>A cup of potent "mountain dew,"<lb/> By the camp-fire's ruddy light;<lb/> Let
                        us drink to a spirit as real and true,<lb/> As ever drew blade in
                        fight;<lb/> And dashed on the Tyrant's lines of steel,<lb/> For God and his
                        People's right!</p>
                    <p>By Heavens! It seems that his very name<lb/> Embodies a thought of fire;<lb/>
                        It strikes on the ear with a sense of flame,<lb/> And the life blood
                        boundeth higher,<lb/> While the pulses leap and the brain expands,<lb/> In
                        the glow of grand desire.</p>
                    <p>Hark! In the day dawn's misty gray,<lb/> Our bugles are ringing loud,<lb/>
                        And not for the bliss of the coming fray,<lb/> On the war-steeds, fierce and
                        proud,<lb/> We list for the word that shall launch us forth<lb/> Like bolts
                        from the mountain cloud.</p>
                    <p>We list the word! and it comes at length<lb/> In strains so mighty and
                        clear,<lb/> That we rise to the sound with an added strength<lb/> And our
                        souls grow glad to hear,<lb/> And a stir, like the breath of a boiling
                        storm,<lb/> Thrills thro' us from van to rear.</p>
                    <p>Then with the rush of the whirlwind freed,<lb/> We rush by a secret way,<lb/>
                        And merry on sabre, helmet and steed,<lb/> Do the Autumn sunbeams play.<lb/>
                        And the Devil must sharpen his keenest wits,<lb/> To rescue "his own"
                        to-day.</p>
                    <p>Ho! ye who dwell in fertile vales,<lb/> In the pleasant land of Penn,<lb/>
                        Who feast on the fat of her fruitful dales,<lb/> How little ye dream or
                        ken,<lb/> That the Southern Murat has bared his hand<lb/> That Stuart rides
                        again.</p>
                    <p>Close up! close up! we have traveled long,<lb/> But a jolly night's in
                        store;<lb/> A night of wassail, and wit, and song,<lb/> In yon Yankee town
                        before!<lb/> Quick, Sergeant, spur to the front in haste,<lb/> And knock at
                        the Mayor's door."</p>
                    <p>Behold, he comes with a ghost-like grace,<lb/> And his knee joints out of
                        tune,<lb/> And the cold, cold sweat runs down his face,<lb/> In the light of
                        the Autumn moon,<lb/> While his palsied tongue like an ancient Crone,<lb/>
                        But mutters a hollow groan.</p>
                    <p>He cannot speak but his buxom dame,<lb/> With her trembling daughter
                        nigh,<lb/> Shrieks out, "O! honor their virgin fame!<lb/> Pass the poor
                        maiden by."<lb/> (Whereon, with grievous heave and sob,<lb/> She paused in
                        her speech--to cry.)</p>
                    <p>Rise up! we leave to the cherished brood,<lb/> Our vengeance is seeking
                        now,<lb/> The fame which springs from the brutal mood,<lb/> That crimsons a
                            <emph rend="italic">woman's</emph> brow;<lb/> For sons are we of a
                        courtly race,<lb/> And bound by a knightly vow--</p>
                    <p>Rise! we war with the strong alone!<lb/> For where was the caitiff
                        found,<lb/> To sport with an outraged woman's moan,<lb/> Where the Southern
                        trumpets sound?<lb/><emph rend="italic">Tho the blood of the martyred fair
                            makes red,</emph><lb/><emph rend="italic">The wastes of the Southern
                            ground!</emph></p>
                    <p>Enough, while I speak of the Past, my lad,<lb/> There's coming--(hush, lean
                        thee near!)<lb/> There's coming a raid that shall drive them mad,<lb/> And
                        cover their land with fear!<lb/> And you and I by the blessing of God,<lb/>
                        Aye, you and I shall be there!"</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints a poem honoring Jeb Stuart.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
