<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1867/va.au.vv.1867.10.30">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/08/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-10-30">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day norm="">30</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1867.10.30.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1867.10.30.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Folly</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Can it be possible that the 3,000,000 black people in the U. S., whose
                        ancestors were captured, as savages, by the ancestors of the 36,000,000
                        whites now living here, are such fools as to suppose the said 36,000,000 are
                        going to be bothered much longer with them? The common sense of the white
                        people says: "<emph rend="italic">no</emph>, we have made fools of ourselves
                        over this matter long enough and it must be settled." We pity the colored
                        people but we can't help them, unless they help themselves, by working and
                        letting politics alone.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper asserts that whites will soon declare that they will no longer
                    "be bothered" with blacks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper declares that the most "remarkable fact" of the election is that
                    "all the darkies voted radical, but still they say to us 'd--n the yankees.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>How to Settle Our Difficulties</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">white</emph> people of the United States formed a
                        Constitution. The best talent of all sections was employed, and it has been
                        pronounced a "master piece" by the world. But, even under it, the
                        deversified interests, the local prejudices, and the evil nature of man
                        created the most terrible war of recorded time. That war has been over three
                        years and still there is no settlement of our difficulties. Is there no
                        solution, are the people of this country to be forever wrangling and
                        quarrelling? The great mass want peace and quiet, and, if there is no other
                        way to get it, they prefer a military despotism at once. The Southern white
                        people accept the fact, that this is to be one Government, but they ask a
                        fair chance in it.</p>
                    <p>We do not allude to the past, to minor issues, to slavery, the war and its
                        bloody record, or any thing that small politicians may say or do to retain
                        power and place. The great fact stares the American people in the face; that
                        their much boasted Republic is a failure; that a parcel of negroes have
                        caused trouble enough, and that it is to the interest <emph rend="italic">of
                            all</emph> to settle every question, that now divides the <emph
                            rend="italic">white people</emph>, at once and forever.</p>
                    <p>How to do it is the trouble. The framers of the Constitution made provision
                        for a Convention of all the States, upon the application of two thirds. It
                        was a wise provision, the <emph rend="italic">prescient</emph> of great
                        minds, and it should be used by the white people of America now. The war,
                        the present Congress, the President and all, have tried to settle the
                        questions, which divide the people of what was the United States. <emph
                            rend="italic">All have failed</emph>. Now let the people of all the
                        States, forgetting the past, call a Convention of the States and send to it
                        their best men. Let them divest themselves of all prejudice, and send to it
                        their wisest and most experienced men. If they can not settle upon a form of
                        Government, that will do justice to all, and suit this age and people, then
                        Liberty and free Government are lost. Can't we try it?</p>
                    <p>Is there honesty, is there common sense enough among the white people on this
                        continent to throw aside small politicians; to forget the past and face the
                        great issues of the day, as a mighty, free people should? We hope so but
                        fear not. We fear that the day when the Lion and the Lamb shall lie down
                        together, when the conqueror and the conquered, shall dwell together in
                        unity and peace, is far distant but, then, <emph rend="italic">these
                            questions must be settled</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper advocates a Convention of the States at which the white people of
                    the country will get together to solve their differences and "settle upon a form
                    of Government, that will do justice to all." The war, and the even more bitter
                    political disagreements since, show that the Republic, as organized now, is a
                    failure.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Virginia Elections</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At the date of this writing, says the National Intelligencer, the returns of
                        the election just held in Virginia are insufficient to show with any
                        certainty how that State has voted; but we imagine a majority will be to
                        have voted for a convention, and we apprehend also a negro majority secured
                        in that body. This result was intended from the beginning; the frauds in
                        registration and appointment all show that it was a foregone conclusion. The
                        negroes appear to have generally voted as a body, and the two races were
                        pitted one against the other. The few negroes in Richmond and Lynchburg who
                        attempted to vote the Conservative ticket were at once set upon by the
                        infuriated blacks, and barely escaped with their lives, by the desperate
                        exertions of the police, aided by the Federal military. The mob of
                        blood-thirsty negro savages, whom the Radicals propose to invest with the
                        political power of this noble old Commonwealth, yielded slowly before the
                        evident determination of the military to enforce order. These latter acted
                        with much greater forbearance, we imagine, than they would have done if
                        white men had thus defied their authority, and interrupted the peaceful
                        progress of the election.</p>
                    <p>Such is "reconstruction" in Virginia--a black carnival of license, ushered in
                        by fraud, violence, and meditated murder, until things have now come to such
                        a pass, that in the capital of the State which gave us Washington,
                        Jefferson, and Madison, the cry of these demoralized blacks is not merely
                        for the property of the whites, and the blood of their own race who vote
                        independently, but for that, also, of the Northern resident who refuses to
                        endorse their Jacobin projects. Against these last Hunnicutt gives the sign,
                        and the faithful pack echo the cry, "Kill the d--n Yankee; kill him, shoot
                        him!" and the words were at once followed by an effort of the mob to
                        accomplish their murderous purpose.</p>
                    <p>Here we behold the first fruits of the "Congressional policy" of
                        reconstruction. No State has been, so far, restored to the Union; but a
                        class of, heretofore orderly and peaceful laborers, have been transformed
                        into savages athirst for blood and rapine. White men of America, how long
                        will you stand it?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article calls Reconstruction a "black carnival of license, ushered in
                    by fraud, violence and meditated murder," which is transforming "heretofore
                    orderly and peaceful laborers" into "savages athirst for blood and rapine."
                    Early election results foreshadow a black majority at the Convention secured
                    allegedly by fraud and violence against conservative black voters.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Great Struggle--Our Duties South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Valley Virginian agrees with the National Intelligencer's
                    characterization of the recent elections as "the beginning of a stupendous
                    struggle, which is to involve the very existence of free institutions."
                    Conservative citizens must fight against the intrenched power of "the enemy"
                    that make up the Congressional leadership and have access to all-important
                    patronage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>"Whoa January"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper advises against discharging African American workers before
                    another source of labor is secured.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper has only one message for black voters who supported the Radicals:
                    "Go along with your rat killing. If you can stand it we can. WE ARE WHITE."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad Enterprise--What a Great Virginia Mind Thinks
                    of It</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Clinton" writes a letter to the editors of the Valley Virginian urging
                    Augusta voters to support the county's proposal to buy $300,000 in bonds in the
                    proposed Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad. The Railroad will link Covington,
                    Alleghany County, with the Ohio river, ensuring that the trade of the West will
                    pass through Augusta. With this accomplishment, Virginia can become one of the
                    greatest and most prosperous carrying states in the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors urge that conservatives elected to the convention "go and do
                    the best they can. It is a hard task but that makes it all the more honorable."
                    Meanwhile, "the white people at home" should "organize thoroughly and prepare to
                    sustain their delegates better than they did at the polls."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Members of Convention Elected</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrison</ln>
                        <fn>Powell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Southall</ln>
                        <fn>James C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper prints the names of convention members elected statewide,
                    designating whether they are "conservative," "radical," or "negro radical."
                    Augusta elected Joseph A. Waddell and Powell Harrison, both conservatives.
                    Augusta, Albemarle and Louisa also elected James C. Southall, a conservative, as
                    a floating delegate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1867.10.30.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Immigration</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper calls for a meeting of Augusta's farmers to be held at the next
                    circuit court in order to encourage white immigration to the county. "Land
                    owners must do this work, or submit to negro rule and confiscation."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors declare that the voters of Augusta "deserve all they will get"
                    for weak turnout in the recent elections. "Leading men in each neighborhood must
                    devote a little time to public duties, if they desire to preserve their
                    liberties, and bring out a full vote."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Employment Agency</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper endorses establishment of an employment agency in Augusta in
                    which "white men and women, who are willing to work, may be brought to the
                    notice of those needing labor."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>"Freedom!"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper alleges that "a colored man who voted the Conservative ticket at
                    Waynesboro', in this county, on the 22d, was assaulted by another colored man
                    for thus voting."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The District</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The following is the vote total for the election district including
                    Augusta, Albemarle and Louisa: Southall won a 520 vote majority over Tukey in
                    Augusta; a 660 vote majority in Albemarle, and a 115 vote majority in the
                    district as a whole. Tukey won a 1,065 vote majority over Southall in Louisa.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Question</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper asks why the "farmers who are talking so much about white
                    immigration" did not donate seed wheat to the Polish colony in Spotsylvania.
                    Augusta gave only 16 bushels, 5 of which were contributed by Jacob Baylor. "If
                    you want immigration, gentlemen, be at least as liberal as the yankees in the
                    North-west; offer inducements, reduce the price of land, and feed those who
                    come."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Sport</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>Hauntz</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Pheasants, partridges, and squirrels are plentiful near Staunton, and the
                    town's sportsmen are "having a good time." Hauntz Scherer, the "unequaled
                    marksman," donated birds for a feast for the editors of the Virginian. "A couple
                    of 'sports' from N. Y., and two dogs, were here last week on a 'raid.' We
                    understand they enjoyed themselves hugely, and went away rejoicing--chained to
                    the dogs."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Great Work</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors argue that the prosperity accompanying construction of the
                    Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad can defeat Reconstruction and help Virginia regain
                    its powerful place in the Union. "People of Augusta, this is the way to relieve
                    yourselves from the infernal tyranny that now crushes you to the earth! Build
                    railroads, encourage immigration, gain strength materially, and, our word for
                    it, History has been written to little purpose if we can not soon say, proudly
                    and truly, 'Sic Semper Tyrannis.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Election Returns of Augusta County</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>For a Convention</p>
                    <p>Dist. No. 1. (Staunton,) white, 16; colored, 174.<lb/> Dist. No. 2.
                        (Staunton,) white, 19; colored, 230.<lb/> Dist. No. 3. (Middlebrook,) white,
                        26; colored, 142.<lb/> Dist. No. 4. (Greenville,) white, 20; colored,
                        73.<lb/> Dist. No. 5. (Waynesboro',) white, 13; colored, 192.<lb/> Dist. No.
                        6. (New Hope,) white, 51; colored, 80.<lb/> Dist. No. 7. (Mt. Sidney,)
                        white, 28; colored, 30.<lb/> Dist. No. 8. (Mt. Solon,) white, 20; colored,
                        83.<lb/> Dist. No. 9. (Churchville,) white, 40; colored, 70.<lb/>
                        Total--white 233; colored 1024.</p>
                    <p>Against a Convention</p>
                    <p>District No. 1, white 250; colored 1. District No. 2, white 218; colored 3.
                        District No. 3, white 172; colored 0. District No. 4, white 217; colored 0.
                        District No. 5, white 244; colored 4. District No. 6, white 131; colored 0.
                        District No. 7, white 118; colored 0. District No. 8, white 172; colored 1.
                        District No. 9, white 124; colored 0. Total--white 1646; colored 9.</p>
                    <p>Conservatives</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Waddell.</emph>--District No. 1, white 248; colored 1.
                        District No. 2, white 210; colored 3. District No. 3, white 160; colored 0.
                        District No. 4, white 217; colored 0. District No. 5, white 244; colored 4.
                        District No. 6, white 131; colored 0. District No. 7, white 118; colored 0.
                        District No. 8, white 170; colored 1. District No. 9, white 124; colored 0.
                        Total--white 1631; colored 9.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Harrison.</emph>--District No. 1, white 248; colored 1.
                        District No. 2, white 208; colored 3. District No. 3, white 169; colored 0.
                        District No. 4, white 217; colored 0. District No. 5, white 244; colored 4.
                        District No. 6, white 129; colored 0. District No. 7, white 118; colored 0.
                        District No. 8, white 170; colored 1. District No. 9, white 123; colored 0.
                        Total--white 1626; colored 9.</p>
                    <p>Republicans</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Fultz.</emph>--District No. 1, white 14; colored 174.
                        District No. 2, white 20; colored 230. District No. 3, white 26; colored
                        142. District No. 4, white 19; colored 73. District No. 5, white 13; colored
                        192. District No. 6, white 53; colored 80. District No. 7, white 20; colored
                        30. District No. 8, white 21; colored 83. District No. 9, white 40; colored
                        70. Total--white 226; colored 1024.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Gray.</emph>--District No. 1, white 11; colored 174.
                        District No. 2, white 16; colored 230. District No. 3, white 26; colored
                        142. District No. 4, white 19; colored 73. District No. 5, white 13; colored
                        192. District No. 6, white 55; colored 80. District No. 7, white 28; colored
                        80. District No. 8, white 21; colored 33. District No. 9, white 40; colored
                        70. Total--white 229; colored 1024.</p>
                    <p>Conservative</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Southall</emph>--District No. 1, white 252; colored 1.
                        District No. 2, white 208; colored 8. District No. 3, white 168; colored 0.
                        District No. 4, white 217; colored 0. District No. 5, white 244; colored 4.
                        District No. 6, white 131; colored 0. District No. 7, white 118, colored 0.
                        District No. 8, white 169; colored 1. District No. 9, white 124; colored 0.
                        Total--1631; colored 9.</p>
                    <p>Republicans</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Tukey.</emph>--District No. 1, white 12; colored 174.
                        District No. 2, white 15; colored 230. District No. 3, white 26; colored
                        142. District No. 4, white 19; colored 72. District No. 5, white 13; colored
                        192; District No. 6, white 3, colored 0. District No. 7, white 27; colored
                        30. District No. 8, white 24; colored 38. District No. 9, white 50; colored
                        70. Total--white 176; colored 943.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Gordon</emph>--District No. 1, white 2; colored 0.
                        District No. 2, white 3, colored 0. District No. 3, white 0; colored 0.
                        District No. 4, white 0; colored 0. District No. 5, white 0; colored 0.
                        District No. 6, white 50; colored 80. District No. 7, white 0; colored 0.
                        District No. 8, white 0; colored 0. District No. 9, white 0; colored 0.
                        Total--white 55; colored 80.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints the Augusta County election returns.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1867.10.30.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
