<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1867/va.au.vv.1867.06.12">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/24/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-06-12">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day norm="">12</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1867.06.12.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1867.06.12.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Shall We Live?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In all seriousness we asked our people, last week, to think over this
                        proposition. It is no idle question, but one that deeply interests us, as a
                        peculiar people, for what is the life of a people but their distinguishing
                        characteristics--their prominent ideas of living and playing a part in this
                        great moving, active age?</p>
                    <p>From the formation of the present Government of the U. S., two distinct ideas
                        have controlled the two great sections.--The North, owing to the nature of
                        its people; the poverty of its soil and the severity of its climate has
                        always been for protection--for consolidation, and for having new fields
                        opened, by the general Government, for the enterprise and daring of its
                        surplus population. With their extension over the fertile fields of the
                        West,--an empire given to the common Union by the generous South--they
                        carried their peculiar ideas of life and Government. Every neighborhood had
                        its "piece of Boston Common," in the shape of the "teacher" and the
                        "lecturer," and that leaven was used to permeate the whole mass--whether
                        foreign or native born. Hence, on the breaking out of the war, we found the
                        North and the West united on the question, not of Union, but of
                        consolidating and centralizing the General Government.</p>
                    <p>The people of the South, blessed by Providence with the most genial climate
                        and the most productive soil on earth, to say nothing of a laboring class
                        peculiarly fitted for the task of developing its wondrous agricultural
                        resources, naturally became a home people. Rejoicing in the almost fabulous
                        increase of his wealth, disturbed by none of the struggles of the outside
                        world, the Southerner employed the leisure afforded, by exemption from
                        manual labor, in cultivating a natural taste for politics and theoretically
                        building up a model Republic. Proud of their heritage and of their past
                        achievements they became, almost to a man, strict constructionists of that
                        Constitution their greatest minds had given form and substance to; and were
                        bitterly opposed to enlarging the powers of the central head, or creature,
                        as they considered it, at Washington. Thus this people, by force of habit
                        and education, became a peculiar people--a distinct race, as opposed to the
                        centralizing ideas of the North. The election of Lincoln, pre-shadowing the
                        triumph of the Northern idea, found the South, independent of the question
                        of slavery, enthusiastically united in resistance to the full development of
                        that idea, in the affairs of the Nation. These separate and distinct ideas
                        of government, coming in conflict, both supported by brave and determined
                        people, culminated in the bloodiest war of recorded time and, "woe's the
                        day," it resulted in the triumph of the North. He who calls it a "nigger
                        war"--a "foolish war," or seeks for its cause in the little side issues of a
                        mighty contest of ideas, insults the intelligence of the whole American
                        people, and should be laughed to scorn, for attributing to Giants the weak
                        ambition and the little motives of Pigmies.</p>
                    <p>No people can point to a prouder record, no race can exhibit so grand a
                        struggle for an idea, or show a more brilliant galaxy of heroes, who fought,
                        suffered and died to maintain their idea, of free Constitutional Government.
                        The survivors of that glorious struggle--the comrade, the widow, the orphan,
                        have no cause to blush for those "boys in grey" who now "sleep the sleep
                        that knows no waking." But while the living may dwell with mournful pride on
                        their deeds--while the heart swells at the recollection of their acts of
                        devoted daring--acts that will go sounding down the corridors of time,
                        forever, in song and story--we must admit that the Northern idea has
                        practically gained the victory. And surely it becomes us, as a sensible
                        people, to adopt this idea, to engraft so much of its theory of life upon
                        ours, as will enable us to live and move with the tide which is soon to rush
                        upon us. The victory of the North, the triumph of the idea of
                        centralization, settled question far above petty squabbles for office, the
                        dirty work of parties, the mean tyrannies of military commanders, the
                        continued supremacy of the Radical party or the fate of four million
                        negroes. Over the bloody path of war; over a million slain; amid a desolated
                        and almost ruined people, that triumph proclaims, <emph rend="italic">that
                            the people of the U. S. shall be one people</emph>; this government one
                        consolidated government, and that the people of the earth intend to make the
                        seat of the Centralized American Empire, in that magnificent country,
                        popularly known as "The South."</p>
                    <p>Hard as it is, this, people of the South, is the issue you must meet. There
                        is no way to dodge it--no place to hide yourselves; no appeal from the fiat
                        of an all-wise and all-powerful God. Little men, poor weak creatures, who
                        hid themselves during the progress of the great revolution; Bourbons who
                        never forget and never learn, have crawled out of their holes and are vainly
                        trying to lead you in this hour of trial. Some urge you to rush blindly and
                        disgracefully into the Radical party, and others, equally as blind, prate
                        about the "Constitution" and the "reserved rights of States." The cowards
                        and fools who would have you sneak into the Radical party, and the childish
                        old men, who talk about "reserved rights," and an "uprising in the North,"
                        are not the men to follow. One would paralyze your energies by tying you to
                        a dying party--the other beguile you with promises of rights that have been
                        stamped out, forever, in blood. There is but one path of safety--one road to
                        wealth and power. Stand together--accept the conquering idea, mould it to
                        your purposes, use it and live.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article argues that the war was fought over differing interpretations
                    of the constitution caused by sectional peculiarities. The more industrial
                    nature of the North caused it to favor a consolidated government, while the
                    agricultural South supported strict construction of federalism. The Northern
                    viewpoint won, however, and southerners must now adapt it to their lifestyle in
                    order to prosper.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Future</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Baltimore Gazette concludes an article on the Pacific R. R. as follows:</p>
                    <p>"But if it be satisfactory to reflect upon the magnitude and value of the
                        magnificent region that is to be so rapidly thrown open to the American
                        people, and upon the development and material prosperity which may await it,
                        it is a difficult matter to venture upon any conjectures concerning its
                        political future. It is perfectly clear to us that this country can no
                        longer be governed under our old Constitution as now interpreted. As a
                        confederation of independent, sovereign States we might, with some few
                        modifications of our former system, have gone on in tolerable harmony for
                        year to come. As a consolidated empire we cannot get along with republican
                        institutions. In so large a territory conflicting sectional interests of a
                        violent character and on a stupendous scale will constantly manifest
                        themselves. With these Congress will be constantly meddling, and as they
                        will all have their vehement representatives and advocates on the floor,
                        that body will mostly fail to reconcile them, and it will always embitter
                        growing enmities. The attempt to maintain in this country the political
                        system under which we lived before the war will inevitable fail. The
                        Government will be compelled to organize permanently in the North and West
                        the crushing despotism it has set up in the South, or else this generation
                        will live to see the United States resolved into several nations or to
                        witness repudiation and more civil war. The Pacific Railroad gives the
                        country practical possession of a magnificent domain which is so soon to
                        teem with a thriving population and to grow powerful in wealth and
                        resources, but whether good or evil is to result from its development
                        remains to be seen."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This excerpt from the Baltimore Gazette argues that as America expands
                    westward, it will grow increasingly difficult to maintain republican
                    institutions. The government will be forced to erect the same "crushing
                    despotism it has set up in the South" in order to maintain control over the
                    West.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>A Sacred Duty.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We honestly believe, from the lights before us, that Captain Jackson, and his
                        assistant Registrars, for Augusta, will give us a fair registration. We
                        believe they have but one idea in performing their duty--<emph rend="italic"
                            >viz</emph>, a strict obedience to General Schofield's order. We regret
                        to learn that some good men will not register. This is all wrong. It can
                        hurt <emph rend="italic">no honest man</emph> to register and secure the
                        inestimable privilege of voting. In fact it is a sacred duty all owe to
                        themselves and their country. If you have any doubts go to the Registrars
                        and satisfy yourself, but never let it be said that a <emph rend="italic"
                            >free citizen</emph> of "West Augusta," "shirked" a duty so plain, or
                        "dodged" a responsibility so incumbent upon him.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors state their opinion that the registrars will be fair in
                    carrying out their duties, and urge all Augusta citizens to register and vote.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Colonization</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reprints and item from the Journal of Commerce which asserts that
                    the popularity of African colonization by African Americans is increasing, and
                    declares it "the only hope of Africa."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>A Little Too Fast</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It is rumored that some prominent (?) men in Augusta and the Valley have a
                        decided leaning towards the Radical party, but hesitate about coming out
                        boldly until they see which "way the wind blows" at the election. This
                        policy on their part is commendable, and we advise them to watch the signs
                        well. The Radical party, North, is doomed. It has nearly accomplished its
                        mission, and its weakness is shown by the desperate efforts it is making to
                        sustain its "fallen fortunes," by recruits from the South. Its final
                        collapse is only a question of time, and we advise "prominent (?) men" to
                        look well to their action and be very cautious what they do. The end is not
                        yet.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors caution any Augusta resident who is leaning toward the Radical
                    party that its days are numbered in both the South and the North.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Instructions to Registrars. Another Order From General Schofield.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints an order from General Schofield clarifying voter
                    eligibility rules. Anyone who voluntarily joined the Confederate Army, aided it
                    by voluntary donations of food, supplies, horses, etc., or served in any
                    governments that furthered the war effort will be disqualified. Basic
                    humanitarian aid to the sick and wounded will not be penalized. Persons whose
                    status is still in doubt will have to take an oath which the registrar must then
                    accept as binding.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1867.06.12.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>35 new buildings are going up in Staunton and its suburbs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert Boyd, of Ky., sold his mail contracts from Staunton to Bonsack's and
                    Cedar Grove to Col. M. G. Harman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Shameful</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A gentleman of Augusta has estimated that there remain in the county
                    300,000 bushels of corn for sale. "Say that there is half of it, and isn't it a
                    proud record to add that Augusta has not given a grain to the starving people
                    South?"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Wheat</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An intelligent farmer of Augusta reported that "there had never been as
                    much wheat sown in Augusta; that it never looked or headed so well, and that it
                    would be the largest yield ever made in the County." Prices remain inexplicably
                    high, however.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Registration in Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The registration books for Staunton and Middlebrook will be opened on June
                    22nd. Staunton's First District will open at the Court House and the Second
                    District at the Market House. "Each voter must register and vote in his own
                    magisterial district."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>A Revolution in the Iron Business</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The native genius of the Valley again adds its tribute to the material
                        interests of the world. Lorenzo Sybert, of Mt. Solon, after 25 years of
                        study, has discovered the secret of making cast Steel out of common Iron. He
                        has improved on Messinmer's process, and can turn out pure cast steel, from
                        a common "blast furnace" as rapidly as pig metal can be made. By his process
                        he can put a steel rail, with a tempered face, on any railroad, as cheap as
                        the common iron rail. This process has been patented, and the most
                        scientific men North say it is certain to revolutionize the Iron business of
                        the world. All hail! Mr. Sybert, your name will go down to posterity as one
                        of the benefactors of your race--and you add another triumph to the
                        inventive genius of your native Valley.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sybert</ln>
                        <fn>Lorenzo</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This article comments on Mt. Solon resident Lorenzo Sybert's achievements
                    in the iron business.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powell</ln>
                        <fn>H. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stribling</ln>
                        <fn>Ellen M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stribling</ln>
                        <fn>Francis T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latane</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>H. L. Powell, of New York, and Miss Ellen M. Stribling, daughter of Dr.
                    Francis T. Stribling, were married in Staunton's Trinity Church on June 5th by
                    the Rev. J. A. Latane.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillock</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whiteside</ln>
                        <fn>Emma V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooke</ln>
                        <fn>G. G.</fn>
                        <sf>Rev.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>B. F. Gillock and Miss Emma V. Whiteside, both of Salem, were married on
                    May 21st by the Rev. G. G. Brooke.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1867.06.12.04" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Valley Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Randolph</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garnett</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>According the President's report at the meeting of the stockholders of the
                    Valley Railroad, the estimated cost of construction is $58,000 per mile,
                    totaling $6,610,500. The report defends the expense by arguing that increased
                    trade will more than make up for it. Efforts to link the planned Valley road
                    with Baltimore were also discussed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
