<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1867/va.au.vv.1867.04.03">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/10/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-04-03">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day norm="">3</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1867.04.03.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1867.04.03.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>152 guests arrived at the American Hotel last week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A few Words on the Convention Question</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial comes out in favor of a Constitutional Convention, even if
                    it means accepting the demands of Congressional Radicals. The South is forced to
                    do so anyway, the editors argue, so white Virginians should register, vote, and
                    be sure to control the ensuing Convention. "Most of those who demur, in such
                    vehement and sometimes abusive words, to the doings of the Senate are those 'who
                    never set a squadron in the field,' or smelt gun powder during the war. Let
                    those who shouldered the musket be the ones to lead in the reconstruction of the
                    government." "In the words of General Longstreet, we 'must recognize the fact
                    that we are a conquered people,' and manfully perform the duties that condition
                    imposes upon us. Do this like men; do your duty towards the colored people; send
                    the best men available to the Convention, and in less than ten years you will
                    see a new Dominion and a new South--rich, prosperous and free!"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper denounces a hypocritical Congress who, in the case of Mexico,
                    protest against the establishment of a foreign despotism on American soil, but
                    do not take into consideration the "domestic military despotism, which is now
                    over-riding the Constitution and Liberties of a people embraced in the limits of
                    what was once the United States."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>How they Missed It.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The yankees are fond of sensation, and of doing (whether good or evil) what
                        will make people stare. At the close of the late war they had the finest
                        opportunity ever offered to them of taking mankind by surprise and of doing
                        what would have been the talk of the world for all time to come. Had the
                        Federal government only observed the faith plighted over and over again,
                        during the progress of the war, in the time of its agony and fear, by
                        admitting back into the Union of their fathers, without condition, the
                        people whom they were pleased to term their "erring brethren," a spectacle
                        of magnanimity and good faith would have been presented to mankind which has
                        had no parallel in the sixty centuries of the world's existence. As it is,
                        they have but fallen into the old ruts, in which the car of conquering
                        despotism has run, since history began its sad story of the pride and
                        tyranny and faithlessness of the oppressors, and the woes and sorrows of the
                        oppressed. The atrocities of the past two years, probably do not exceed the
                        horrors of Austrian and Russian tyranny, and are equaled perhaps by England,
                        France and other civilized powers. Hence--nobody stares and nobody
                    wonders!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article asserts that the North missed a chance to surprise and impress
                    the world by quickly and graciously reuniting with the defeated South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>A Virginia Soldier's opinion of the Senate and its Traducers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Baltimore, MD., March 22, '67.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Messrs. Editors:</emph>--In some of your exchanges, you
                        no doubt have seen it strongly intimated that certain Senators of the
                        Virginia Assembly are about to resign, influenced to that action by what
                        they insinuate to be the compromise of "manhood" by that body. Now, I am no
                        politician, and by the blessing of God, never will be; but when I see men
                        from whose mouths the word "manhood" comes forth tainted with the poison of
                        cowardice, dare to take upon themselves to rebuke a body composed of the
                        wisdom and chivalry of Virginia, the pen that otherwise would never have
                        miscribed their names, becomes animated with the desire to mete them their
                        merited rebuke. Men, whose antecedents considered, strangely enough, from
                        members of the Virginia Assembly, essay now to pass judgement upon their
                        nobler colleagues; upon men who if they did not during the war, carry arms
                        in battle, at least gave their hearty support in aid of our struggle, and
                        better still, do not labor under the disgraceful charge of national
                        duplicity. Men, who intrepid in the knowledge of unblemished innocence,
                        treat with dignified loathing the pratings of peaceful warriors. These are
                        the sages who may now expect the tongue lashings of fawning demagogues.</p>
                    <p>Audacity sometimes reaches an elevation which draws from noble spirits
                        unconscious praise. Such is the feeling we have when we read the atrocious
                        suggestions of that abandoned old man in Congress. With such emotions are
                        our bosoms stirred when we look back to the scenes of revolutionary violence
                        in France.</p>
                    <p>But the innate smallness of the men I speak of, forever precludes them from
                        the possibility of thus ascending, and binds them down to subversive
                        weapons, to carping and caviling. Men who during the war never snapped a
                        cap, and who had an unheard of aversion to our honored grey; who, like the
                        Irishman, worshipped the Virgin one day and the Devil the next, according as
                        the fluctuating tide of war swept over their homes, thereby hoping (and
                        successfully) to propitiate the constituents thus respectively represented,
                        and who were wont to ensconce themselves in comfortable homes, with hearts
                        at rest save about their individual selves, now turn <emph rend="italic"
                            >men, statesmen, warriors</emph>, and lift their puny voices in
                        opposition to the action of a bold and wise majority.</p>
                    <p>Before their twaddle should thus be heard, let them remove the leprous stigma
                        which attaches to their names. Let them first in peaceful pursuits convince
                        dissenting fellow citizens, that other causes than those imputed, blotted
                        their escutcheons with what posterity will call cowardly turpitude. Let the
                        debt incurred by absence from our bloody fields, be partially paid by whole
                        souled co-operation for the benefit of our people.</p>
                    <p>Our law-giving power is virtually dead. Let those aspiring champions of
                        "manly resistance," with the motto "de mortuis nil nisi bonis" inscribed on
                        their phylacteries, retire to their "comfortable homesteads" and despised
                        and rejected by their acquaintances, at heart let them brood over their
                        degradation, their self-forfeited claim to unimpeachable courage, if ever
                        hereafter to be received in the circle of suffering patriots, to come, wiser
                        and sadder, better and braver men.<lb/> Truly, &amp;c., R. B.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This letter to the editor denounces politicians who did not serve in or
                    support the Confederate military during the war, and now obstruct action on a
                    Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1867.04.03.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Clean Up</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper urges Staunton to follow Winchester's lead in appointing a
                    Sanitary Committee. "Now is the time to go to work. Don't wait for the
                    authorities, but let every man put his own house, back yard, &amp;c., in
                    order. It's the only way to fight the Cholera."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Our Dead</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arnald</ln>
                        <fn>Charley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Memorial Fair and Dinner raised about $169 for the benefit of the
                    Cemetery. The Ladies of Staunton are planning a "grand Fair and dinner" for May
                    10th, the day set aside for decoration of the graves of the Confederate dead.
                    Contributions can be sent to Charley Arnald.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Aid For the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The counties of the lower Valley are sending aid to the destitute in the
                    deep South. "Old Augusta should not lag behind in giving her mite. Won't some of
                    our leading farmers take the matter in hand? Remember 'he who giveth to the
                    poor, lendeth to the Lord.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Registration</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>General Schofield is preparing to register voters under the Military act,
                    and the Convention is planned for June. "Let every man who can register. Not to
                    do so would be about as sensible as 'inaction' would have been in old Jubal, at
                    Fisher's Hill."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Mail Contracts From Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>S. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reynolds</ln>
                        <fn>S. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ennis</ln>
                        <fn>John J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trotter</ln>
                        <fn>A. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The following mail contracts have been awarded: Staunton to Sangersville,
                    S. D. Jones, $160; to Huntersville, by the Springs, S. J. Reynolds, $2,500; to
                    Cedar Grove Mills, Robert Boyd, $619; to Bonsack's, Robert Boyd, $3,333; to
                    Winchester, John J. Ennis, $3,500; Cady's Tunnel to Bath Court House, A. D.
                    Trotter, $740.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>In Memoriam.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The resolutions of the Augusta Fire Company, tell the sad news and convey to
                        his friends and comrades the mournful tidings that George Paul Scherer, of
                        Company I., 5th Va. Reg't., Stonewall Brigade, is no more. He died at the
                        residence of his father in Staunton, last Thursday morning, March 28th, aged
                        26 years. Paul Scherer, as familiarly known, entered the service April,
                        1861, with the West Augusta Guards, of which company he had been a member
                        from its organization. He was every inch a soldier, and his appearance was
                        remarked upon, even in that fine looking, well drilled and disciplined
                        Company. He was wounded at the 2d Battle of Manassas and at Mine Run, but
                        lost but few days from the field. He was taken prisoner at the Wilderness,
                        May 5th, because his noble spirit would not allow him to stay back, though
                        very ill. He was exchanged Nov. '64, and soon afterwards joined his Command
                        and was in every battle up to Appomattox Court House. He was acknowledged by
                        all, officer and men, to be one of the best, if not the best soldier, in the
                        Regiment, and was selected to receive one of the two medals, given by a lady
                        to the "two bravest and best soldiers in the Regiment." He was a member, in
                        good standing, of the Odd Fellow's and Masonic Lodges.</p>
                    <p>No young man in Staunton was more universally popular, and no death has
                        caused a greater sensation in our community. His funeral was the largest
                        ever seen in Staunton: the Fire Company in full uniform, with their engine
                        draped with evergreens and crape, headed by his old comrades, of the
                        Stonewall Band, followed his body to the grave. All classes of our people
                        turned out to pay respect to one, who though he had his faults, had "fought
                        a good fight" for his country, and shown himself a soldier and a man. But he
                        is gone; the gallant soldier; the kind messmate; the generous friend, the
                        cheerful companion has departed from among us. In tendering our heartfelt
                        condolence, to the bereaved family of our friend, we can only add: "Peace be
                        with the dead! Regret cannot wake them. With a sigh for the departed, let us
                        resume the dull business of life, in the certainty that we shall also have
                        our repose."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>George Paul</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper prints an obituary and tribute for George Paul Scherer, a veteran
                    of the Stonewall Brigade.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Runnels</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel D. Myers, of the Valley Virginian Office, and Miss Maggie J.
                    Runnels, of Staunton, were married last Thursday by the Rev. W. A. Harris.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ayers</ln>
                        <fn>W. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLaughlin</ln>
                        <fn>Isabella D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W. L. Ayers and Miss Isabella D. McLaughlin were married on March 27th by
                    the Rev. W. E. Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Leander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Laughlin</ln>
                        <fn>Mary F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Preston</ln>
                        <fn>T. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Leander Wright and Miss Mary F. Laughlin were married on March 27th by the
                    Rev. T. L. Preston.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dull</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Livick</ln>
                        <fn>S. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Preston</ln>
                        <fn>T. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alexander Dull and Miss S. F. Livick were married on March 28th by Rev. T.
                    L. Preston.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engleman</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arehart</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Karicofe</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. H. Engleman and Miss Sarah J. Arehart, both of Augusta, were married on
                    March 21st by the Rev. J. W. Karicofe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Herring</ln>
                        <fn>Robert Lee</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert Lee Herring, aged 3 years and 1 day, died in Staunton on March 26th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowry</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George W. Mowry, aged 58 years, died at his residence near New Hope on
                    March 29th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1867.04.03.04" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Roanoke Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This selection from the Roanoke Times asserts that a united white race has
                    nothing to fear from universal suffrage. "A little kindly conciliation and
                    patient teaching on our part will soon enable the newly enfranchised colored man
                    to see that his own interest requires him to co-operate with his former master,
                    and, after all, his best friend, rather than follow the lead of his designing
                    deceivers, who would rob him of his paltry savings and lure him into a
                    destructive contest of races."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
