<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1867/va.au.vv.1867.11.06">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/09/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-11-06">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day norm="">6</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1867.11.06.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>The Effect of the Northern Elections--What the Democrats Propose--An Amendment
                    Acceptable</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article concurs with the New York World that the Democratic victories
                    in the northern elections may "prevent the Africanization of the South," and
                    pave the way for the end of Reconstruction.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1867.11.06.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Confederate Rank</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial asserts that recognizing Confederate rank in addressing
                    veterans is "no indication of a rebellious and treasonable spirit," but
                    acknowledgement of "actual existence." All Confederate veterans are paroled
                    soldiers, their rank still intact.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Great Question</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Conservative Press of the State is again running blindly into the
                        discussion of questions that only serve to divide the people. All sorts of
                        plans are proposed to defeat the Constitution to be formed by the coming
                        Convention, and none of them practical. There are movements on foot which
                        will give organization, discipline and force to the Conservative masses of
                        the State, if properly responded to. In the meantime, let us cease wordy
                        warfare over delusive ideas. As the Charlottesville Chronicle well says,
                        "Guerrillas cannot fight against Regulars." Therefore be patient, be
                        prudent, and look for the "better time coming."</p>
                    <p>Our great want is material strength, which necessarily brings political
                        power. The State needs white labor, a labor that will identify itself with
                        the people, and add to its material wealth. Brains she has in abundance, and
                        uncultivated lands to support millions, but, without the labor, what are the
                        brains and land worth? It is time to turn our attention to the great
                        necessities of the South, and leave the tom-foolery of politics to the rich
                        and prosperous yankees. They can afford to indulge in such luxuries. We
                        could once, but cannot now, unless we are forced to it to protect ourselves.</p>
                    <p>While organizing for a purpose, let us not neglect the most important
                        element--WHITE IMMIGRATION. The <emph rend="italic">land owners</emph> of
                        this State have its destiny in their hands, but they must be liberal to
                        realize it. They must encourage the millions of Europe to come among us, by
                        cheap lands and kind treatment when they come. Once here, they will
                        assimilate with our people; develope our resources; make us and themselves
                        powerful and great. This will settle Hunnicut, the negro question,
                        Constitution and all. Will the "brains" of the State see that her
                        "uncultivated lands" are soon thickly settled by white people? This is the
                        great question, and we urge the Conservative press of the State to devote
                        more time to it, and less to politics.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial denounces those who waste time coming up with schemes to
                    resist and defeat the constitution to be written at the Convention. Instead,
                    southerners should devote their time to building material prosperity and
                    attracting white immigrant labor. Political power will follow.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A Northern exchange well says: "Out of every dollar the laboring man earns,
                        about sixty cents is taken indirectly to keep indolent negroes, to maintain
                        military despotisms over eleven States, and enrich abolition officials. This
                        is why our poor men are kept poor, and our laboring men complain of hard
                        times. It is the high prices and high taxes that take their money, and it is
                        the negro bureau, military despotism, and abolition officials that make
                        taxes high. To get rid of these, Radicalism must be voted out of power."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper applauds an item blaming high taxes and poverty on the Freedman's
                    Bureau and Republican rule.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The following are the state wide vote totals. 164,198 persons voted
                    overall. 104,589 were for a convention and 59,180 against. 89,533 African
                    Americans voted for a convention and 629 against. 13,000 whites were for a
                    convention and 58,043 against.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Only Remedy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Now that the negroes have drawn a blood line between themselves and the
                        whites, and have manifested a fierce and stubborn determination to establish
                        their supremacy, at the hazard of ruin to all our interests, it becomes us,
                        says the Richmond <emph rend="italic">Whig</emph>, to cast about for the
                        means of self-protection. We must get white population from the North and
                        from Europe. We must make every effort to do so, and incur any sacrifice
                        that may be necessary to accomplish it. Ten of the most productive States of
                        the Union must not be given up to ignorant negroes to become sterile wastes.
                        We must get white population enough to secure the ascendency, if we have to
                        give away one-fourth, or even one-half of our lands. We must not stand upon
                        the price. With black ascendency our lands will, in process of time, become
                        valueless, for our laborers will be our political masters, and they will fix
                        their wages by law and make them and the taxes on all property so onerous
                        that property holders will be poorer than paupers.</p>
                    <p>The negroes (with some few honorable exceptions, never to be forgotten) have
                        raised their hands against the whites and threaten us with ruin, simply
                        because we are white. They have embarked in a wild crusade against all
                        white--the Northern white and the foreigner as well as the whites of the
                        South. There is but one way of arresting and turning back this threatening
                        tide of negro fanaticism and ignorance, and that is by presenting to people
                        at the North and abroad such inducements as they will be unable to resist.
                        No matter where the whites shall come from or what may be their antecedents,
                        they will make common cause with us, for it is against their skin, color and
                        kindred that this crusade has been set afoot.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article asserts that the election results show that African Americans
                    "have drawn a blood line between themselves and the whites," and are aiming at
                    establishing "supremacy." The only way the south can "protect" themselves is to
                    secure white majorities by encouraging immigration from the North and Europe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1867.11.06.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Of the 4,823 registered voters in Augusta, only 2,912 went to the polls.
                    The 1,011 who did not vote were "all whites of course."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Col. Bolivar Christian and A. B. Cochran, both of Staunton, addressed a
                    meeting of the Independent Order of Odd Fellows at Mount Sidney.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Religious</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weed</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Father</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. Father Weed is pastor of the Catholic Mission stationed in
                    Staunton. The mission extends from Manassas junction, through Gordonsville and
                    on to Charlottesville and Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>County Court--October Term</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>John Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ferguson</ln>
                        <fn>D. O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bosserman</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Freed</ln>
                        <fn>Albert G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunlap</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brownloe</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Rourk</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawkins</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smiley</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Quick</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuey</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Withrow</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ward</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCarty</ln>
                        <fn>Patrick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yount</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The County Court met for the October term, John Marshall McCue presiding.
                    D. O. Ferguson and Joseph D. Craig sat as associate justices. The following were
                    appointed Surveyors of the Public Roads: William Bosserman, Albert G. Freed,
                    John Dunlap, John Brownloe, Daniel O'Rourk, John Hawkins, Alexander M. Smiley,
                    Samuel W. Quick, John A. Shuey, and Henry Palmer. The vote on the Chesapeake and
                    Ohio Railroad subscription will be postponed until December 19th. Bolivar
                    Christian, William Withrow, Jr., and W. A. Burke were appointed proxies for
                    Augusta County as stockholder in the Virginia Central Railroad at their next
                    meeting; and Marshall Hanger, M. G. Harman, and H. M. Bell were appointed
                    alternates. William Ward, white, was convicted of attempted rape and sentenced
                    to one year in jail. In Commonwealth vs. Patrick McCarty, McCarty was fined one
                    cent and costs for assault and battery. Martin Yount, Surveyor of Roads, was
                    fined one cent and costs. Several deeds and wills were admitted to the record.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Matheney</ln>
                        <fn>W. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stanton</ln>
                        <fn>Nella</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W. M. Matheney and Mrs. Nella Stanton, both of Staunton, were married on
                    October 4th by the Rev. Mr. Taylor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bunch</ln>
                        <fn>Martha J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawes</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. P. Wright and Martha J. Bunch, both of Augusta, were married on October
                    8th by the Rev. H. H. Hawes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fishburne</ln>
                        <fn>N. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Van Lear</ln>
                        <fn>Ella L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>See</ln>
                        <fn>S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>N. G. Fishburne and Miss Ella L. Van Lear, all of Augusta, were married on
                    October 10th by the Rev. S. M. See.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahaney</ln>
                        <fn>John T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Riley</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John T. Mahaney and Miss Sarah M. Riley, both of Augusta, were married on
                    October 10th by the Rev. J. L. Clark.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davies</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W. H. Davies, M. D., and Miss Margaret A. Phillips were married on October
                    17th by the Rev. J. Pinkerton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henkle</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>Angeline</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>R. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David Henkle and Mrs. Angeline Woodward, both of Augusta, were married on
                    October 21st by the Rev. R. P. Kennedy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Demasters</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Horatio</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James W. Campbell and Miss Virginia Demasters, both of Augusta, were
                    married on October 15th by the Rev. Horatio Thompson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Glossbrenner</ln>
                        <fn>M. L. Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yonce</ln>
                        <fn>W. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James H. Turner and Miss M. L. Jane Glossbrenner, both of Augusta, were
                    married on October 23rd by the Rev. W. B. Yonce.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1867.11.06.04" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Bachelors' Perils</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper warns bachelors against visiting families with daughters as it
                    will "eventually drift into matrimony." Even though he has convinced himself he
                    is seen more as a brother, and could never choose one out of a family of several
                    sisters, he will inevitably end up favoring one, usually the youngest,
                    especially if he is middle-aged. Soon his visits will be forced to take on a
                    different character.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
