<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1862/pa.fr.sd.1862.01.28">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>7/8/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1862-01-28">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>28</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.01.28.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The President and Fugitive Slaves of Rebels</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints the proclamation of President Lincoln whereby he declared that the
                    government cannot return fugitive slaves to owners in the states that have
                    declared war on the United States, since those states have repudiated the
                    protection of the U. S. government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1-3; further particulars of the battle at Mill
                Springs, Kentucky, columns 4 and 5; story reporting the construction of new
                fortifications on the Rip Raps near Fortress Monroe, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.01.28.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Weary Not in Well Doing</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The Committee on Hospital Supplies, make their appeal to the 'loyal women
                    of the country. The mission is one which belongs very much to your sphere. It
                    can be accomplished only by your agency.'"</excerpt>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges the women of Pennsylvania to form Ladies' Aid Societies in every
                    village and town, as well as church and school societies, to make sure that all
                    women contribute necessary supplies for the soldiers who are ill in hospitals
                    throughout the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Spirit and Abolitionism!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>When will the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> cease blowing and scribbling
                        upon this favorite theme? It has really become as great a passion with it as
                        that of the renowned Don Quixote, whose fertile imagination on one occasion
                        conjured up an army of warriors, against whom the chivalrous knight believed
                        it to be his holy mission to engage in deadly combat. He could not be
                        persuaded that they were a flock of sheep any more than our Democratic
                        Quixote believes that the poor Abolitionists are other than monsters and
                        fiends! A weekly paper is a poor medium through which to issue his fierce
                        philippics against the dangerous Abolition combination in the North, and the
                        new editor might as well vacate for a season his chair editorial, pocket the
                        Richmond papers from which to cull his favorite texts, mount some fleet
                        Rosinante, and fulminate without limit against Abolitionism in his
                        journeyings through his native county. What a sight of good he might
                        accomplish to himself pecuniarily and to his party politically! What a
                        notoriety he might acquire, and what ovations would meet him in the
                        welcoming shouts of the throng when he would pull up the "old hoss" at every
                        favorite stopping place! Then he would be in the broad way of establishing
                            <emph rend="italic">his</emph> mission as was the famous hero of
                        Servantes. When accomplished, he could then write the story of his thrilling
                        adventures, and become an "immortal" by their publication in the quarto
                        sheet of the <emph rend="italic">Valley Spirit</emph>. Jupiter Custos! why
                        don't you undertake the great work, man, at once? Begin <emph rend="italic"
                            >your</emph> movement when Gen. M'Clellan shall have closed around the
                        traitorous scamps of Secessia, and begun to strike his crushing blows upon
                        the head of the Rebellion. If your field of operations in Franklin County is
                        but a "pent-up Utica," you will become as notorious at home as the gallant
                        leader of our armies will become famous throughout the country.</p>
                    <p>We had written thus far when our eyes rested on the following strangely
                        fashioned lines in the last <emph rend="italic">Spirit:</emph></p>
                    <p>"It must be patent to every mind that the Abolition party is an enemy to the
                        present Administration."</p>
                    <p>What does the editor mean here? Did he not publish to the people of Franklin
                        Co., in a previous number of his paper, that by the advent of a certain
                        "fiendish party to power," the Southern people had become alarmed? The
                        Abolition party, in the last number of his paper "is an enemy to the present
                        Administration," and they are consequently not in power, while the "fiends"
                        have ceased to alarm the rebel slave-holder! Maybe the new editor is
                        endeavoring to mollify his outraged Republican friends, and means hereafter
                        to speak in more respectful terms of the Republican party, who really did
                        make their advent to power! Or, perhaps, as there are certain lucid
                        intervals with every political Quixote, he has forgotten his previous
                        ravings, and his momentary sanity prompts him to be courteous and dignified
                        even to his political opponents. The new editor may deserve a better fate,
                        but we fear his political madness will prompt him at times to the utterance
                        of such extravagant denunciations of even those in his own party, who are
                        tainted in the least with the anti-slavery feeling, that he will not only
                        make himself very ridiculous, but very unpopular. We close with the proffer
                        of our counsel, and beg the editor's permission to use a little Latin for
                        his own private car: <emph rend="italic">Monito in tempore!</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Encourages the editor of the Valley Spirit to quit his job at the newspaper
                    and instead travel through the county preaching against abolitionism. Expresses
                    bewilderment at the Spirit's most recent proclamation whereby he declares that
                    "the Abolition party is an enemy to the present Administration" when in the past
                    he has repeatedly denounced that administration.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Battle of Blue's Gap</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A letter from Mr. H. R. Treher, who formerly resided in Chambersburg, to
                    his parents in Loudon. Mr. Treher participated several weeks ago in the battle
                    of Blue's Gap in western Virginia and describes his part in it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Article noting the surrender of Biloxi, article describing the process for
                extraction of turpentine from trees, column 3; news from England, from China of a
                coup d'etat, and from Missouri, column 4; advertisements, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.01.28.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Death of Charles Linderman</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lindeman</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes the death several weeks prior of Mr. Charles Linderman, a citizen of
                    Chambersburg who had moved to Bendersville, Anderson County, where he was
                    teaching music. Mr. Linderman was about 24 years old. His remains were brought
                    to Chambersburg for burial.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Trial of Jacob McFerren for the Murder of John Welsh</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFerren</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>C. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>Geo.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn>F. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn>J. M'D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClellan</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Cormick</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allison</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phalon</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koons</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Laughlin</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plough</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shannon</ln>
                        <fn>D. M. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKinnie</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheiry</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowermaster</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Relates "the facts of the case" as they were presented at trial and reports
                    that the jury handed down a verdict of not guilty. Messrs. G. W. Brewer, C. S.
                    Eyster, and District Attorney George Eyster represented the Commonwealth, and
                    Messrs. F. M. Kimmell, W. Reilly, J. M'D. Sharpe, Wm. McClellan, and W. S.
                    Everett represented the defendant. The jury consisted of R. M'Cormick, D. Myers,
                    W. Allison, M. Phalon, W. Koons, J. Laughlin, B. Huber, P. Plough, D. M. B.
                    Shannon, J. McKinnie, A. Sheiry, and J. Bowermaster.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports proceedings of the recent session of court held in Chambersburg on
                    the previous Monday.</summary>
                <note>The names involved in court proceedings are listed in the Valley Spirit in the
                    January 29, 1862, issue.</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hetrich</ln>
                        <fn>Geo.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lincks</ln>
                        <fn>Saloma</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Geo. Hetrich and Miss Saloma Lincks, both of Chambersburg, were married
                    on January 26.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 4 and 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.01.28.04">
            <pageNote>Proceedings of Congress, column 1; prices current, column 1; advertisements,
                columns 2-5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
