<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1862/pa.fr.sd.1862.05.06">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>7/16/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1862-05-06">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>06</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.05.06.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Correspondence between Com. Farragut and the Mayor of New Orleans</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The city is yours by the power of brutal force--not by the choice or
                    consent of its inhabitants."--Mayor of New Orleans, John F. Monroe......"Your
                    occupying the city does not transfer their allegiance from the Government of
                    their choice to one which they have deliberately repudiated."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Publishes the correspondence between Mayor Monroe of New Orleans and
                    Commodore Farragut, the commanding officer of the U. S. flagship Hartford. In
                    his letter, Commodore Farragut requests that the mayor surrender the city to his
                    forces, and, in reply, Mayor Monroe concedes, but makes clear that he does so
                    primarily because he is helpless to resist.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Rebel Barbarities</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The joint Committee on the Conduct of the War, have made a report in regard
                        to the barbarous treatment by the Rebels, at Manassas, of the remains of
                        officers of the United States Army, killed in the battle there.</p>
                    <p>They examined a number of witnesses whose testimony is submitted. The facts
                        disclosed are of a repulsive, shocking and painful character. The Committee
                        say, in conclusion:</p>
                    <p>"The members of your Committee might content themselves by leaving this
                        testimony to the Senate and the people without a word of comment; but when
                        the enemies of a just and generous Government are attempting to excite the
                        sympathy of disloyal men in our own country and to solicit the aid of
                        Foreign Governments by the grossest misrepresentations of the objects of the
                        war and of the Republic, this, the most startling evidence of their
                        insincerity and inhumanity, deserves some notice at our hands.</p>
                    <p>"History will be examined in vain for a parallel to this rebellion against a
                        good Government--long prepared for by ambitious men, who were made doubly
                        confident of success by the aid and counsel of former Administrations, and
                        the belief that their plans were unobserved by a magnanimous people.</p>
                    <p>"They precipitated the war at a moment when the General Administration had
                        jut been changed, under circumstances of astounding perfidy, without a
                        single reasonable ground of complaint, and in the face of repeated
                        manifestations of moderation and peace on the part of the President and his
                        family, they took up arms and declared that they would never surrender until
                        their rebellion had been recognized, or the institution established by our
                        fathers had been destroyed. The people of the loyal States, at last
                        convinced that they could preserve their liberties only by an appeal to the
                        God of battles, rushed to the standard of the Republic in response to the
                        call of the Chief Magistrate.</p>
                    <p>"Every step of this monstrous treason has been marked by violence and crime.
                        No transgression has been too great and no wrong too startling for its
                        leaders. They disregarded the sanctity of the oaths they had taken to
                        support the Constitution; they repudiated all their obligations to the
                        people of the free States; they deceived and betrayed their own fellow
                        citizens and crowded their armies with forced levies and they drove from
                        their midst all who would not yield to their despotism, and filled their
                        prisons with men who would not enlist under their flag. They have now
                        crowned the rebellion by the perpetration of deeds scarcely known even to
                        savage warfare.</p>
                    <p>"The investigations of your committee have established this fact beyond
                        controversy. The witnesses called before us, were men of undoubted veracity
                        and character. Some of the men occupy high positions in the army, and others
                        high positions in civil life. Differing in political sentiments, their
                        evidence presents a remarkable concurrence of opinion and of judgment.</p>
                    <p>"Our fellow-countrymen, heretofore sufficiently impressed by the generosity
                        and forbearance of the Government of the United States, and by the barbarous
                        character of the crusade against it, will be shocked by the statements of
                        these unimpeached and unimpeachable witnesses, and foreign nations must,
                        with one accord, however they have hesitated heretofore, consign to lasting
                        odium the authors of crimes which, in all their details, exceed the worst
                        excesses of the Sepoys of India."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Publishes the findings of the Committee on the Conduct of the War in their
                    investigation of the "barbarous treatment by the Rebels" of the dead and dying
                    officers of the United States army following the battle at Manassas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Letter from Camp Shiloh--The Pea Ridge Reconnoisance in Force</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In a letter from Camp Shiloh, or Pittsburg Landing, a correspondent of the
                        Chicago <emph rend="italic">Tribune</emph>, under date of April 24th,
                        writes:</p>
                    <p>General Halleck is evidently determined not to let the grass grow under his
                        feet.--This morning being the first day since the rains that it was possible
                        to move artillery upon these execrable roads, he ordered a reconnoissance
                        [sic] in force of the enemy's position on the road to Corinth. Early in the
                        morning a portion of the division of Gen. Johnson and Col. Stumbaugh, the
                        batteries of Capts. Terrell, Muchler, Goodspeed, and of Company H, Fifth
                        regiment regular army, took up their line of march on the Corinth road, with
                        three days' rations in their haversacks. The cavalry consisted of the Fourth
                        Illinois, Col. Dickey, Second Kentucky, Third Kentucky, and Second Indiana,
                        and a few companies of regulars, under the command of Major King. The
                        Thirty-fifth Ohio and the Sixteenth Regular Infantry also accompanied the
                        pieces.</p>
                    <p>I recognized as part of Gen. M'Cook's division the Thirty-second and
                        Thirty-sixth Indiana, the Fifteenth and Forty-ninth Ohio, Seventy-seventh
                        Pennsylvania, Thirtieth and Thirty-ninth Indiana, Thirty-fourth Illinois,
                        and Seventy-sixth Ohio, with a battery.--Among the guns were five or six
                        twenty-pound Parrotts and several Napoleons. The whole was under the command
                        of Andrew Jackson Smith, General of Division, a very excellent officer, as I
                        learn from old United States army men.</p>
                    <p>About nine miles from the landing, the force came upon and surprised a
                        regiment or two of rebel infantry encamped in front of Pea Ridge, near the
                        town or hamlet of Monterey. The rebels at first formed in line of battle,
                        and delivered a volley, but fled immediately, many of them throwing away
                        their arms. A number of them occupied a log-house, from which they also
                        fired upon our men.</p>
                    <p>The nature of the country--it being pretty thickly wooded--prevented our
                        troops forming in line, and they moved by the flank, in columns of four
                        deep. The column was led by a regiment of regulars, which had been in the
                        late action, but is mostly composed of recruits. It was found, I heard from
                        an officer friend, impossible at first to bring these men under fire, and
                        the Eighth Missouri, Colonel Peckham, being ordered to the front, passed by
                        them at the charge, and soon took posession [sic] of the log-house and camp
                        of the enemy.</p>
                    <p>In the meantime a force had been detailed to make a reconnoissance [sic] on
                        the Purdy road. It was under the command of Col. Wood, the acting brigadier
                        in Wallace's division. Of this force I have as yet nothing definite, but
                        last night heard heavy firing to the front evidently artillery, and this
                        morning, at day light Company A, Chicago Light Artillery, Lieut. Wood
                        commanding, were ordered out with two days rations, so that some sharp work
                        is in progress.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A correspondent of the Chicago Tribune gives a report of General Halleck's
                    movements at Camp Shiloh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1 and 2</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.05.06.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Barbarism of Slavery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The descriptions of cannibal warfare seem to have been the model of the
                    slaveholding barbarians."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The report of the joint Congressional Committee on the Conduct of the War,
                        exposing the atrocities perpetrated upon the Union prisoners, and our
                        wounded and dead, is destined to create a strong and indignant feeling in
                        every part of the civilized world.</p>
                    <p>The witnesses examined by the Committee were men of undoubted character and
                        truthfulness. They testify with one accord that the traitors were animated
                        by the most savage and fiendish motives. As an evidence of the atrocity that
                        characterized the rebel soldiery during and after the battle of Bull Run, it
                        was in evidence before the Committee, that the wounded Union soldiers were
                        bayoneted while lying on the field; that, in many instances, they were
                        stripped entirely naked and buried with their faces downward, as an
                        indignity; that their remains were exhumed from the grave, their bones taken
                        by the Southern Slave-drivers and Sepoys as trophies, to be exhibited as
                        evidences of their valor and heroism.</p>
                    <p>In dwelling upon these revolting exposures, says "Occasional," the Washington
                        correspondent of the <emph rend="italic">Press</emph>, the question is
                        irresistibly presented whether a rebellion thus disgraced by inhumanity and
                        crime deserves the countenance, much less the sympathy, of the people of the
                        loyal States. Our brave countrymen who have gone forth to defend our
                        imperilled [sic] Constitution, and whose arms are blessed by the prayers of
                        their mothers and daughters and sisters at home, and who proclaim as they
                        advance into the seceded territory, that their motto is restoration an not
                        revenge, are subjected to treatment from which the roving Bedouin and the
                        fiery Cossack would shrink with terror. The descriptions of cannibal warfare
                        seem to have been the model of the slaveholding barbarians. When we contrast
                        the forbearance of the Government, its charity, its generosity, its humanity
                        in the reception and care of the rebel prisoners, with the mutilation of our
                        wounded and the desecration of our dead, with the insults and ignominy
                        heaped upon all who fell into hands of the leaders of this great treason;
                        when we dwell upon the indiscriminate barbarities upon the armed and the
                        unarmed, the old and the young, the unprotected and fugitive mother and her
                        little children, we may well appeal to civilization and Christianity to
                        judge between us and our infuriated adversaries. The Northern man who will
                        not see in this contrast an invocation to patriotic action, a stimulant to
                        forego all respect for the assassins and murderers who sustain the cause of
                        the rebellion, should be marked with the scorn and detestation of his race.
                        What? Constitutional rights for such as these? Who will ask it? Who will now
                        contend that the authors of these crimes shall not be punished, that their
                        worthless lives shall not answer to the stern behests of justice, and their
                        estates shall not be confiscated? What party will dare to refuse to denounce
                        them? </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Echoes the opinion of "Occasional," the Washington correspondent of the
                    Philadelphia Press who questions whether a rebellion that has committed the
                    unspeakable and degrading acts that the Southern soldiers committed at Manassas
                    deserves the respect or the sympathy of the people of the Northern states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Arming the Contrabands</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Bulletin</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We have no idea that these blacks would ever make good soldiers in the
                    field. . . . Doubtless, with the taste for finery that characterizes the
                    Africans, they will be very proud of their uniforms, and the pleasure of wearing
                    them will excite their ambition to make good soldiers."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It is stated positively, says the Philadelphia <emph rend="italic"
                        >Bulletin</emph>, in letters from Washington, that the Secretary of War has
                        fully determined to have "contrabands" uniformed, armed and equipped at the
                        forts captured on our Southern coast. The orders have been issued for the
                        requisite supply of arms and uniforms. The Zouave style of dress has been
                        selected, with braided jackets and baggy red trousers.</p>
                    <p>We have no idea that these blacks would ever make good soldiers in the field.
                        But for garrison duty, with a proper proportion of well-trained white
                        officers, they may be very serviceable. They are peculiarly well fitted for
                        summer service at those localities in the South where the health of
                        unacclimated whites is likely to suffer. Doubtless, with the taste for
                        finery that characterizes the Africans, they will be very proud of their
                        uniforms, and the pleasure of wearing them will excite their ambition to
                        make good soldiers. The determination of the Secretary of War to employ the
                        contrabands in this way will meet with general approval from the people.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Secretary of War has determined to arm former
                    slaves--"Contrabands"--and position them at the forts captured on the Southern
                    coast.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Gen. Fremont and the Guerillas [sic]</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that General Fremont is determined to clear his ranks of "rebel"
                    guerrillas. Such groups have arisen in part from the orders given by Governor
                    Letcher of Virginia to the people living in the mountain regions of the state to
                    carry on guerrilla warfare.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that Parson Brownlow has declared himself a slaveholder, but argued
                    that if slavery had to end to preserve the Union, then "let slavery go to the
                    dogs."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Remarks that the Breckinridge papers are protesting a new society called
                    "The Loyal Union," which resolves that only loyal men should be elected to
                    office. The Dispatch comments that it is "no wonder the Breckinridgers kick
                    against such an association."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Yorktown Evacuated!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"I shall pursue the enemy to the wall."--G. B. M'Clellan, Maj.-Gen.</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Proclaims that the Confederate troops have retreated from Yorktown toward
                    Richmond. The Union forces are now in possession of many of the enemy's guns,
                    ammunition, camp equipment, and so forth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>From Gen. Halleck's Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists the official figures of casualties in each division that were killed,
                    wounded, or missing at Pittsburg Landing. The total number of killed, wounded,
                    or missing is 13,763.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Capture of Fort Macon--400 Prisoners Taken</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report of the capture of Fort Macon after eleven hours' bombardment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Confederacy Supplied with Funds</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Inquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates a story allegedly told by a prisoner released from Richmond
                    claiming that the Confederates kidnapped about seventy members of a "Donkard"
                    settlement--peopled with "hard-working, long-bearded, inoffensive people"--in
                    Rockingham County, Virginia. Reports that the Confederates held them for ransom
                    until one of their number was able to procure $22,500 in hard silver for the
                    release of most of the captives. The others were forced to work among the
                    "negroe teamsters."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements for political candidates, column 1; additional items regarding
                the fall of New Orleans, column 4; report of a movement against Southern troops by
                General Mitchell at Huntsville, Alabama, column 4</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.05.06.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Aping the Chivalry</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that some "secesh" women carry old horse pistols and other deadly
                    weapons. Remarks that anyone would prefer to face "powder and ball" rather than
                    "the fire of a Rebel woman with a long tongue."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Glorious Victory!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the bells rang in Chambersburg when it was learned that the
                    Confederates retreated from Yorktown.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Press</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"In future ages, those who read the full history of the conspiracy will
                    wonder whether the authors of the rebel atrocities belonged to the human race of
                    the nineteenth century, or whether they were not infernal spirits of wickedness
                    and depravity."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that as they were leaving New Orleans, General Lovell's men fired
                    on the residents of the city who cheered the approach of U. S. forces. Remarks
                    that this action demonstrates the "barbarity" to which the Confederates are
                    prone.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Difference</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Comments that, as "a contemporary" has remarked, the Republicans are
                    attempting to defeat the rebellion, while the Democrats are merely trying to
                    defeat the Republicans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maurer</ln>
                        <fn>B. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steffey</ln>
                        <fn>Annie C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. B. L. Maurer, of Chambersburg, and Miss Annie C. Steffey of
                    Williamsport, Maryland, were married in Hagerstown on April 30.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eberly</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eberly</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Mary Eberly, aged 55 years, died on April 2 in Johnson County, Iowa,
                    after a protracted sickness. She was the wife of Peter Eberly, formerly of
                    Chambersburg, and still had many relatives who reside in Franklin County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>advertisements, columns 3-5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.05.06.04">
            <pageNote>Prices current, column 1; advertisements, columns 1-5;</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
