<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1862/pa.fr.sd.1862.04.08">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>7/15/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1862-04-08">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day>08</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote>Issue number 95, published April 4, 1862, is missing.</editionNote>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.04.08.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Later from East Florida</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that General Sherman has sensed great loyalty to the Union among
                    the residents of Florida.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1 and 2; chronicle of incidents that occurred at Pea
                Ridge, Arkansas, and in Eastern Tennessee, column 4</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.04.08.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Democratic Conservatism</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A liberal course of policy, in the peaceful days of the past, was a benign
                        political philosophy which numerous well-thinking persons respected oftener
                        than they openly applauded. The very some of a noble magnanimity, with this
                        class of persons, was the dispassionate and liberal advocacy of measures of
                        public polity, and the fervent and eloquent appeals to the people to oppose
                        the dangerous tendency of the extreme views of those who were earnestly
                        contending for a principle of right, without regarding the popular cry that
                        they were far "in advance of all political parties. With such advocates of
                        liberal views--such advocates of the boasted "Union-saving" <emph
                            rend="italic">conservatism</emph>--concession after concession to the
                        South, which has been preparing to involve our country in her present
                        troubles, was the very height of "National Conservative Democracy"--or,
                        rather, the very depth of Northern political infamy!</p>
                    <p>This "national" party, entrusted with the administration of public affairs
                        for so many years, had at last lost its once formidable influence. And why?
                        Not because of its disruption during the late Presidential campaign, and the
                        subsequent election of Mr. Lincoln; but because many of its prominent men,
                        among whom was one of its candidates for the Presidency, (Breckinridge),
                        have since joined the accursed conspiracy against the Government. What a
                        comment upon the boasted <emph rend="italic">conservatism</emph> of the once
                        jubilant Democracy, whose title of "national" erst attracted to their party
                        standard the multitudes of honest men in the North! With such a "national
                        conservative" party in power, controlled by designing Southern politicians
                        and statesmen, can men marvel now that the least check given in the past to
                        Southern arrogance and pretension, and to the rapid strides of the Slave
                        Oligarchy to power, has been met by brutal outrage and insult, and not by
                        manly discussion? Can they wonder that, while these bellicose Southern
                        oligarchs ever claimed the right to clamor on the <emph rend="italic"
                        >pro</emph> side of the slavery question, in Northern cities and inland
                        towns, during Presidential contests, Southern "conservative" Democrats have
                        threatened and brutally assaulted anti-legislature for discussing and
                        maintaining the opposite side of the question? Charles Sumner would have
                        been stricken by as many dagder [sic] thrusts as Caesar bore, had he visited
                        the delectable Arcadia of Southern "chivalry" and Slavery, and claimed the
                        right of speech! He well knew that if the "honorable" representatives of
                        Southern Slavery would brutally assault him in the sacred precincts of the
                        Capital of his country, for exercising the freedom of speech guaranteed to
                        all, reason and justice would appeal in vain to the worse than brutal
                        constituents!</p>
                    <p>How does Democratic "national conservatism" progress now? Is it disposed
                        still to affiliate with traitors, while it maintains a studied reticence
                        upon the treason of its leaders? Democratic "conservatism"! What has it lead
                        [sic] to! All the compromise measures of good and great men had only the
                        effect of securing temporary safety to the Union, and not averting
                        permanently its threatened dissolution. The glowing eloquence of Clay, could
                        he have returned to earth, would have plead in vain to the conspirators on
                        the eve of the Rebellion. No compromise, no concession, no effort made to
                        stay the causeless war made upon our Government, could have been of any
                        avail. The temporizing policy of the "Conservative Democracy" had rendered
                        Southern leaders too arrogant at last to heed Northern counsel, or suffer
                        Northern men to take part in the administration of the Government. And now,
                        in view of the evils which have resulted from the truckling policy of the
                        Democracy, we entertain the hope that the political sky of the future will
                        not again be darkened, after peace shall have been restored, by a too ready
                        affiliation of Northern with Southern Democratic leaders, and the consequent
                        renewal of Southern control and arrogant pretension.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Attacks the Democratic Party, implicating it in the rebellion and
                    condemning its connections with slaveholders who do not display the honor they
                    profess.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Recruiting Stations Closed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that an order has been issued that abolishes recruiting stations
                    throughout the North, including one hundred and seventy-five in Pennsylvania
                    alone.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Reorganization of the Democrat Party</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We have faith in the ability of the Government to crush the Rebellion, but
                    its future stability, as well as the peace and prosperity of the country,
                    demands that the American citizen, to discharge his duty intelligently at the
                    ballot box, must not attach himself blindly to party as too many honest
                    Democrats have heretofore done, and through the machinations of bad leaders, lay
                    the foundation for future trouble and danger to the Union and to the
                    Government."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We insert an article in another column, under the caption of "Danger Ahead,"
                        which we ask every candid, every thinking and reflecting man, and every
                        lover of the Union, to read, ponder over and digest. It is from
                        "Occasional," the regular Washington correspondent of Forney's <emph
                            rend="italic">Press</emph>, a most sagacious, candid and reliable
                        writer, of which the reader will be convinced after reading the article.</p>
                    <p>As early as the 26th of June, 1860, (nearly two years ago,) he warned the
                        country of what would inevitably occur if the Democratic party would
                        continue to blindly follow its leaders in the path they were conducting it.
                        His predictions were verified, and a perusal of them now must impress all
                        with the idea that they were little less than inspired prophecy.</p>
                    <p>Again is "Occasional" lifting his warning voice to his countrymen. He warns
                        them that an attempt to reorganize the Democratic party, on its former
                        basis, is now being made, under the leadership of such men as Vallandigham,
                        of Ohio, and says the success of the movement would be "a calamity only
                        second to that civil war produced by Davis, Toombs, and Yancey," and that
                        the struggle in which the people are now engaged "to maintain the Government
                        will have been a struggle for nothing, and the blood shed in defence of the
                        Republic will have been shed in vain," in the event of the restoration of
                        that party to power.</p>
                    <p>Let honest Union Democrats see to it, in the future, that they are not again
                        made, as they were in the past, to follow the lead of the enemies of the
                        country. In the past, thousands of them did so "ignorantly in unbelief," and
                        knowing that "through ignorance ye did it," being led astray by your false
                        prophets and soothsayers--such as the <emph rend="italic">Valley
                        Spirit</emph>--you are, in a measure excusable. "The times of this
                        ignorance" the country was compelled to wink at; but now, seeing into what a
                        miserable and deplorable condition your past career has plunged the country,
                        it behooves all honest Democrats to see well to their future course. We have
                        faith in the ability of the Government to crush the Rebellion, but its
                        future stability, as well as the peace and prosperity of the country,
                        demands that the American citizen, to discharge his duty intelligently at
                        the ballot-box, must not attach himself blindly to party as too many honest
                        Democrats have heretofore done, and through the machinations of bad leaders,
                        lay the foundation for future trouble and danger to the Union and to the
                        Government. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Endorses the article by the Forney's Press Washington correspondent that
                    warns against the reorganization of the national Democratic party along the
                    lines it followed before the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Senator Cowan's Speech</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Remarks that Senator Edgar Cowan of Pennsylvania has been very soft on
                    "Rebels and the Rebellion" and that he even vote against the expulsion from
                    Congress of Senator Bright of Indiana.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>News from the Mississippi River near Corinth, Mississippi, from Fortress
                Monroe, from Fort Pulaski, from Washington, column 3; news from Island No. 10, West
                Virginia, and Cincinnati, column 4; advertisements, columns 4 and 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.04.08.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Danger Ahead!</head>
                <origin>Forney's Press</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The regular Washington correspondent of Forney's <emph rend="italic"
                        >Press</emph>, who signs himself "Occasional," under date of the 3d inst.,
                        writes the following important communication.--Let every reader peruse it
                        attentively, and see if there is not still more danger ahead for our
                        country, if, as he says, the Democratic party shall be again reorganized
                        upon its old basis, efforts to that end being now actively at work under the
                        leadership of those who sympathize with the Rebellion.</p>
                    <p>To show that he is correct, "Occasional" quotes a number of passages from his
                        former letters to the <emph rend="italic">Press</emph>, which seem like
                        prophecy, and which should add great weight to what he says now:</p>
                    <p>There are none so blind as those who refuse to see. I may be denounced, as
                        indeed I know I am--by selfish and mercenary partisans, who look forward to
                        a reorganization of the Democracy as one of the methods by which they are to
                        reassume power and to recall the convicted traitors of the Slave States--I
                        may be denounced by such men for insisting that the success of this plan of
                        resurrecting sympathy with treason under the mask of Democracy, would be
                        preparatory to the worst of evils to the country; but such is my fixed and
                        unchangeable conviction.--Those who doubt as well as those who denounce this
                        prophecy--those who believe in it and those who will not see it--have only
                        to transfer themselves back to a period less than two years ago, when in
                        this same correspondence I told my readers that the efforts of the enemies
                        of Douglas were preparative steps to disunion, and that the success of these
                        efforts would be, not merely the overthrow of a brave and well-tried
                        statesman, but eventually of the destruction of the Republic. After the work
                        of the conspirators was done at Charleston and at Baltimore, and all the
                        four candidates for President, Lincoln, Douglas, Bell, and Breckinridge,
                        were formally in the field, I continued to insist that the latter was the
                        leader of the Disunionists, and that the object of his friends was to break
                        up the Government.--There was but one term to designate the principles and
                        the purposes of these men.</p>
                    <p>On the 26th of June, 1860, I said:--</p>
                    <p>Gradually but surely, the administration [of James Buchanan] is whipping its
                        adherents into the support of the <emph rend="italic">Disunion Secession
                            ticket, headed by Breckinridge and Lane.</emph></p>
                    <p>On the 27th of the same month I said:--</p>
                    <p>The Secession leaders in Baltimore, in and out of the Convention, declared
                        that they preferred to see Lincoln President to Douglas. This was the shout
                        of Yancey and his set from the Gilmore House, and this was the response of
                        the Seceders. I mark down the fact for a special purpose.</p>
                    <p>On the 14th of August, of the same year, "Occasional" said:--</p>
                    <p>That there is a strong body of men in the South who are bent upon breaking up
                        the Confederacy, is now beyond controversy. That these men have determinated
                        [sic] to make the election of Lincoln, should he be elected, a pretext for
                        the inauguration of this scheme of Disunion, is as clear to my mind as the
                        noon-day sun.</p>
                    <p>On the 16th of the same month I said:--</p>
                    <p>One fact ought to be kept constantly in view by the Democratic masses in the
                        present struggle, and that is the complete identity between Breckinridge and
                        Buchanan. The leader of the Breckinridge or Disunion party is the President.</p>
                    <p>On the 26th of the same month, the following appears:--</p>
                    <p>The Breckinridge men not only went out of the National Convention when they
                        found they had lost the game, but will go out of the Union if they lose the
                        Presidency, or the Republicans should win it.</p>
                    <p>In my letter of the 12th of September, the following appears:--</p>
                    <p>Any one at this centre, who reads the Southern papers, and hears the Southern
                        extremists, will be compelled to admit that the foes of the Republic in that
                        quarter are resolved to resort to violent courses should their projects in
                        reference to Breckinridge and Lane be defeated in November.</p>
                    <p>Maintaining the same position steadily down to the day of the election,
                        "Occasional" said on the 24th of October:</p>
                    <p>The conspirators in the Southern States are actively at work. Undoubted
                        intelligence constrains me to the belief that a wide-spread Disunion
                        movement is in process of secret and rapid formation, and that we shall see
                        the first evidences immediately after the November election, should the
                        result prove to be favorable to Mr. Lincoln. All conservative men will ask,
                        why do not the extreme men of the South wait for the overt act? If Mr.
                        Lincoln is elected, is he to have no chance to show his hand? Is he in
                        advance to be proscribed and persecuted?"</p>
                    <p>And in a speech quoted from Sam Houston, delivered in Austin, Texas, before
                        the election, this point was made a text of fruitful comment.</p>
                    <p>"I do not say," he asserted, "that all these Southern constitutional
                        Democrats are Disunionists, but I do say that all the Disunionists are
                        Southern constitutional Democrats."</p>
                    <p>On the 31st of October, I quoted an extract from the Vicksburg (Mississippi)
                            <emph rend="italic">Citizen</emph>, announcing the forthcoming speech of
                        Jefferson Davis on the 4th of November, in that city, in which this language
                        is used:</p>
                    <p>"Jefferson Davis will doubtless be the generalissimo of the Southern army."</p>
                    <p>After the Presidential electoin [sic], when the drama began rapidly to unfold
                        itself, I said, December 6, 1860:</p>
                    <p>Well may James Buchanan, President of the United States, employ the language
                        of the great French monarch--"After me the deluge!" We are on the eve of a
                        revolution, bloodless as yet, to which he furnished alike the initiative and
                        the stimulant.</p>
                    <p>I make these extracts, not for the purpose of proving the fulfillment of my
                        prophecies, but to remind my readers of the indignation with which the men
                        who supported Breckinridge, and Breckinridge himself, claiming to be
                        Democrats par excellence, denied the allegations herein set forth, and
                        particularly that which distinctly charged that the result of their
                        movements would be the overthrow of the Union. They claimed that they were
                        the true Union men, and denounced me as a calumniator for persisting in a
                        different opinion. They would not see the consequences of their
                        conduct--would not believe that Mr. Breckinridge was craftily preparing to
                        transfer them to the tender mercies of the Secessionists--and, even after
                        the "Star of the West" was fired into, and when their chosen candidate went
                        over to the public foe, they continued blind to the enormous guilt of the
                        conspirators, and saw in the Republican party alone the real enemy of the
                        Union.</p>
                    <p>I speak, of course, of the politicians in the Breckinridge organization. I
                        have better hopes of the masses. Will they not take a lesson from the page
                        of history here revealed, and now believe me when I tell them that <emph
                            rend="italic">the present attempt to reorganize the Breckinridge party
                            looks to a calamity only second to that civil war produced by Davis,
                            Toombs, and Yancey?</emph> Doubtful before, they must now admit that
                        consequences confirmed all my former predictions. Should Mr. Vallandigham
                        succeed in his plan of reconstructing the Breckinridge party, he will
                        undoubtedly flatter himself that the reconstruction of the Union will
                        restore his influence and the influence of his former associates in the
                        national councils. It was well said on a recent occasion that the intellect
                        and power of the late Democratic party are now in arms against the Republic,
                        and if these elements can be brought back, <emph rend="italic">the struggle
                            to maintain this Government will have been a struggle for nothing, and
                            the blood shed in defence of the Republic will have been shed in
                        vain.</emph></p>
                    <p>OCCASIONAL.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Washington correspondent of Forney's Press warns that if the Democratic
                    party does reorganize along the same lines as they followed before the war, the
                    nation will find itself in grave danger.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Distressing Accident</head>
                <origin>Waynesboro Record</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that Mr. Ephraim Snyder, who lives near Mount Hope, felled a tree
                    that accidentally struck his eleven-year-old son and killed the boy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The President's Emancipation Scheme</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Bulletin</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Let Congress now pass the bill for abolishing slavery in the District of
                    Columbia, and we may, with a still better grace, be able to ask for the sympathy
                    of civilized Europe in our war against the slave-owners."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The United States Senate has adopted the resolution recommended by the
                        President, in favor of compensating the States for the slaves that may be
                        emancipated under State laws. The vote was 32 in favor to 10 against the
                        resolution, the opposition being from the Senators from the Border and
                        Pacific States. As this resolution had previously passed the House by a
                        large majority, it is to be understood now as representing the avowed policy
                        of the legislative as well as of the executive branch of Government.</p>
                    <p>It is a subject for congratulation that, on this difficult and dangerous
                        subject of slavery, the Government has arrived at a policy which, while it
                        imposes no wrong upon any portion of the people, distinctly and avowedly
                        looks to the ultimate extinction of slavery. The civilized nations of the
                        world have never been able to understand how a republic, established on
                        principles of freedom, should foster and protect slavery. We have lost the
                        confidence of the European nations, from this very cause, and during the
                        present war against the slave-owners, we have continually been reproached
                        with the charge that, if victorious, slavery was likely to be perpetuated,
                        and that there was more chance of its extinction by a dissolution of the
                        Union, than by its preservation. The adoption of the President's resolution
                        enables us to deny this. The United States Government solemnly announces
                        itself in favor of emancipating the negroes, though it leaves the formal
                        enactments to the States themselves, offering, however, to pay them for
                        whatever loss their citizens may suffer.--This is a decided step forward and
                        we congratulate the country upon it. Let Congress now pass the bill for
                        abolishing slavery in the District of Columbia, and we may, with a still
                        better grace, be able to ask for the sympathy of civilized Europe in our war
                        against the slave-owners.--<emph rend="italic">Phila. Bulletin.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses approval of the recent decision by Congress to endorse President
                    Lincoln's proposal to offer compensation to the states that emancipate their
                    slaves.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>advertisements, columns 3-5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.04.08.04">
            <pageNote>Reprint of the list of jurors for the upcoming court sessions to be held at
                Chambersburg, column 1; report that the earth's population of human beings is
                estimated at about one billion, column 1; prices current, column 2; advertisements,
                columns 2-5;</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
