<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1862/pa.fr.sd.1862.03.07">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>7/13/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1862-03-07">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>07</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.03.07.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The First Year of Mr. Lincoln's Administration</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Bulletin</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gives an account of the first year of Abraham Lincoln's administration.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>An Expedition to Eastport, Alabama</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints the report submitted to the navy department from Lieutenant Given,
                    who recently conducted an expedition by gun boat up the Tennessee River to
                    Eastport, Alabama. The report states that Union sentiment is strong South
                    Tennessee and North Alabama.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1 and 2; poem, column 3</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.03.07.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Somebody is Lying</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> has kept up a constant howl about
                        Abolitionism, charging the present Rebellion upon the policy and acts of the
                        Republican, or, "Abolition" party, as it calls it. This has been and is the
                        burden of its weekly issue, mixed up with just such arguments against the
                        course pursued by the Government to restore the Union as those used by the
                        veriest Southern Rebels that now run unhung.</p>
                    <p>Somebody is lying--who is it? In connection with Mason and Slidell, the South
                        has a host of agents in England and France to beg those Governments to
                        recognize the Slave Oligarchy as an independent power. Among these agents is
                        the notorious Wm. L. Yancey, of Alabama, and others equally base, who have
                        addressed a letter to the British Parliament for the purpose of operating
                        upon the anti-slavery sentiment of England, and thus prejudice our
                        Government in our estimation, the better to secure favors from the English
                        Government. In that letter these base traitors have, among other things,
                        made the following honest and truthful declarations:--</p>
                    <p>"It was from no fear that the slaves would be liberated that secession took
                        place. The very party in power has proposed to guarantee slavery forever in
                        the States, if the South would but remain in the Union. Mr. Lincoln's
                        message proposes no freedom to the slave. * * * * * * The great object of
                        the war, therefore, is not to free the slave, but to keep him in subjection
                        to his owner, and to control his labor through the legislative channels
                        which the Lincoln government designs to force upon the master."</p>
                    <p>Somebody is lying in this matter, and we leave the reader to judge who it is.
                        The <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> says, but for the election of Lincoln
                        and the fear of the South that the Republican party would abolish Slavery,
                        there would have been no attempt at subverting the Government. Yancey says,
                        "It is from no fear that the slaves would be liberated that Secession took
                        place," &amp;c.</p>
                    <p>Does not this prove most conclusively that the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Spirit's</emph> assertions are most untruthful and reckless. The truth is,
                        that as soon as the Southern politicians found that they could no longer
                        control the Government, and shape its policy for their own benefit, at the
                        expense of the working millions of the Free States, they determined to break
                        it up. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Questions whether the Valley Spirit or William Yancey is telling the truth.
                    The Valley Spirit has argued that the "Abolitionist Party"--the
                    Republicans--drove the South out of the Union, while Yancey has written that the
                    South does not fight to preserve slavery in the face of the abolitionist
                    tendencies of President Lincoln, who they admit guaranteed that slavery would be
                    preserved under his government, but to protect their political power.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Tax Bill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following is an abstract of the Tax Bill as reported to the House of
                        Representatives, at Washington, on Monday last:</p>
                    <p>It provides for the appointment, by the President, of a Commissioner of
                        Internal Revenue, with a salary of five thousand dollars. His office is to
                        be in the Treasury Department, with a suitable number of clerks. The country
                        is to be divided, as the President may direct, into convenient Election
                        Districts, with an Assessor and Collector to to [sic] be appointed by the
                        President for each District, who shall have power to appoint such Deputies
                        as may be necessary. The bill provides for a duty</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>On spiritous liquors</cell>
                            <cell>15 cents per gallon.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>On ale and beer</cell>
                            <cell>$1 per barrel.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>On stem and leaf tobacco</cell>
                            <cell>3 cents per pound.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Do. to add when manufactured</cell>
                            <cell>5 cents.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>On sugars (according to value).</cell>
                            <cell>5, 10 and 20 cents per pound.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>On lard and linseed oil, burning fluid and crude coal</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>oil</cell>
                            <cell>5 cents per gallon.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>On refined coal oil</cell>
                            <cell>10 cents per gallon.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>On gas per 1000 cubic feet</cell>
                            <cell>25 cents.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>On Bank Note Paper</cell>
                            <cell>5 cents per pound.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>On Writing Paper</cell>
                            <cell>2 " " "</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>On Printing Paper</cell>
                            <cell>3 mills " "</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>On Soap</cell>
                            <cell>5 " "</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>On Salt</cell>
                            <cell>4 cents per 100 pounds.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>On Sole Leather</cell>
                            <cell>1 cent per pound.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>On Upper Leather</cell>
                            <cell>1/2 " " "</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>On Flour</cell>
                            <cell>10 cents per barrel.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>All other manufactures, 3 per cent, ad valorem.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Railroad passengers, 2 mills per mile of travel.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Commutation tickets, 3 per cent.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Steamboat travel, 1 mill per mile.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Omnibuses, Ferry boats and Horse Railroads, 3 per cent, on gross
                                receipts from passengers.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>On advertisements, 5 per cent, on amount of receipts
                            annually.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>For use of carriages, annually, from $1 to $10, according to
                                value.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>On Gold Watches</cell>
                            <cell>$1 per annum.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>On Silver Watches</cell>
                            <cell>50 cts "</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>On Gold Plate</cell>
                            <cell>50c per ounce.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>On Silver Plate</cell>
                            <cell>3c "</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>On Billiard Tables</cell>
                            <cell>$20.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>On Slaughtered Cattle</cell>
                            <cell>50 cents each.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>On Hogs</cell>
                            <cell>10 " "</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>On Sheep</cell>
                            <cell>5 " "</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>On Licences--Bankers</cell>
                            <cell>$100</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Auctioneers</cell>
                            <cell>20</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Wholesale Dealers</cell>
                            <cell>50</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Retail Dealers in Liquors</cell>
                            <cell>20</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Retail Dealers in Goods</cell>
                            <cell>10</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Pawnbrokers</cell>
                            <cell>50</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Rectifiers</cell>
                            <cell>100</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Brewers</cell>
                            <cell>50</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Hotels, Inns and Taverns (graduated according to rental)</cell>
                            <cell>from $5 to 200</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Eating Houses</cell>
                            <cell>10</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Commercial Brokers</cell>
                            <cell>50</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Other Brokers</cell>
                            <cell>20</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Theatres</cell>
                            <cell>100</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Circuses</cell>
                            <cell>50</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Bowling Alleys (each alley)</cell>
                            <cell>5</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Wholesale Pedlars</cell>
                            <cell>50</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Other Pedlars</cell>
                            <cell>$5 to $20</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Coal Oil Distillers, &amp;c.</cell>
                            <cell>20</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>On Incomes, 3 per cent, on all over $600, deducting the income
                                derived from dividends, &amp;c., which are taxed
                            separately.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>On Railroad Bonds and Dividends of Banks and Saving Institutions</cell>
                            <cell>3 per cent.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>On payment of all salaries of Officers, in the Civil, Military and
                                Naval service of the U. S., (including Members of Congress)</cell>
                            <cell>3 per cent.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>On Legacies and Distribution Shares of the personal property of
                                deceased persons, (according to the degrees of relationship) from</cell>
                            <cell>1@65 per cent.</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>And stamp duties on all kinds of legal and commercial papers, all patent
                        medicines, telegraphic messages, and all goods by expresses.</p>
                    <p>The Tax Bill contains one hundred and five sections, and is one of the
                        longest of any kind ever before prepared--months of preparation having been
                        bestowed upon it.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides a listing of the amount of taxation on specific goods according to
                    the tax bill presently before Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Death of Brig-Gen. Lander</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report the death of Brigadier-General Frederick W. Lander, the first Union
                    officer above the rank of colonel to die while in active service.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>France and America</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints the segment of the French Senate's address to the Emperor that
                    concerns the United States civil war. Provides a number of reasons why France
                    should not involve itself in the conflict.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Evacuation and Burning of Columbus</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the capture of Columbus, Kentucky, by Union forces.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>News from Missouri and Tennessee, column 4; news from the upper Potomac,
                column 5; advertisements, column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.03.07.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>An Interesting Scene</head>
                <origin>Hagerstown Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that four or five thousand people turned out to see the Union
                    troops cross the Potomac into Virginia the previous Sunday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Tax on Whisky</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Remarks that if it is correct that the distillers of the United States sell
                    600 million gallons of whiskey per year, the proposed tax of 15 cents per gallon
                    on whiskey would mean an annual revenue of nine hundred thousand dollars for the
                    government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Spring Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that Union voters of the North Ward of Chambersburg will meet at
                    the White Swan on Saturday evening, March 15, at 7 o'clock to select a party
                    ticket for the spring election. The Union voters of the South Ward will meet at
                    the Indian Queen hotel at the same time on the same night.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements interspersed with articles, columns 1 and 2; news from
                Nashville, Boston, Washington, column 2; advertisements, columns 3-5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.03.07.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Two Projects</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There will be a division of sentiment in Congress on the proper attitude
                        which our Government should assume towards the States now in rebellion. Mr.
                        Ashley, of Ohio, has a bill, which is on the basis of the Sumner
                        resolutions, and has been approved by the Committees on Territories of the
                        Senate and the House, which virtually destroys all State Governments, and
                        establishes Territorial Governments in their places, without any power to
                        legislate for the protection of slavery, which is thus virtually abolished.
                        In opposition to this scheme is a bill offered by Senator Davis, of
                        Kentucky, which provides for the punishment of traitors, but protects the
                        loyal inhabitants of States in re-organizing their State Governments.--Each
                        bill is declared by its friends to have the support of the Administration,
                        but it is believed that the Cabinet are divided.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on two different plans in Congress for dealing with the states that
                    have seceded.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Distinguished Duel</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes a duel at Fort Donelson between one of Colonel Birge's
                    sharpshooters and a Southern soldier.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Letter from Major Zagonyi concerning the disbanding of the Fremont body guard,
                column 1; prices current, column 2; advertisements, columns 2-5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
