<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1862/pa.fr.sd.1862.02.04">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>7/9/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1862-02-04">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>04</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.02.04.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Gen. Lane's Expedition</head>
                <origin>Cincinnati Commercial</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Predicts that General Lane will be "mischevious" to the enemy and will not
                    be "tender" to slavery on his upcoming expedition. He plans to march with his
                    men through Arkansas and Texas to the Gulf of Mexico.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Whipped to Death</head>
                <origin>Albany Statesman</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Albany <emph rend="italic">Statesman</emph>, publishes a letter from
                        Hooker's Division on the Potomac, stating that Samuel Cox, of Port Tobacco,
                        Md., a returned rebel, whipped a negro to death for informing the Federal
                        commander that he (Cox.) had arms for rebel use secreted in his house. The
                        slave had escaped, but was delivered up to Cox. The correspondent says:</p>
                    <p>"Cox tied the man to his horse and rode at a rapid rate, the poor slave
                        running to keep up behind him. When he left the regiment, he had on a pair
                        of good shoes, but when he reached his master's house his shoes were gone,
                        and his bleeding feet were found to be bursting open from coming in contact
                        with pebbles and stone. He had been dragged eleven miles behind his master's
                        horse! They arrived home at 11 o'clock on Friday. He tied him to a tree and
                        called his overseer, Franklin Roby, and a man by the name of John Robinson.
                        They commenced whipping him about twelve o'clock and whipped him until three
                        o'clock, three hours, taking turns with the whip; when one was tired and
                        breathless another would apply the lash.</p>
                    <p>"The only words he uttered up to 2 o'clock were, "I shall not live after
                        this." "Oh, no, you rascal, I intend to kill you!" said Cox. "Mr. Cox," said
                        Robinson, "he is dying." "No he is not. He is stout-hearted and able-bodied.
                        He can stand as much more. However, give me the whip, let his blood rest
                        upon my head," replied Cox. The lash was then applied until about two hours
                        before day.--About 3 o'clock he was cut down and sank to the earth
                        insensible. He had on a new cotton shirt when they began to whip him, and
                        when they were done there was nothing left of it but the collar-band and
                        wristbands. Then commenced the rubbing down to bring back sensibility, but
                        all of no avail. Their unfortunate victim breathed his last before sundown
                        on Saturday evening. Thus perished a loyal negro at the hands of a traitor."</p>
                    <p>That a person (even if he is black) who brings valuable information to our
                        forces should be given up to a rebel to be whipped to death, does not speak
                        well for the good sense or justice of the officer who is responsible for
                    it.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints a letter describing the treatment by Samuel Cox, of the Southern
                    forces, of a slave whom Cox whipped to death for informing the federal commander
                    where Cox had hidden arms for the use of Southern troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Steel Armor Tested</head>
                <origin>North American</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The testing of these steel vests at Washington must be regarded as
                    carrying into the army the armor principle which is creating so great a
                    revolution in the navy, and the novelty of the principle should not cause us to
                    hesitate in its trial, as the advantages likely to arise from its success are
                    obvious."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Informs readers that a steel cuirass to be used for armor by artillerymen
                    and cavalry soldiers is being tested.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The New Secretary of War</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Offers a physical description of Secretary Stanton and remarks that he has
                    systematized the schedule of operations of the War Department, so that specific
                    days are set apart for army affairs, Congressional visits, and "the reception of
                    the people."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1 and 2; news from Mexico and information concerning a
                skirmish at Occoquan Bridge, column 5.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.02.04.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Suggestion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Why should our land forces who capture valuable property from the same
                    enemy, (such as cannons, guns, clothing, tents, provisions, horses, cattle,
                    &amp;c., all of which can be used by the Government,) be deprived of an
                    equitable share of prize-money in such captured property?"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Proposes that soldiers who capture equipment belonging to the Southern
                    forces be compensated as sailors are given the rights to property seized on the
                    seas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Rejoicing in England over the Settlement of the Trent Affair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the English public expressed satisfaction at the release of
                    Mason and Slidell, implying that the English are relieved that war with the
                    United States had been averted.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Outlook</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Bulletin</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Bulletin surveys the whole of the military scene and concludes that
                    "there is more hope of an advance along the whole line than we have yet seen."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Difference</head>
                <origin>Lebanon Courier</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Those who value the rotten old Buchanan organization more highly than they
                    do the Union, will persist in trying to distract the people by party lines,
                    while those who are patriotic enough to value the Union above the party in these
                    perilous times, will unite in strengthening the arm of President Lincoln under
                    the responsibilities that treason has brought upon him."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the People's State Committee has met and decided not to hold a
                    convention, but to stand by the President because of his efforts to maintain the
                    Union. On the other hand, the Lebanon paper notes, the Committee of Breckenridge
                    Democrats has determined to hold a "straight out party convention" prior to the
                    next election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Tax Bill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides information on the tax bill pending in Congress without
                    criticizing it. Reports that it is "confidently expected" that the tax will
                    secure an annual revenue of at least 150 million dollars for the national
                    government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>News from Europe, column 2; reports from Washington that positive relations
                between the United States and Great Britain have been restored and that Secretary
                Chase approves the making of treasury notes legal tender, the measure presently
                before the House, column 3;new from Fortress Monroe, column 3; advertisements,
                column 4 and 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.02.04.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Remarks that ladies rarely wear dresses in the street since Balmoral skirts
                    have come into fashion.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Recovering</head>
                <origin>Fulton Democrat</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that Lieutenant James Wishart conducted a short visit to Fulton the
                    previous week. The Lieutenant is on furlough in order that he might recover from
                    being struck by lightning in Kentucky.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Old Folks Concert</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that an "Old Folks" Concert will be held shortly in which
                    vocalists will wear costumes and sing hymns and songs from "old Revolutionary
                    times."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Accidental Shooting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the shooting in Cumberland County of a woman named Pye. The lady
                    was making beds in the second story of a building when the rifle her brother was
                    handling accidentally went off, and the bullet struck the woman in the head,
                    killing her almost instantly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Pennsylvania Southern Expedition</head>
                <origin>Harrisburg Patriot</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Governor Curtin is attempting to assemble an expedition made
                    up exclusively of Pennsylvania troops to travel to the Southern coast.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Terrible Railroad Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The constantly recurring disaster from the sheer neglect on so many of our
                    railroads, has been borne with criminal forbearance by the American community
                    too long."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports a collision near Baltimore of two trains, one of which was owned by
                    Messrs. Wunderlich, Nead &amp; Co. of Chambersburg. Mr. Henry Kupffender of
                    Chambersburg, who had charge of the Wunderlich, Nead &amp; Co. train, was
                    crushed between the broken cars and died instantly. Urges the state legislature
                    to pass legislation that would "prevent the almost daily occurrences of public
                    butcheries on badly managed and badly conditioned roads."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings--Second Week</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Graham</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Lellan</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shireman</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tritle</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piper</ln>
                        <fn>Polly</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyarmond</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ely</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McNair</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christ</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beaver</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Divilbiss</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tenley</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lytle</ln>
                        <fn>J. Milton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lytle</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tankersly</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Easton</ln>
                        <fn>Hezekiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newcomer</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newcomer</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phreaner</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Molly</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Behm</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forbes</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Summarizes court proceedings from the second week of the session. Reports
                    that Judge Graham of Carlisle rather than Judge Nill presided. The court found
                    in favor of Keystone Mutual life Insurance Company in their case against William
                    M'Lellan for $174.87 1/2. George Tritle settled with J. H. Shireman by giving
                    the plantiff his note for $115 for the value of a reaper and mower. The case of
                    Polly Piper vs. Catharine Dyarmond was referred to three auditors. The court
                    found in favor of Solomon Ely and ordered Andrew McNair to pay him $10.68 "on a
                    book account." John Snider was ordered to return possession of a tract of land
                    in Montgomery township to the plantiff William Christ. The court found in favor
                    of William McGrath in "an action in ejectment for 70 acres of mountain land" and
                    ordered the defendant to pay six cents in damages and six cents for costs. The
                    court awarded $27.50 in damages paid by James Tenley to Frederick for "rents,
                    issues and profits of 13 acres of land." The court found in favor of the
                    plantiff in the case of Abraham Carbaugh against J. Milton Lytle, the executor
                    of the estate of David Lytle, deceased. The court ordered Hezekiah Easton and
                    Mary Newcomer to pay the plantiff J. R. Tankersly $869.43 on an action involving
                    a guardian's bond. William Phreaner, Charles Molly, and Samuel Behm were
                    required to pay $110 to plantiff George W. Brewer for professional services. The
                    court found in favor of William Forbes and ordered James and Elizabeth Patterson
                    to pay $127.68.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Gordon, the Slave Trader</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the petitions for commuting the sentence of the slave trader
                    Gordon, who is to be executed next month, were presented to President Lincoln
                    the previous Friday. They will be passed along to the attorney general, who will
                    decide the matter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cashman</ln>
                        <fn>Reuben</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Susan M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Reuben Cashman and Miss Susan M. Palmer, daughter of Daniel Palmer,
                    Esq., were married on January 30. All are from the vicinity of Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Abraham A. Price and Miss Elizabeth Stover, both of Waynesboro', were
                    married on January 30.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>Benj. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Benj. C. Snyder and Miss Elizabeth A. West, both of Hamilton township,
                    on January 21.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forney</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Cleary</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Jacob Forney, of St. Thomas township, and Miss Mary M'Cleary, of
                    Hamilton township, were married on January 30.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Muma</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. James Muma and Miss Mary Myers, both of the vicinity of Fannettsburg,
                    were married on January 30.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fetter</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Margaret Fetter, aged 88 years, died of paralysis on January 30 near
                    Orrstown.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 3-5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.02.04.04">
            <pageNote>Proceedings of Congress, column 1; prices current, column 2; advertisements,
                columns 2-5</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
