<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="sd1862/pa.fr.sd.1862.03.25">
    <header>
        <title>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>7/14/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1862-03-25">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>25</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>bi-weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.03.25.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Rebel Buckner and George D. Prentice</head>
                <origin>Louisville Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Journal prints a letter from a Confederate general imprisoned in
                    Massachusetts and adds a number of remarks ridiculing the general.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Rebel Outrages</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Press</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The poisoning of wells, the wanton tearing up and destruction of railroads,
                        engines, and cars, the employment of thousands of remorseless savages, the
                        seizure and abuse of the possessions of their own friends--these are the
                        characteristics of a rebellion which challenges the indignation and
                        amazement of the civilized world. When we reflect that the men guilty of
                        these excesses claim to be enlightened, and persist in charging upon the
                        United States Government their own public and private crimes, we may well
                        pause before the sublime spectacle of the moderation and magnanimity of our
                        own moderation and magnanimity of our own soldiers. Who can doubt the object
                        of the traitors when they began this war? It was not to secure their rights
                        but to inflict irreparable injury upon the authority that had defended them,
                        and nothing but the bravery of our troops has prevented the repetition of
                        these barbarities on Northern soil. Is it not surprising that such marauders
                        and ruffians should find men to sympathize with them in the loyal
                        States--men who, while ignoring the vices and villainies of the traitors,
                        openly rejoice over their victories and bewail their defeats?--<emph
                            rend="italic">Phil. Press.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists the kind of "outrages" that it alleges Southern troops to have
                    committed and notes that these outrages indicate the unjustness of the
                    rebellion.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Moving Day</head>
                <origin>New York Post</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>All Fools' Day is approaching, and another trial of the patience of all
                        careful and prim housewives, who do not fancy the excitement of moving day,
                        consequent upon the general displacement and breaking up of certain
                        household gods [sic], is also approaching. One day is too short a space of
                        time for the laborious and tedious efforts of movers, and we would suggest
                        to those families, who have piles of furniture and trash from garret to
                        cellar, to occupy Friday and Saturday in their removal. The Sabbath could
                        then be enjoyed in the absence of all dread of the succeeding Monday or
                        Tuesday, and it would prove emphatically, in more than one sense, a day of
                        rest and peace.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that Jefferson Davis is planning to honor the custom of "moving day"
                    in the Southern states by moving from Richmond to Raleigh. Also points out that
                    he continues to move the "poor wearied rebels" from one place to another.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1 and 2; anecdote concerning Mrs. Lincoln, column
            4</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.03.25.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>War Taxation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There is, perhaps, no debt so hard to the American people to pay as their
                        taxes. Whilst this seems to be the case, the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Spirit</emph> (which avails itself of every opportunity to put forth its
                        secession proclivities, and thus aid indirectly in the cause of rebellion)
                        attempts to poison the minds of its readers by holding up before them the
                        most erroneous ideas of the national taxation which this hellish rebellion
                        has rendered necessary for the government to levy. If the <emph
                            rend="italic">Spirit</emph> would pause and reflect a little, it might
                        ascertain that the leaders in this rebellion have always acknowledged
                        allegiance to its party, and have felt insulted when called anything else
                        than Democrats. It might see, too, that where it finds a traitor it will
                        find one who was formerly a Democrat, and that the most influential among
                        traitors have been eulogized and puffed in its columns. It finds fault too
                        with those in power, distorts, misconstrues, and perverts whatever is said
                        or done by them. A message or proclamation may be so plain that the
                        school-boys may understand it, yet the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph>,
                        true to its instincts, goes to work, and, if nothing else will do, most
                        glaringly falsifies the whole affair. We could not occupy our columns with
                        extracts from this secession sheet, but will only call attention to what we
                        consider a correct view of the taxation, which we as loyal citizens must
                        cheerfully bear. Those who have undertaken to destroy our Government have
                        brought upon us a terrible civil war, which must be quelled. The loyal
                        people of the North have put forth their energies to accomplish this
                        purpose. The question naturally presents itself, how can the enormous
                        expenditure which this will create be met? It is answered in a word,
                        Taxation. Without this, our Government cannot succeed, and the <emph
                            rend="italic">Spirit</emph> well knows that its efforts to poison the
                        public mind upon this question is going no loyal service to our cause.</p>
                    <p>We have good men in the field and on "the wave," with able generals and
                        admirals, but that will avail nothing unless our Government sustain its
                        credit. The present generation should not be required to meet the heavy
                        expense of this war, and as posterity will be benefitted [sic] as much and
                        more than the present generation, then they in justice should be compelled
                        to bear a pat of this burden. How can this be done? The answer is, by
                        Taxation.</p>
                    <p>But what will be the extent of this taxation? The amount expended in this war
                        alone may amount to six hundred millions. This is indeed a large sum, but to
                        a country like ours it is small, and should not occasion a murmur. Let the
                        loyal people of the North pay the interest annually, which amounts to
                        thirty-six millions, and less than one-third of what our Government cost the
                        people a year, when James Buchanan was President. The Secretary of the
                        Treasury says, that the real and personal values in the States loyal to the
                        Union are eleven thousand millions of dollars, and the yearly surplus
                        earnings of the loyal people are estimated at more than four hundred
                        millions of dollars. Now a tax of nine per cent, on this <emph rend="italic"
                            >surplus</emph>, would pay the interest on six hundred millions. This,
                        when properly considered, is not so alarming after all, and in times like
                        these, and for objects like those which now claim the attention of our
                        Government, any man who refuses to pay nine per cent. of his surplus
                        earnings does not deserve the protection of a good government. And the man
                        who will misconstrue these facts, and endeavor to excite the public mind to
                        a misapprehension of this matter is not a loyal citizen, nor is the <emph
                            rend="italic">Spirit</emph> in this respect a loyal paper.</p>
                    <p>Our honest farmers and laborers have nothing to fear from taxation; it will
                        not be so burdensome as they at first blush might suppose. Even should it
                        prove burdensome, is it not better to lie peaceably under a good government,
                        with heavy taxes, than to be compelled to submit to a worse government with
                        still heavier taxes. The blessings of a government like ours are invaluable,
                        and cannot be estimated by money.</p>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> talks and prates about the flood of
                        paper money that will flow over our country. This, however large the flood
                        may be, will injure no man, if the credit of the Government be sustained and
                        the interest of the national debt promptly met by taxation. We must not
                        become frightened because the country suffered from the vast amount of paper
                        that was issued during the Revolution. It is true that this paper became
                        worthless, but is was because there was no limit to its issue, and no
                        provision for its redemption or the payment of interest. The Congress of
                        that day had no power to lay a tax, and the States being entirely without
                        resources, and acting without any material understanding, became at variance
                        with each other. There then was no taxation, no provision for the payment of
                        interest, and no redemption, and consequently the paper money which was
                        issued wholesale, rapidly sank to its proper level of worthlessness. The
                        people know something of the history of this paper currency, and therefore
                        dread it. Let them, however, consider the peculiar circumstances of our
                        Government at that day, the character of that paper currency, and the
                        condition of our Government now, its vast resources and power, and the
                        legislation upon taxation, and no one can have the least apprehension, but
                        cheerfully unite in aiding the Government by the payment of their full share
                        of taxation. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Denounces the Valley Spirit for criticizing the tax that has been
                    established to pay the war debt in the North. Points out that the Southerners
                    who, according to the Spirit, are responsible for the war consider themselves to
                    be Democrats and argues that the amount of taxation necessary will mean no
                    hardship for a country as wealthy as the United States.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The War on the Mississippi</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides further details of the fight at "Island No. 10" in the Mississippi
                    River.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>News from Kentucky, column 4; advertisements, columns 4 and 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.03.25.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>An Arrival</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmel</ln>
                        <fn>Francis M.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Relates that the late President Judge of Chambersburg, Francis M. Kimmel,
                    Esq., moved to Chambersburg from Somerset last week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>See to Your Chimnies!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges residents who intend to move from their homes to employ a "sweep" to
                    clean their chimneys.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Snow and Mud</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Points out that the recent snow and mud, mixed with occasional rain, have
                    put the streets and sidewalks of the town in bad shape. Suggests that the
                    authorities in Chambersburg should consider having the streets paved or else
                    having them scraped as soon as possible.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Who are Entitled to Pensions</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains that all disabled soldiers are entitled to pensions, but that the
                    law does not provide pensions to children and widows of soldiers who have been
                    killed in the present war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Moving Day</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Remarks that the first of April is approaching, the traditional day for
                    moving.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Substitutes for Coffee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Go where you will you [sic] hear the subject discussed, and slipping into
                    houses you are regaled with the odor of burning peas, rye, barley or whatever is
                    designed for a substitute."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Presents three different substitutes for coffee, since the price of real
                    coffee and tea is very high.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Methodist Conference</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brittain</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that the East Baltimore Conference of the Methodist Episcopal
                    church has ended, "after a stormy session" and lists the new appointments for
                    Carlisle District. A. Brittain was appointed to serve at Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Election in North Ward</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamman</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that the Republican candidate, P. Hamman, Esq., won the election
                    in the North Ward for Justice of the Peace.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>advertisements, columns 3-5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.sd.1862.03.25.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>General McClellan</head>
                <origin>North American</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that McClellan should be given time to make his move against the
                    South and that his critics should be patient if they cannot be sympathetic.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Prices current, column 2; advertisements, columns 2-5;</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
