<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1864/va.au.ss.1864.01.12">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>9/20/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 9/30/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1864-01-12">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>12</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1864.01.12.01">
            <pageNote>Page one is missing.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1864.01.12.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Army News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that a cavalry under the command of General Lee captured a train of
                    Yankee wagons in Hardy County. The cavalry took possession of 125 cattle, 25
                    wagon-loads of hides, 125 mules, and 200 prisoners.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Exemptions and Details</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Exemptions should depend not upon the favor of officials and the process
                    of details; but upon the necessities of the country, and should be extended by
                    law, not as favors to individuals, but as wise concessions to the industry of
                    the country."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Richmond <emph rend="italic">Enquirer</emph> says that instead of
                        depleting the industry of the country to strengthen the army, the wiser and
                        only true policy as [sic] the adoption of measures which, by preventing
                            <emph rend="italic">desertions</emph>, shall maintain the strength of
                        the army at its highest point, according to its muster rolls. Why put more
                        men in the army when its organization and discipline is so defective that
                        those already in the army are permitted to desert in such numbers as to
                        dangerously diminish its strength? Already, in many parts of the country,
                        the lawless violence of deserters had made p[r]operty insecure, and put life
                        in jeopardy. The House Committee on Military Affairs may succeed in
                        increasing the names upon the muster rolls, and the expenses of the war, and
                        that without materially improving the strength of the army; but it will be
                        at the expense of the Quartermaster, Commissary and Ordnance Departments,
                        injuriously affecting the present productions of the country, and
                        prohibiting the creation of those articles which are consumed, but not
                        produced, in the Confederacy. </p>
                    <p>Exemptions should depend not upon the favor of officials and the process of
                        details; but upon the necessities of the country, and should be extended by
                        law, not as favors to individuals, but as wise concessions to the industry
                        of the country. A good and sound principle is worth a thousand favors of
                        detail; it is liable to no corruptions, and cannot be bought or bribed. The
                        exempt is then a citizen, but when detailed, he is the subservient creature
                        of a bureau. Industry cannot be supported by details; it is wrong in
                        principle and will be found impracticable. The present exemption law
                        recognizes the necessity of supporting and sustaining industry; it exempts,
                        because certain trades are absolutely necessary. It is upon the only proper
                        and wise principle.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls for a sounder and stricter principle upon which exemptions should be
                    granted.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Coersion [sic] of States</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints remarks of John Hamilton from the 1788 New York Convention that
                    condemn the coercion of states by other states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asks readers to send socks and flannels to soldiers who need them to
                    survive the cold winter weather.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Our True Policy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We believe that if the Yankees could be thoroughly satisfied that the war
                    would be a very long one--that we have it in our power to extend it, if
                    necessary, through a decade or score of years, they would be willing to make
                    peace upon our own terms."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>As we stated last week, we believe that our true policy is to prepare for a
                        long war and not to expend all of our resources and men and means in one
                        campaign. The way to make the war short is to prepare to make it long. The
                        Petersburg <emph rend="italic">Express</emph> says that the great
                        consideration with us now is, how we can best provide for the maintenance of
                        our army and people through the years of the war that are yet to come. We
                        had as well make up our minds to the certainty that the war will be a long
                        one, and brace up our hearts accordingly. If we will do this and calmly and
                        energetically adopt the proper measures for securing success to our military
                        operations, we will act wisely. We believe that if the Yankees could be
                        thoroughly satisfied that the war would be a very long one--that we have it
                        in our power to extend it, if necessary, through a decade or score of years,
                        they would be willing to make peace upon our own terms. From the very first
                        their cry has been for "a short and sharp" one, and they have endeavored to
                        make it so. Let the prospect, then, be opened before them of an interminable
                        war, except by their own retirement from it. Let them see that we can keep
                        our present forces in the field and clothe them out of our own resources,
                        and they will soon begin to turn their thoughts to peace. One way of thus
                        impressing them is for Congress to shape its legislation earnestly towards
                        encouragement of production amongst us, in all its varieties--food of every
                        kind, clothing, leather, iron, and whatever articles our mechanics can by
                        skill and industry turn out in their shops for agricultural and other uses,
                        domestic as well as public. Hence we see the importance of keeping every man
                        at work who can contribute by his labor to the better cultivation of the
                        self, to the wants of the army and to the material welfare of the country.
                        In short, production, in all its numerous departments should be the main
                        business, and to promote it, Congress and the Government should exert all
                        their efforts. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Suggests that the South should prepare for a long war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>As Was Expected</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that a recent proposal to convert the Confederacy into one great
                    military camp has only encouraged the Yankees to believe the South is desperate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>A Fight in Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Richmond Examiner</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes fist fight between two Confederate Congress members, who
                    disagreed on the evidence presented regarding charges against commissaries and
                    quartermasters.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Butler's Rule in Eastern North Carolina</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that General Butler has ordered all persons in eastern North
                    Carolina between 18 and 45, white and black, to take an oath of allegiance to
                    the United States.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Honors to Gen. John H. Morgan</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes reception of General John H. Morgan of Kentucky when he arrived
                    in Richmond last Thursday. Notes that crowds gathered to welcome him.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A Business View</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Tells the story of a businessman who refused to act desperate and suggests
                    readers should learn lessons for the Confederacy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>For the Spectator: An Appeal From the Army For Books</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Camp Pegram's Brigade, <lb/>52d Va. Regiment, Jan. 6, 1864.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Editor--By the goodness of God, the army of Northern Virginia is
                        permitted another winter to enjoy rest and quiet, though it be in the camp
                        away from their homes. The 52d Regiment is now snugly fixed in winter
                        quarters and has a fair prospect of so remaining for several months. It is
                        not necessary to say that camp life, in winter quarters, with no adequate
                        means of entertainment, is to the last degree dull and tedious, and that the
                        old proverb, "an idle brain is the devil's workshop," has no slight bearing
                        upon our condition. Therefore we call upon our friends, who are enjoying the
                        comforts and privileges of home exempt from the exposures and privations of
                        the soldier's life, to assist us to spend the winter.</p>
                    <p>We would respectfully request that the ministers of the various churches in
                        Staunton (Rev. Messrs. Baker, Latane, Taylor, Dice and Miller) and the
                        ministers of the different churches thro'out the county, would, from their
                        pulpits notify their several congregations that any donations of Books which
                        they would present to the soldiers of the 52d Regiment, will be received by
                        them, and duly forwarded to the regiment. We believe that this donation will
                        be made, and can be, with no trouble and at trifling expense.</p>
                    <p>Almost every family has in its library some good book which has been read,
                        and re-read and with them has lost its power to entertain, the loss of such
                        a book would scarcely be felt, but if sent to the soldiers, would serve to
                        while away many a weary hour, and even though the books which would serve to
                        interest us are highly prized by them, would not the fact that they could be
                        procured at the conclusion of the war, be an argument in favor of presenting
                        them to the defenders of the country. The character of the library, we thus
                        hope to become possessed of, should be composed of books of a miscellaneous
                        character inasmuch as there are so many various tastes in a regiment to
                        gratify. Let not however the number of religious books be small, for
                        religion after all should be the soldier's chief concern. Hoping to meet
                        with a prompt and speedy response to our request, and asking you to give
                        this a place in your paper,</p>
                    <p>I am yours truly, <lb/>John McGill, Chaplain.</p>
                    <p>N.B. Mr. Albert Garber will receive the donations from the various ministers,
                        at his store.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>John McGill, Chaplain</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGill</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Chaplain</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latane</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dice</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>Albert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Asks that the ministers of Staunton churches--Rev. Messrs. Baker, Latane,
                    Taylor, Dice, and Miller--encourage their congregations to donate books to the
                    52nd Virginia Regiment, in order to help the soldiers pass the time during the
                    winter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Enlargement of the Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Cites a Charleston Mercury statistic which states that 200,000 men are
                    absent from the army, either as stragglers, deserters, or detailed men. Suggests
                    that this should not cause too much alarm as long as the government and
                    civilians are vigilant in bringing the deserters back.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The War Tax in Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that taxes have not been assessed in the northwestern part of
                    Virginia, while the patriotic people in the eastern part of the state have
                    already paid theirs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Cotton Planting in Florida</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that the Florida legislature has outlawed the planting of cotton and
                    tobacco over a certain amount for the remainder of the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Swamp Dragons</head>
                <origin>Rockingham Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Union's "Swamp Dragons" are robbing loyal Southerners in
                    Hardy and Pendleton counties and generally treating them very badly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheat</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sale</ln>
                        <fn>James E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Atkinson</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Atkinson</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On December 15, 1863, Rev. J. C. Wheat married James E. Sale of Rockbridge
                    County to Lizzie G. Atkinson, daughter of Alexander Atkinson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>F. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ghattan</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finley</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel B.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. F. G. Bowman married Capt. Charles Ghattan, of Rockingham County, to
                    Lizzie Crawford, daughter of Samuel Finley, Esq., on January 6.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Preston</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knisely</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Susan S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. Thomas L. Preston married George W. Knisely, of Lewis County, to Susan
                    S. Wilson, daughter of James Wilson, on January 5.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hildebrand</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah Catherine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hildebrand</ln>
                        <fn>Gabriel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hildebrand</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Susan Catherine Hildebrand, daughter of Gabriel and Susan Hildebrand, died
                    of diphtheria on January 6 at the age of 14.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guthrie</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elizabeth L. Guthrie died at age 60 on December 18, after a long illness.
                    She was a member of the Presbyterian church, and she left six daughters and two
                    sons behind.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1 and 7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
