<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1864/va.au.ss.1864.03.29">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>9/1/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 9/8/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1864-03-29">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>29</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1864.03.29.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Lincoln's War Unpopular</head>
                <origin>New York News</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The New York <emph rend="italic">News</emph> shows that Lincoln's war is not
                        popular in the North, as the administration papers maintain, but, on the
                        contrary, that the people "yearn for peace and will have it." To learn the
                        true sentiment of the people of the North, "we must not go," says the New
                        York News, "to the columns of the pensioned press of the dynasty at
                        Washington; nor to the manufacturer of New England or New York, or
                        elsewhere, who have grown fat on the carnage of better men; nor to the
                        traders, or jobbers, or contractors, or place-men, or parasites--the myriad
                        of jackals who feed on the bloody offal of the strife. We have only to
                        contemplate the simple and naked facts, that with a population three times
                        that of the States at war with us, and a fighting population proportionately
                        much larger--with bounties proffered, such as never tempted cupidity, in any
                        war before--<emph rend="italic">we are compelled to seduce foreigners from
                            their homes to fight our battles for pay</emph>, and are driven to the
                        still more <emph rend="italic">degrading necessity</emph> of committing the
                        honor of our flag and the vindication of our manhood <emph rend="italic">to
                            the hands of negroes, bond and free</emph>. Not the relentless grasp of
                        a most merciless and unconstitutional, conscription, nor the seduction of
                        bounties large enough to make a poor man's fortune, <emph rend="italic">can
                            now drag or entice</emph> American citizens, except in numbers
                        absolutely insignificant, to fight the battles of this war. It is insolent,
                        as well as idle and absurd, to talk of the "popularity" of any war that can
                        command no warmer support than this, from a brave and impulsive people. If
                        the hearts of the people were in the war, they themselves would be in the
                        field to fight to the death. If they sincerely believed it to be a war in
                        which they ought to offer themselves as a sacrifice, they would crowd to the
                        very horns of the altar, without threat or bribe. That they shrink from the
                        contest--that they will devote all the little earnings of their lives to
                        purchase exemption--<emph rend="italic">that they cannot be tempted or
                            forced into the ranks</emph>, while there is an escape--all these things
                        tell the story. The people do not feel any longer that the war is their war.
                        They may support a little while because the government is waging it and the
                        flag is waved over it. Some of them may be willing it should continue,
                        because it pays themselves or their friends large profits, or keeps up their
                        influence or advances their party, or flatters their vanity or gratifies
                        their rancor. But the great current of public feeling and opinion runs in
                        its favor no longer. It has now no hold on public enthusiasm. Its popularity
                        is dead! </p>
                    <p>If the Administration really believes that all this is false--if it is
                        persuaded that the popularity of the war continues, let it abandon the
                        conscription and the bounty system and make the experiment of volunteer
                        enlistments <emph rend="italic">for a single week</emph>. That brief space
                        of time would suffice for the entire solution of the problem. If such an
                        experiment, however, be deemed hazardous, let Mr. Lincoln and his
                        counsellors make a still simpler one. Let them tell the people the <emph
                            rend="italic">truth</emph> for a single month, if the thing be possible,
                        if not let them endeavor to do it for a fortnight. Let Mr. Chase give us the
                        real amount of the public debt and of his means and provisions for its
                        payment. Let him inform us of the amount of taxes which we must endure to
                        avert the shame of repudiation now without increasing the debt a single
                        dollar. Instead of see-sawing between greenbacks and bonds, which appears to
                        be the substance of his financial policy, and concocting paltry schemes for
                        jobbing in gold on Wall street, let him trust the people, if he dare, with
                        the facts from which they may know their own solvency, or insolvency, and
                        appeal to them to meet the issue, face to face. Let Mr. Seward try if he can
                        write one solitary despatch without some intentional perversion of the
                        truth, and confine himself to the legitimate purposes of diplomatic
                        correspondence abroad, instead of loading the files of the State Department
                            <emph rend="italic">with claptrap and misrepresentation for home
                            consumption and deception</emph>. Let Mr. Stanton, instead of flooding
                        the country with false bulletins from irresponsible or fictitious sources
                        undervaluing the strength and resources of the enemy, exaggerating their
                        wants and sufferings, multiplying their reverses and our triumphs, give
                        himself up, for ever so brief a space, to <emph rend="italic">the
                            dissemination of the truth</emph>, which the people are entitled to have
                        in regard to a struggle for which they are taxed to the utmost in treasure
                        and blood. With what face can he assert the war to be the people's war,
                        when, after having caused the press to teem with telegrams, announcing the
                        almost universal and enthusiastic re-enlistment of the veterans of the army,
                        he has caused the President to refuse to give the House of Representatives
                        any information on the subject, on the ground that it would be "<emph
                            rend="italic">prejudicial to the public interest?["]</emph> If the
                        Administration will not venture to pursue the plain, straightforward course
                        we indicate, let it cease to prate of its war policy as rooted in the
                        confidence of the people. If the people uphold it, why conceal from the
                        people what they uphold? Or, is it that the war can be maintained in its
                        pretended popularity, only so long as the people are kept from knowing what
                        it is and what it promises. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Highlights reports in Northern newspapers that suggest the war is unpopular
                    in the North.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Richelieu</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses gratitude on behalf of members of Company A, 25th Virginia
                    Regiment, to the ladies of Augusta County for supplying them with food and
                    clothing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"On hearing of the above facts, many members of the company, although more
                    accustomed to handling the musket than the pen, resolved to try to show to their
                    fellow citizens at home that there exists in Old Augusta some men as mean and
                    avaricious as even Yankee land can boast of."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Camp "STONEWALL BRIGADE," <lb/>Feb. 20th 1864. </p>
                    <p>Mr. EDITOR:</p>
                    <p>Allow me through the medium of your well known paper to direct the attention
                        of the citizens of Augusta to one of the most hardhearted and mercenary acts
                        that has been perpetrated in our county since the commencement of the war.
                        The circumstances of the case are these--At the late battle of "Paynes Farm"
                        on the 27th of November, one of the best and bravest soldiers in the 5th,
                        Va. Infy., (Co. E.) fell mortally wounded whilst charging the enemy; his
                        admiring and sympathizing comrades, out of their own small means, made up
                        money enough to have the body taken from the battle field and sent to
                        Augusta County for burial, that their gallant comrade might rest beneath the
                        soil that he had so long defended so bravely and loved so well. The
                        distressed widow of the deceased soldier, on the arrival of the body at
                        home, took the twenty dollars which is allowed by the county to the wives of
                        soldiers for their support, and wishing to pay the last sad rites to her
                        husband in the usual manner, went to a prominent cabinet maker in
                        Greenville, for a coffin, the usual price of which was twenty or twenty-five
                        dollars, but he refused to let her have it on any terms unless she paid him
                            <emph rend="italic">forty</emph> dollars cash, refused to credit her for
                        the remaining twenty dollars, and had it not been for the generosity of some
                        kind neighbors in making up the money, this cabinet-maker, whose heart must
                        surely resemble in durability one of his coffin plates, would have left the
                        remains of our beloved comrade unburied yet. </p>
                    <p>On hearing of the above facts, many members of the company, although more
                        accustomed to handling the musket than the pen, resolved, to try to show to
                        their fellow citizens at home that there exists even in Old Augusta some men
                        as mean and avaricious as even Yankee land can boast of. We do not mention
                        the name either of the deceased soldier or of him who so cruelly treated his
                        widow, as we hope he will take warning by this exposure of his degrading and
                        disgraceful conduct and--"go and sin no more."</p>
                    <p>Very Respectfully, <lb/>Many members of Co. "E." 5th, Va. Infy. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Many members of Co. E, 5th Va. Infy.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Authors express concern and disappointment about a recent case in which a
                    widow of a 5th Infantry soldier was charged an exorbitant price for a coffin.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Maj. Gen. John C. Breckinridge</head>
                <origin>Richmond Enquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It may be that you will have to fight against odds--two to one--but
                    inspired by such a cause, you should whip them--two to your one."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>One of Jackson's Men</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Recounts the "short but thrilling speech" given by Maj. Gen. John C.
                    Breckinridge before Colonel W. L. Jackson's brigade at Camp Cameron.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>For the Spectator: A Sketch from Life</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Fellow soldiers, are you going to permit this man to go unscathed? Are you
                    going to stand like dumb brutes and see your fellow soldiers shot to death,
                    while your worst enemy--the Speculator--roams up and down the country at large?"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"In a deep vale, shut out by Alpine hills from the rude world," there once
                        lived an humble dweller of the forest who earned his bread by the sweat of
                        his brow and partook of the bounties of munificent nature beneath his own
                        vine and fig tree, where there was none to molest or make him afraid. With
                        "conscience void of offence" he lived at peace with his Maker and all
                        mankind. But, alas! grim visaged war sent his agent into this Eden to bring
                        forth this simple "child of nature" to do battle for his country. Without a
                        moment's warning he was hurried away from his forest home and the dear
                        little ones who were wont to climb upon his knee and make glad his heart
                        with their ceaseless caroling. Unaccustomed to war, and knowing nothing of
                        the privations to be endured he went forth without blankets or clothing,
                        never thinking that he would have to sleep upon the cold wet ground with
                        nothing to protect his shivering body from the wintry blast. After a few
                        months suffering in the service of his country, he received the sad
                        intelligence of the illness of his wife. When he thought of that loved one
                        at home--the idol of his heart--lying prostrate upon her couch, the victim
                        of insidious disease, and of those dear little ones who could not minister
                        to her wants and who were likely to suffer from hunger, he lost sight of his
                        duty to his country, and in one wild paroxysm of anxiety, threw down his
                        musket, plunged into the dark wilds of the forest without thought of duty or
                        danger. Onward he pressed day and night, all heedless of weariness and
                        hunger, until he found himself by the prostrate form of his bosom companion
                        ministering to her every want. After providing for his family, as best he
                        could, he was about returning to his command, when the hand of disease laid
                        him low. When he had partially recovered, he was again hurried off under
                        guard to his regiment, where he was ordered to the guard-house; and after
                        suffering as never man suffered for some three or four months, he was
                        arraigned before that honorable (?) body--the court-martial, where he was
                        sentenced to be <emph rend="italic">shot to death with musketry</emph>. </p>
                    <p>Come with me poor, wayworn soldier, with your tattered garments--you who have
                        stood by my side when the leaden hail fell thick and fast; let me take a
                        stroll in the direction of yonder splendid mansion. See, the candles are
                        lighted in the parlor and hall. Listen, there is a sound of music and
                        revelry there. Let us go to the gate, Lazarus-like, that we may learn
                        something of the pomp of this world. The bacchanalian song is struck up, the
                        dance begins, and all moves on as "merry as a marriage bell."</p>
                    <p>Who is this man that can revel in luxury and riotous living, while every one
                        else is mourning in sack-cloth and ashes on account of the great calamity
                        which is now resting upon and devouring us? From whence all this luxury and
                        grandeur? Go ask the poor widow and orphan children of him who poured out
                        his heart's blood in defence of his country. They will tell you who it was,
                        in the beginning of this war, that made loud professions of patriotism and
                        persuaded their husbands and fathers to go forth and do battle for their
                        country while he remained at home and wrung the last morsel of bread from
                        them that he might "dress in purple and fine linen, and fare sumptuously
                        every day." With him swindling is not only one of the prerequisites of
                        trade, but a virtue. With a smile upon his face, such as we might well
                        imagine Satan wore when he approached our first parents, he meets the
                        soldier and asks, "<emph rend="italic">When are you going back
                        again?</emph>" </p>
                    <p>Let us bring these two characters face to face that we may compare them for a
                        moment. The one served his country until the sickness of his family requires
                        his presence, when he left in order to rescue them from starvation, for
                        which he was <emph rend="italic">tied to a stake and shot to death</emph>. </p>
                    <p>The other never did a day's service, but on the other hand has done more to
                        break down and destroy our country than the avowed enemy, and yet, strange
                        as it may seem, he is permitted to go unmolested, unrebuked.</p>
                    <p>Fellow-soldiers, are <emph rend="italic">you</emph> to permit the man to go
                        unscathed? Are <emph rend="italic">you</emph> going to stand like dumb
                        brutes and see your fellow-soldiers shot to death, while your worst
                        enemy--the <emph rend="italic">Speculator</emph>--roams up and down the
                        country at large? May my tongue cleave to the roof of my mouth, and my right
                        arm forget her cunning if I fail to heap upon him my maledictions! Come
                        forth, you miserable recreant, you loathesome vulture who has been feeding
                        upon the vitals of our country; take your place in the criminal box with
                        this poor soldier and let the world judge between you and him. </p>
                    <p>He <emph rend="italic">left</emph> his post to rescue his family from
                        starvation. You avoided your country's call that you might <emph
                            rend="italic">remain</emph> at home and filch the bread from his poor
                        starving children. He persuaded no one to leave his post of duty. You have
                        caused hundreds to desert, by hoarding up the necessaries of life, so that
                        their wives and families could not get them. He caused no dissatisfaction in
                        the ranks. You have caused more croaking, more rebellious feeling than all
                        other causes put together. He was guilty only of desertion, you of <emph
                            rend="italic">high treason</emph>. </p>
                    <p>I do not ask those high in office, who have screened this man from the
                        beginning of the war and who had the other shot, to render a verdict in the
                        case. But I ask those who shouldered the musket and marched to the "field of
                        carnage and bloodshed," who have withstood the leaden hail of the enemy
                        without flinching, whom they consider deserving of death in this case.</p>
                    <p>This man, with patriotic sentiments upon his tongue, and treason written in
                        blazing characters upon his penurious soul, <emph rend="italic">may</emph>
                        go unscathed through this world; but I would just remind him that the
                        Supreme Judge of high Heaven, He who passed sentence upon a certain rich man
                        many years ago, <emph rend="italic">shall be his Judge</emph>. </p>
                    <p>JUSTICE, <lb/>Co. F, 5th Va. Infantry. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Justice, Co. F., 5th Va. Infantry</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Suggests that it is the treasonous speculator, not the hard-working soldier
                    in the field, who really deserves death.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Poetry, fiction, and classifieds, columns 1-4</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1864.03.29.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Butter</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asks for anyone with good butter to come to the Spectator office and learn
                    how to trade it for gold or currency.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Details Should Be Liberally Granted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>As the labor of the Valley is done chiefly by white persons, and as the
                        conscription act, together with the repeal of the exemption of those who had
                        employed substitutes, will abstract nearly all of the productive labor from
                        this section, unless a very liberal system of details be adopted, and as
                        supplies are needed as much as soldiers, and as the Valley of Virginia is
                        entitled to be called the great granary of the State, the best thing, in our
                        humble opinion, the Department could do would be to grant details to all
                        those in the Valley who are engaged in agriculture, and who are not now in
                        the military service. If the labor be withdrawn from the Valley, there will
                        be some danger that there will not be sufficient supplies raised in this
                        State to feed Gen. Lee's army, and as we cannot depend upon the limited
                        means of transportation to ensure supplies from the South--even granting the
                        supplies to be there--it might necessitate the withdrawal of that army from
                        this State. The necessitated withdrawal of that gallant army from Virginia
                        by any cause whatever would depress the spirits of the people, not only in
                        this State, but in the whole South, more than all the defeats we have
                        suffered since the war. We have no idea that anything else than the want of
                        supplies can cause the withdrawal of that army from Virginia. It is
                        altogether important that proper provision be made to ensure a sufficiency
                        of supplies, and nothing would go so far to secure that result as the
                        retention of sufficient labor in the Valley to cultivate its fruitful soil.
                        Unless details be liberally granted to those engaged in productive labor,
                        the fertile lands of the Valley will lie idle, and no crops will be raised
                        where, otherwise, abundant harvests would be gathered, and a sufficient
                        supply obtained to furnish the armies in Virginia. Details of this character
                        should be liberally granted in all such sections as the Valley where the
                        soil is fertile and slave labor scarce. What we have said of the Valley
                        applies to most of the counties of Western Virginia.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Suggests that soldiers from the Valley of Virginia be granted details more
                    readily in order to take advantage of the soil there and provide food for
                    soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Cheering Signs</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Draws on reports of growing discontent in the North to suggest that the
                    future of the Confederacy looks bright.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>'Camp Maryland' At Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the establishment of a new camp in Staunton which will organize
                    recruits from Maryland into companies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Age</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Encourages readers to subscribe to "The Age," a monthly magazine that the
                    Spectator's editors consider one of the South's best publications.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Four Per Cent Certificates</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that four percent certificates of deposit can be used to pay
                    taxes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Exemption By State Authority</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that a recent letter written by Virginia's Governor Smith announces
                    his intention to exempt from military duty anyone essential to the operation of
                    the state government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Timely Alarm</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myerley</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Tells how George Myerley learned that his house was on fire when the flames
                    set off a gun.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Execution of a Deserter</head>
                <origin>Rockingham Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that John Mick, Company C of the 62nd Regiment, was executed after
                    being caught deserting the army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>On To Richmond</head>
                <origin>Lynchburg Republican</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains that Confederate troops will be ready to meet any attempt on
                    Richmond by the Yankees.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Yankees Recruiting In Ireland</head>
                <origin>Dispatch</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that the Yankees are openly recruiting troops in Ireland and
                    questions Britain's claim to neutrality.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Presbyterian General Assembly</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the General Assembly of the Presbyterian Church in the
                    Confederacy will meet on the first Tuesday in May in Charlotte, North Carolina.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relays report from a Maryland man that there is considerable support for
                    the Confederacy in that state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Richmond Enquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Informs readers of Yankee plans to launch another raid from western
                    Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Hard Fight--The "Stonewall Brigade" Defeated--The fight Renewed and The
                    "Stonewall Brigade" Successful</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"I write this account of our snowball battle hoping it may entertain some
                    of our friends, and also to correct some of the rumors which reach our homes,
                    that we are all depressed and in low spirits about our affairs. I assure you
                    these are all false."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>CAMP STONEWALL BRIGADE. <lb/>March 24th, 1864. </p>
                    <p>Mr. EDITOR:</p>
                    <p>Thinking our friends [of whom I hope there are many] in Augusta, would like
                        to hear what the boys of the old "Stonewall" are doing these snowy times, I
                        thought I would tell you of a big fight we had yesterday.</p>
                    <p>Day before yesterday was one of the worst days we have had this year. It
                        commenced snowing early in the day, and continued until late in the night,
                        in consequence of which we found, on awaking in the morning, old mother
                        earth covered with snow about fifteen inches deep. This was just what our
                        boys wanted. We were beginning to think Winter would pass away without our
                        having a snow-ball.</p>
                    <p>Quite early in the morning, the 4th and 5th formed and started to storm the
                        camp of the other three regiments. We succeeded in routing them after some
                        very heard [sic] fighting. But this was not enough to appease our desire for
                        fun, so a part of the whole brigade, together with some Louisanians, and
                        commanded by a Louisana Col. drew up in line in front of Dole's, Georgia
                        brigade, and challenged them to combat, which they were not at all loth
                        [sic] to accept; but quickly forming, charged for a small bridge across a
                        ravine which divided the contending parties and led by Gen. Dole in person.
                        Here occurred one of the most stubborn fights of the kind ever known.</p>
                    <p>Gen. Dole tried several times to force his horse over, but in vain. He was at
                        last knocked from horse, and, supposing him badly hurt, both sides ceased
                        firing. We then agreed to let them cross over and have half of the field.</p>
                    <p>It may be well here to state, that a great many of our side, thinking the
                        fight over, and hearing that the 3rd Gen. Stuart's brigade, was in
                        posses[s]ion of our Camp, left the field. By this we were considerably
                        weakened. In the mean time Gen. Dole was bringing out every man.</p>
                    <p>Well, all the preliminaries being arranged, the fight soon became general.
                        First one party would charge and then the other, and the tide of battle
                        ebbed and flowed without either gaining any decided advantage. Thus things
                        continued for some time; but after a while our boys had to give way. We
                        would rally every few paces, and stand for some moments, but finally they
                        proved to[o] many for us. We wished very much for Gen. Walker, but no one
                        apprised him of it. They continued to drive us until we reached our camp,
                        where they halted and went back exulting over their victory. Nothing could
                        please them more than to say that they had whipped the "Stonewall brigade"
                        for it has ever been a source of envy to many brigades that any one should
                        take the name of him who, when living, they loved to follow to fields of
                        glory, and whose memory, now that a kind of Providence has taken him away,
                        they revere and hold most sacred.</p>
                    <p>Hostilities now ceased for a while, but the mortification of a defeat, a
                        thing unknown to the army of Northern Virginia, much less the "Stonewall
                        brigade," was rankling in the bosom of every man.</p>
                    <p>About this time, Gen. Dole and Staff undertook a raid through our camp. They
                        were greeted on all sides with showers of ball, during which two of the
                        party lost their hats. They claimed that it was as successful as
                        Kilpatrick's. Gen. Walker now rode out and formed the brigade, determining
                        to fight to the last, but such was the enthusiasm of our boys, when led by
                        our gallant Brigadier, that we broke their line the first charge, and drove
                        them through their camp in complete rout. After giving three cheers for Gen.
                        Walker and the "Stonewall Brigade," we returned to camp entirely satisfied
                        with our day's work.</p>
                    <p>I write this account of our snowball battle hoping it may entertain some of
                        our friends, and also to correct some of the rumors which reach our homes
                        that we are all depressed and in low spirits about our affairs. I assure you
                        these are all false. Our boys are all in fine spirits and look forward to
                        the coming campaign with anything but feelings of despondency, and hope, ere
                        the beginning of another year, with the blessing of the God of battles, to
                        free Virginia's soil from the presence of our unscrupulous and blood-thirsty
                        foe.</p>
                    <p>PRIVATE.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Private</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides narration of latest come-from-behind success of the Stonewall
                    Brigade.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>E. Wilfong, Lieut. Co. G, 31st Va. Vols.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilfong</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Offers correction to an announcement which erroneously stated that Lieut.
                    Wilfong had gotten married.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A Wife!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"A wife! she must be the guardian angel of his footsteps on earth, and
                    guide them to Heaven; so firm in virtue that should he for a moment waver, she
                    can yield him support and place him upon its firm foundation."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>What a sacred name, what a responsible office! she must be the unspotted
                        sanctuary to which wearied men flee from the crimes of the world, and feel
                        that no sin dare enter there. A wife! she must be as pure as spirits around
                        the everlasting throne, that man may kneel to her in adoration, even in
                        adoration without abasement. A wife! she must be the guardian angel of his
                        footsteps on earth, and guide them to Heaven; so firm in virtue that should
                        he for a moment waver, she can yield him support and place him upon its firm
                        foundation; so happy in conscious innocence that, when from the perplexities
                        of the whole world, he turns to his home, he may never find a frown where he
                        sought a smile. Such, my son, thou seekest in a wife; and reflect well ere
                        thou choosest. Open not thy bosom to the trifler; repose not the head on the
                        breast which nurseth envy, and folly and vanity. Hope not for obedience
                        where the passions are untamed, and expect not honor from her, that honoreth
                        not the god that made her.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains to young men what they should look for in a wife.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relays report from an officer who visited West Virginia that almost all of
                    the Virginia soldiers there have refused to reenlist.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>John B. Watts</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watts</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Watts acknowledges the encouragement he has received to run for clerk
                    of the circuit court but suggests he would not be a successful candidate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>William S. H.</fn>
                        <sf>Acting Brigadier General</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that William S. H. Baylor, Acting Brigadier General commanding the
                    Stonewall Brigade, was shot while riding in the last charge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that one thousand Confederate prisoners have been sent from Camp
                    Chase, Ohio, to Fort Delaware.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>A Card</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Wm. L. Balthis</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Balthis</ln>
                        <fn>William L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William L. Balthis announces his candidacy for office of sergeant of the
                    Corporation of Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces candidacy of John W. Hanger for magistrate in the New Hope
                    District.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Matheny</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. C. Matheny announces his candidacy for clerk of the circuit court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Religious Notice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stirewait</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that Rev. Mr. Stirewait will preach in the Lutheran church next
                    Sabbath.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ramey</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fitch</ln>
                        <fn>Lucy F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. R. Smith married Michael Ramey of Rosser's Brigade, Co. A, 12th
                    Regiment, and Lucy F. Fitch, on March 23 near Rockland Mills.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brower</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hester</ln>
                        <fn>John T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Via</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. John Brower married John T. Hester, Company I, 12th Georgia Regiment,
                    and Mary Via, on March 24.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baird</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>David W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fuller</ln>
                        <fn>Ann E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. William S. Baird married David W. Price of Washington County and Ann
                    E. Fuller on March 24.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>L. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn>W. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>W. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut. Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moffett</ln>
                        <fn>M. Lina</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moffett</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. W. T. Richardson married Lieut. Col. W. P. Thompson, 19th Virginia
                    Cavalry, to M. Lina Moffett, daughter of the late Henry Moffett Esq., of
                    Pocahontas County, on March 22 at the Augusta County home of Mrs. L. S. McCue.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Catherine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Mary Catherine Woodward, consort of S. M. Woodward, died on March 17
                    at age 66.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dinkle</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dinkle</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Elizabeth Dinkle, wife of Jacob Dinkle, died of paralysis on March 21
                    at age 61.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Friend</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Charlie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>S. Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces death of Charlie Wilson, infant son of Samuel C. and S. Kate
                    Wilson, who died of dysentery on October 11.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Tribute of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>David Echard, Chairman</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echard</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFarland</ln>
                        <fn>J. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blakely</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Golladay</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armentrout</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steele</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brand</ln>
                        <fn>Thos. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bradley</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grills</ln>
                        <fn>Lycurgus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prints copy of resolutions made by members of Company E, 5th Virginia
                    Infantry, honoring their comrades who died in the past year: Captain Lycurgus
                    Grills, Robert Blakely, John H. Golladay, John Armentrout, Robert Steele, Thomas
                    H. Brand, Joseph H. Thomas, and John H. Bradley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Adjt. &amp; Insp. General's Office</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>S. Cooper, Adj't and Insp'r General</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that the Bureau of Conscription will begin enrolling all persons
                    between ages of 17 and 18 years, and between 45 and 50 years, to serve in the
                    war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 5-7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
