<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1864/va.au.ss.1864.02.09">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>9/21/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 9/30/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1864-02-09">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>9</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1864.02.09.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Confederate States Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the proceedings of the Confederate Congress, including the
                    passage of a bill to tighten military exemption rules by a vote of 44 to 31 in
                    the House.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Lincoln's Draft Consolidated</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains that Lincoln's latest call for a draft will boost the total number
                    of men he wants drafted to 500,000.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Writ of Habeas Corpus in Georgia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints copy of a Georgia law that requires anyone applying for a writ of
                    Habeas Corpus to pay $2,500.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Of the slaves who have fallen into the hands of the enemy during the
                    present war, not less than one half perished by want, disease and violence."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses the fate of former slaves.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Legislature</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summarizes proceedings of the Virginia legislature. Notes that bills
                    concerning the relief for soldiers' families, the liability of the government
                    for slaves lost in the service, and the protection of sheep were considered.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Lincoln's Call to Re-Election</head>
                <origin>New York World</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"He is used to all the violations of the Constitution that are possible to
                    any President, and by a frequent practice does easily that which may come
                    awkwardly to any other man."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints sarcastic list of reasons why Lincoln is qualified for a second
                    presidential term.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>For the Spectator: Information Wanted!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Don't imagine, gentle reader, that my wife or daughter has eloped with some
                        gentleman with bars or stars upon his collar, for I have neither. Nor that
                        my brother or some other near relative has been missing for months, of whom
                        nothing can be heard; but the information wanted is this: 1st, Why is it
                        that Quartermasters and Commissaries with the rank and pay of Captain or
                        Major can dress finer, ride finer and faster horses than company or field
                        officers of the same rank and pay? 2d, Why is it that Commissaries can feed
                        their horses on corn-meal at the rate of from two to three gallons per day,
                        and themselves on ham, sweet potatoes, molasses and every other good thing
                        that the country can afford, while a private or company officer does not
                        know that there is such a thing in existence? 3d, Why is it that a certain
                        gentleman who volunteered for the war in the Spring of 1862, has been at
                        home ever since that time without doing one day's duty and without putting a
                        man in his place, has never been reported by the officers of his company or
                        regiment, while another member of the same company who has over a hundred
                        thousand dollars less to fight for than the other gentleman referred to, has
                        been reported by the same officers as a deserter, because he happened to be
                        detained on his way to the army by Gen. Lee's order?</p>
                    <p>I do not pretend to know anything about military law, nor civil
                        jurisprudence; but I claim to have a little common sense, which has always
                        enabled me to distinguish right from wrong; so when I see a man with the
                        rank of Captain or Major exposing himself to the enemy's balls as well as to
                        the trials and perplexities of camp life, and then at the close of each year
                        finds himself in debt from five hundred to a thousand dollars, while another
                        man, with the same rank and pay, lives upon the fat of the land, never heard
                        a minnie, and at the end of each year buys a farm for twenty or thirty
                        thousand dollars cash down, when every body knows that before the war he
                        couldn't pay his liquor bills, I am forced to conclude that all is not
                        right. So, also, when I see a man, no difference what his age may be,
                        volunteer for the war and then go home and remain there unmolested and
                        unreported by the officers under whom he volunteered, while all others are
                        reported as deserters, if they happen, from any cause whatever, to remain a
                        day or two over their time, am I compelled to come to the same conclusion.
                        And when I see that same man riding around through the country buying
                        everything he can get hold of and then selling it for double what he gave,
                        while the other man, who is no more a volunteer than he, and who stands upon
                        precisely the same footing in his company, has to have his name banded
                        around, not only through the army, but in his native county as a deserter,
                        simply because he failed to report up to time owing to the fact that Gen.
                        Lee had ordered all men to be stopped at Gordonsville, I am constrained to
                        believe that justice has fled from her temples on earth and awaits us only
                        on high to measure out what is right between man and man! I do not pretend
                        to say that these things are not right in the eyes of the military, but from
                        where I stand, beneath a musket and forty rounds of cartridges, it does not
                        look so; consequently, any information on the subject will be gratefully
                        received by</p>
                    <p>JUSTICE, Co. F, 5th Va. Infantry.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Justice, Co. F, 5th Va. Infantry</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asks why it is that quartermasters and commissaries enjoy special
                    privileges, and why some men are sitting at home instead of fighting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>RICHMOND, Feb 1, 1864.</p>
                    <p>MR. EDITOR: The County Court of Augusta at the December term conferred upon
                        me the authority to purchase a quantity of corn for the use of the families
                        of soldiers and others, to the extent of 10,000 bushels, provided the cost
                        and expense of transportation does not exceed $4.00 per bushel. I have made
                        use of all the facilities which my position gives me here, to get the
                        information needed, to enable me to carry out the wish of the Court. I
                        regret to say that in consequence of the great demand in Virginia and North
                        Carolina for corn, to say nothing of the wants of the army, that the price
                        has enhanced so much in the extreme South as to render it utterly impossible
                        to meet its wishes. Last evening, I met an intelligent Commissary of General
                        Lee's army just from South Alabama and Georgia who informs me the price of
                        corn there is $2.25 per bushel, to which $1.00 for transportation must be
                        added.</p>
                    <p>Permit me to say I am gratified at the refusal of the Court to make the levy
                        of the negroes. I learned at Drawy's Bluff, on Saturday last, from an
                        officer high in command there, that no more negroes were wanted in that
                        quarter, that the soldiers could do all that was necessary to be done, and
                        that he fully concurred in General Lee's view of the matter, who said he
                        thought the negroes had better be left on the farms to Raise corn and let
                        the soldiers Raise the embankments.</p>
                    <p>Yours truly, <lb/>J.M. McCue.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>J. M. McCue</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Explains that rising prices have made it difficult to purchase corn for
                    soldiers' families. Supports keeping slaves at home to continue planting and
                    harvesting corn.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>J. Gordon Riley, Capt. P.A.C.S.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Riley</ln>
                        <fn>J. Gordon</fn>
                        <sf>P. A. C. S.</sf>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jackson</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thanks the women of the Churchville and Hebron Soldiers' Aid Societies for
                    donating socks to Colonel William S. Jackson's Brigade.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mr. Editor: I am under the impression that there is a law imposing a fine
                        upon any one refusing to receive Confederate Money. Why is it that many
                        farmers having corn for sale refuse to receive it for corn. I know many who
                        desire to purchase corn, and other grain, for their horses and families
                        &amp; cannot procure it without the gold, or silver, which few can
                        command. Confederate money has been denounced as trash, worth nothing. I
                        refer the present generation to the good old honest days of the revolution.
                        How about the resources of the country then, and at the present time. Are
                        not our resources infinitely better now than then. I wish to God there was
                        as much patriotism now, as there was then. I hope some steps will be taken
                        by Congress to put a stop to such proceedings. A great deal of suffering
                        will be experienced by the poor, as well as by those better off from this
                        very cause. Many tillers of the soil need grain for their horses, who cannot
                        procure it, for the want of gold and silver.</p>
                    <p>A FARMER</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>A Farmer</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges farmers to stop refusing Confederate money as payment for corn.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads, columns 1-2</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1864.02.09.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Yankees Near Richmond</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that several Yankee regiments crossed the York River Railroad near
                    Richmond a few days ago.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Movements on the Rapidan</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that two Yankee attempts to cross the Rapidan River have failed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Spirit of the Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"When the enemy learns that we are not only disposed and willing, but
                    prepared to continue the war for an indefinite period, they will think of
                    stopping the further effusion of blood, but not before."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The spirits of the people have revived within the past several weeks, and a
                        general impression seems to prevail that we will defeat the enemy in the
                        chief engagements which will take place in the ensuing campaign. Our armies
                        are in fine spirits and our soldiers in all of them are re-enlisting with a
                        spirit which reflects great credit upon their bravery, fortitude and
                        patriotism. The soldiers in the armies of the enemy are re-enlisting slowly
                        and relnctantly [sic], whereas the noble soldiers in our armies are
                        re-enlisting with a "perfect rush." The armies of the enemy will, it is
                        thought, be recruited chiefly by <emph rend="italic">raw levies</emph>, who
                        will be unable to stand before our brave and tried veterans, whose flags
                        have waved in triumph over so many bloody fields of battle. Whilst we will
                        be stronger in the next campaign than ever before, the enemy will be weaker
                        than at present. We cherish the hope that we will be able, in the next
                        campaign, to recover all the territory of the South now in the possession of
                        the enemy. If this hope be realized, the enemy will see that we will be able
                        to continue the war for an indefinite period. </p>
                    <p>The result of this war will not be determined by numbers or bravery so much
                        as by fortitude and persistent determination. We must be prepared to
                        continue the war, and must submit to its evils with patient endurance. Time
                        will crown that party with success which will exhibit the greater fortitude.
                        We have not so much to dread from the enemy as from our own people. We can
                        meet the enemy without dread; but the apprehension of unwise Legislation on
                        the part of our Congress creates a feeling of alarm which the armed hosts of
                        the enemy fail to inspire. We should not expend all of our strength [on] one
                        desperate effort. We should not abstract too many from labor, for it is as
                        necessary that the army should be fed as that it should be armed. We must,
                        also, retain a reserve of men for military service to supply the places of
                        those who may fall in battle or be disabled by disease. The next campaign
                        may end the war, but wisdom dictates that we should make preparations to
                        continue it for a longer time, for it is just as probable, nay more so, that
                        the next campaign may <emph rend="italic">not</emph> terminate it. When the
                        enemy learns that we are not only disposed and willing, but <emph
                            rend="italic">prepared</emph> to continue the war for an indefinite
                        period, they will think of stopping the further effusion of blood, but not
                        before. </p>
                    <p>We should show the enemy that we are not relying solely upon the operations
                        of a single campaign, but that we intend to protract the struggle, if
                        necessary, for years, and will transmit it, if needs be, as a woful [sic]
                        inheritance to our children and children's children to the third and fourth
                        generation. We should show them that we have faith in the sentiment that,</p>
                    <p>"Freedom's battle, once begun, <lb/>Bequeathed from bleeding sire to son,
                        <lb/>Though baffled oft, <lb/>Is ever won." </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>States that the Confederate army is in good spirits, and that soldiers are
                    rushing to reenlist. Also notes that citizens must still brace themselves for a
                    long and protracted war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Good News From North Carolina</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Confederate forces successfully turned back a Yankee attack on
                    Newburn, NC. Includes copies of dispatches summarizing the damage and
                    casualties.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Capture of a Yankee Train</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists supplies and numbers of people taken during the capture of a Yankee
                    train near Williamsport, Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>A Raid to Madison Court-House</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that a Yankee cavalry seized fifteen to twenty Confederate soldiers
                    during an attack on Madison Courthouse last Sunday. Notes that a traitor named
                    Robinson is to blame.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Yankees Refusing to Reenlist</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Says that the Yankee cavalry force has been seriously diminished after
                    Wilcox's ninth army corps refused to reenlist.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Good News from the Blackwater</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that Confederate forces foiled a Yankee attempt on a cotton factory
                    in Isle of Wight County and took 150 prisoners in the process.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Canvass in Yankee Land</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Vote for the man that avows, and pledges himself to carry out in good
                    faith, the ancient Democratic principles of State supremacy, and of
                    constitutional nullity of all attempted coercion of a State by Federal power."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints excerpt from the New York Freeman's Journal and Catholic Register
                    that urges voters to vote Democratic in order to bring an end to the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>General Lee on the War</head>
                <origin>South Carolinian</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that General Lee was overheard saying that with 20,000 more men in
                    his army, and 40,000 more in General Johnston's army, the Confederacy will
                    easily beat back the Yankees.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>New York Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The war policy of the present administration has entirely superseded the
                    constitution, and we now live under a regime as purely military as that of Rome
                    under the Caesars."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints the New York Herald's critical remarks about President Lincoln.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Noble Little Girl</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises a Mississippi girl for sending two hundred yards of jeans and other
                    items of clothing to the army over the past two years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Notice to Exempts and Persons Not Enrolled</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reminds men previously exempted from the service that they must report to
                    authorities with proof that they have a legitimate claim to exemption.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The New Conscription</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that new examining boards are being set up for the medical review
                    of all conscripted men.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dice</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunlap</ln>
                        <fn>Jno. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knowles</ln>
                        <fn>Catherine A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. Mr. Dice married Jno. J. Dunlap and Catherine A. Knowles on February
                    4.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dice</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Day</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew M.</fn>
                        <sf>C. S. A.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>St. Clair</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. Mr. Dice married Andrew M. Day, C. S. A., and Lizzie C. St. Clair on
                    February 4.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rice</ln>
                        <fn>Archibald S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barger</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barger</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On February 4, Rev. Martin Garber married Archibald S. Rice and Eliza Jane
                    Barger, daughter of Jacob Barger.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Reports on skirmishing in Tennessee, columns 2-3; classified ads, columns
            6-7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
