<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1864/va.au.ss.1864.04.05">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Amy Murrell</taggerName>
            <tagDate>9/1/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 9/8/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1864-04-05">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day>5</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1864.04.05.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>An Impressive Scene-- Bishop Meade and Gen. Lee</head>
                <origin>Montgomery Advertiser</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>S. S.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes how General Lee wept by the death bed of Bishop Meade of
                    Virginia, and how Meade in turn gave Lee his blessings to continue fighting the
                    Yankees.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Offers thoughts on what women think about themselves.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Way to Grow Rich</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Nothing is more easy than to grow rich. It is to trust nobody, to befriend
                        none; to heap interests upon interests, cent upon cent; to destroy all the
                        finer feelings of nature, and be rendered mean, miserable and despised, for
                        some twenty or thirty years, and riches will come as sure as disease,
                        disappointment and a miserable death.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides a critical view of what it means to be rich.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Comforting to Old Maids</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on a custom in New Hampshire that prevents any woman from ever
                    becoming an old maid by encouraging men to bid money for single women.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Sorghum</head>
                <origin>Lexington Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Offers suggestions for producing abundant and healthy quantities of
                    sorghum.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Weights and Measures</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides a table with the weight measurement of individual bushels of corn,
                    wheat, and other crops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Plant Mustard</head>
                <origin>Columbus Sun</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The author urges readers to plant mustard, which he considers a necessary
                    and profitable crop.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Practical Amalgation [sic]</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Tells about a case in Chicago where a white woman brought charges of
                    seduction against a black man.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Plain Talk</head>
                <origin>Louisville Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that Lincoln has compromised the Constitution in his prosecution of
                    the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Speech of Hon. Mr. Lamar, On the Confederate Cause in Europe</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints portion of a speech given by Hon. L. Q. C. Lamar before a Macon,
                    Georgia, audience. Lamar argues that Britain is among the European supporters of
                    the South, despite the fact that it has not officially recognized the
                    Confederacy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Cheap Soap</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Offers a recipe for making soap inexpensively.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Abstract of the Speech of Hon. A. H. Stephens</head>
                <origin>Columbus Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints portion of Alexander Stephens speech. Stephens offers reassurance
                    about the availability of necessary supplies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Folly and Wickedness of Continuing the War</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It would be madness to expect that men who had taken up arms so defiantly
                    and struggled so courageously as the South have done, should throw them down and
                    submit to their conquerors, especially when they had so little to hope and so
                    much to fear."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides extract from speech given in New Jersey by a Northern legislator
                    that suggests the costs of continuing to fight the South are too high.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Cotton, Cotton Yarns, Cotton Cloth and Cards for the People of Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on an act passed by the Virginia legislature that would make cotton
                    products more readily available to the state's residents.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Love Undiminished By Amputation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates touching story of a woman who vowed to continue loving an English
                    soldier who lost both an arm and a leg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The Darkey</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the killing of a black regiment near Yazoo City.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified ads and poetry, columns 1-2, report of skirmishing in Alabama,
                column 5</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1864.04.05.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Latest News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Lincoln is calling out the entire militia force of the North,
                    and that several hundred Northern men have taken up arms against the President.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Government Property</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Supports a bill before the Confederate Congress that would require citizens
                    who possess guns, bayonets, and other government property to pay taxes on that
                    property or else return it to the government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Justices of the Peace</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Clarifies intent of recent legislation exempting justices of the peace from
                    military service.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Taxes in Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the successful collection of taxes in Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Grant's Programme</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Outlines what is rumored to be General Grant's plan for wiping out the
                    South by the end of the summer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>More Deserters to be Shot</head>
                <origin>Rockingham Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that three more Virginia soldiers are to be shot for having
                    deserted the army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>From the Stonewall Brigade</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Tells about the adventure of three members of the Stonewall Brigade, who
                    approached a Yankee cavalry near the Rapidan River, fired shots, and returned
                    safely to camp.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Militia Organization</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains how Confederate authorities would organize all men between 18 and
                    45 into the militia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>From Fredericksburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the capture of three Confederate soldiers near Fredericksburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>A Good Suggestion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Suggests that instead of paying planters with currency, the government
                    should give them necessary farm implements when impressing their crops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Richmond Enquirer Says:</head>
                <origin>Richmond Enquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints the Richmond Enquirer's opinion that the defeat of Lincoln's army,
                    rather than any negotiation with the Yankees, will bring peace.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>More Confederate Captures--Two Yankee Schooners Seized</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the destruction of two Yankee schooners by members of the 15th
                    Virginia Cavalry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>No Time to Lose</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that conscripts between ages of 17 and 19, and between 45 and 50, can
                    organize into companies at any time.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Enlistment of Deserters</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reminds readers that the enlistment of deserters violates Confederate law.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Northern News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints copies of various Yankee dispatches, U.S. Congressional news, and
                    Lincoln proclamations.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Gen. Imboden's Command</head>
                <origin>Rockingham Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The soldiers, a very large proportion of whom are intelligent gentlemen,
                    are beginning to take a deep interest in spiritual matters, so that there is
                    reason to hope for a still better condition of things in this department of our
                    army."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have recen[t]ly learned some interesting and gratifying facts in
                        connection with the state of religious feeling in Gen. Imboden's command.
                        The Brigade Chaplain, Rev. Geo. G. Brooke, of the Baltimore Conference of
                        the M. E. Church, is an earnest, zealous, pious, and most industrious
                        laborer in that department of God's moral vineyard. Since the Brigade has
                        been encamped where it now is, about 50 of the soldiers have professed
                        religion and joined one or the other branches of the christian church. "A
                        camp church" has been established, into which have been gathered all the
                        members of the different churches. Preaching and other religious services
                        and a good many tracts and other religious books have been circulated and
                        read in the command. The soldiers, a very large proportion of whom are
                        intelligent gentlemen, are beginning to take a deep interest in spiritual
                        matters, so that there is reason to hope for a still better condition of
                        things in this department of our army. Rev. Mr. Brooke is assisted in his
                        labors of love by Rev. Jno. Lafferty, chaplain to the 18th Reg't., a
                        talented, zealous, and highly intelligent member of the Va. Annual
                        conference.--Rock. Register.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the growth of religious activity among members of General
                    Imboden's Brigade.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Table for the Times</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Table provides a look at the devaluation of Confederate currency.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>In the County Court of Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burnett</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf>D. C.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Justices of Augusta County Court offer resolutions of condolence to the
                    family of William Guy, Esq., recently deceased.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>J. Gordon Riley, Captain and Inspector of Cavalry Equipments, C. S. Arsenal</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bear</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. Gordon Riley offers thanks to the people of Churchville, and especially
                    to J. H. Bear and family, for being so kind while he recovered from injuries.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mr. EDITOR:</p>
                    <p>I wish to call the attention of the proper authorities to the subject of
                        desertion, as some who have left their posts, since last summer, are now
                        skulking about home and friends, and are engaged in pilfering through the
                        neighborhood. As the campaign will open in a few weeks, I think it is the
                        duty of all officers and men to be at their posts without any further delay,
                        and it is the duty of those, who have it in charge, to arrest every
                        deserter, and mete out to him such punishment as the military code provides.</p>
                    <p>A CITIZEN.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>A CITIZEN</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls for the punishment of deserters, who can be seen walking the streets
                    and pilfering through the neighborhood.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Paragraph Matrimonial</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"If you get a good wife, you will be the happiest fellow alive! If you get
                    a bad one, you may as well sell yourself for two and sixpence, at once!--Just as
                    well consider all these things beforehand, young man!"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Choosing a wife is a perilous piece of business. Do you suppose there is
                        nothing of it but evening visits, bouquets, and popping the question? My
                        dear simple young man, you ought not to be trusted out by yourself alone!
                        Take care that you don't get the China article, that looks exceedingly
                        pretty on the mantlepiece, until the gilt and ornament are all rubbed off,
                        and then is fit only for the dust-pile! A wife should be selected on the
                        same principle as a calico gown. Bright colors and gay patterns are not
                        always the best economy. Get something that will wash and wear. Nothing like
                        the suns and showers of matrimony to bleach out these deceptive externals.</p>
                    <p>Dont' [sic] choose the treasure by gas light, or in a parlor sitting. Broad
                        daylight is the best time--a kitchen the most sensible place. Bear in mind,
                        sir, that the article once bargained for, you can't exchange it if it don't
                        suit. If you buy a watch and it don't run as you expected, you can send it
                        to a jeweler, to be repaired; in the case of a wife, once paired, you can't
                        repair. She may run in the wrong direction--very well, sir, all that is left
                        for you is to run after her, and an interesting chase you will probably find
                        it! If you get a good wife, you will be the happiest fellow alive! If you
                        get a bad one, you may, as well sell yourself for two and sixpence, at once!
                        Just as well consider all these things beforehand, young man!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Compares women to china and fabric in explaining to young men how they
                    should go about picking a wife.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Preston</ln>
                        <fn>T. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houston</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Livingston</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. T. L. Preston married Rev. William Houston and Mary Waddell on March
                    24, at the home of the bride's father, Dr. Waddell Livingston, in Waynesboro.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hammack</ln>
                        <fn>C. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reubush</ln>
                        <fn>David H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rubush</ln>
                        <fn>C. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. C. B. Hammack married David H. Reubush and C. F. Rubush on March 27.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newman</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Nancy R. Newman died on March 2 of pneumonia at age 64.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Eveline</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Eveline Bell died on March 26 of paralysis in her home in Augusta
                    County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A. F. Kinney, Clerk</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>A. F.</fn>
                        <sf>Clerk</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sipes</ln>
                        <fn>Angeline</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Collins</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sipes</ln>
                        <fn>Henry F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>In Sipes v. Sipes, Angeline Sipes seeks a divorce from Henry F. Sipes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A. F. Kinney, Clerk</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>A. F.</fn>
                        <sf>Clerk</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sullivan</ln>
                        <fn>John O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sullivan</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>In Sullivan v. Sullivan, John O. Sullivan seeks a divorce from Eliza O.
                    Sullivan.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A. F. Kinney, Clerk</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>A. F.</fn>
                        <sf>Clerk</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craun</ln>
                        <fn>Jas. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craun</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>In Craun v. Craun &amp; Imboden, James R. Craun seeks payment of a debt
                    owed to him by Daniel M. Craun and John D. Imboden.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A. F. Kinney, Clerk</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>A. F.</fn>
                        <sf>Clerk</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craun</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craun</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craun</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craun</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>In Craun v. Craun, George and Joseph Craun, executors of the John Craun
                    estate, seek payment of debt from Daniel Craun.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A. F. Kinney, Clerk</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>A. F.</fn>
                        <sf>Clerk</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Churchman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lambert</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lambert</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kibler</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yates</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kibler</ln>
                        <fn>B. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hale</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>In Churchman v. Lambert, et. al., John Churchman seeks payment of debts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A. F. Kinney, Clerk</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>A. F.</fn>
                        <sf>Clerk</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reynolds</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Croft</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn>Henry H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doom</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>In Reynolds v. Croft, Peck, &amp; Doom, Joseph Reynolds seeks to
                    establish a title bond.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Notice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennerly</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces meeting of the Augusta Medical Society on April 14.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Overseers of Poor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf>President</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that the annual Overseers of the Poor meeting will be held next
                    Monday at the poor house.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Reports of skirmishing in Tennessee and Alabama, column 3</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
