<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1859/pa.fr.vs.1859.10.26">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1859-10-26">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day>26</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.10.26.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Insurrection at Harper's Ferry</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"Frederick, Md., Oct 17 - An insurrection is reported to have taken place at
                        Harpers [sic] Ferry. An armed band of Abolitionists have full possession of
                        the United States Arsenal, at Harper's Ferry.</p>
                    <p>"The express train running East was fired into twice and one of the railroad
                        hands, a negro, was killed while trying to get the train through the town.</p>
                    <p>HARPER'S FERRY, Oct 18 - 3 o'clock, A.M. The conflict on the Bridge was
                        fought mainly by the Railroad Tonnage men, from Martinsburg, led by Captain
                        Alburti. Evan Dorsey, a conductor of the Railroad Company, was killed, and
                        conductors Bowman and Hollett were wounded.</p>
                    <p>No damage was done to the Railroad or bridge by the rioters.</p>
                    <p>6 o'clock, A. M. Preparations are now making for the attack on the Armory.
                        The soldiers are posted all around the grounds, and for the last hour
                        everything has been quiet.</p>
                    <p>George Turner, a graduate of West Point, and one of the most distinguished
                        citizens in this vicinity, was shot yesterday, whilst coming into town. He
                        died during the night. He has a brother living in Baltimore, married into
                        the Patterson family.</p>
                    <p>Three of the rioters are lying dead in the streets; there are also three in
                        the river, and several are said to be lying within the Armory enclosure.</p>
                    <p>The following is the list of killed among the citizens and
                        soldiers:--Fountain Beckham; Haywood, a negro porter at the railroad
                        station; Jos. Burney of Harper's Ferry, Evan Dorsey and Gen. Richardon, of
                        Waterbury.</p>
                    <p>The rioters have just sent out a flag of truce, saying that if they are not
                        protected by the soldiers here at present, they will hang all they capture.</p>
                    <p>The Armory Stormed.</p>
                    <p>Harper's Ferry, October 18 - 8 o'clock - The armory has just been stormed and
                        taken, after a determined resistance.</p>
                    <p>Col. Shutt approached with a flag of truce and demanded the surrender of the
                        armory--After expostulating for some time, the rioters refused.</p>
                    <p>The Marines then advanced and make a charge, endeavoring to break open the
                        door with sledge hammers, but it resisted all their effort.</p>
                    <p>A large ladder was then used as a battering ram, and the door gave way. The
                        rioters fired briskly and shot three of the Marines who exchanged shots
                        through the partly broken door. The Marines then forced their way through
                        the break, and in a few minutes all resistance was at an end.</p>
                    <p>The rioters were brought out amidst the most intense excitement, many of the
                        armed militia present trying to get an opportunity to shoot them.</p>
                    <p>Captain Brown and his son were both shot; the latter is dead and the former
                        dying. He lies in the armory enclosure. He talks freely, and says that he is
                        the old Ossawattomie Brown whose feats in Kansas have had such wide notice.
                        He says his whole object was to free the slaves and justifies his actions;
                        says that he had possession of the town and could have murdered all the
                        people.</p>
                    <p>J. G. Anderson was also shot down in the assault. He was from Connecticut.
                        The dead body of a man shot yesterday was found within the armory.</p>
                    <p>Brown declared that there were none engaged in the plot but those who
                        accompanied him.</p>
                    <p>The prisoners are retained within the armory enclosure.</p>
                    <p>Flight of the Insurgents--Troops to Be Dispatched in Pursuit.</p>
                    <p>Harper's Ferry, Oct. 18--Noon--Soon after storming the Armory, four dead
                        bodies of the insurgents that were shot yesterday, were found within the
                        enclosure. Captain Brown and his son are dangerously wounded.</p>
                    <p>Soon after the assault on the Armory, some firing took place from the hills
                        on the Maryland shore, supposed to be a "parting salute" from Cook and his
                        party, who left on Monday morning. The fire was returned with a general
                        volley, but both parties were too distant to do damage.</p>
                    <p>A company of volunteers were sent in pursuit of the fugitives.</p>
                    <p>There are probably a thousand armed men congregated here. Reinforcements have
                        been pouring in all night, from all parts of the surrounding country.</p>
                    <p>Only two of the insurrectionists are unwounded, with Edwin Coppick, white,
                        from Iowa, and Shields Green, colored, also from Iowa.</p>
                    <p>The party originally consisted of twenty-two persons; of whom fifteen are
                        killed, two mortally wounded, two unhurt, and three escaped with the slaves
                        on Monday morning.</p>
                    <p>Description of the Engagement by an Eye Witness.</p>
                    <p>Baltimore, Oct 18--An eye witness who has returned from Harper's Ferry,
                        describes the scenes there as follows:</p>
                    <p>The first attack was made by a detachment of the Charleston [sic] Guards, who
                        crossed the Potomac River above Harper's Ferry, and reached by the canal on
                        the Maryland side. Smart firing occurred, and the rioters were driven from
                        the bridge. One man was killed here and another arrested. The latter ran out
                        and tried to escape by swimming the river. A dozen shots were fired after
                        him. He partially fell, but rose again, and threw his gun away, drew his
                        pistols, both of which snapped, drew his Bowie knife, and cut all heavy
                        accouterments off, and plunged into the river. One of the soldiers was about
                        ten feet behind. The man turned round, threw up his handsm and cried, "Don't
                        shoot." The soldier fired, and the man fell into the water with his face
                        blown away. His coat skirts were cut from his person, and in the pockets was
                        found a Captain's commission to Capt. T. H. Leeman <emph rend="italic">from
                            the provisional government of the United States.</emph> The commission
                        was dated October 15, 1859, and signed A.W. Brown, Commander-in-Chief of the
                        Provisional Government of the United States.</p>
                    <p>A party of five of the insurgents, armed with Minie [sic] Rifles, and posted
                        in the Rifle Armory were expelled by the Charlestown Guards. They all ran
                        for the river, and one who was unable to swim was drowned. The other four
                        swam out to the rocks in the middle of the Shenandoah, and fired upon the
                        citizens and troops assembled upon both banks. This drew upon them the
                        muskets of between two and three hundred men, and not less than four hundred
                        shots were fired at them from Harper's Ferry--about 200 yards distant. One
                        was shot dead, the second, a negro, attempted to jump over the dam, but fell
                        shot, and was not seen afterwards; the third was badly wounded, and the
                        remaining one was taken unharmed. The white insurgent wounded and captured,
                        died in a few moments after, in the arms of our informant. He was shot
                        through the breast, arm and stomach. He declared there were only nineteen
                        whites engaged in this insurrection.</p>
                    <p>For nearly an hour, running and random firing was kept up by the troops
                        against the rioters. Several were shot down, while many managed to limp away
                        wounded.</p>
                    <p>During the firing the women and children ran shrieking in every direction,
                        but when they learned that the soldiers were their protectors, they took
                        courage and did good service in the way of preparing refreshments and
                        attending the wounded.</p>
                    <p>Our informant, who was on the hill when the firing was going on, says all the
                        terrible scenes of battle passed in reality beneath his eyes. Soldiers could
                        be seen pursuing singly and in couples, and the crack of the musket and
                        rifle was generally followed by one or more of the insurgents biting the
                        dust. The dead lay in the streets where they fell. The wounded were cared
                        for.</p>
                    <p>Captain Brown's wounds consist of a sword cut in the forehead, and a bayonet
                        wound in the kidneys.</p>
                    <p>Another of the rioters killed was named S. Taylor.</p>
                    <p>J. C. Anderson, a ringleader, who stopped conductor Phelps yesterday, was
                        killed in the first attack by the Virginians. Anderson was a fine looking
                        man, with a flowing white beard.</p>
                    <p>Some of the Maryland Volunteers are in pursuit of Captain Cook's party.</p>
                    <p>A body of forty men, mounted, left this afternoon for Harper's Ferry, to
                        pursue the rioters. It is reported that many of them have escaped and are
                        secreted in the mountains. A negro named Green, who was conspicuous in the
                        fugitive slave riot at Harrisburg some years ago, was among the insurgents.</p>
                    <p>Interesting Details--Capt. Brown and His Recent Movement--The Other
                        Leaders--Commencement of the Insurrection--Departure of Cook for
                        Pennsylvania.</p>
                    <p> Baltimore, Oct 18--The following interesting narrative of the recent events
                        at Harper's Ferry, is gleaned from the report of the editor of the <emph
                            rend="italic">American,</emph> who accompanied the troops from this city
                        and returned this evening.</p>
                    <p>The principal originator of the short but bloody existence of this
                        insurrection was, undoubtedly, Capt Jno. Brown whose connection with the
                        scenes of violence in the border warfare of Kansas, then made his name
                        familiarly notorious to the whole country. Brown made his first appearance
                        in the vicinity of Harper's Ferry more than a year ago, accompanied by his
                        two sons, the whole party assuming the name of Smith. He inquired about land
                        in the vicinity, and made investigations about the probability of finding
                        ores, and for some time boarded at Sandy Point, a mile east of the Ferry.
                        After an absence of some months he reappeared in the vicinity, and the elder
                        Brown rented or leased a farm on the Maryland side about four miles from the
                        Ferry. They bought a large number of picks and spades, and this confirmed
                        the belief that they intended to mine for ores. They were seen frequently in
                        and about Harper's Ferry, but no suspicion seems to have existed that "Bill
                        Smith" was Captain Brown, or that he intended embarking in any movement so
                        desperate or extraordinary. Yet the development of the plot leaves no doubt
                        that his visits to the Ferry, and his lease of the farm were all parts of
                        his preparation for the insurrection, which he supposed would be successful
                        in exterminating slavery in Maryland and Western Virginia.</p>
                    <p>Brown's chief aid was John E. Cook, a comparatively young man, who had
                        resided in and near the Ferry for some years. He was first employed in
                        tending a lock on the Canal, afterwards taught School on the Maryland side
                        of the river, and after a brief residence in Kansas, where it is supposed he
                        became acquainted with Brown, returned to the Ferry and married there. He
                        was regarded as a man of some intelligence, known to be anti-slavery, but
                        not so violent in the expression of his opinions as to excite any
                        suspicions. These two men, with Brown's two sons, were the only white men
                        connected with the insurrection that had been seen previously about the
                        Ferry. All were brought by Brown from a distance, and nearly all had been
                        with him in Kansas.</p>
                    <p>The first active movement in the insurrection was made about half past ten
                        o'clock on Sunday night. William Williamson, the watchman on the Harper's
                        Ferry bridge whilst walking across towards the Maryland side was seized by a
                        number of men who said he was their prisoner and must come with them. He
                        recognized Brown and Cook among the men, and knowing them, he treated the
                        matter as a joke, but enjoining silence, they conducted him to the armory,
                        which he found already in their possession. He was retained till after
                        daylight and then discharged. The watchman who was to relieve Williamson at
                        midnight, found the bridge lights all out and was immediately seized.
                        Supposing it an attempt at robbery he broke away and his pursuers stumbling
                        over, he escaped.</p>
                    <p>The next appearance of the insurrectionists was at the house of Col. Lewis
                        Washington, a large farmer and slave-owner, living about four miles from the
                        Ferry. A party, headed by Cook, proceeded there, aroused Colonel W. and told
                        him he was their prisoner. They also seized all the slaves near the house,
                        and took the carriage and horse and a large wagon with two horses. When Col.
                        Washington saw Cook, he immediately recognized him as a man who had called
                        upon him some months previous, to whom he had exhibited some valuable arms
                        in his possession, including an antique sword presented by Frederick the
                        Great to Gen. George Washington, and a pair of pistols presented by Gen.
                        Lafayette to Washington, both being heirlooms in the family. Before leaving,
                        Cook challenged Colonel Washington to a trial of skill at shooting, and
                        exhibited considerable certainty as a marksman. When he made his visit on
                        Sunday night he alluded to his previous visit and the courtesy with which he
                        had been treated and regretted the necessary which made it his duty to
                        arrest Col. W. He, however, took advantage of the knowledge he obtain by his
                        former visit, to carry off all the valuable collection of arms, which Col.
                        W. did not reobtain till after the final defeat of the insurrection. From
                        Col. Washington's the party proceeded with him as a prisoner, in his own
                        carraige [sic], and twelve of his negroes in the wagon, to the house of Mr.
                        Allstadt, another large farmer, on the same road. Mr. A. and his son, a lad
                        of 16 years of age were taken prisoners, and all the negroes within reach
                        being forced to join the movement, they returned to the armory at the Ferry.
                        All these movements seem to have been made without exciting the slightest
                        alarm in the town, nor did the detention of Captain Phelps' train at the
                        upper end of the town attract attention. It was not till the town thoroughly
                        waked [sic] up and found the bridge guarded by armed men, and a guard
                        stationed at all the avenues, that the people found they were prisoners. A
                        panic appears to have immediately ensued, and the number of the
                        insurrectionists at once increased from fifty (which was probably their
                        greatest force, including the slaves who were forced to join them,) to from
                        500 to 600.</p>
                    <p>In the meantime a number of workmen knowing nothing of what had occurred,
                        entered the Armory and were successively taken prisoners, until they had at
                        one time not less than sixty men confined in the Armory. Among those thus
                        entrapped were Armistead Ball, Chief Draughtsman of the Armory; Benjamin
                        Mills, Master of the Armory, and J. E. P. Dangerfield, Pay Master's Clerk.
                        These three gentlemen were imprisoned in the engine house (which afterwards
                        became the chief fortress of the insurgents) and were not released till
                        after the final assault. The workmen were imprisoned in the large building
                        father down the yard, and were rescued by a brilliant Zouave dash, made by
                        the Railroad Company's men, who came down from Martinsburg. This was the
                        condition of affairs at daylight, about which time Captain Cook, with two
                        white men, and accompanied by thirty negroes, and taking with them Colonel
                        Washington's large wagon, went over the bridge and struck up the mountain on
                        the road toward Pennsylvania.</p>
                    <p>It was then believed that the large wagon was used to convey away the
                        Paymaster's safe, containing $18,000 Government funds, and also that it was
                        filled with Minnie rifles, taken out to supply other bands in the mountains,
                        who were to come down on Harper's Ferry in overwhelming force. These
                        suppositions both proved untrue, as neither money nor arms were disturbed.
                        The news spread around, and the people came into the Ferry, the first
                        demonstrations of resistance were made to the insurrectionists. A general
                        warfare commenced, chiefly led by a man named Chambers, whose house
                        commanded the Armory yard.</p>
                    <p>The colored, man, Hayward, a railroad porter, was shot early in the morning,
                        for refusing to join the movement. The next man shot was Joseph Burley, a
                        citizen of the Ferry. He was shot standing in his own door. About this time
                        Samuel P. Young, Esq., was killed while coming into town on horseback. The
                        insurrectionists by this time, finding a general disposition to resist them,
                        had nearly all withdrawn within the armory grounds, leaving only a guard on
                        the bridge. About noon the Charlestown troops, under command of Colonel
                        Robert Baylor, having crossed the river some distance up, and marched down
                        on the Maryland side to the mouth of the bridge, firing a volley, they made
                        a gallant dash across the bridge, clearing it of the insurrectionists, who
                        retreated rapidly down towards the armory. In this movement one of the
                        insurrectionists, Wm. Thompson was taken prisoner.</p>
                    <p>The Shepardstown troops next arrived, marching down the Shenandoah side and
                        joining the Charlestown force at the bridge. A desultory exchange of shots
                        followed, one of which struck Mr. Fountain Beckham, Mayor of the town and
                        agent of the Railroad Company, in the breast, passing entirely through his
                        body. The ball was a large elongated slug, making a dreadful wound. He died
                        almost immediately. Beckham was without arms and was exposed only for a
                        moment whilst approaching the water station. His assailant, one of Brown's
                        sons, was shot almost immediately, but managed to get back into the engine
                        house, where his dead body was found to-day. The murder of Mr. Beckham
                        excited the populace, and a cry was immediately made to bring out the
                        prisoner Thompson. He was brought out on the bridge and shot down from the
                        bridge. He fell into the water, and some appearance of life still remaining,
                        he was again riddled with balls.</p>
                    <p>Sharp fighting ensued, and at this time a general charge was made down the
                        street from the bridge towards the Armory gate, by the Charlestown and
                        Shepardstown troops and the Ferry people from behind the Armory wall. A
                        fusillade was kept and returned by the insurrectionists from the Armory
                        building. Whilst this was going on the Martinsburg levies arrived at the
                        upper end of the town, and entering the Armory grounds by the rear, made an
                        attack from that side. This force was largely composed of railroad
                        employees, gathered from the tonnage trains at Martinsburg, and their attack
                        was generally spoken of as showing the greatest amount of fighting pluck
                        exhibited during the day.</p>
                    <p>Dashing on, firing and cheering, and gallantly led by Capt. Alburstis they
                        carried the building in which the armory men were imprisoned and released
                        the whole of them. They were, however, but poorly armed, some with pistols
                        and others with shot guns, and when they came within range of the engine
                        house, where the <emph rend="italic">elite</emph> of the insurrectionists
                        were gathered, and became exposed to their rapid and dexterous use of
                        Sharpe's rifles, they were forced to fall back, suffering pretty severely.
                        Conductor Evan Dorsey, of Baltimore, was killed instantly, and Conductor
                        George Richardson received a wound from which he died during the day.
                        Several others were wounded among them a son of Dr. Hammond, of Martinsburg.</p>
                    <p>A guerrilla warfare was maintained the rest of the day, resulting in killing
                        two insurrectionists, and the wounding of a third. One crawled out through
                        the culvert leading into the Potomac, and attempted to cross to the Maryland
                        side, whether to escape or to convey information to Cook is not known. He
                        was shot while crossing the river, and fell dead on the rocks. An
                        adventurous lad waded out and secured his Sharpe's rifle, and his body was
                        afterwards stripped of a portion of its clothing. In one of his pockets was
                        found a Captain's commission drawn up in full form and declaring that the
                        bearer, Capt. Lehman, held that command under Major Gen. Brown.</p>
                    <p>A light mulatto was shot just outside the armory gate. The ball went through
                        his throat, tearing away all the great arteries, and killing him instantly.
                        He name is not known but he was one of the free negroes who came with Brown.
                        His body was left exposed in the street up to noon yesterday, to every
                        indignity that could be heaped upon it by the excited populace. At this time
                        a tall, powerful man, named Evan Stephans, came out from the armory,
                        conducting some prisoners, it was said, and was shot twice in the side and
                        breast. He was captured and taken to a tavern, and after the insurrection
                        was quelled, was turned over to the United States authorities, in a dying
                        condition.</p>
                    <p>During the afternoon, a sharp little affair took place on the Shenandoah side
                        of the town. The insurrectionists had also seized Hall's Rifle works, and a
                        party of their assailants found their way in through the mill race, and
                        dislodged them. In this encounter, it was said, three of the
                        insurrectionists were killed, but we found but one dead body--that of a
                        negro--on that side of the town.</p>
                    <p>Night, by this time, had set in, and the operations ceased. Guards were
                        placed around the Armory, and every precaution taken to prevent escapes.</p>
                    <p>Arrival of the Baltimore Military.</p>
                    <p>At eleven o'clock on Monday night, the train with the Baltimore military and
                        the marines arrived at Sandy Hook, where they waited for the arrivals of
                        Col. Lee who was deputised by the War Department to take command.</p>
                    <p>Aaron Stephens, a wounded prisoner, said he was a native of Connecticut, but
                        had lived in Kansas, where he knew Captain Brown. He had also served in the
                        United States Army. The sole object of the attempt, he said, was to give the
                        negroes freedom, and Brown had represented that as soon as they seized the
                        Armory the negroes would flock to them by thousands, and would soon have
                        force enough to accomplish their purpose--one for which he would sacrifice
                        his life. But he thought Brown had been greatly deceived. He said
                        preparations had been made for some months for the movement, but the whole
                        force consisted of seventeen white men and five free negroes.</p>
                    <p>This statement was repeated without variation by all the prisoners with whom
                        we conversed. All agreed as to the number of persons engaged in the movement
                        and as to its object, which some of them called the work of philanthropy.</p>
                    <p>Lewis Leary, a negro, who was shot at the rifle mill, stated, before he died,
                        that he enlisted with Captain Brown, for the insurrection, at a fair held in
                        Lorraine county, Ohio, and received money to pay his expenses. They all came
                        down to Chambersburg, Pa., and from there traveled across the country to
                        Brown's farm.</p>
                    <p>The Prisoners.</p>
                    <p>Besides Capt. Brown, the prisoners taken are his son, who is seriously
                        wounded in the abdomen, and is not likely to live; Edward Cuppuck, who
                        belongs to Iowa, and a negro named Shields Green, who came from Pittsburgh
                        to join Brown.</p>
                    <p>The stories of these men are precisely alike. They agree as to the objects
                        they proposed to accomplish, and the number of persons engaged in the
                        movement. Young Brown, in answer to a question, said there were parties in
                        the North connected with the movement, thus differing from his father on
                        this point.</p>
                    <p>Coppuck [sic], the other white prisoner, is quite young, and seems less
                        shrewd than the others. He said he did not wish to join the expedition; and
                        when asked gave a reply which showed the influence which Brown had over him.
                        He said: "Ah! You gentlemen don't know Capt. Brown. When he calls for us, we
                        never think of refusing to come."</p>
                    <p>Several slaves were found in the room with the insurrectionists, but it is
                        not believed they were there willingly. Indeed, Brown's expectation as to
                        the slaves rushing to him, was entirely disappointed. None seem to have come
                        to him willingly, and in most cases were forced to desert their masters.</p>
                    <p>But one instance in which the slaves made a public appearance with arms in
                        their hands, is related. A negro who had been sharply used by one of the
                        town's people, when he found that he had a pike in his hand, used his brief
                        authority to arrest the citizen and have him taken to the armory.</p>
                    <p>Treatment of the Prisoners.</p>
                    <p>The citizens imprisoned by the insurrectionists all testify to their lenient
                        treatment. They were neither tied nor insulted, and beyond the outrage of
                        restricting their liberty, were not ill used. Captain Brown was always
                        courteous to them, at all times assured them that they should not be
                        injured. He explained his purposes to them, and whilst he had the workmen in
                        confinement, made no abolition speech to them.</p>
                    <p>Col. Washington speaks of him as a man of extraordinary nerve. He never
                        blanched during the assault, though he admitted through the night, that
                        escape was impossible, and he would have to die. When the door was broken
                        down, one of his men exclaimed, "I surrender!" The Captain immediately cried
                        out, "there's one surrenders, give him quarter!" and at the same moment
                        fired his rifle at the door.</p>
                    <p>During the previous night, he spoke freely with Col. Washington, and referred
                        to his sons. He said he had lost one in Kansas, and two here. He had not
                        pressed them to join him in the expedition, but did not regret their loss.
                        They had died in a glorious cause.</p>
                    <p>The position of the prisoners in the engine house during the firing on
                        Monday, and at the moment of the final attack, was a very trying one.
                        Without any of the incentives of combat, they had to risk the balls of their
                        friends, but happily they all escaped. At the moment when the doors were
                        broken in, the prisoners, at the suggestion of Col Washington, threw up
                        their hands, so that it might be seen they were not combatants.</p>
                    <p>Seizure of Arms.</p>
                    <p>During Wednesday morning, one of Col Washington's negroes came in and
                        reported that Capt. Cook was in the mountain, only three miles off. About
                        the same time some shots were said to have been fired from the Maryland
                        hills, and a rapid fusilade [sic] was returned from Harper's Ferry. The
                        Independent Greys of Baltimore immediately started on a scouting expedition,
                        and in two hours returned with two wagons loaded with arms and amunition
                        [sic] found at Captain Brown's house. The arms consisted of boxes filled
                        with Sharpe's rifles, pistols, &amp;c., bearing the stamp of the
                        Massachusetts Manufacturing Co., Chicopee, Massachusetts. There were found a
                        quantity of U. S. ammunition, a large number of spears, sharp iron bowie
                        knives fixed upon poles, a terrible looking weapon, intended for the use of
                        the negroes, with spades, pickaxes, shovels and everything that might be
                        needed, thus proving that the expedition was well provided for, that a large
                        party of men were expected to be arms, and that abundant means had been
                        provided to meet all expenses.</p>
                    <p>How all these supplies were got up to this farm without attracting
                        observation is strange. They are supposed to have been brought through
                        Pennsylvania. The Greys pursued Cook so fast that they secured part of his
                        arms, but with his more perfect knowledge of localities, he was enabled to
                        evade them. On their arrival at the Ferry with their spoils, they were
                        greeted with hearty cheers. The wagons were driven into the custody of the
                        Government. As every body else helped themselves, why should not the Greys
                        have a claim to the spoils.</p>
                    <p>The insurrectionists did not attempt to rob the Pay Master's department at
                        the armory. A large amount of money was there but it was not disturbed.</p>
                    <p>Perfect order having been restored the military, with the exception of the U.
                        S. Marines who remained in charge of the prisoners, left in the various
                        trains for their homes. An immense train brought the Baltimore troops home,
                        accompanied by the Frederick troops to the junction, with that freedom from
                        accident or detention, characteristic of the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad.</p>
                    <p>Baltimore, Oct 19</p>
                    <p>The following important intelligence from Harper's Ferry has just been
                        received. Last evening a detachment of marines, accompanied by some of the
                        volunteers, made a visit to Capt. Brown's house. The first visit was to the
                        school house, and not Brown's residence, as supposed yesterday. They found a
                        large quantity of blankets, boots, shoes, clothes, tents, fifteen hundred
                        pikes with large blades affixed, and also discovered documents throwing much
                        light on the affair. Among them are the printed constitution and by-laws of
                        the organization, showing or indicating a ramification throughout the
                        various States of the Union, and they also found letters from various
                        individuals from the North--one of Fred. Douglas, containing ten dollars for
                        the cause--also a letter from Gerret Smith about the matter, and a check or
                        draft by him for $200, endorsed by the cashier of a New York bank, whose
                        name is not recollected. All these documents are in the possession of Gov.
                        Wise. The Governor has issued a proclamation offering $1,000 reward for the
                        capture of Cook. A large number of armed men are now scouring the mountains
                        in pursuit of him. The following is the anonymous letter received by Gov.
                        Floyd, of which mention has been made:</p>
                    <p>Cincinnati, Aug. 20, 1859</p>
                    <p>Sir: I have lately received information of a movement of so great importance
                        that I feel it to be my duty to impart it to you without delay. I have
                        discovered the existence of a select association having for its object the
                        liberation of the slaves at the South by a general insurrection. The leader
                        of the movement is old John Brown, late of Kansas. He has been in Canada
                        during the winter, drilling the negroes there, and they are only waiting his
                        word to start for the South to assist the slaves. They have one of their
                        leading men (a white man) in an armory in Maryland, where it is situated I
                        have not been able to learn. As soon as everything is ready, those of their
                        number who are in the northern States and Canada are to come in small
                        companies to their rendezvous, which is in the mountains in Virginia. They
                        will pass down through Pennsylvania and Maryland and enter Virginia at
                        Harper's Ferry. Brown left the North about three of four weeks ago, and will
                        arm the negroes and strike the blow in a few weeks; so that whatever is done
                        must be done at once. They have a large quantity of arms at their
                        rendezvous, and probably distributing them already. As I am not fully in
                        their confidence, this is all the information I can give you. I dare not
                        sign my name to this, but trust that you will not disregard the warning on
                        that account."</p>
                    <p>Sometime during yesterday morning the O'Reilley line repairer, whilst
                        repairing the line between Harper's Ferry and Martinsburg, was shot at by
                        Capt. Cook himself, whom he recognized.</p>
                    <p>[second dispatch.]</p>
                    <p>The following is the number of killed and wounded during the recent
                        insurrection; Killed, five citizens, fifteen insurgents. Wounded, three
                        insurgents; prisoners five insurgents.</p>
                    <p>The prisoners have been committed to Charlestown jail to await the action of
                        the grand jury, when they will be indicted and tried in a few days. The
                        arrangement about the jurisdiction has been settled in this way. The local
                        authorities are to try the prisoners for murder, and in the meanwhile the
                        United States authorities will proceed on the charge of treason. Gov. Wise
                        said to Mr. Oulds, the United States District Attorney, that he had no
                        objection to the General Government proceeding against the prisoners--that
                        is, what will be left of them by the time the Virginia authorities are done
                        with them. Brown is better to-day, and has made a full confession of his
                        operations.</p>
                    <p>Letter from Gerrit Smith to Captain John Brown.</p>
                    <p>Petersboro, June 4 '59.--Capt. John Brown--My Dear Friend: I wrote you a week
                        ago, directing my letter to care of Mr. Kearney. He replied informing me
                        that he had forwarded the letter to Washington. But as Mr. Morton received
                        last evening a letter from Mr. Sanborn saying your address would be to your
                        son's home, viz: West Andover, I therefore write you without delay, and
                        direct my letter to your son. I have done what I could thus far for Kansas,
                        and what I could to keep you at your Kansas work. Losses by endorsements and
                        otherwise have brought me under heavy embarrassments the last two years, but
                        I must continue to do in order to keep you at your Kansas work. I send you
                        herewith my draft for $200. Let me hear from you on the receipt of this
                        letter. You live in our hearts, and our prayer to God is, that you may have
                        strength to continue in your Kansas work. My wife joins me in affectionate
                        regard to you, dear John, whom we both hold in very high esteem.</p>
                    <p>I suppose you put the Whitman note into Mr. Kearney's hands. It will be a
                        great shame if Whitman does not pay it. What a noble man is Mr. Kearney !
                        How liberally he has contributed to keep you in your Kansas work!- - Your
                        friend, "GERRIT SMITH."</p>
                    <p>On the back of this letter is endorsed - "Gerrit Smith answered June 17th and
                        enclosed E. B. Whitman's note and H. Tubman's receipt."</p>
                    <p>Description of "Captain" John E. Cook.</p>
                    <p>Baltimore, Oct 20--The following description of "Captain" Cook, one of the
                        leaders of the recent insurrection at Harper's Ferry, for the arrest of whom
                        $1000 reward is offered, stands five feet four inches to give feet six
                        inches in hight; [sic] weighs 132 pounds; walks with his breast projecting
                        forward, and head leaning toward the right; has light hair, with a small
                        growth around the upper lip; has a sallow complexion, and sharp, narrow
                        face.</p>
                    <p>Baltimore, Oct 20--In a conversation held with Capt Brown yesterday, in the
                        presence of Senator Mason, Hon. Messrs. Faulkner, Vallan- [illegible] and
                        others, he made several answers which clearly demonstrate the complicity of
                        numerous persons in the Northern, Western and Eastern States. He refused to
                        answer the question whether he had had a conference with Gilldings, on Ohio,
                        about his Virginia expedition. He admitted that he had correspondence with
                        parties at the North on the subject, and had numerous sympathizers in all
                        the free States.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports about Harper's Ferry from Frederick, MD; Baltimore; and Harper's
                    Ferry. Subheadings are: Flight of the Insurgents--Troops to be Despatched in
                    Pursuit; Description of the Engagement by an Eyewitness; Interesting
                    Details--Capt. Brown and His Recent Movement--The Other Leaders--Commencement of
                    the Insurrection--Departure of Cook for Pennsylvania; Arrival of the Baltimore
                    Military; The Prisoners; Treatment of the Prisoners; Seizure of Arms. Also
                    mentions letters from Gerrit Smith and Frederick Douglass to Brown. Does not
                    seem to mention Chambersburg. Takes up 5 columns.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/oct59.html#10.26a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.10.26.02">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.10.26.03">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.10.26.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Harper's Ferry Rioters Canonized</head>
                <origin>Tribune</origin>
                <commentary>There is significance in these remarks from the Tribune.</commentary>
                <excerpt> "Considerate <emph rend="italic">Tribune!</emph> How carefully has it ever
                    refrained from exciting ignorance to deeds of violence, in order that its
                    cherished plans might be consummated! How anxious, always, to preserve a spirit
                    of harmony in trying times when the Union was agitated with fears of civil war!
                    How uniformly cautious not to approve of blood-shed in the settlement of
                    troubling questions!" </excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There is a significance in these remarks from the Tribune:</p>
                    <p>"Never before was such an uproar raised by twenty men as by Old Brown and his
                        confederates in this deplorable affair. There will be enough to heap
                        execration on the memory of these mistaken men. We leave this work to the
                        fit hands and tongues of those who regard the fundamental axioms of the
                        Declaration of Independence as 'glitering [sic] generalities.' Believing
                        that the way to Universal Emancipation lies not through insurrection, civil
                        war and blood shed, but through peace, discussion, and the quiet diffusion
                        of sentiments of humanity and justice, we deeply regret this outbreak; but,
                        remembering that, if their fault was grievous, grievously have they answered
                        it. We will not, by one reproachful word, disturb the bloody shrouds wherein
                        (John Brown and) his compatriots are sleeping. They dared and died for what
                        they felt to be the right, though in a manner which seems to us fatally
                        wrong. Let their epitaphs remain unwritten until the not distant day when no
                        slave shall clank his chains in the shades of Monticello, or by the graves
                        of Mount Vernon."</p>
                    <p>Pathetic <emph rend="italic">Tribune!</emph> How the very cockles of its
                        heart seems stirred at the fate of those "mistaken men!" What [illegible]
                        hands of superior workmen? Posterity will take care of their memories,
                        regretful <emph rend="italic">Tribune;</emph> they are already embalmed in
                        the hearts of those who seek an anti-slavery Bible and an anti-slavery God.</p>
                    <p>Considerate <emph rend="italic">Tribune!</emph> How carefully has it ever
                        refrained from exciting ignorance to deeds of violence, in order that its
                        cherished plans might be consummated! How anxious, always, to preserve a
                        spirit of harmony in trying times when the Union was agitated with fears of
                        civil war! How uniformly cautious not to approve of blood-shed in the
                        settlement of troubling questions! How fearful lest an allusion to <emph
                            rend="italic">rifles</emph> should surreptitiously creep into its
                        peace-teeming columns!</p>
                    <p>Heart-broken <emph rend="italic">Tribune! you</emph> shall write the epitaphs
                        of the martyrs whose manner of death was so fatally wrong. Who so well
                        fitted for the task of decking the tomb as the nurse who rocked the
                            cradle?--<emph rend="italic">Pennsylvanian.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Complains about the medium that Brown took to get his message across. The
                    Tribune argues that abolition is good, but not through violence. The Spirit then
                    goes on from this premise and calls the Tribune pathetic for making Brown and
                    his followers into martyrs.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/oct59.html#10.26b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Insurrection at Harper's Ferry</head>
                <origin>Baltimore Exchange</origin>
                <excerpt>"'My name is John Brown. I am well known. I have been known as Old Brown of
                    Kansas. I'm from Litchfield county; Connecticut, and have lived in divers [sic]
                    places. Two of my sons were killed here to-day, and I'm dying too. I come here
                    to liberate slaves, and was to recieve [sic] no reward.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following is a portion of a detailed and circumstantial account of the
                        late insurrection at Harper's Ferry, furnished by the special reporter of
                        the Baltimore <emph rend="italic">Exchange:</emph></p>
                    <p>When the marines brought out their prisoners an immense cry of "hang them"
                        filled the air, and young men with rifles jumped from the walls and the
                        bridge into the armory yard, and were pressing to where they were, fully
                        intent on killing them, but the marines were ordered to protect them, and
                        drive back those who were eager for their blood. The bodies of the dead and
                        dying men where [sic] brought out and laid on the grass, but it was
                        impossible to keep the crowd back. Captain Brown told the crowd not to
                        maltreat him, that he was dying, and that he would soon be beyond all
                        injury. Major Russell had him conveyed into a room of one of the department,
                        and kindly ordered all attention to be paid him. Brown looked up, and
                        recognizing Major Russell said, "You entered first. I could have killed you,
                        but I spared you." In reply to which the Major bowed and said, "I thank
                        you."</p>
                    <p>Major Russell kindly admitted me to the room where Brown was lying, and I
                        held the following conversation with him. I asked--</p>
                    <p>What is your name--where were you born, and how old are you?"</p>
                    <p>"My name is John Brown. I am well known. I have been known as Old Brown of
                        Kansas. I'm from Litchfield county; Connecticut, and have lived in divers
                        [sic] places. Two of my sons were killed here to-day, and I'm dying too. I
                        come here to liberate slaves, and was to recieve [sic] no reward. I have
                        acted from a sense of duty, am contented to await my fate, but I think the
                        crowd have treated me badly. I'm an old man, and yesterday I could have
                        killed whom I chose, but I had no desire to kill any person, and would not
                        have killed a man had they not tried to kill me and my men. I could have
                        sacked and burned the town, but did not. I have treated the persons who I
                        took as hostages kindly, and I appeal to them for the truth of what I say. I
                        am sixty-three years old."</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Reporter--</emph>"When did you first conceive this move?"</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Brown--</emph>"While in Kansas. After my property was
                        destroyed, one of my sons killed, and my happiness destroyed by the slave
                        party of Kansas, I determined to be revenged. I also was moved in this
                        matter by a hope to benefit the negroes."</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Reporter--</emph>"Where did you get all your rifles and
                        the pikes which are here? Who furnished you with them?"</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Brown--</emph>"My own money. I did not receive aid from
                        any man. Cook is not a son of mine. If I had succeeded in running off slaves
                        this time, I could have raised twenty times as many men as I have now, for a
                        similar expedition. But I have failed. I did not intend to stay here so
                        long, but they (the citizens) deceived me by proposing compromises which
                        they had no intention of carrying out. I am not in any man's employ."</p>
                    <p>Brown complained that the crowd who were clamorous for his blood were
                        treating him unkindly and unfairly, after the kindness and leniency he had
                        shown the citizens and the town. He also said that he was fully convinced
                        that he was dying in a righteous cause. It is not however, propable [sic]
                        that he will die until he has been tried by a jury, as the only wound he
                        sustained is a cut across the head with a sabre. The sum of four hundred and
                        eighty dollars was found on his person, which was placed with the paymaster
                        for safe keeping.</p>
                    <p>Ed. Copie states that he is from Iowa. He made the aquaintance [sic] of Brown
                        last winter in Iowa, where Brown told him of this scheme and asked him to
                        join the expedition. Copie states as follows: - "We were to be well paid for
                        our time and trouble. We never made a direct bargain as to how much we were
                        to receive. Old man Brown was not to pay us, but I don't know who was. The
                        rifles were furnished by the Massachusetts Aid Society. They were first sent
                        to Kansas but the excitement having died away, they were of no use, and
                        Brown got the rifles for this ex-(illegible) Chambersburg, Franklin county;
                        they were then hauled from there to Brown's house by a man who lives in
                        Greencastle. I don't know who made the pikes or picks I have said all the
                        prayers I have to say, and am ready to die."</p>
                    <p>The negro's name is Gains. He says he lived in Harrisburg, Pennsylvania, and
                        that Brown had induced him to come over to Maryland and work for him; that
                        he did so and was induced to go into the insurrection.</p>
                    <p>Gains is a bad fellow, and no truth in him. He told several palpable lies
                        while telling his story.</p>
                    <p>The prisoners were in the hands of the marines. After they had been taken,
                        the Independent Grays, Capt. B. L. Simson, heard that Capt. Cook, with other
                        insurgents, were over in Maryland. They proceeded to the spot designated,
                        and found the arms and other articles which had been removed from the
                        armory, together with the wagons and horses. They returned with them to the
                        Ferry. A large number of persons are out on horseback, hunting for Cook and
                        his companions.</p>
                    <p>The little wagon which Brown brought with him was found in the armory yard.
                        It contained pikes, picks, shovels, kindling bark saturated with fluid, and
                        a number of whistles of peculiar construction, which when sounded give forth
                        a strange trilling note.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Another report about Harper's Ferry, actually after the raid. Mentions that
                    the guns were sent from Kansas to Chambersburg. Article refers to Gains, a black
                    conspirator, as a liar.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/oct59.html#10.26c</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>From Washington</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"Gov. Wise, in his Richmond speech, says he has a bushel of Capt. Brown's
                    correspondence, but not all of it. A carpet bag full was taken to Baltimore, and
                    improperly used. The letters in his possession proved that prominent men at the
                    North were implicated in the affair."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Washington, Oct. 23--Gov. Wise, in his Richmond speech, says he has a bushel
                        of Capt. Brown's correspondence, but not all of it. A carpet bag full was
                        taken to Baltimore, and improperly used. The letters in his possession
                        proved that prominent men at the North were implicated in the affair.
                        "Whether our sister States in the North will allow such men to remain among
                        them unrebuked or unpunished remains to be seen. If any one should smuggle
                        off Gerrett Smith some night, and bring him to me, I would read him a moral
                        lecture, and then send him back home." He had remained at Harper's Ferry to
                        prevent the application of lynch law in Virginia. There was no question of
                        jurisdiction to be settled, as he made up his mind fully, and after
                        determining that the prisoners should be tried in Virginia, he would not
                        have obeyed an order to the contrary from the President of the United
                        States.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report on Gov. Wise's reaction to Harper's Ferry.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/oct59.html#10.26d</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>A Colored Military Company Disbanded</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"E. C. Wilson, Adjutant General of the State of Pennsylvania, has taken
                    forty muskets which were in possession of the colored military company that
                    paraded in this city a few months since."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Philadelphia, Oct. 22--E. C. Wilson, Adjutant General of the State of
                        Pennsylvania, has taken forty muskets which were in possession of the
                        colored military company that paraded in this city a few months since.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The state of Pennsylvania has seized the guns of a black militia company in
                    Philadelphia.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/oct59.html#10.26d</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.10.26.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Insurrection at Harper's Ferry</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"It is only necessary to trace the visible footprints of the insurgents to
                    be convinced that the conspiracy has a more wide-spread existence than people
                    are generally disposed to believe."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In the present issue of our paper will be found full and accurate details of
                        the recent Abolition insurrection at Harper's Ferry. This attempt to subvert
                        the Government of the United States by a handful of crazy fanatics may seem
                        ridiculous, and hardly worthy of serious attention for a moment. But there
                        is another light in which the matter is to be viewed and one that presents a
                        more alarming aspect. This outbreak is only the beginning--the foreshadowing
                        of more serious troubles. That an extensive organization exists, in various
                        States, to overthrow the Government by means of a general and servile
                        insurrection there can no longer be a doubt. The frustration of this rash
                        beginning has not by any means broken up the organization. It will only have
                        the effect to make the conspirators more cautious in their working, and more
                        desperate and determined in their next attempt. It is only necessary to
                        trace the visible footprints of the insurgents to be convinced that the
                        conspiracy has a more wide-spread existence than people are generally
                        disposed to believe. We find the marauders of Kansas the active men in the
                        plot--the same men, the same means, and the same arms, used in that war,
                        have been brought into requisition in this outbreak. It is only a renewal of
                        the Kansas trouble in the heart of our country--brought home to our own
                        doors. All the treasonable machinery of that war have been put in operation
                        to shock the moral sense and excite the fear of our community with horrid
                        tales of rapine and murder at our own firesides.--Where the awful
                        responsibility for this state of things rest the people can no longer be so
                        blinded by their political prejudices, as not to see--With the evidence now
                        before them they must be considered willfully blind, hereafter, if they do
                        not repudiate the party whose seditious principles have sown the seed of
                        this insurrection broad-cast over the land.</p>
                    <p>It is not, however, at this time, of the general character, or political
                        tendencies of the insurrection that we wish to speak. Our community has by
                        some means, of which we were entirely unaware, become mixed up with this
                        insurrection. While we were harbouring, for months these desperadoes among
                        us we do not believe that a single one of our white citizens was in any way
                        connected with them, or even suspected their designs. In regard to our
                        blacks it is believed that a portion of them knew the object of these men,
                        were associated with them, and would have joined them if successful. There
                        is no sympathy in this community for the fugitives, and if any of them
                        should come this way they will receive no assistance or protection from any
                        of our citizens. It is the sentiment of one and all, in this community, to
                        have the outlaws arrested and receive that punishment which their crimes
                        demand.</p>
                    <p>The first trace we can find of these men among us was in the month of July
                        last. They were doubtless here previous to that time. Old Brown, passing by
                        the name of Smith, and a couple of men he called his sons. A man by the name
                        of John Henrie, who Brown on one occasion said was his son, was also among
                        the first comers and was the last to leave. This man is among the killed by
                        the name of "Capt. Kagi." Mrs. Cook, wife of Col. John E. Cook, gave us the
                        information that this man's name was John Henrie Kagi, and that he had been
                        one of Brown's men in Kansas. Large quantities of arms, and munitions of
                        war, were received at our warehouses, from time to time, upon which Brown
                        paid the freight, which in some instances amounted to seventy dollars.--
                        Some of the boxes containing Sharps Rifles came through from Kansas, and
                        other freight from Connecticut. The lance handles were shipped from that
                        State. Henrie remained here pretty much all the time superintending affairs.
                        [Line illegible] at a time, or merely passing through to Harrisburg, or
                        other points. While here he transacted business through our Bank having had
                        several drafts cashed on New York. He was here at the time Fred Douglas
                        lectured and was in the Hall that night with Henrie and several others of
                        the party. Our citizens had little idea how strongly Fred Douglas was backed
                        up on that occasion. Brown had no doubt an interview with Douglas at the
                        time and the object of Douglas' visit to the place is now fully explained.
                        Henrie was with Douglas at the house of the colored man at which Douglas
                        stopped. When Douglas left he gave out that he would return in October,
                        about the time the outbreak took place. It is quite likely he will postpone
                        his visit now to the <emph rend="italic">great disapointment</emph> [sic] of
                        some of his admirers here! The last time Brown was known to have been in
                        this place was on the 7th of October, when he brought the wife of Col. John
                        E. Cook here and left her at a private boarding house. The man Henrie (Kagi)
                        was the last of the gang known to have been here. He left for Harper's Ferry
                        on Friday the 14th just in time to meet his just doom. Brown or Henrie do
                        not seem to have made the acquaintance of any of our white citizens while
                        among us, though it is known they were intimate with some of our negroes.</p>
                    <p>The whole number of white men engaged in the insurrection were no doubt
                        sojourners with us at different times during the summer. Nine white men and
                        two negroes can be identified as having been here. Brown and his two sons,
                        Henrie, Leeann, Tided, Mermaid, Taylor and Coppice, were well known by name
                        in the neighborhood where they boarded. Other strangers of whose appearance
                        we have a full description were also seen in their company--The negro called
                        "Emperor of New York"--taken prisoner is said to be the black man who was
                        upon the stage with Douglas the night he lectured in this place. He did not
                        go back with Douglas and was not seen in this place afterwards. Brown
                        frequently visited here with a horse and wagon. The man called Tidd was also
                        here at one time for freight with a mule and wagon. Merriam was here a week
                        or ten days before the outbreak. He was very active in writing letters, and
                        telegraphing to different points. Some of his dispatches to Boston cost him
                        as much as $6. He hired a horse and buggy and in company with Henrie, it is
                        supposed, visited Harper's Ferry. He returned and left in the cars. This man
                        was not at the Ferry at the time of the insurrection.</p>
                    <p>It is not known whether Cook ever visited this place previous to the
                        insurrection. There is a rumor afloat that he was here sometime ago and
                        stopped at the house of a colored man. The general impression here is that
                        if Cook ever visited this place it was very privately and under an assumed
                        name. It cannot be recollected by the persons who have been observing these
                        men that any one answering to the description given of Cook was noticed
                        among them. His wife has been boarding in this place for the past two weeks.
                        Her mother resides at Harper's Ferry, and is a widow lady by the name of
                        Kennedy. Cook married her their [sic] about fifteen months ago. They have
                        one child about five months old which the mother has with her. Mrs. Cook is
                        quite young looking, very lady-like in her manners, and appears to possess a
                        considerable degree of shrewdness. She states very frankly that she has no
                        fears of her husband being captured. That he was all through the Kansas wars
                        and was often pursued while there but was never taken.--That he is <emph
                            rend="italic">well acquainted with the roads in this part of the
                        country</emph> and will have no diffulty [sic] in making his escape. Mrs.
                        Cook remained here until Monday morning last when she took the early train
                        for Harrisburg. She had previously engaged passage in the stage for Harper's
                        Ferry but for some reason changed her mind and left suddenly for Harrisburg.</p>
                    <p>On Friday last this community was thrown into a state of excitement by the
                        appearance on our streets of a man supposed to be Cook. The particulars in
                        relation to this man are, so far as we can gather them, briefly as
                        follows:--A gentleman on his way to town, in a buggy, overtook a man on
                        foot, on the Waynesboro road, coming in the direction of town. He asked to
                        be allowed to ride a few miles and was taken into the wagon. He had a bundle
                        in his hand which appeared to be a gun wrapped in a blanket. When within a
                        mile or two of town he left the buggy under the pretense of taking another
                        road, but it seems he came directly to town. He was pointed out to some of
                        our citizens by the man in whose buggy he had ridden and his movements
                        watched. He passed down Second street and turned up East King street, and
                        without making an inquiry, went straight to the house at which Brown and his
                        men boarded when here. He entered the room in which Mrs. Cook was sitting,
                        had some conversation with her, inquired if any of "the boys" had arrived,
                        and advised her not to go back to Harper's Ferry. He left immediately by the
                        rear of the house, passed down the garden where he concealed his gun under a
                        gourd, and although immediate pursuit was made he could not be found. The
                        Gun, wrapped in a blanket was picked up where he had placed it. It is a
                        Sharp's Rifle and appears never to have been used. It had no load in when
                        found. On Saturday a couple of our citizens left for Carlisle expecting him
                        to pass through that place.--They were not disappointed in their
                        expectations. They found him there and had him arrested and committed to
                        jail to await the demands of the Governor of Virginia. These gentlemen left
                        the same day for Harper's Ferry for the purpose of bringing parties on to
                        Carlisle to recognize this man. He says he is not Cook, that his name is Wm.
                        Harrison. We have a rumor here that this man is Albert Haslett, incorrectly
                        reported among the killed at the time of insurrection. This we think a
                        mistake. A few days will determine his name--there is no doubt about him
                        being one of the insurgents. There are parties in this town, we believe, who
                        could identify him if disposed to give the information. When taken he was
                        heavily armed, having on his person four revolvers and two Bowie knives. The
                        parties who visited Harper's Ferry to obtain [line illegible] day night and
                        left early next morning for Carlisle. They keep their own counsels, but from
                        what little they are disposed to tell, the impression is gaining strength
                        that the man arrested in Carlisle is John E. Cook. These gentlemen brought
                        with them from Harper's Ferry one of the lances, or pikes, intended to be
                        placed in the hands of the negroes. It is a murderous looking weapon and
                        would have proven a terrible instrument of destruction in the hands of the
                        blacks. No one can look at it and not feel that all engaged in this hellish
                        plot deserves [sic] the gibbet.</p>
                    <p>The very latest information obtained respecting the man arrested at Carlisle
                        would appear to identify him as Albert Haslett Lieutenant to Capt. Cook.
                        Gov. Wise has made a requisition for his surrender to the authorities of
                        Virginia to stand his trial with the rest of the insurgents.</p>
                    <p>It will no doubt seems [sic] to many impossible that these men lived among us
                        for months-- transacted business through our Bank and Warehouses, kept up an
                        extensive correspondence through our Post Office, and using the Telegraph
                        occasionally and yet no one suspected their real character or designs. As
                        incredible as this may seem, it is nevertheless true. Our community can
                        scarcely be brought to realize it even now, and seem astounded at their own
                        blindness. We feel very confident they have no aiders, abettors or
                        sympathizers among us and this may account for our complete ignorance of
                        their true object. They found none here to whom they could express their
                        opinions or make known their intentions. It is true that at one time, during
                        their stay among us, they were thought to be a gang of burglars.--This was
                        after the robbery of the Warehouse, and from certain circumstances connected
                        with that affair it is not at all unlikely that some of the gang may have
                        had some hand in the robbery. There was not sufficient proof, however, to
                        justify the arrest of any of the parties, and that suspicion against them
                        seems to have died out. While residing here they kept to
                        themselves--expressed no insurrectionary opinions to any one--paid their
                        bills regularly, and in every respect behaved themselves in such a correct
                        and orderly manner as to attract little attention. Our community can
                        certainly rest under no blame for not discovering and thwarting the schemes
                        of these rebels. We cannot be accused of being more blind than the people
                        about Harper's Ferry who knew more about them than we did and never
                        mistrusted them until they found themselves in pretty much the same fix that
                        Paddy had the Hessians-- "surrounded!" We will stand no imputations against
                        Chambersburg until Harper's Ferry defines its position!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes Harper's Ferry as "only the beginning--the foreshadowing of more
                    serious troubles." Very upset about the (inadvertent) role that Chambersburg
                    played. Goes through the conspirator's appearances in town and how the citizens
                    were duped. Includes mention of Douglass visit. Discusses capture of Cook in
                    Carlisle after passing through Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/oct59.html#10.26g</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Preliminary report on the County agricultural fair.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Markets in column 5. Married and deaths too dark to make out.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.10.26.06">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.10.26.07">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.10.26.08">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
