<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1859/pa.fr.vs.1859.05.18">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1859-05-18">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>18</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.05.18.01">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.05.18.02">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.05.18.03">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.05.18.04">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.05.18.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Improvements</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>It is gratifying to witness the evidences of improvement which are
                    everywhere going on around us at the present season. The large number of
                    dwelling houses in the course of construction in the various parts of our town
                    gives evidence of the rapid growth of this place, both in size and population,
                    and the most encouraging hope for its future welfare and prosperity.</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--It is gratifying to witness the evidences of improvement which are
                        everywhere going on around us at the present season. The large number of
                        dwelling houses in the course of construction in the various parts of our
                        town gives evidence of the rapid growth of this place, both in size and
                        population, and the most encouraging hope for its future welfare and
                        prosperity. Without enumerating the many fine residences put up within the
                        past year we would note the following improvements now in progress and
                        rapidly approaching to completion:</p>
                    <p>Geo. J. Mason is erecting a dwelling house on Second street between Catherine
                        and German streets.</p>
                    <p>John Smith is putting up a brick dwelling in the same neighborhood.</p>
                    <p>Henry Greenwald--a brick house on German street between Main and Second
                        streets.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Yeager a brick building on the corner of Washington and Water streets.</p>
                    <p>A German man not known a building back on Water street.</p>
                    <p>L. Wampler a back building to his residence on Main street.</p>
                    <p>Samuel McKesson a back building to the property on which he resides on Main
                        street.</p>
                    <p>Chas. Hutz has purchased the property adjoining the residence of Dr. A. H.
                        Senseny and has re-constructed the front house, and erected a large and
                        commodious back building. Mr. Hutz intends to reside in this property
                        himself; the repairs are now nearly finished, and when completed, it will be
                        a very convenient and comfortable residence.</p>
                    <p>J. Allison Eyster is erecting five dwelling houses of brick, to be three
                        stories in height, on Washington street between Main and Second streets.
                        These building will be splendid specimens of architectural taste and add
                        much to the locality in which they are erected.</p>
                    <p>Samuel Reisher has added an aditional story to his house--making it a three
                        story building. Mr. Reishers improvement will add much to the appearance and
                        convenience of his property, which is now among the most desirable in
                        location and construction in the town.</p>
                    <p>Eyster &amp; Bros: have purchased the Rhodes property on West Queen
                        Street and are erecting an elegant front building intended as a residence
                        for Mrs. Geo. Eyster.</p>
                    <p>Miss Martha C. Hock is putting up a fine two story brick residence on the
                        Cadow lot, on East Queen Street.</p>
                    <p>Hiram Senseny has just completed three dwelling houses on Washington street
                        extended.</p>
                    <p>Eyster &amp; Bros: have purchased the old Cooper property, on East Market
                        Street, remodeled the building formerly used as a Cabinet-ware room and
                        converted it into an elegant and convenient dwelling house. They have also
                        put up a large and well finished back building to the same property. This is
                        now one of the most complete properties in town. It will be occupied by Mr.
                        J. K. Shryock as a private residence.</p>
                    <p>Charles W. Eyster has erected a large brick back building attached to his
                        residence on West Market Street.</p>
                    <p>Mathew Gillan has purchased the Faber property and is improving it in the
                        most extensive and handsome manner. He has already erected a wing extending
                        back 62 feet, from the front house, on the east side. The front building
                        will be entirely re-constructed and extended 28 additional feet front, with
                        a wing on the west side running back 70 feet. This whole property is
                        undergoing an entire and thorough renovation, and when the work of repairing
                        and improving, which is now going on steadily, is completed, it will be one
                        of the most commodious and desirable properties anywhere to be found. Mr.
                        Gillan has just erected on this property a large brick barn, two stables and
                        wagon house, all under one roof, extending 61 feet in length and 24 feet
                        deep. This building is constructed in the most substantial and convenient
                        manner.</p>
                    <p>Chas. Be Miller (Landscape Gardener,) has purchased one of the "Circus Lots"
                        on West Market street, upon which he is erecting a snug residence. From the
                        well known taste of this gentleman in beautifying and improving property, we
                        have no doubt that in a few years his property will be quite an ornament to
                        that end of the town.</p>
                    <p>John Miller. (Hotel) has just completed an extension to his house. This
                        improvement is of brick and is quite a handsome addition to the appearance
                        of the house, as well as a convenience which Mr. Miller's increasing custom
                        demands.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Cooper, a gentleman from Gettysburg, has purchased the property between
                        Hoke's Store and Montgomery's Hotel, and is engaged in improving it in a
                        thorough and handsome manner. It is his intention to construct a large and
                        commodious store room in the front building . . . [text missing].</p>
                    <p>Saml. M. Armstrong has just finished a large brick dwelling house and store
                        room on Second Street between Market and Queen Streets.</p>
                    <p>F. S. Gillespie has erected a brick dwelling on Second Street north of
                        Market.</p>
                    <p>George Flack is engaged in improving his property by the erection of a large
                        back building constructed of brick.</p>
                    <p>Geo. Deitz is about completing a very handsome brick residence on Second
                        street near the Falling Spring.</p>
                    <p>At the northern end of town the "Lamp of Alladin" seems to have been at
                        work--quite a little city has sprung up there, which, by common consent, is
                        termed "CLARKSVILLE," and which bids fair to extend itself along the turn
                        pike and railroad <emph rend="italic">ad infinitum</emph>. In addition to
                        the many handsome and substantial buildings erected within the past year in
                        this delightful locality, we hear of some ten or a dozen under contract to
                        go up the present season in this neighborhood.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mason</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greensweld</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yeager</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wampler</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKeeson</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huts</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Senseny</ln>
                        <fn>A.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>J. Allison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reisher</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heck</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Senseny</ln>
                        <fn>Hiram</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shyrock</ln>
                        <fn>J.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>Mathew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cooper</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillespie</ln>
                        <fn>F.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flack</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deitz</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>List of new construction and home improvements in town.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/may59.html#5.18a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Announcements</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces upcoming concert, circus, military encampment, and theater
                    engagements. Also requests housing for strangers.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>PT Barnum and Dan Rice ads in columns 5 and 6.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.05.18.06">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.05.18.07">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.05.18.08">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
