<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1859/pa.fr.vs.1859.11.02">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1859-11-02">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day norm="02">2</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote>Some pages need to be renamed. See individual pageNotes.</editionNote>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.11.02.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Harper's Ferry Trouble; Trial of the Insurrectionists</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Proceedings of Harper's Ferry trial, from Charlestown. Takes up entire
                    first page.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/vsjbnov59.html#11.2a</note>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.11.02.01">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.11.02.02">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.11.02.03">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.11.02.02a">
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Narrative of the Democratic Expedition up Salt River</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Democracy</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Liggett</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grigg</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cooper</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>Hi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ripper</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>Solly</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nead</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn>McDowell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jacoby</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mawny</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keyser</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sellers</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>Tom</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitaker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAllen</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter from Salina detailing a Democratic expedition up river.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Fruits of Black Republicanism</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"What has taken place at Harper's Ferry is but a trifle in comparison with
                    what will some day occur, if conservative men of all political creeds do not
                    unite with the Democracy to put down the sectional party that has disturbed the
                    peace of the country."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Blames Harper's Ferry on Black Republicans. Argues that Douglass' August
                    speech had something to do with the attack as well.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/vsjbnov59.html#11.2b</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Important Documents--Giddings Clearly Implicated</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"We rejoice to learn that, so far as the revelations are yet made known,
                    not a single Democrat has been engaged in this conspiracy."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Text of letters written to and from Brown and co-conspirators while they
                    were in Chambersburg. Complains about the coverage of the raid in the Republican
                    press, which hasn't been critical enough.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/vsjbnov59.html#11.2c</note>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Page is misnumbered in top left corner.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.11.02.03a">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Arrest of Capt. Cook</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fitzhugh</ln>
                        <fn>Claggett</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Logan</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Two men from Quincy captured Cook, one of the Harper's Ferry Conspirators,
                    near Mont Alto. Details of papers about the conspiracy found on his person.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/vsjbnov59.html#11.2h</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"The Exhibition was in every way successful. The display of live stock,
                    which was generally from our own county, composed some of the finest ever placed
                    on exhibition."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--The First Annual Exhibition of the Farmers and Mechanics Industrial
                        Association, of this county, closed on Friday last. The Exhibition was in
                        every way successful. The display of live stock, which was generally from
                        our own county, composed some of the finest ever placed on exhibition. The
                        superiority of the stock was the general subject of remark by all visitors.
                        We regret that we cannot particularize and give proper credit to our Farmers
                        for the very fine specimens of their stock entered. by an arrangement of the
                        Managers, the names of the exhibitors were not allowed to be attached to the
                        articles on exhibition. There may be some good reason for this regulation,
                        but we cannot perceive it. If it is intended to keep the judges in the dark
                        that no favoritism may be shown in awarding premiums, it is but a poor
                        compliment to the honesty of the judges, while it does not accomplish the
                        purpose intended. Exhibitors generally made it a point to be on hand and
                        show off their portion of their stock, or explain the operation of their
                        machinery, when the judges go around, and thus they become pretty well
                        booked up as to who are the exhibitors. This regulation has certainly an
                        injurious tendency, and if persisted in must be a great drawback on future
                        exhibitions. As a general thing exhibitors do not enter articles merely with
                        a view of obtaining the premium. A little pride in their stock or products,
                        or as an advertisement for their wares, is the incentive. If this is taken
                        away visitors as well as exhibitors, will hereafter take but little interest
                        in our Fairs.</p>
                    <p>The articles exhibited in every department were of a very superior order, and
                        gave the highest degree of satisfaction to all visitors. The display of
                        Flowers, Vegetables and Farm products were very extensive, and for quality
                        would have competed with any offered in the State.</p>
                    <p>In the department of Household Articles the display was very creditable to
                        the taste and skill of our ladies.</p>
                    <p>The variety of Farming implements and machinery was very large and the
                        articles generally of superior workmanship, and well adapted to the uses for
                        which they were constructed.</p>
                    <p>We must refer our readers to the List of Premiums awarded for particular
                        information as respects the superiority of articles and the names of the
                        exhibitors.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report on the successful County fair. Complains that the exhibitions did
                    not include names, which allows the judges to grade them blindly. However, this
                    deprives the exhibitors of public recognition and thus pride in their
                    achievements.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/nov59.html#11.2a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>"Capt. Kagi"</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henrie</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Spirit expresses doubts that Kagi was actually among those killed during
                    the insurrection at Harper's Ferry, arguing that the only time his name appears
                    is on a list provided by Brown himself.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/vsjbnov59.html#11.2d</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Albert Hazlett</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Hazlett, one of Brown's men who was reported killed at Harper's Ferry, is
                    in jail in Virginia.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/vsjbnov59.html#11.2g</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Departure of Captain Cook</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Details of Cook's departure from Chambersburg to prison in Charlestown.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/vsjbnov59.html#11.2e</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Rumors</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Various rumors circulating on the subject of Harpers Ferry, including one
                    story that Kagi has been seen in town and another that Cook was about to be
                    rescued.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/vsjbnov59.html#11.2f</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Insurgents About</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Three boys out hunting in Beatty's woods found some rifles, ammunition,
                    books, and bandages. The Spirit believes that these are signs that Harper's
                    Ferry conspirators Tidd, Coppee and one of the Browns have been hiding out after
                    escaping.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/vsjbnov59.html#11.2i</note>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoffman</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cover</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on October 27.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bannerman</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Southall</ln>
                        <fn>Cathrine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on October 13.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shyrock</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shyrock</ln>
                        <fn>J.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shyrock</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Infant son died on October 22.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Page is numbered incorrectly on the upper left. Official state election
                returns in Col. 4. Markets in col. 5.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.11.02.06">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.11.02.07">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.11.02.08">
            <pageNote>Continuation of Harper's Ferry articles from page 1.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
