<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1859/pa.fr.vs.1859.02.23">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Will Thomas</taggerName>
            <tagDate>1/29/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>3rd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1859-02-23">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>23</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.02.23.01">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.02.23.02">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.02.23.03">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.02.23.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Who Are the Friends of "Freedom?"</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"The vote of the Black Republicans and their anti- American allies of the
                    Know Nothing party, upon the Oregon question, shows in the clearest possible
                    light the professions of friendship for "freedom" and "popular sovereignty."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The "freedom" shriekers in Congress have demonstrated their hypocrisy lately
                        in the most glaring manner. The vote of the Black Republicans and their
                        anti- American allies of the Know Nothing party, upon the Oregon question,
                        shows in the clearest possible light the professions of friendship for
                        "freedom" and "popular sovereignty." Oregon is a free State, and there is
                        not the remotest possibility that it will ever be changed in that respect.
                        The Constitution is republican in form, there is more than the requisite
                        population, and the only possible excuses these croakers in Congress can
                        possibly have had for voting against her admission as a State, are, the
                        niggers are not recognized as the equals of an infinitely superior race, and
                        there is there and overwhelming Democratic majority; so these "traitors to
                        freedom," these "dough faces of the first water," voted almost to a man
                        against the bill. They were entirely willing to place their names upon the
                        Congressional record as enemies to the admission of any more "free" States
                        with Democratic proclivities. Only fifteen Republican members voted in favor
                        of "freedom" and seventy three voted against it. We hope this fact will be
                        carefully remembered.</p>
                    <p>The leading negro advocate in the United States, the New York <emph
                            rend="italic">Tribune</emph>, openly justifies the vote given by these
                        "freedom" champions. That paper says:</p>
                    <p>"We hold that the great body of the Republicans voted just right on this
                        question, and of course that the fifteen who separated from, opposed and
                        defeated them, did a grievous wrong."</p>
                    <p>So, then, it is "a grievous wrong" to vote for the admission of a "free
                        State" into this glorious confederacy, in the judgment of the sectional
                        fanatics who control the columns of that unscrupulous and malignant partisan
                        paper. The New York <emph rend="italic">Times</emph> makes the following
                        admission:</p>
                    <p>Oregon is a free State--her Constitution prohibiting slavery--and she will
                        unquestionably always remain so."</p>
                    <p>Yet the <emph rend="italic">Times</emph> opposes her admission, as well as
                        its Black Republican rival, the <emph rend="italic">Tribune</emph>. Oregon
                        is a Democratic State, and is likely to remain so; white men are there
                        acknowledged to be superior to negroes--which are quite sufficient reasons
                        for the hypocritical Abolitionists objecting to her being allowed to enter
                        the great family of republican sovereignties.</p>
                    <p>The Black Republican journals admit that the votes of the two Senators from
                        Oregon settle the political complexion of the United States Senate, for the
                        next six years. It will be Democratic beyond all peradventure. The admission
                        of Oregon will give us three more votes at the next Presidential election.
                        To be sure they will not be needed, but they will be not the less welcome on
                        that account.</p>
                    <p>Our readers will not fail to bear in mind how faithful to the cause of
                        "freedom" the Republicans in Congress have shown themselves--<emph
                            rend="italic">Philad'a Argus</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article complains about the hypocrisy of Republican and Know-Nothing
                    so-called advocates of freedom, who oppose the admission of states with
                    Democratic proclivities. The issue was brought to a head by the admission of
                    Oregon. Article complains about the New York Times and New York Tribune.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/feb59.html#2.23a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Presidential Message, Congressional proceedings, Letter from
            Washington</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.02.23.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Legislative</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>G.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolff</ln>
                        <fn>Bernard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heyser</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Report of new county laws and petitions.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The 22nd</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"The Chambers Artillery, Light Dragoons, and St. Thomas Artillery parade
                    our streets through the day and made a handsome and creditable appearance--"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--The anniversary of Washington's birth day was celebrated in this place by a
                        grand military parade. The Chambers Artillery, Light Dragoons, and St.
                        Thomas Artillery parade our streets through the day and made a handsome and
                        creditable appearance--The proficiency in drill and maneuvering displayed by
                        those companies is the best and highest encomium that can be passed on the
                        military talents of their respective commanders. In the evening we had a
                        grand Military Ball, at Franklin Hall, which was well attended by "brave men
                        and fair women" who enjoyed themselves in a very pleasant manner.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report of celebration of Washington's Birthday, which included a parade and
                    Military ball, featuring Chambers Artillery, Light Dragoons and St. Thomas
                    Artillery.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/feb59.html#2.23b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Protection</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"--The Protection Hook and Ladder Company is now fully organized and
                    disciplined."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--The Protection Hook and Ladder Company is now fully organized and
                        disciplined. It numbers sixty five members--The following named gentlemen
                        have been elected Directors:--John H. Reed, P. B. Housum, J. P. Culbertson,
                        A. J. Brand, F. S. Gillispie and Nicholas Snider. The second regular stated
                        meeting of the Company will be held at their Hall on Friday evening
                    next.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Housman</ln>
                        <fn>P.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>J.P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brand</ln>
                        <fn>A.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillespie</ln>
                        <fn>F.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Salder</ln>
                        <fn>Nicholas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announcement of Directors for Protection Hook and Ladder Company.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/feb59.html#2.23d</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Bank Clerk</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Taylor appointed clerk in Bank of Chambersburg.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>St. Thomas School Meetings</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--Meetings were held at Highland's school house on Monday evening the 7th of
                        February, 1859, at Sinkhole school house Tuesday evening the 8th, at
                        Butler's school house, on Wednesday evening the 9th, at Gelwicks' school
                        house on Thursday evening the 10th, and at St. Thomas Friday evening the
                        11th, all of which were regularly organized. At all the above meetings the
                        county superintendent, P. M. Shoemaker, was introduced to the large and
                        eager audience which he addressed in an elegant, appropriate and instructive
                        style, on the working of the present school system and the great benefit
                        resulting from the county superintendency and also visiting and examining
                        the schools during the day in which were a number of citizens, directors and
                        teachers of the township, who were well pleased with the examination of the
                        schools and the active and energetic part Mr. P. M. Shoemaker took in the
                        schools of St. Thomas and their welfare. It is generally, and in some parts
                        of the county almost unanimously, believed that it is the principal that
                        will give life and energy to the schools of the county. The following
                        resolutions were also passed:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved.</emph> That we approve of the County
                        Superintendency. <lb/><emph rend="italic">Resolved.</emph> That our Thanks
                        be tendered Mr. P. M. Shoemaker for the able, eloquent and instructive
                        addresses delivered in St. Thomas Township.</p>
                    <p>J. W. COBLE, Secretary.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoemaker</ln>
                        <fn>P.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coble</ln>
                        <fn>J.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Series of meetings held around the district to introduce Shoemaker, the
                    county superintendent. Resolutions praising and thanking him.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/feb59.html#2.23c</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kramer</ln>
                        <fn>A.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>N.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kroh</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kroh</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on February 16.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>J. Smith</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>Humphry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curren</ln>
                        <fn>Deborah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on January 27.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>J. Smith</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLelland</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noble</ln>
                        <fn>Elyn</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on February 17.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>W.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Loefffler</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Goettman</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on February 17.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henry</ln>
                        <fn>S.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pfoutz</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Malons</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on February 3.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Murry</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on February 6 at age 60.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Column 1 is "General News," short items. Markets in column 4.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.02.23.06">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.02.23.07">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.02.23.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Constitution and By-Laws of the Young Mens Christian Association of
                    Chambersburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Constitution and Bylaws of newly formed YMCA.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
