<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1859/pa.fr.vs.1859.04.20">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/21/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1859-04-20">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day>20</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.04.20.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>An Address Delivered Before the Teacher's Association of Franklin County, at
                    Chambersburg, November 19th 1858</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Respectfully submitted by H. Omwake</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Omwake</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Address delivered before county Teacher's Association on "Professional
                    Intercourse Among Teachers." Suggests that the association improve teaching
                    through teaching each other.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Accident on the Chambersburg Turnpike</head>
                <origin>Bedford Gazette</origin>
                <excerpt>"Mr. Barnhart's own escape is a matter to be wondered at. Just as the
                    timbers began to crack and sink beneath his team, he stepped from the portion of
                    the bridge that went down. He had been walking with the two front horses (which
                    escaped by the breaking of the coupling chain) and thus was saved from the
                    perilous fall which otherwise would have awaited him."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--On Saturday last, as Mr. Samuel Barnhart, of this place, was driving his
                        six horse road team over the bridge at the "Narrows," a short distance below
                        town, the flooring and supporting timbers of the bridge, gave way, and the
                        wagon and four of the horses attached to it, dropped through into the stream
                        beneath! The depth of the water underneath the bridg, is estimated to have
                        been from twelve ot fifteen feet. The wagon was loadened, principally, with
                        flour, the weight of the whole load being about 100 cwt. A Considerable
                        quantity of the flour was lost and some of the remainder damaged so as to
                        render its sale of no advantage to the owner. The four horses that went
                        through the bridge with the wagon, were saved, which seems miraculous,
                        indeed, when we think of the height they fell (some 25 feet) and the danger
                        of the entanglement in the harness and wagon gears, in the deep water into
                        which they were plunged. Mr. Barnhart's own escape is a matter to be
                        wondered at. Just as the timbers began to crack and sink beneath his team,
                        he stepped from the portion of the bridge that went down. He had been
                        walking with the two front horses (which escaped by the breaking of the
                        coupling chain) and thus was saved from the perilous fall which otherwise
                        would have awaited him. Take it all in all, this accident was most
                        extraordinary.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Bedford Gazette</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnhart</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Barnhart's wagon and team were involved in an accident when the bridge they
                    were crossing collapsed.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/april59.html#4.20a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>An Unworthy Hero</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"--It appears that Dan Webster, the alleged fugitive slave, who was carried
                    about Philadelphia like a conquering hero by the negroes and abolitionists of
                    that staid city, after his discharge from custody, is no better than he should
                    be--in short, a very unworthy object of the sympathy of moral and law-loving
                    people, white or colored."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--It appears that Dan Webster, the alleged fugitive slave, who was carried
                        about Philadelphia like a conquering hero by the negroes and abolitionists
                        of that staid city, after his discharge from custody, is no better than he
                        should be--in short, a very unworthy object of the sympathy of moral and
                        law-loving people, white or colored. The <emph rend="italic">North
                        American</emph> lets us into a little secret connected with Dan's domestic
                        life, which wonderfully detracts from the romance with which his over-
                        zealous friends surrounded him:</p>
                    <p>"A fact has transpired in relation to Daniel which, if before made public,
                        would have somewhat lessened the sympathy felt for him. It is that, when he
                        absconded or escaped from Virginia, he left behind him a wife to whom he was
                        married by a minister of the Gospel. As he was married to another female in
                        Harrisburg, it follows that Daniel was guilty of bigamy. Had he been
                        remanded by the Commissioner, Mr. Brewster's intent was to have given,
                        towards purchasing his freedom, the fee received from the claimants, and a
                        hundred dollars in addition. We understand that one of the colored witnesses
                        has since acknowledged that he knew, at the time he swore to the contrary,
                        that Daniel was an escaped slave, and that the District Attorney is now
                        considering whether or not to cause his arrest on a charge of perjury."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Takes issue with favorable press that allged Fugitive slave Dan Webster has
                    been receiving in Philadelphia. Accuses Webster of bigamy, possible perjury.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/april59.html#4.20f</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.04.20.02">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.04.20.03">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.04.20.04">
            <pageNote>Sickles trial</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.04.20.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Court Week</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--The trials before Court last week were generally of a very unimportant
                        character. Negro fights and petty assault and battery cases, made up the
                        bulk of the business. The Judge was "down upon" the nuisance, but Grand
                        Juries <emph rend="italic">won't</emph> ignore bills, and "Squires <emph
                            rend="italic">will</emph> make costs, let his honor grumble as he may.
                        We proposed some time ago to have our Court House, during court week,
                        indited as a nuisance. We think it would not be difficult to make out as
                        strong a complaint against it as against "Toad Island." the negroes of that
                            "<emph rend="italic">nuisance</emph>," and other similar localities
                        about town, regularly take possession of our Court House each session to
                        have their drunken fights fought over again and fixed up <emph rend="italic"
                            >according to law!</emph> How ridiculous. Now, in the name of the people
                        of this county, we call upon his Honor Judge Kimmel to put a stop to this
                        wasteful expenditure of the time and money of its citizens, or make a public
                        example of those who encourage this <emph rend="italic">very low
                        business</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmel</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Trials before court week of "unimportant character," especially "negro
                    fights" and petty crime. Complaint that these fights, drunkenness, and other
                    crimes take up too much court time and taxpayer money.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/april59.html#4.20b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Directors</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wier</ln>
                        <fn>J.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewster</ln>
                        <fn>G.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>A.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dull</ln>
                        <fn>J.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mason</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zieger</ln>
                        <fn>G.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingard</ln>
                        <fn>A.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>C.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McMaster</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Board of directors of Franklin Railroad</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Sudden Death</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sellenberger</ln>
                        <fn>Phillip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died suddenly, at age 32. Tanker sect preacher.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Sudden Death</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cunningham</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died suddenly in his store on 04/13.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Admitted</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchell</ln>
                        <fn>J.A.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Young men admitted to the local bar.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Toad Island</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"--The Grand Jury, at the present term of Court, reported the buildings
                    erected on "Toads Island" by Nicholas Uglow, to be a public nuisance."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--The Grand Jury, at the present term of Court, reported the buildings
                        erected on "Toads Island" by Nicholas Uglow, to be a public nuisance. The
                        matter was given over into the hands of the Prosecuting Att'y who will "put
                        it through" to the satisfaction of Court, Jury, and the "rest of
                    mankind."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Uglow</ln>
                        <fn>Nicholas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Uglow's buildings on Toads Island, the free black neighborhood, were
                    declared a public nuisance.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/april59.html#4.20c</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A Good Idea</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"It is the intention, we understand, in future, to devote our entire term
                    of Court for the special purpose of trying the filthy cases among the colored
                    population of our county. This will afford them time to gather together as many
                    cases as will occupy the Court and ??, and also to crowd our pretty Court House
                    with a crowd of drunken, worthless darkies who can ornament the building by
                    poking their heads out of the windows, standing around in every hall and corner,
                    and squirting tobacco juice on the passers by. While this arrangement is being
                    made it is also intended to give notice to the public that J. L. Doehart has the
                    best, cheapest and prettiest stock Hats, Caps &amp;c, this side of
                    Philadelphia. Just give him a call and ask. "</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--It is the intention, we understand, in future, to devote our entire term of
                        Court for the special purpose of trying the filthy cases among the colored
                        population of our county. This will afford them time to gather together as
                        many cases as will occupy the Court and time; and also to crowd our petty
                        Court House with a crowd of drunken, worthless darkies, who can ornament the
                        building by poking their heads out of the windows, standing around in every
                        hole and corner, and squirting tobacco juice on the passers by. While this
                        arrangement is being made it is also intended to give notice to the public
                        that J. L. Dechert has the best, cheapest and prettiest stock of Hats, Caps,
                        &amp;c, this side of Philadelphia. Just give him a call and see.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>See transcript for entire text.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/april59.html#4.20d</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings-April Term, 1859</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mater</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parker</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Little</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ramsey</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Minnich</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houser</ln>
                        <fn>Shearer</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blane</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>Catherine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parker</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nave</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Little</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCracken</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hastings</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harlagher</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Straley</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kobbler</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harnenlaben</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Varner</ln>
                        <fn>Johnston</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pensel</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rock</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rock</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rock</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Francis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dick</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winture</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wisebrenner</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wall</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Court proceedings, by case. Includes counsel for prosecution and
                defense.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>For the Valley Spirit</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt> "We would merely, through the medium of your paper, <emph rend="italic"
                        >suggest</emph> to the present owners of the F. R. R. to examine this
                    point--give us a bridge and thereby protect the traveling public from meeting
                    with a terrible Railroad accident and, as all must admit, save the destruction
                    of human life." </excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>MR. EDITOR:--Much has been said during the past winter in regard to relaying
                        and putting into running order the long neglected "Franklin Railroad."
                        Scarcely a number of your excellent and widely circulated paper has appeared
                        but what contained an article or short notice in regard to it, either for
                        meetings of the citizens, or stockholder, or from agents for materials for
                        its reconstruction. This is as it should be; and too much praise cannot well
                        be bestowed upon the citizens of Greencastle and vicinity, and the north and
                        south western portions of the county for the indefatigable seal and
                        commendable liberality displayed by them. The road had been sold, and the
                        subject of refitting it several times agitated; but has as often failed. At
                        present, it is to be hoped that we shall soon have it as a "reality." The
                        road evidently must and will be a decided advantage to the citizens residing
                        between Chambersburg and Hagerstown. We wish them a hearty success, and to
                        the present stockholders a profitable investment.</p>
                    <p>The design of this communication is to call the attention of the present
                        owners of the said road to the deep cut where their road crosses the public
                        road leading from Chambersburg to Waynesboro'. It must be self evident to
                        even a casual observer (for it takes no eagle eye to discern it) that,
                        crossing the F. R. R., at this point is fraught with imminent danger to the
                        traveler when once the "Iron Horse" is put on the track. There is a vast
                        amount of travel done on this road second to no similar road in the County.
                        It is the only highway leading from the southern part of our County, so
                        densely populated as the Townships of Washington, Quincy, &amp;c., to
                        our County seat--the place for the shipment of their produce for the Eastern
                        markets. Now we do think, in all candor, that the F. R. R. at this point
                            <emph rend="italic">should be bridged</emph>. All persons in the least
                        acquainted with said place, do admit that a bridge at this point is of
                        indisputable necessity. The cut is so <emph rend="italic">deep</emph>, that
                        persons coming <emph rend="italic">from</emph> Chambersburg are unable to
                        see a train of Cars coming <emph rend="italic">in</emph>, and persons coming
                            <emph rend="italic">towards</emph> Chambersburg are unable to see a
                        train of Cars coming <emph rend="italic">out</emph>. And so steep that when
                        once in the cut with a team of Horses, or Carriage, escape is utterly
                        impossible. The cut is sufficiently deep, (14 or 16 feet from where the
                        original bed of the Waynesboro' Road crossed the hill) when bridged to be
                        high enough to enable a flue of a first class Locomotive to pass through.</p>
                    <p>Then the people crossing would be up 14 or 16 feet instead of in a narrow
                        cut, only 10 or 12 feet wide, <emph rend="italic">and on the track</emph>.</p>
                    <p>The truth of the matter is it should have been attended to in Jasper E.
                        Brady's time, when Robert Yates was the original contractor for the
                        construction of this part of the road, <emph rend="italic">and when
                            shinplasters were as plenty as the leaves of Autumn</emph>. At that time
                        it would have cost the original Company but a mere trifle, before digging
                        the deep narrow ravine through which the people are now compelled to travel.</p>
                    <p>Much has been done by high authority to prevent railroad catastrophies. We
                        would merely, through the medium of your paper, <emph rend="italic"
                        >suggest</emph> to the present owners of the F. R. R. to examine this
                        point--give us a bridge and thereby protect the traveling public from
                        meeting with a terrible Railroad accident and, as all must admit, save the
                        destruction of human life. This seems to be an imperative duty.</p>
                    <p>GUILFORD.</p>
                    <p>NEW FRANKLIN, April 8th, 1859.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Guilford.; New Franklin April 8th, 1859</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brady</ln>
                        <fn>Jasper</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yates</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter about the refurbishment of long-neglected Franklin Railroad,
                    specifically the crossing with Chambersburg/Waynesboro road.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/april59.html#4.20e</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rorso</ln>
                        <fn>P.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Housum</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maxwell</ln>
                        <fn>Lydia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on 04/12</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/april59.html#4.20g</note>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Col. 1 has announcements of tax collection. Humorous note: "'Antrim folks'
                will have a very pleasant opportunity to fork over their taxes. . . ." Markets in
                col. 5.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.04.20.06">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.04.20.07">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.04.20.08">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
