<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1859/pa.fr.vs.1859.12.14">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1859-12-14">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day>14</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.12.14.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Truth About Helper</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report on the character of Hinton R. Helper, from a North Carolina Senator.
                    Illegible at the bottom.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Literature and Book Notices</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.12.14.02">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.12.14.03">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.12.14.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Helper and His Friends--Their Revolutionary Platform</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"The diabolical institution (slavery) subsists on its own flesh. At one
                    time children are sold to procure food for the parents; at another, parents are
                    sold to procure food for the children. Within its pestilential atmosphere
                    nothing succeeds; progress and prosperity are unknown; initiation and
                    slothfulness ensue; everything becomes dull and unprofitable; wretchedness and
                    desolation stand or lie in bold relief throughout the land; an aspect of most
                    melancholy inactivity and dilapidation broods over every city and town;
                    ignorance and prejudice sit enthroned over the minds of the people; usurping
                    despots wield the sceptre of power; everywhere, and in everything, between
                    Delaware Bay and the Gulf of Mexico, are the multitudinous evils of slavery
                    apparent."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mr. Helper <emph rend="italic">alias</emph> Heifer, a native of North
                        Carolina, who some years ago, left his State for his State's good, published
                        a book in which he expressed the following sentiments:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">"No man can be a true patriot without first becoming an
                            Abolitionist</emph>."</p>
                    <p>"Henceforth, sirs, we are demandants, not suppliants. We demand our rights--
                        nothing more, nothing less. <emph rend="italic">It is for you to decide
                            whether we are to have justice peaceably or by violence; for, whatever
                            consequences may follow, we are determined to have it one way or the
                            other</emph>.",</p>
                    <p>"The diabolical institution (slavery) subsists on its own flesh. At one time
                        children are sold to procure food for the parents; at another, parents are
                        sold to procure food for the children. Within its pestilential atmosphere
                        nothing succeeds; progress and prosperity are unknown; initiation and
                        slothfulness ensue; everything becomes dull and unprofitable; wretchedness
                        and desolation stand or lie in bold relief throughout the land; an aspect of
                        most melancholy inactivity and dilapidation broods over every city and town;
                        ignorance and prejudice sit enthroned over the minds of the people; usurping
                        despots wield the sceptre of power; everywhere, and in everything, between
                        Delaware Bay and the Gulf of Mexico, are the multitudinous evils of slavery
                        apparent.</p>
                    <p>"Inscribed on the banner which we herewith unfurl to the world, with the full
                        and fixed determination to stand by it or die by it, unless one of more
                        virtuous efficacy shall be presented, are the mottoes which, in substance,
                        embody the principles, as we conceive, that should govern us in our
                        patriotic warfare against the most subtle and insidious foe that ever
                        menaced the inalienable rights and liberties and dearest interests of
                        America."</p>
                    <p>"1. Thorough organization and independent political action on the part of the
                        non-slaveholding whites of the South.</p>
                    <p>2. Ineligibility of pro-slavery slaveholders; never another vote to any one
                        who advocates retention and perpetuation of human slavery.</p>
                    <p>3. No co-operation with pro-slavery politicians; no fellowship with them in
                        religion; no affiliation with them in society.</p>
                    <p>4. No patronage to pro-slavery merchants; no guest-ship in slave-waiting
                        hotels; no fees to pro-slavery lawyers; no employment to pro-slavery
                        physicians; no audience to pro-slavery parsons.</p>
                    <p>5. No more hiring of slaves by non-slaveholders.</p>
                    <p>6. Abrupt discontinuance of subscription to pro-slavery newspapers."</p>
                    <p>This book, containing the above extracts, recommending treason and
                        insurrection, the abolition by violence of an institution which fifteen
                        sovereign States of the Union approve and maintain, under the express
                        sanction and guarantees of the Constitution; and the excommunication of all
                        who uphold that institution, and their exclusion from social, religious, and
                        business fellowship,--has been openly and emphatically endorsed, and a
                        hundred thousand copies of it circulated by the leaders of the Black
                        Republican party, including sixty-eight members of Congress, whose names we
                        append:</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Schuyler Colfax</cell>
                            <cell>J. E. Farnsworth</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Anson Burlingame</cell>
                            <cell>C. C. Knapp</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Owen Lovejoy</cell>
                            <cell>R. E. Fenton</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Amos P. Granger</cell>
                            <cell>Philemon Bliss</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Edwin B. Morgan</cell>
                            <cell>Mason W. Tappan</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Galusha A. Grow</cell>
                            <cell>Charles Case</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Joshua R. Giddings</cell>
                            <cell>T. Davis, (Iowa)</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Edward Wade</cell>
                            <cell>James Pike</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Calvin C. Chaffee</cell>
                            <cell>Homer E. Boyce</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>William H. Kelsey</cell>
                            <cell>Isaac D. Clawson</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>William A. Howard</cell>
                            <cell>A. S. Murray</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Henry Waldon</cell>
                            <cell>Robert B. Hall</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>JOHN SHERMAN</cell>
                            <cell>Val. B. Horton</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>George W. Palmer</cell>
                            <cell>Freemen H. Morse</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Daniel W. Gooch</cell>
                            <cell>David Kilgore</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Henry L. Dawes</cell>
                            <cell>William Stewart</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Justin S. Morrill</cell>
                            <cell>Samuel R. Curtis</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>I. Washburne, Jr.</cell>
                            <cell>John M. Wood</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>J. A. Bingham</cell>
                            <cell>John M. Parker</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>William Kellogg</cell>
                            <cell>Stephen C. Foster</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>E. B. Washburne</cell>
                            <cell>Charles J. Gilman</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Benjamin Stanton</cell>
                            <cell>Charles B. Hoard</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Edward Dodd</cell>
                            <cell>John Thompson</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>C. B. Thompkins</cell>
                            <cell>J. W. Sherman</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>John Covode</cell>
                            <cell>William D. Brayton</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Cad. C. Washburn</cell>
                            <cell>James Buffinton</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Samuel G. Andrews</cell>
                            <cell>O. B. Matteson</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Abraham B. Olin</cell>
                            <cell>Richard Mott</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Sidnew Dean</cell>
                            <cell>George R. Robbins</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Nathaniel B. Durfee</cell>
                            <cell>E. P. Walton</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Emory B. Pottle</cell>
                            <cell>James Wilson</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>DeWitt C. Leach</cell>
                            <cell>S. A. Purviance</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>John F. Potter</cell>
                            <cell>F. E. Spinner</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>T. Davis, (Mass.)</cell>
                            <cell>S. M. Borroughs.</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Quotes from Impending Crisis on the evils of slavery. The Spirit claims
                    that Helper recommends treason and insurrection. List of Republicans in Congress
                    who support Helper's views.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/dec59.html#12.14a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column/>
                <head>For the Valley Spirit</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>[illegible]</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter that describes abolitionism as profoundly dangerous to the Union.
                    The Democracy is on the side of the Union, unlike the Republicans.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Pottawatomi Creek Massacre</head>
                <origin>Westport (Mo.) Border Star</origin>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report about John Brown's crimes in Kansas.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Execution of the Insurgents</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Further details of the execution of John Brown and his men.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Virginia Legislature: Message of Gov. Wise--The Harper's Ferry Outrage
                    Fully and Freely Discussed</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"Unless the numerical majority will cease to violate the confederate faith,
                    and cease to disturb our peace, to destroy our lives and property, and to
                    deprive us of all protection and redress, under the perverted forms and
                    distorted workings of the Union, we must take up arms. The issue is too
                    essential to be compromised any more.--We cannot stand such insults and outrages
                    as those committed at Harper's Ferry, without suffering what is even worse than
                    the death of our citizens--without suffering dishonor--the death of a State!"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Both Houses of the Legislature of Virginia were organized at Richmond on
                        Monday.</p>
                    <p>The Governor's Message reviews the Harper's Ferry affair at great length. It
                        speaks of the spirit of fanaticism and one idea of Abolitionists, which has
                        seemed to madden whole masses of one entire section of the country; which
                        enters into religion, education, politics, and prayers, courts of justice,
                        and legislatures; which has trained up three generations in moral and social
                        habits of hatred to the masters of African slaves in the United States, but
                        turns not upon slavery elsewhere; which has sent comfort and counsellors,
                        and would have sent rescue, to assassins, robbers, murderers and traitors,
                        whom it has sent to felon's graves. Unless the numerical majority will cease
                        to violate the confederate faith, and cease to disturb our peace, to destroy
                        our lives and property, and to deprive us of all protection and redress,
                        under the perverted forms and distorted workings of the Union, we must take
                        up arms. The issue is too essential to be compromised any more.--We cannot
                        stand such insults and outrages as those committed at Harper's Ferry,
                        without suffering what is even worse than the death of our citizens--without
                        suffering dishonor--the death of a State!</p>
                    <p>'Tis not to be denied that we have many sound and sincere friends in the
                        non-slaveholding States; but the conservative elements are passive, whilst
                        the fanatical are active. The former are fast diminishing, whilst the latter
                        are increasing in number and force.</p>
                    <p>With regard to the insurgents, the message says: 'Tis mockery to call them
                        monomaniacs. The leader himself spurned the plea, and it was not put in upon
                        the trials. They were prompted by the evil spirits of incendiarism, which
                        demoralized numerous hosts behind them who now sympathise with their deeds
                        before the world. These men hired them--even to madness--and that John Brown
                        despised the hypocritical cant of their pretenses that he was insane. The
                        execution of our laws was necessary to warn future victims not again to be
                        tools of this sympathy. We have friends or we have not, in the States whence
                        these invaders came. They must now be not only conservative, but active, to
                        prevent invaders coming. It was impossible for so much sympathy to exist
                        without exciting bad men to action of rescue or revenge. On this reasoning
                        he acted.</p>
                    <p>He had been compelled by the apprehension of a most unparalleled border war
                        to place the State in as full a panoply of military defense as if a foreign
                        enemy had invaded the United States. Indeed, one of the most irritating
                        features of this predatory war is, that it has its seat in the British
                        provinces, which furnish asylums to our fugitives and send them and their
                        hired outlaws upon us, from depots and rendiavous [sic] in bordering States.
                        There is no danger from our State of colored people. The slaves taken
                        refused to take arms, and the first killed was a respectable free negro
                        while running from the "philanthropists" who came to liberate the black
                        race.</p>
                    <p>In closing the message the Governor says: We must rely upon ourselves and
                        fight for peace-- we must organize and arm--we must demand of each State
                        what position she means to maintain in the future with respect to slavery,
                        and provisional constitutions, the laws of the United States, and the
                        provisions of our State laws for its protection in our federal relations,
                        and to be governed according to the manner in which the demand is answered.
                        We are in arms!</p>
                    <p>With regard to the reports and rumors of organized conspiracies, the Governor
                        says they were from so many sources, so simultaneous, or far apart, from
                        persons so unlike in evidences of education, they could be from no
                        conspiracy to hoax. But he relied not so much upon them as upon the earnest,
                        continued and general appeal of the sympathisers with the crimes of the
                        insurgents.</p>
                    <p>Let us defend our own positions or yield it at once, or let us have action
                        and resolve on a definite settlement. No more temporizing the
                        Constitution--no more compromise.</p>
                    <p>The other convicts await execution. They will be executed, unless the General
                        Assembly orders otherwise. This will meet the open invasion, but acts only
                        on the individual convicts and does not settle the question of our peace and
                        protection in the future.</p>
                    <p>It remains only for me to offer myself--all that I am and all that I have, to
                        the Commonwealth, whenever she may order me or mine in her service, when the
                        term of my present office closes.</p>
                    <p>The second message makes detailed recommendations and alludes to State
                        matters generally.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report from the Virginia legislature on Gov. Wise's annual message and on
                    Harper's Ferry. Virginia feels that it is somewhat under siege from Northern
                    states.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/dec59.html#12.14b</note>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Congressional report.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.12.14.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Editorial Deserts</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praise for editors and the good work that they do for their
                parties.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Sudden Death</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"Mrs. John Senger, of Washington township, in this county, while witnessing
                    the immersion of her son-in-law, at a Tunker Meeting held recently up the
                    Falling Spring was attacked by apoplexy and died within a few hours after."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>At Work in Earnest</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gitt</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Gitt has been engaged as a surveyor for the new railroad to run from
                    Gettysburg to Waynesboro.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Change</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonner</ln>
                        <fn>B.E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCreary</ln>
                        <fn>I.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Bonner has retired from the Franklin Ledger.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Perpetuity of the Union</head>
                <origin>Baltimore Daily Exchange</origin>
                <commentary>"We commend to conservative sentiments catalogued in your following
                    article, which a current thinking friend furnished us, copied from the Baltimore
                    Daily Exchange and desires its republication to shame the schemers and fanatics
                    who preach up dissolution of the Union."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Original title = The Citizens of Richmond. Anger about the Tribune's
                    favorable coverage of Brown. Also complains about Emerson and Beecher. Stresses
                    dangers to the Union.</summary>
                <note>In Browser</note>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn>Kealon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clugston</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolfinger</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on December 9.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn>E.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunsaker</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kaufman</ln>
                        <fn>Amanda</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on December 1.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn>E.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lesher</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn>Barbara</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on December 8.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn>E.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Canaday</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Goshert</ln>
                        <fn>Mariah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married "some time ago."</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Markets in column 5.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.12.14.06">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.12.14.07">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.12.14.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Woman's Appeal on Behalf of the Union and the Constitution</head>
                <origin>Morning Pennsylvanian</origin>
                <excerpt>"The fanatics of the North have now entirely thrown off the thin mask they
                    have hitherto worn, and openly proclaim their determination to free the slaves
                    by any means and any sacrifice to the South."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Though I am no advocate of "Women's Rights," save in their appropriate
                        sphere, by the domestic hearth, and in the <emph rend="italic">home</emph>
                        department yet I would ask from you a brief space in your paper, that as a
                            <emph rend="italic">wife</emph> and <emph rend="italic">mother,</emph>
                        and, therefore, holding a large stake in the welfare of our country, I may
                        make an appeal to the hearts of those who for political purposes are
                        striving to exasperate the sectional prejudices of the people; and who, for
                        the gratification of a paltry ambition, and in the much abused name of <emph
                            rend="italic">liberty</emph> and <emph rend="italic">religion,</emph>
                        are willing to sever the fraternal bonds of our confederacy, and plunge our
                        peaceful and happy country into the horrors of civil war. I am no
                        politician--no missionary with strength and courage to attempt the Quixotic
                        enterprise of reforming society and redressing wrongs, but I have never
                        turned away where woman's true ministry was needed, nor hardened my heart
                        against the cry of the poor and oppressed; if I believed that freedom would
                        be a blessing to the race of slaves at the South, I should be a most
                        strenuous advocate for <emph rend="italic">general</emph> emancipation; but
                        believing, as I do from my inmost soul, that it would be a <emph
                            rend="italic">curse,</emph> whose blighting influence would be felt
                        alike by masters and slaves, I feel irresistibly impelled to protest against
                        it, though the "still small voice" of my appeal may be lost and unheeded
                        amid the wild warfare of political passion. The fanatics of the North have
                        now entirely thrown off the thin mask they have hitherto worn, and openly
                        proclaim their determination to free the slaves by any means and any
                        sacrifice to the South. They would turn loose on their white brethren a
                        horde of ignorant and ferocious savages, who, freed from all restraints, and
                        owning no law save that of their own unbridled passions, would soon convert
                        the smiling and prosperous homes of the South into waste and barren deserts.
                        A war of races, when once commenced, <emph rend="italic">must be</emph> one
                        of extermination, nor would the conflict cease until one or the other was
                        utterly destroyed. But granting that this is an extreme view to take of the
                        case, still the result of emancipation could not be otherwise than ruinous
                        to the South, because only by <emph rend="italic">slave labor</emph> can the
                        culture of the great staples of the Southern States be carried on to
                        advantage. The experiment has been tried in the British West Indies, and the
                        result has been alike disastrous to slave and master; the negro is
                        inherently idle and improvident, he will not work to-day that he may have
                        food for to-morrow, he would far rather bask in the sunshine and let the
                        future provide for itself. Were the North therefore sufficiently strong to
                        use coercion, and bestow immediate freedom on the slaves, it needs no
                        prophetic fire to predict the result. Perfectly intoxicated with their
                        liberty, they would construe it into a right to pass their time either in
                        sleep or lawless revelry, the majority of them would refuse to work for any
                        wages, the rich soil of the South would be an uncultivated waste, and where
                        peace and smiling plenty formerly reigned, would be seen nought but
                        desolation and despair. The lure held out to the laboring classes in the
                        North, to secure the election of the Republican party is, that slave labor
                        once disposed with will render wages higher and work more scarce, an
                        invention truly worthy of the "Father of Lies." No white man could stand the
                        burning sun which is to the swarthy sons of Africa but a genial heat; and to
                        persons not thoroughly acclimated it is almost certain death to breathe the
                        pestilential atmosphere of the rice fields.--But even if white labor could
                        be made equally available, and the planters not be entirely ruined by the
                        freedom of their slaves, how is it intended to dispose of these millions of
                        our sable brethren, so suddenly made their own masters? Do the Christian
                        philanthropists at the North advocate their being sent back to Africa, there
                        to relapse into heathenism--or was it Captain Brown's intention to take them
                        off in a body to the far West, and form a new settlement on utopian
                        principles, where freedom would be allowed a thorough and practical
                        development? No political economist has yet advanced an idea on the subject
                        of the disposition of the slaves when once liberated, and it is one which
                        might indeed afford matter for grave and anxious debate.--But this question
                        it is not my present purpose to discuss. I merely state the difficulty which
                        I would be glad to have satisfactorily answered. My wish now is to prove, if
                        possible, that the majority of the slaves are happier and more contented in
                        their present position than they would be if the ill-advised plans for their
                        benefit could be carried into effect by their self-called friends. The North
                        does not understand the slave system, which, as it exists at the South is a
                        Patriarchal form of government, and <emph rend="italic">love,</emph> not
                            <emph rend="italic">fear,</emph> is generally the ruling principle. The
                        would-be philanthropists, who expend so much sentiment on the sufferings of
                        the slaves, we find no language strong enough to execrate the cruelly of
                        their masters, should look on both sides of the question and qualify
                        themselves to form a <emph rend="italic">just</emph> opinion before they
                        attempt to influence others. Let them take a calm dispassionate view of the
                        subject, and they will find, perhaps, that the sympathy expended on their
                        sable brethren would find a more legitimate field among the laboring classes
                        at the North. The slaves are well fed and clothed. The interest of their
                        owners requires that they should be so. Should sickness occur they have good
                        medical attendance, and are carefully nursed, and when old age incapacitates
                        them from labor, they are taken care of for the sake of former services,
                        until death closes the scenes. How is it with the <emph rend="italic">white
                            slaves</emph> at the North? Go to one of the large factories where the
                        staple of the South is wrought into cloth; do you consider the operatives
                        who toil from morn till night, in an unwholesome atmosphere, and amid the
                        noisy din of machinery, more free and happy than the Southern slaves? So
                        long as the white laborer has health and strength to work, he can obtain
                        needful food and clothing, but when disabled by sickness or accident, are
                        his wages continued by his benevolent master? By no means; with his
                        usefulness ends all claim upon his employer. When helpless with old age or
                        disease, he is thrown upon [his] own resources, and humanity shudders to
                            <emph rend="italic">think</emph> of the sufferings which are only <emph
                            rend="italic">known</emph> to the All-seeing eye of God! We employ our
                        domestics at the North so long only as they are useful to us; when they
                        become sick or infirm we do not consider ourselves pledged to support them;
                        on the contrary, we believe that we are fully justified in replacing them
                        with more efficient help; with their after fate we have no concern. While
                        they were with us we paid for their services and there our responsibility
                        ended. How different it is in Southern families. The domestics about the
                        house are considered in the light of <emph rend="italic">humble
                        friends,</emph> rather than <emph rend="italic">slaves,</emph> and in
                        sickness and old age are sure of kindness and a comfortable support. I spent
                        last winter on a sugar plantation in Louisiana where I had every opportunity
                        of forming an opinion of the institution of slavery as it exists at the
                        South, and but for the want of <emph rend="italic">freedom,</emph> which in
                        their case is but an empty name, I consider their situation infinitely
                        preferable to that of the laboring classes at the North.--There was no
                        attempt to bias my judgement in the matter, nor were the family whose guest
                        I was, placed under any constraint by the idea that there was "a chiel among
                        them takin' notes." We rarely conversed on sectional topics, and it seemed
                        to be forgotten that I was not really one of themselves. The slaves appeared
                        to me happy and contented, and there was certainly every provision made for
                        their comfort which a kind and considerate master could suggest. I walked
                        around the fields where they were at work, and not a single instance of
                        cruelty or oppression ever came to my knowledge [text missing] of all <emph
                            rend="italic">extra work</emph> performed by the slaves, writing down on
                        paper the amounts due, which they presented on Christmas Eve to the master,
                        who, seated at a table with a pile of silver and gold before him liquidated
                        the claims as they were handed in. Old and young were assembled in a body,
                        and none seemed to go away empty or dissatisfied. During the holiday week
                        the annual ball and supper, given to the slaves at the master's expense,
                        took place,--music, dancing and feasting continued until a late hour next
                        morning, and a scene of more perfect enjoyment it would be difficult to find
                        anywhere on earth than existed among these artless children of nature. Nor
                        are they debarred from <emph rend="italic">religious</emph> instruction, as
                        many seem to think. On Sunday afternoon, the lady of the mansion assembled
                        all who <emph rend="italic">chose</emph> to come-- for there was no
                        compulsion,--read to them in the Scriptures, taught them the "Belief" and
                        the Lord's Prayer, and closed the exercises by repeating a hymn which they
                        delighted to sing. Such is slavery at the South--the institution which
                        fanaticism is moving must share a common ruin should fanatics [text appears
                        to be missing] and is involved in that of the South, and that both not to
                        perceive how much of her own prosperity [text appears to be missing]
                        short-sighted, so blind to her own interest as heaven and earth to destroy.
                        Is the North so unscrupulous politicians prevail against justice and right.
                        The South has never been the <emph rend="italic">aggressor</emph> in this
                        sectional warfare, nor seemed disposed to retaliate on the North, the
                        injuries and insults which have been heaped upon her; on the contrary the
                        magnanimous forbearance of her sons has truly proved that</p>
                    <p>"Forgivness [sic] to the <emph rend="italic">injured</emph> doth belong,
                        <lb/>They never pardon who <emph rend="italic">commit</emph> the wrong."</p>
                    <p>But there is a limit beyond which patience ceases to be a virtue. When that
                        is reached, and it cannot now be far distant, farewell to the peace and
                        prosperity of our country! But is there no conservative party--no "forlorn
                        hope"--to step into the breach and save the Union in this hour of desperate
                        peril? Is there no one to fill the place of Henry Clay in the sublime and
                        blessed office of <emph rend="italic">Peace-maker</emph>--to say to the
                        North and to the South, "Ye are brethren, do not wrong and defame each
                        other; your ancestors fought side by side in defense of one common
                        country--do not raise your fratricidal hands against kindred breasts, nor
                        seek to destroy the noble edifice cemented by the blood of your sires?" To
                        such an appeal let all true patriots respond with heart and hand, and
                        rallying around the standard of the Constitution never cease their efforts
                        until our noble confederacy stands on a firm basis, and "peace and good
                        will" once more unite North and South in the bonds of fraternal
                    fellowship.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Woman appealing on behalf of Union. Begins with caveat that she is not an
                    advocate of women's rights. She argues that the South has not been the aggressor
                    in present conflict. Patience may soon cease to be a virtue. Some pro-slavery
                    argument stuff.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/dec59.html#12.14c</note>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
