<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1859/pa.fr.vs.1859.07.06">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1859-07-06">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="06">6</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.07.06.01">
            <pageNote>Entire page is the text of a speech made by J. Jackson of Georgia in House of
                Representatives about slavery in the territories.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.07.06.02">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.07.06.03">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.07.06.04">
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Address of the State Committee</head>
                <origin>Pennsylvanian</origin>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Spirit publishes the address of the Democratic State Central Committee and
                    praises it highly. Describes crisis of opposition to the party. Address is in
                    columns 3-6.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.07.06.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Hagerstown Trial</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"To the Manny machine we award the meed of excellence as the best Mower.
                    Judging from the width of the cut, and the facility with which the cutting bar
                    can be raised or lowered, whilst in motion, we think it entitled to all claimed
                    for it as a mower."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--At a trial of Reapers and Mowers, at Hagerstown, on the 23d inst., the
                        Manny Machine made its cut in grain of six feet, with a draft of 380 lbs.,
                        while the Whitenack made a cut of 4 ft., 6 inches and drew 350 lbs. In the
                        trial at mowing, the Committee says:</p>
                    <p>"To the Manny machine we award the meed of excellence as the best Mower.
                        Judging from the width of the cut, and the facility with which the cutting
                        bar can be raised or lowered, whilst in motion, we think it entitled to all
                        claimed for it as a mower."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Manny Machine wins at a contest held in Hagerstown.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/july59.html#7.6d</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Robbery</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanderow</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Smith was arrested for trying to rob Vanderow's house, near
                Waynesboro.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Fourth</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"The Sunday Schools, with the exception of the Lutheran and Presbyterian,
                    had their usual pic-nics, and the small fry their accustomed amount of
                    jolification."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--The Eighty-Third Anniversary of our National Independence passed off, in
                        this place, very quietly, and without any demonstration of a general
                        character.</p>
                    <p>The Sunday Schools, with the exception of the Lutheran and Presbyterian, had
                        their usual pic-nics, and the small fry their accustomed amount of
                        jolification.</p>
                    <p>The German Reformed School celebrated in Lehmans Woods and under the
                        excellent arrangement of their Committee, of which Mr. Mathew Gillan was
                        chairman, every thing was done up in admirable style. The Declaration of
                        Independence was read by Wm. Heyser Esq., and eloquent and patriotic
                        addresses delivered by Chas. G. Fisher, Geo. Stenger and Rev. Bauseman. At
                        this celebration all passed off very pleasantly and the children seemed to
                        enjoy themselves in a happy and delightful manner.</p>
                    <p>The Methodist School held their jolification in Shetters Woods, where they
                        passed the day in pleasant and agreeable festivity. This celebration was
                        largely attended by the children of other schools and by our citizens old
                        and young generally. The Declaration was read in a very happy manner by Clay
                        McCauley, and Hon. Wilson Reilly, I. H. McCauley and W. S. Everett Esqrs.
                        made respectively, very able and appropriate addresses, which were well
                        received and added much to the pleasures of the occasion.</p>
                    <p>Our Band spent the day, by invitation, at Caledonia Springs, and had a gay
                        old time of it all round.</p>
                    <p>Our fine military company were out in full feather and done up some excellent
                        firing. We never saw them look, march, or drill, better.</p>
                    <p>In the evening we had Fire works and a Balloon ascension in the Diamond.</p>
                    <p>We believe the day passed off to the satisfaction of all concerned and
                        without an accident or unpleasant occurrence to mar it's enjoyment.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillam</ln>
                        <fn>Matthew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heyser</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foster</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bauseman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn>Clay</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn>I.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>W.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Celebration of the 4th of July. Described as passing very quietly, with
                    Sunday School picnics, a band, and military companies.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/july59.html#7.6a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Major General</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elections held for officers of 15th Division of Penna. Uniformed Militia.
                    Franklin Co. voted for Walker of Fannettsburg.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Death of an Old Citizen</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blood</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Blood, a former teacher in county schools, died on July 3.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Smash Up</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"--On Sunday last a large frame building, erected on Toad Island, as a
                    brick shed, was blown down and the material of which it was composed smashed up
                    into very convenient firewood. The delectable inhabitants of the island took
                    advantage of the disaster and their chimnies were soon observed to smoke as they
                    had seldom smoked before."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--On Sunday last a large frame building, erected on Toad Island, as a brick
                        shed, was blown down and the material of which it was composed smashed up
                        into very convenient firewood. The delectable inhabitants of the island took
                        advantage of the disaster and their chimnies were soon observed to smoke as
                        they had seldom smoked before.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Shack blown down on Toad Island. Article contains sarcastic comments about
                    "delectable" (i.e. free black) inhabitants.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/july59.html#7.6c</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Pic Nic</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"We were much pleased with the lady-like deportment of the pupils under
                    care of Mr. Reeves. There were no romps or tom boys in the crowd which speaks
                    well for the discipline introduced in this institution."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--On Saturday morning last the pupils, in the advanced classes, attached to
                        the to the Female Seminary of the Rev. Mr. Reeves, of this place, were
                        permitted through the kindness of Mr. Dull, the gentlemanly Superintendent
                        of the Franklin Railroad, to take a jaunt, of about six miles, in a
                        passenger car, over the finished portion of the road. The car was generously
                        tendered for the occasion by Col. O. N. Lull of the Cumberland Valley Road,
                        and the whole train under charge of that able and careful engineer Mr. Jacob
                        Switzer. We would like to say something in praise of the <emph rend="italic"
                            >pro tem</emph> "conductor" of the train--the Ajax of the <emph
                            rend="italic">Transcript</emph>--but then our vocabulary of eulogistic
                        terms is not ample enough to reach him.--Let expressive silence &amp;c.
                        We, through his munificence, occupied the distinguished and pecuniary
                        comfortable position of a "dead head."</p>
                    <p>The scholars, with Mr. Reeves and his assistant teachers, left the cars at
                        Heagy's woods, a spot admirably adapted for rural enjoyment, where they
                        spent the day very pleasantly in rambling through the groves, partaking of
                        the good things provided for the occasion, games, speeches &amp;c. In
                        the evening they returned to town by a car specially sent out to convey them
                        home, all expressing themselves highly delighted with their excursion, and
                        no doubt much benefited by the agreeable recreation. We were much pleased
                        with the lady-like deportment of the pupils under care of Mr. Reeves. There
                        were no romps or tom boys in the crowd which speaks well for the discipline
                        introduced in this institution. We are gratified to announce the fact that
                        this school is now in a most flourishing condition, and that under the
                        excellent management of its present accomplished and gentlemanly Principal
                        it has attained a degree of popularity and prosperity which is spoken of by
                        all in terms of merited and high commendation.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reeves</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dull</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lull</ln>
                        <fn>O.N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The advanced students at the Female Seminary took a six-mile trip on the
                    new Franklin Railroad and then picnicked in the woods. The Spirit was pleased
                    with their ladylike deportment.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/july59.html#7.6b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>At a Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>Jno.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>Sam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Board of Directors of the Chambersburg School District passed
                    resolutions honoring David Robinson.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Chambersburg Academy</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shyrock</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frey</ln>
                        <fn>B.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Praises performance of students and teachers at school
                examination.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Emrick</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hammon</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married at German Reform Parsonage on July 3.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>Stephen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>B.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Stephen, age 13, died of apoplexy on June 28.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sample</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sample</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs Sample, age 45, died on July 1; her son , age 17 on July 2.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hiffelman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Age 78 years, died on June 22.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Age 2, died on July 2.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Markets in column 3. Page includes a report from Kansas Constitutional
                convention.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.07.06.06">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.07.06.07">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.07.06.08">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
