<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1859/pa.fr.vs.1859.02.16">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Will Thomas</taggerName>
            <tagDate>1/29/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>3rd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1859-02-16">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="00"/>
            <day norm="00"/>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.02.16.01">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.02.16.02">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.02.16.03">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.02.16.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Support The Government</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"Pennsylvania is not asking for a tariff for protection, but simply that
                    she may receive the benefits which a necessary tariff will confer upon her. She
                    has the right to ask for this, and more, from her Southern brethren; she might
                    well ask them to strain a point in her behalf were she so inclined, for she has
                    never faltered or fallen back when the compromises of the Constitution were in
                    danger, or her sacred rights were assailed."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Remarks that Congress has not passed any public legislation in its first
                    2/3 session. Article covers the issues of the tariff, appropriations, public
                    expenditures. Expresses resentment toward the South's stance on the tariff,
                    arguing that, unlike the South, Pennsylvania has asked for special treatment
                    from the law.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Have We a Democratic Party Among Us?</head>
                <origin>Buffalo Post</origin>
                <commentary>"This question is promptly and well answered in the following paragraph
                    which we clip from the Buffalo Post."</commentary>
                <excerpt>"Surviving the ignominy heaped upon it by incompetent and designing men--
                    outliving the assaults of open enemies and secret foes--the Democratic party
                    will in 1860 take the field under the banner of its time honored principles,
                    and, despite the howlings of its adversaries, it will again achieve victory."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"Some of the blatant Opposition and falsehearted Democratic presses of the
                        country are tickling their readers by propounding the above interrogatory.
                        Children are said to be pleased with a straw, even, and so we suppose we
                        ought not to deprive the Opposition of the meagre crumbs of comfort afforded
                        them in this innocent pastime. They will find out when the ballot boxes are
                        closed in 1860, that there <emph rend="italic">is</emph> a Democratic party
                        among us, and a successful one, too. The glorious past history of this
                        country is but a record of the triumphs of the Democratic party. It has
                        already controlled the Government of the United States three fourths of the
                        time during its existence, and we venture the prediction that it will
                        continue to do so.-- Surviving the ignominy heaped upon it by incompetent
                        and designing men-- outliving the assaults of open enemies and secret
                        foes--the Democratic party will in 1860 take the field under the banner of
                        its time honored principles, and, despite the howlings of its adversaries,
                        it will again achieve victory."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article asks, "Does the Democratic party still exist?" And answers,
                    emphatically, "yes," and suggests that the 1860 election will prove it.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/feb59.html#2.16a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.02.16.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Franklin Railroad Company</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weir</ln>
                        <fn>J.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>A.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zeigler</ln>
                        <fn>G.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cooke</ln>
                        <fn>Jay</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McMaster</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>G.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dull</ln>
                        <fn>J.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mason</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weagard</ln>
                        <fn>A.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>C.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>A.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fahnstock</ln>
                        <fn>H.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Election of Franklin Railroad Company board of directors for
                1859.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Row</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"Considerable of a muss was kicked up on the Diamond "all of a sudden" on
                    Monday night, by a negro boy hitting a white man with a stone, and breaking a
                    glass in the large bulk window of Shryock &amp; Co's Book Store."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--Considerable of a muss was kicked up on the Diamond "all of a sudden" on
                        Monday night, by a negro boy hitting a white man with a stone, and breaking
                        a glass in the large bulk window of Shryock &amp; Co's Book Store. A
                        crowd of excited men and boys, too numerous to compute, gave chase to the
                        negro and after a pretty long run succeeded in capturing him. He was taken
                        before 'Squire Hammon, when bail was entered for his appearance to answer
                        the charge.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Halimon</ln>
                        <fn>Squire</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article reports that a "Negro boy" was arrested purportedly after throwing
                    a rock and starting a fight with a white man at a store in town.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/feb59.html#2.16b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Fire at the Poor House</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"About 12 o'clock on Saturday night last, the large barn at the County Poor
                    House was discovered to be on fire, and so rapidly did the flames spread that
                    everything contained in it, except two colts, was consumed. Eight farm horses,
                    seventeen head of fat cattle and cows, about one hundred and fifty bushels of
                    wheat, which had been put in bags ready for removal to the mill, several wagons,
                    and nearly all the farming implements belonging to the farm were consumed."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--About 12 o'clock on Saturday night last, the large barn at the County Poor
                        House was discovered to be on fire, and so rapidly did the flames spread
                        that everything contained in it, except two colts, was consumed. Eight farm
                        horses, seventeen head of fat cattle and cows, about one hundred and fifty
                        bushels of wheat, which had been put in bags ready for removal to the mill,
                        several wagons, and nearly all the farming implements belonging to the farm
                        were consumed. The loss to the county by this fire will exceed $5,000. . .
                        .[text missing]. . . upon a worthless scoundrel who has, at times, been an
                        inmate of the institution, and has frequently threatened to burn down the
                        buildings. We hope the guilty wretch may be discovered, and punished as his
                        crime deserves.</p>
                    <p>Since writing the above three men, paupers at the institution, have been
                        arrested and sent to jail, charged with having set fire to the barn.</p>
                    <p>The following is a list of the property destroyed, as nearly as can be
                        ascertained by the Directors and Steward:</p>
                    <p>8 horses valued at $1,200 00</p>
                    <p>6 sets wagon and 6 sets plow gears, 125 00</p>
                    <p>12 head of fat cattle, 600 00</p>
                    <p>5 head of stock cattle, 100 00</p>
                    <p>8 head of sheep, 32 00</p>
                    <p>125 bushels of wheat, 156 25</p>
                    <p>300 bushels of corn, 198 00</p>
                    <p>1 wagon, 75 00</p>
                    <p>Horse Power and Thrashing Machine, 125 00</p>
                    <p>6 shovel plows, 30 00</p>
                    <p>1 set of hay ladders, 12 00</p>
                    <p>Barn furniture, 200 00</p>
                    <p>50 tons hay, 500 00</p>
                    <p>Straw, 100 00</p>
                    <p>2 ox yokes, 6 00</p>
                    <p>Barn, wagon shed, horse power shed, &amp;c., &amp;c., 1,800 00</p>
                    <p>Total loss, $5,338 25</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Carlisle Democrat</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Fire at the county Poor House destroyed more than $5,000 worth of property.
                    Three paupers arrested and charged with setting the fire. Includes an itemized
                    list of property destroyed.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/feb59.html#2.16c</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>W.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Decmert</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seides</ln>
                        <fn>Helen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Jacob Decmert married Miss Helen Seides on February 15 at Evangelical
                    Lutheran Church.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rodrock</ln>
                        <fn>W.D.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bushman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clugston</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. John Bushman married Miss Mary Clugston on February 10 at Eastern
                    Hotel.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sill</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lambs</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Alexander Lambs married Miss Rebecca Anderson on February 3.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>L.N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rieder</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marrs</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marrs</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. David Rieder married Miss Martha Marrs, daughter of Mr. Joseph Marrs,
                    on January 27.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>L.N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>Judge</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Robert Johnston married Miss Martha Orr, daughter of Judge Orr, on
                    February 3.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keller</ln>
                        <fn>Anna M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on November 30, in Guilford, age 79.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Martha, age 36, died at Alto Dale on February 9.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Book Notes. Markets in col. 4.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.02.16.06">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.02.16.07">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.02.16.08">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
