<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1859/pa.fr.vs.1859.10.12">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1859-10-12">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day>12</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.10.12.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Come Out And Vote</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"If we poll as many votes next week as we did in 1856, we shall triumph. We
                    ought to be able to do this. There is just one thing that stands in our way, and
                    that is the disposition sometimes shown by some of our friends, to stay at home
                    and let the election take care of itself. Here and there a Democrat is found
                    saying to himself, 'Well, I believe I won't go to the election to-day--my vote
                    won't make much difference anyway.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We again urge upon every member of our party the importance of attending the
                        election. We were beaten in this county last fall, not because we had not
                        strength enough to have carried our ticket, but because several hundred of
                        our voters stayed at home. If we had polled the same vote we pulled in 1856,
                        our whole ticket would have been elected. If we poll as many votes next week
                        as we did in 1856, we shall triumph. We ought to be able to do this. There
                        is just one thing that stands in our way, and that is the disposition
                        sometimes shown by some of our friends, to stay at home and let the election
                        take care of itself. Here and there a Democrat is found saying to himself,
                        "Well, I believe I won't go to the election to-day--my vote won't make much
                        difference anyway." Now this may do where there is a Democratic majority of
                        several thousand, though even there every man ought to turn out, especially
                        when there is a State ticket in the field. But no Democrat should talk and
                        act thus in a close county like ours. As we remarked last week, five votes
                        lost by staying at home in each election district will make a loss of over
                        one hundred in the county. Parties being nearly balanced here, we need our
                        whole vote. We can not afford to let many of our voters stay at home. It is
                        all nonsense for a man to stay away because he thinks "one vote won't make
                        much difference." If everybody did so, there would be no votes cast at all.
                        It is the <emph rend="italic">ones</emph> that make the <emph rend="italic"
                            >hundreds</emph>, and the <emph rend="italic">hundreds</emph> that make
                        the <emph rend="italic">thousands</emph>.</p>
                    <p>Our friends understand this as well as we do, but we have thought it our duty
                        to remind them of it. The fault will not be ours if we are not successful.
                        Those who stay at home, under the mistaken notion that their votes are of
                        little account, will be to blame if we are not victorious. To all we say
                        again, <emph rend="italic">turn out and vote</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An article urging Franklin voters to come to the polls.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/oct59.html#10.12a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>One Vote</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"Democrats of Franklin! Let us have no tie votes. Let us have no opposition
                    candidate elected by a majority of three. Let us have a full turn out and a
                    clean victory. Do not stay at home, or you will be sorry for it."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At the Congressional elections in Kentucky last August, there was a tie vote
                        in one of the districts. If just <emph rend="italic">one</emph> more
                        Democratic voter had come out, the Democratic candidate would have been
                        elected.</p>
                    <p>In another Congressional district, the opposition candidate was elected by a
                        majority of <emph rend="italic">three</emph>. There are plenty of Democrats
                        in that district who now see how foolish it was for them to stay away from
                        the polls.</p>
                    <p>Democrats of Franklin! Let us have no tie votes. Let us have no opposition
                        candidate elected by a majority of three. Let us have a full turn out and a
                        clean victory. Do not stay at home, or you will be sorry for it. <emph
                            rend="italic">Every man of you come out, and then every man on your
                            ticket will be elected</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Another article urging Frankin voters to come to the polls.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/oct59.html#10.12b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Column 1 is in German. Seems to be saying that the Democratic party is good,
                and the Republicans are not. Other political articles on this page as well,
                including a report on the California elections. Also reports from Adams County in
                columns 5-6.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.10.12.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>TRUTH WILL OUT</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article about the canal swindles. Seems to be the same as in October 5
                    issue on page 1.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>This page is mostly political.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.10.12.03">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.10.12.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Danger to the Union</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Opposition is "sneering" at dangers to Union. Union cannot endure in
                    present climate of Northern hostility to the South. Blames Republicans for
                    antagonizing Southerners.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Last Dodge--Bogus Tickets</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt>"Mr. DAVID LAREG was furnished with a horse and buggy and posted off on
                    Saturday forenoon up the Loudon pike, to carry these bogus tickets to various
                    districts. No doubt he took a good bundle of them to BILLY McGRATH, who would
                    like to cheat his way into the Sheriff's office."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Republican managers in this borough had a large number of bogus tickets
                        printed on Saturday last, for distribution among unsuspecting Democrats,
                        whom they are intended to deceive. These tickets all contain the names of
                        Col. McCLURE and GEORGE EYSTER. Most of them have McGRATH on for Sheriff;
                        but a few, which will be distributed in this town by a bogus Democrat,
                        contain the name of Mr. LEONARD YEAGER, a respectable citizen, who is not a
                        candidate, in place of the name of JACOB SELLERS. The ticket with Mr.
                        YEAGER'S name on is intended to cheat German Democratic voters.</p>
                    <p>Mr. DAVID LAREG was furnished with a horse and buggy and posted off on
                        Saturday forenoon up the Loudon pike, to carry these bogus tickets to
                        various districts. No doubt he took a good bundle of them to BILLY McGRATH,
                        who would like to cheat his way into the Sheriff's office.</p>
                    <p>The Republican managers are concentrating their efforts on McCLURE, EYSTER
                        and McGRATH. They are making a sacrifice of their Assemblymen, their
                        Treasurer, their Commissioner, their Director and their Auditor, to elect
                        the three named above. Even their State ticket is sunk out of sight.
                        Everything is made to give way to McCLURE, EYSTER and McGRATH. The blood of
                        half a dozen slaughtered Republican candidates will be upon the head of
                        these men.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yeager</ln>
                        <fn>Leonard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sellers</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lareg</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn>Billy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Claims that the Republicans printed up bogus ticket to distribute to
                    Democrats. They hoped these would confuse voters, especially the Germans.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/oct59.html#10.12c</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Lots of politics, digs at the Transcript especially.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.10.12.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Our Ticket</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Goes through the entire Democratic ticket, by office.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Of Orrstown, age 63, on October 4.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>List of Causes for Trial</head>
                <origin/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerr</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingart</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Simpson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keyser</ln>
                        <fn>N.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McNulty</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foreman</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>N.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolfe</ln>
                        <fn>G.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christ</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>Jno.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carlisle</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seibert</ln>
                        <fn>Phillip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lancaster</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Aston</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Short</ln>
                        <fn>W.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oaks</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strock</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Disert</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rupert</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pearon</ln>
                        <fn>N.P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noel</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ehrerer</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rinehart</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rinehart</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spice</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kirkpatrick</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eckman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seibert</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finley</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>Johann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stark</ln>
                        <fn>Isabelle</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sidre</ln>
                        <fn>Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sidre</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gainer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutton</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutton</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christy</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Criswell</ln>
                        <fn>A.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>J. and H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLellan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hurst</ln>
                        <fn>A.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Monn</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Monn</ln>
                        <fn>Conrad</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barber</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ashe</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neuman</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hammond</ln>
                        <fn>Phillip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moshery</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevenson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Francis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Windham</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn>L.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McOurney</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marsourd</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurshner</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weld</ln>
                        <fn>G.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Landig</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finley</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>How</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rice</ln>
                        <fn>P.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>List of cases coming to trial at October court.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Column 6 has list of Grand and Traverse jurors for October Court.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.10.12.06">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.10.12.07">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.vs.1859.10.12.08">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
