<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0303"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A0303">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: James B. McCutchan to His Cousin,
                    July 27, 1862</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county james b mccutchan to his cousin, july 27 1862</title>
        <author>McCutchan, James B. </author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A0303</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501811</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta : James B. McCutchan to his Cousin, July 27, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta james b mccutchan to his cousin, july 27 1862</title>
            <author>James B. McCutchan</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Rockbridge Historical Society
                            Collection, Special Collections, Leyburn Library, Washington and Lee
                            University, Lexington, Virginia.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Special Collections, James G. Leyburn Library, Washington and Lee University</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-07-27">1862-07-27</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties, Family, Home
                        Front, Military Authority, Prisons/Prisoners, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A0303T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>McCutchan's letter talks about his bad cold, the new preacher in camp, and refers
                    to several friends and family members. The letter also makes reference to the
                    fact that he has been charged with informing on his cousin, James R. McCutchan,
                    but the details are not made clear.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-07-27">July 27 1862</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Near Gordonsville</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Cousin</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>This is Sunday and I don't know how I can <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> myself more pleasantly
                    than in writing you a short letter, although I don't feel much in a humor of
                    writing or doing anything else, I have a bad cold sore throat and headache, we
                    had a short march yesterday left camp about 5 o'clock marched to Gordonsville a
                    distance of 5 miles stayed there until nearly sundown then marched back to camp.
                    we marched very fast for a while and got very warm and it rained on us before we
                    got to camp. I got very wet and lying on the damp ground all night is what gave
                    me such a cold. I don't think I have had the cold as bad for six months. The
                    company is <orig reg="generally">generly</orig> well some few are complaining.
                    We have a very nice camp here in a beautiful grove. The Brigade is all together,
                    have very good water for Eastern <abbr expan="Virginia">V<hi rend="super"
                        >a</hi>.</abbr> We have a very good chaplain now, have preaching every
                    Sunday and prayer meeting every night, Warden is his name, he is a very nice man
                    and a good preacher. I met with <unclear>Mr.</unclear> Wheat at the spring
                    today, would not have known <pb n="2"/> him but heard him remark to another man
                    that was with him that Lizzie was well and that Mrs. Buchanan is dead. I found
                    out from that that he was from your neighborhood. I then made some <orig
                        reg="inquiries">enquiries</orig> about your mother, and found out who he
                    was. Cousin Lizzies boy or yours I don't know which I was slightly acquainted
                    with last winter. I had forgotten him. You said in your last letter that you had
                    a message for me from an old acquaintance. I am very anxious to know who and
                    what it was. I intend to have gone up to your neighborhood when I was at home
                    but could not make it suit and so many of your <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> was sick, I hope
                    you will excuse me. I also hope you all have gotten well ere this. I suppose you
                    are well and healthy by this time. I was surprised to see that you had grown so
                    much but it had been some time since I had seen you. I would have liked very
                    much to have had a chat with you but <orig reg="circumstances"
                    >sircumstances</orig> would not permit. I might have gone to see you that
                    evening but I am sorry to tell you that I was not there when I was at home nor
                    did have any desire to go. I was charged with things that I am <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <orig reg="innocent">innosent</orig> of. I am sorry that it is so, but as <pb
                        n="3"/> it is so it may remain so far as I am <orig reg="concerned"
                        >conserned</orig> I shant trouble myself about it. I will tell you what it
                    was. I was charged with informing on Ja's R which is entirely false. I did not
                    write a letter to any one in the company while I was at home. I will drop it,
                    will not be pleasant to you and I am <orig reg="sure">shure</orig> it is not to
                    me. I am sorry I did not comply with your wishes about kissing cousin Sue that
                    is <orig reg="surely">shurely</orig> a <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> pleasant task. She is a
                    particular friend of mine I had some nice times with her when I was at home. Oh!
                    I wish this war was over so we all could return to our homes in peace. I think
                    we will know how to appreciate it if it is ever <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> it, which time
                    I hope is not far distant. I will stop writing for the evening, probably will
                    write some more in the morning if nothing happens to <unclear>prevent</unclear>
                    it. I stopped wishing <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> and went to preaching, heard as often did <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> and
                    heard a <orig reg="prayer">prear</orig> from from <abbr expan="General"
                    >Gen'</abbr> Jackson which was <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> as good as I ever heard. I do
                    think this is the best man I ever saw. how thankful we should be that he have
                    such a General <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> is a <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> character.</p>

                <p><pb n="4"/>I must bring my letter to a close <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> this very poor
                    letter and answer soon. Direct to Gordonville. Give my love to all inquiring
                    friends if there be any, receive a good portion for yourself.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your true and Aff cousin</salute>
                    <signed>Ja's B. McCutchan</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">[in recipient's handwriting] Received <lb/> Saw Jim Buck
                        last July 12, 1862 <lb/> George Baylor was killed near <lb/>Gordonsville
                        August 9th 1862 <lb/> Jonnie Kerr died August 11th 1865 <del hand="h1"
                    /></seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
