<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0315"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A0315">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: James H. Skinner to "Mr. Editor",
                    February 17, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county james h skinner to mr editor , february 17 1863</title>
        <author>Skinner, James H.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Sarah Richardson</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 8</num> kilobytes </extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va.</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">A0315</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1998">1998 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501823</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: James H. Skinner to "Mr. Editor", February 17, 1863.</title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county james h skinner to mr editor , february 17 1863</title>
            <author>James H. Skinner </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Photocopy from the collection of Fredericksburg-
                            Spotsylvania County Battlefields National Memorial Military Park,
                            Fredericksburg, Virginia.</p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Fredericksburg and Spotsylvania National Battlefield Park</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-02-17">1863-02-17 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Home Front </term>
                    <term>Regiment: 62nd Va. Inf. </term>
                    <term>Company: none </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp> </resp>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="A0315T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Lieutenant Colonel Skinner of the 62nd Va. writes to the citizens of Staunton
                    thanking them for their support and asking them for more supplies. </p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Mr. Editor</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-02-17">Feb. 17, 1863</date>
                        <name type="place">62nd Va. Inf. Headquarters</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Mr. Editor - </salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Permit me to acknowledge in your column the receipt of <unclear>article</unclear>
                    of clothing, sent to this regiment by Mr. Albert <unclear>G.</unclear> Garber of
                    donation for the Soldiers from Augusta. The bale included 12 pairs of socks, 12
                    pairs of pants, 8 blankets, 2 overcoats, 2 pair of shoes, and sundry articles of
                    underclothing; all of which have been appropriately distributed, and have proved
                    most acceptable. </p>
                <p>The earnest patriotism of our county has been touchingly displayed in the
                    generous aid she has extended to her soldiers in the field, and their families
                    at home. These deeds of noble sympathy are eloquent in their encouragement, and
                    warm the hearts while they shield the bodies of her sons. It gives me sincere
                    pleasure to express, for the regiment, this grateful appreciation of this and
                    other similar acts of kindness. </p>
                <p>I will be pardoned for adding, that the exertions of our people on the behalf of
                    the soldiers should suffer no relaxation: The supplies of clothing furnished by
                    the government are not sufficient to secure the comfort of the army -- The
                    regiment, in the matter of blankets and overcoats, in now quite well off, though
                    a few of the men are yet without overcoats. Of socks, they have a good supply at
                    present; and they may be said, in general, to be for the time very well clothed.
                    They lack, however, in a good many instances, proper underclothing, and I find
                    an increasing demand for pants. The want of shoes is that most felt. At least 70
                    pair are now requested for the comfort of the regiment. - The government has
                    lately furnished - for the lack of leather no doubt - canvas shoes. The soles
                    are good, and they would answer very admirably for summer wear, but it will
                    readily appear how insufficient they must be at this season. I venture on those
                    statements for the benefit of those who will gladly receive any hint, however
                    trivial, which may serve as a guide to their good purposes. </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully, </salute>
                    <signed>Jas. H. Skinner </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
