<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0327"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A0327">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: P.H. Powers to his wife, May 17,
                    1864</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county p h powers to his wife, may 17 1864</title>
        <author>Powers, P. H.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>David Samuel Freed </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 8</num> kilobytes </extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">A0327</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2 </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1998">1998 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501835</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note>
                    <p>This transcription was made from a photocopy.</p>
                </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: P.H. Powers to his wife, May 17, 1864</title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county p h powers to his wife, may 17 1864</title>
            <author>P. H. Powers</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source Copy Consulted: Photocopy from the collection of Fredericksburg-
                            Spotsylvania County Battlefields National Memorial Military Park,
                            Fredericksburg, Virginia.</p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Fredericksburg and Spotsylvania National Battlefield Park</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-05-17">1864-05-17 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Military Strategy, Death/Casualties, Military Authority, Troop Movement,
                        Family, Home Front </term>
                    <term>Regiment: 1st Va. Cav. </term>
                    <term>Company: none </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp> </resp>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="A0327T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Powers shares his disgust at the sight of Union dead left uncared for near
                    Fredericksburg and suggests that U.S. General Grant cares little about his
                men.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Wife</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-05-17">Tuesday May 17 1864 </date>
                        <name type="place">Near Spottsylvania CH</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Wife, </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I write hurriedly to send by a courier just going off. We have had no fighting of
                    any importance since last Thursday. Of which I have written you. The weather
                    continues wet and the mud unfathomiable. You may imagine our discomfort. Sunday
                    the enemy shifted his position, moving near to the Fredericksburg RR. And in the
                    evening I rode over deserted lines and positions of the battle field. A more
                    awful sight never met my eyes. The enemy's dead were lying thick as they had
                    fallen three days before, in every stage of <unclear>corruption</unclear>. They
                    had made no effort to bury hundreds of them. Grant cares not for his men. That
                    is evident from the the way he fights them. And his barbarism in leaving his
                    dead and many of his wounded on the field. Our army is now said to be nearly
                    equal to his. And all seem confident that of final success over him. I pray that
                    it may be so, but since the loss of our beloved General, I confess that I feel
                    unusually despondent. It is natural I reckon. Allowing associations in the war,
                    our informality connected with Gen. Stuart. In times of gloom and danger, his
                    cheering voice and his hopeful smile have always inferred hope and courage on
                    those around him. We miss him sadly, but in his own courage "God's will be
                    done". All is right. Our military family is broken up and scattered. And no
                    corps commander has been appointed yet. Who will take command? I am unable to
                    conjecture. I rejoice that you are not in Richmond during these troubles-</p>

                <p>We rarely get papers now and know not what is going on there. Doubtless you are
                    as well informed even of our own army as I am. As it is almost impossible to get
                    correct information <unclear>lost in the sea</unclear> of the army. A thousand
                    conflicting rumors are circulated. At one time Grant is retreating across the
                    river. And the next moment advancing towards Richmond. My own impression is
                    another and decisive battle will be fought in this vicinity. We have official
                    intelligence of Seigel's <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>in the Valley.</p>

                <p>Of myself I am glad to say I am better in health, if not better in spirit.</p>

                <p>Direct your letters care Maj. <unclear>N.R.</unclear> FitzHugh HQrs Cav Corps
                    through Genl. Lee's Hqrs. Love to all-</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours </salute>
                    <signed>P.H. Powers </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
