<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0326"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A0326">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: P. H. Powers to His Wife, May 15, 1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county p h powers to his wife, may 15 1864</title>
        <author>Powers, P. H.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Peter Brownfeld </name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A0326</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501834</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Phillip H. Powers to His Wife, May 15, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county phillip h powers to his wife, may 15 1864</title>
            <author>P. H. Powers</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>3 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Photocopy from the collection of
       Fredericksburg-Spotsylvania County Battlefields National Memorial Military Park,
       Fredericksburg, Virginia.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>Several lines are cut off from this copy. This is signifed by "...".</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Fredericksburg and Spotsylvania National Battlefield Park</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1864-05-15">1864-05-15</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Death/Casualties</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A0326T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Powers reports on the death of General Stuart, Powers' best friend in the army.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head> 
     U.S. Sanitary Commission 
     <name type="recipient">Wife</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1864-05-15">Sunday May 15, 1864</date>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Dear Wife -</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>The Sabbath moon opens upon us sadly this morning, and with a heart depressed with a dark and
     bitter grief I long to commune with some heart which can sympathize with me - We heard
     yesterday of the death of our noble leader, Genl. Stuart. And the sad news has thrown a gloom
     upon us all. Since the death of the lamented Jackson, no event, no disaster has so affected me.
     Jackson was a great loss to his country and the cause. Genl. Stuart is a great loss to his
     country - but to us, who have been intimately associated with him - to me in particular, his
     loss is irreparable for in him, I have lost my best friend in the army. I cannot realize that
     he is <hi rend="underline">gone</hi>. that I am to see his gallant figure or hear his cheering
     voice no more - "God's will be done." A great man has fallen, and his faults are now <orig
      reg="swallowed">swalled</orig> up and forgotten in the recollection of his eminent virtues -
     his glorious valor and patriotism. May God in His mercy comfort his poor widow! My heart
     sorrows for her as for one very near to me- </p>
    <pb n="2"/>

    <p>The corps organization of the Cavalry is suspended for the present. The personal staff being
     assigned temporarily to the different Cavalry division. Our <abbr expan="Quarter Master"
     >Q.M.</abbr> Department <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> as it is <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> for the present. </p>

    <p>The two armies here still confront each other in line of battle though there has been no
     serious engagements since Thursday when Genl. Johnson's division was repelled and himself and
     many of his men captured the position and some of the artillery was recovered but not the
     provisions. Though in the same day we repulsed every other attack.</p>

    <p>It has been raining for three days and you can hardly imagine how uncomfortable lying in the
     mud and wet every day. Fortunately my neuralgia attack has been worn itself out and affects me
     but very slightly though I am worn out and wearied in mind with continued <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>. Oh
     if it could all end, and <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> ... have been in lines of battle exposed to all the
     inclemency of the weather first the insufferable heat and now the drenching rains - And yet
     they stand and fight-</p>

    <p>And the wounded and the maimed and the dying lie around on that cold wet ground. No <del
      hand="h1"/>
     <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
     <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> to minister to their wounds and the<pb n="3"/> last breath is caught by the
     passing and no listening ear of affection<del rend="none" hand="h1"/> the sound. How long will a merciful
     God persist this war? - And with want of <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> that <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> from <del
      hand="h1"/> never cease.</p>

    <p>Imboden has repulsed the enemy in the Valley and driven them to the the Potomac. All other
     army news you can learn from the papers much better than I can. I saw Brother James yesterday.
     He <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> will. I cannot hear of Harty. I have written you repeatedly <del hand="h1"
     /> our moves, but fear the letters will hardly reach you. I read yours of the 6th <del
      hand="h1"/> Have <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> to the care of <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
     <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> Hugh Chf. <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> Cav Corps. And I am rejoiced that during all this
     turmoil and excitement in Richmond, you are in a place so far removed from this scene of
     danger. And hope you are getting along comfortably. Love to the children and kisses for the
     babes. Tell Kate <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
     <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
     <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
     <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> name of Stuart. As to <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>but speaks of <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> fame and
      <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>honor. </p>

    <p> God be with you my good wife.</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Ever Yours</salute>
     <signed>P.H. Powers</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
