<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0322"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A0322">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: P. H. Powers to Mrs. Powers, March 17, 1863</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county p h powers to mrs powers, march 17 1863</title>
        <author>Powers, P.H.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A0322</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501830</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: P. H. Powers to Mrs. Powers, March 17, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county p h powers to mrs powers, march 17 1863</title>
            <author>P.H. Powers</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: P.H. Powers Letters, Fredericksburg National
       Battlefield.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>Several lines are cut off from this copy. This is signifed by "...".</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Fredericksburg and Spotsylvania National Battlefield Park</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1863-03-17">1863-03-17</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Battle Description, Camp Life, Family, Home Front</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A0322T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Powers discusses camp life and missing his family.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Mrs. Powers</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1863-03-17">March 17th, 1863</date>
      <name type="place">Camp near Fredericksburg</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Dearest Wife</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>Nearly a month has elapsed since I last wrote,. And every day since I have hoped to get some
     tidings of you. But alas, not a word, not a line can i receive, until the heart has indeed
     become sick with a long deferred hope. I should feel this more sensibly, but that everyone that
     I have seen in the Army from Clarke or Jefferson, they hear from home from time to time. And as
     no bad tidings of you come through this source, I argue that you are at least as well off as
     your neighbors. Still, it is a source of uneasing anxiety and uneasiness that i cannot hear
     from you personally. i know my love it is no fault of yours and fully appreciate your
     dependence upon <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>, who either cannot or do not know what it is to be separated
     for months from wife and children, and confined to the monotony of a camp in winter quarters.
     If you would put your letters in the hands of those having friends in the Clarke Cavalry, they
     could be sent out, and then mailed to Richmond. harry Bird told me he heard from hi s family
     repeatedly in that way. And Mr. <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> frequently gets <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> out. One of
     the Randolphs went home a few weeks ago. <sic>Staid</sic> two days ...</p>
    <p> of the County. I would attempt <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>, in myself, but Milroy is represented as
     being such a tyrant, that I should fear the consequences of falling into his hands just at this
     time. </p>
    <p> I must wait and bear. Sometimes I regret not having brought you away with me. Though how
     could you have subsisted at the present price of everything. God only knows. A Major's pay
     would not pay your board. Flour sells <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> for $35 per <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> Bacon
     $1.25. Beef $1 &amp; everything in like proportion. I sincerely trust that you are not
     molested by the Yankees and are enabled to provide yourself with such comforts as you need. If
     there are any goods in the County do not fail to lay in a supply for me. Such as flannel, cloth
     for pants-coat-Hat-etc. And get <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> or <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> to make me a good <del
      hand="h1"/> of Books. Store them away. Events will very probably enable me to get home before
     many months. They say we must have a fight here in a few weeks, and then, perhaps we may clear
     the Valley once more. It is evident that the war will rage this spring with greater fury than
     ever. May God enable our Armies to successfully resist the hordes of Vandals now being thrown
     against us! If we can only hold out this campaign. All will be well days ago. Whither he had
     gone to Lake Ellen-then having been in Richmond several weeks. I regret to have to tell you
     that her health has failed to such an extent that reason has been dethroned. And she is <del
      hand="h1"/> by this time at the Asylum, under Dr. Wribling's treatment. Poor Jim! He returned
     perfectly miserable. He never apprehended such a sad <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> from her continued bad
     health. And was of course shocked, beyond degree at her mental aberration. Doubtless her case
     has been aggravated by long and continued separation from him. Let us pray and <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
     that she may be speedily restored. </p>
    <p> I had intended leaving him as soon as he returned and joining the Cavalry, but I could not
     leave him under such a trial and <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> to remain during this month, provided the
     Conscript Officers permitted me. As I am not regularly enrolled and they have been looking at
     all Regiment Officers of late. And enrolling them in the ranks. When I do leave here, I shall
     attach myself to Gen. Stuart again and serve in the P.n. in some capacity. I can't stand the
     ranks. And besides, from some staff officers. </p>
    <p>All were well in Richmond when last heard from. Mildred has another son. </p>
    <p> With most love to all and many Caresses for my little children Whom I am longing to have in
     my arms <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> more. I am, my own beloved wife.</p>
    <closer>
     <salute>As Ever <lb/> Yours</salute>
     <signed>P.H.P.</signed>
     <seg type="postscript"><abbr expan="Dear">Dr</abbr> Sister-I send you my letter to read
       <sic>altho</sic> it has been written so long that it affords me but little satisfaction. I am
      still in all the doubt &amp; uncertainty about <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> present position and
      whereabouts If I had not the <hi rend="underline"> strong hope </hi> that our army <del
       hand="h1"/> coming in to keep me up I don't know what I should do. I hope <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
      <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> mine satisfactory. I am deeply grieved to hear of poor Ellies situation
      &amp; feel for Ben James. That usually is one of the <hi rend="underline">greatest </hi>
      trials a man can be <hi rend="underline">called </hi> upon to endure. Write to me sometimes.
      Betsey is better. The Dr. thinks she will get well. Send this to Sister C.<lb/>Yours <name
       type="recipient">PMP</name>
     </seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
