<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0331"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A0331">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Adam Wise Kersh to George P. Kersh,
                    October 14, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county adam wise kersh to george p kersh, october 14 1862</title>
        <author>Kersh, Adam Wise </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Matthew Kelly </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 9</num> kilobytes </extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">A0331</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2 </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1998">1998 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501839</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>

            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Adam Wise Kersh to George P. Kersh, October 14, 1862</title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county adam wise kersh to george p kersh, october 14 1862</title>
            <author>Adam Wise Kersh </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Typescript from the collection of Fredericksburg-
                            Spotsylvania County Battlefields National Memorial Military Park,
                            Fredericksburg, Virginia. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from private collection</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-10-14">1862-10-14 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Enlistment, Home Front </term>
                    <term>52nd Va. Inf. </term>
                    <term>F </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp> </resp>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>

    </teiHeader>
    <text id="A0331T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Kersh talks about replacing himself with a substitute soldier and reports on new
                    enlistments arriving in camp.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">George P. Kersh</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-10-14">October 14, 1862 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Bunkershill, Frederick County, VA </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Brother </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I take this opportunity to write you a few lines to let you know that I am well
                    and hope these few lines may find you enjoying the same blessing. I wrote you a
                    few lines on the 4th the day after I arrived. I dont know if you received them
                    or not. I am still in the notion of having a substitute put in if you or Warner
                    can get one. if you or him have not time to attend to getting one you might get
                    some one else to attend to it. We are still in the same old camp that they were
                    when I arrived here. I dont know when we will leave here. we may soon and we may
                    not. Our Camp is 12 miles below Winchester. They say that our Cavalry Pickets
                    are as far as the Potomac and the Yankee Picket are across in Maryland. our boys
                    are not very keen to go back to Maryland. they said it is not very wholesome
                    there. We have no tents now. some have little Yankee tents. The officers all
                    have tents. We build little shanties and cover them with Oil cloth cedar and
                    brush. We are Camped in the Woods. we have plenty of wood. water is little
                    unhandy about half a mile to carry. We have troops Camped all along from here to
                    Winchester and below us a good piece. We get plenty to eat such as it is Bull
                    Beef and bread. Some of the boys are barefooted in our regiment now and their
                    cloths are very dirty and ragged Marching so much. Which makes the confederates
                    very bad. two of our company was wounded in the last fight at Maryland Clint
                    Walker and William Stover not seriously. When I arrived here I found more of the
                    Augusta Reliefs then I expected. we have about forty in our company fit for duty
                    now. </p>
                <p>I suppose the old fifty second numbers about five hundred men now. Conscripts are
                    still coming in. </p>
                <p>I and Frank Arey took a walk to Carpenters Battery last Sunday. We saw Bill Arey
                    George Myers Joe Hawkings and Harve Whitmore. there all well. Front there we
                    went to the fifth regiment. there I saw George Frame David Craun John Sheets
                    some of the Rells and Hansbergers and others. We then went to the tenth and who
                    did meet but Tom Jones and a whole lot of the Bridgewater boys. Tom tried to get
                    in a Cavalry Co. but could not. he is trying to get in some Battery now. he said
                    he saw Rhaney and talked to him about Steve's hat. Chaney said he did not know
                    that Glen had it till they got half way to camp and that he wanted him to take
                    it back. We belong to Earleys Brigade Enells Division. General Jackson's
                    Quarters is about a mile from our Camp. I have not saw him yet. Two men in the
                    forty forth took a notion to fight. they went out side of the guard. One said he
                    was in for fighting fair. the other had his cartridge box on ran up to him and
                    stabbed him twice with bayonet and left. the man he stabbed lived about a day
                    and a half and died. </p>
                <p>As I have nothing worth writing about I will close. Old Jacob Sheets and Phil
                    sheets are ready to leave and I want to send my letter with them. I want you to
                    write to me. direct your letter as you did before except Harman instead of
                    Baldwin. </p>
                <p>I want you to write to me. direct your letter as you did before except Harman
                    instead of Baldwin. </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours Respectfully </salute>
                    <signed>Adam W Kersh </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
