<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0568"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A0568">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: A.M. Chacky to his Brother, February
                    6, 1865</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county a m chacky to his brother, february 6 1865</title>
        <author>Chacky, A.M. </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Murrell </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <idno type="VCDH">A0568</idno>
                <date value="1997">1997</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501865</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note>
                    <p>Archivists have noted that this letter was written from Fishersville, Augusta
                        County, Virginia. </p>
                </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: A.M. Chacky to his Brother, February 6, 1865</title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county a m chacky to his brother, february 6 1865</title>
            <author>A.M. Chacky </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source Copy Consulted: A.M. Chacky Letter, February 6, 1865, (MS 89-007),
                            Civil War Collections, Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic
                            Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Virginia. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1865-02-06">1865-02-06 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Military Authority, State Government</term>
                    <term>Regiment: none </term>
                    <term>Company: </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp> </resp>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees </name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="A0568T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Chacky writes to his brother Ed about fooling a provost guard into letting him on
                    a train to Fishersville. Chacky was a member of Wharton's Division of the Valley
                    Army of Virginia.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Brother</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1865-02-06"><abbr expan="February">Feb.</abbr> 6<hi
                                rend="super">th</hi> 1865 </date>
                        <name type="place">Head Quarters<lb/> Wharton's Division </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear <abbr expan="Brother">Bro</abbr> Ed </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I promised to write to you immediately after arriving at camp but have been
                    pretty busy and have not done so <orig reg="until">untill</orig> the present
                    time. After I left you I went up to the Provost-Marshall's office but found such
                    a crowd then that it was impossible for me to get a pass in time to leave on the
                    train. Consequently I went down to the depot with the the determination in my
                    cranium to "run the block." When a arrived there I found this to be impossible
                    for the guard was too vigilant for me. I then jerked out my letters from <unclear>
                        <orig reg="Ted">Ted</orig>
                    </unclear> Smith directed to <abbr expan="Colonel">Col</abbr> Smith and <abbr
                        expan="General">Gen</abbr> Wharton and marching up to the officer of the
                    guard told him that "here <orig reg="were">was</orig> dispatches from <abbr
                        expan="Governor">Gov.</abbr> Smith that must certainly go up by today's
                    train." He said he could not help it, <hi rend="underline">no</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">one</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">could</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">get</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">on</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">the</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">train</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">without</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">a</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">pass</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">from</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">the</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">Provost</hi>-<abbr expan="Marshall">
                        <hi rend="underline">M.</hi>
                    </abbr> I then thought I <del hand="h1">must</del> would have to <unclear>
                        <orig reg="prolong">prolong</orig>
                    </unclear> my visit in Richmond another day. But just as the cars were about to
                    start, the captain of the guard came to me in company with the officer whom I
                    had solicited to let me pass and asked to see the dispatch which I had to carry.
                    "Certainly said I you can see them." Now in the corner of one was the
                    inscription "Through the kindness of <abbr expan="Major">Maj.</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Breckinridge." (It was the intention of Mr.
                    Smith to send them by <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Breckinridge">B.</abbr> but did not get to do so).<pb n="2"/> This
                    inscription of course <unclear>added substance</unclear> to the subject, and the
                    Captain said if I would bear all responsibility - he would let me pass. And as
                        <del hand="h1">there</del> he did not want to let the guard know anything
                    about the affair he took out his key and let me into the ladies car - there
                    being no entrance at that door. So I had a nice ride in the ladies car the whole
                    way to Fishersville. Did you get off on the Petersburg train or did you have to
                    walk? I felt very sleepy on my way up as I did not go to bed the preceeding
                    night until one oclock. I tell you I made things "<hi rend="underline">
                        <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                        <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    </hi>" with Miss Emma that night. But you do not approve of such things so I
                    will refrain from giving you a description of the affair. We are having a <abbr
                        expan="regular">reg.</abbr> good time here now. Matters have been arranged
                    so we do not have to go to Staunton any more. Another <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> has come
                    in, so we have little or nothing to do. How do you like your <unclear>
                        <orig reg="berth">birth</orig>
                    </unclear> by this time. Have they done anything <hi rend="underline">with</hi>
                    you for staying at home over your time? I am anxious to hear about this and you
                    must write immediately. I have not heard from home since you left. Expect a
                    letter daily. What do you think of Peace by this time? I think that before
                    bright Spring shall unfold her sunny wings the <unclear>land toxin</unclear> of
                    war will have <unclear>peaked</unclear> her clamor and peace and harmony will
                    reign once more in our beloved land. At least this is my hope. Oh! would it not
                    be delightful for us all to be gathered at <hi rend="underline">home</hi> once
                    more and pursue the peaceful avocations of life. You and I would again
                        <unclear>devote</unclear> ourselves to our books and attempt to make
                    ourselves men. You must write soon I will be anxious to hear from you. Tender my
                    respects to Mr. Wirt and others of your mess-mates who may inquire after me. </p>


                <closer>
                    <salute> </salute>
                    <signed>A.M. Chacky </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
