<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0566"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A0566">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: John N. Hull to a Friend, November
                    22, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county john n hull to a friend, november 22 1863</title>
        <author>Hull, John N. </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Murrell </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/ </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <idno type="VCDH">A0566</idno>
                <date value="1997">1997</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501863</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: John N. Hull to a Friend, November 22, 1863</title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county john n hull to a friend, november 22 1863</title>
            <author>John N. Hull </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source Copy Consulted: John N. Hull Letter, November 22, 1863, (MS
                            92-043), American Civil War Collection, Special Collections, Virginia
                            Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Virginia.</p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-11-22">1863-11-22 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Desertion/Leave, Medicine/Hospitals, Troop Movement, Women</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 4th Va. Inf. </term>
                    <term>Company: D </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp> </resp>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item> Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="A0566T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Hull writes to a friend about his desire to leave Winchester. He also mentions a
                    furlough he received on account of his typhoid fever, and talks about how hard
                    it has been for the Confederacy to succeed militarily. Hull was a member of the
                    4th Va.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Friend</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-11-22">Sunday Nov. 22<hi rend="super">d</hi> 1863 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp on the Rapidan Near <orig reg="Orange">Orang</orig>
                            <abbr expan="Courthouse">C.H.</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Friend </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>As I feel quite lonesome this beautiful Sunday morning, My Thoughts <orig
                        reg="wandered">wanded</orig> back to the good Old Times I have spent in
                    Winchester and also in your presence and I thought there would not be any
                    impropriety in dropping you a few lines as I thought you would be glad to hear
                    from me if I am a <unclear>
                        <orig reg="Rebel">Rebel</orig>
                    </unclear> as I believe you are hard on them. Oh<hi rend="super">o</hi> if I
                    could hear that Miss Julie <unclear>Hremer</unclear> was still living when I
                    think of her (and that is often) it seems that it is not Possible that she is
                    dead. some times I think I am <orig reg="dreaming">dreamming</orig>. But Alas it
                    is True Miss Lizzie I have been spending some <del hand="h1">very</del> happy
                    days since I last saw you. I went from Winchester to Staunton and <orig
                        reg="stayed">staid</orig> there in the Hospital a month and I went to my
                    company and did not <pb n="2"/> remain there but a few days when I was taking
                    with the Typhoid fever and got a furlough for 50 days. I just got back. no
                    person ever enjoyed themselves better than I did. It is reported <orig
                        reg="everywhere">every wher</orig> I am engaged to be married. They had a
                    day set. I did not know it <orig reg="until">untill</orig> the time had past. I
                    wish I had of know it sooner I might of not disappointed Them. you know who it
                    is I guess. That Young Lady I was <unclear>
                        <orig reg="corresponding">corresponing</orig>
                    </unclear> with when I was staying with you all. I enjoyed myself very much in
                    her company whilst at home. We took a trip to Richmond while I was at Home. I
                    wish you could of been with us. I often wish I could be at your house. I made My
                    Sisters believe I was engaged to a Miss <orig reg="Dieffendaffer">Dieffendaffer</orig>
                    <orig reg="of">off</orig> Winchester. I just <orig reg="did">done</orig> it to
                    get them to tease me. has Miss Maggey got well and <hi rend="underline">is</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">she</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">married </hi><hi rend="underline">yet</hi>. I guess she is
                    &amp; Miss Camilla &amp; Sallie how are they all also that Good Old
                    Father &amp; Mother <add hand="h1" place="inline">of yours</add> are they
                    well &amp;c<pb n="3"/> give them all my kindest regards. Tell M<hi
                        rend="super">r</hi> Dieffendaffer I hope he will be at Home next time I go
                    to Winchester. M<hi rend="super">r</hi> Williams sends his respects to all I
                    suppose <del hand="h1">he is</del> you are acquainted with him. he claims Miss
                    Maggie as a sweetheart. I am trying to get a transfer to the Calvary in the
                    Valley for I want to see Winchester so bad. We are seeing hard times now.
                    building fortifications along The Rapidan. we are expecting a Battle <orig
                        reg="every">ever</orig> day. our independence is mighty hard to get, but we
                    are not discouraged yet I do not <orig reg="believe">belive</orig> it ever will
                    be settled that is by fighting.</p>

                <p><hi rend="underline">President</hi> Davis reviews our corps tomorrow. I wish he
                    had of <orig reg="stayed">staid</orig> where he belongs for I do hate this
                    inspection. we have been building winter quarters for 2 months but cannot get to
                    stay in them the Yankees got our best <unclear>
                        <orig reg="houses">houses</orig>
                    </unclear>. I wish I was in that fine house beyond Winchester I built. Some mean
                    Yankee is living in it now I expect. <pb n="4"/> If I <orig reg="do  
 not"
                        >donot</orig> get killed in this War I expect to visit old Winchester and
                    hunt me a wife for I have <orig reg="taken">taking</orig> a <orig
                        reg="particular">perticular</orig> favor to the Ladies of that place. all
                    Soldiers speak more of Winchester than any place we ever been at.</p>

                <p>I will bring my badly written letter to a <orig reg="close">clos.</orig> Hoping
                    you will honor me with a letter Tell all of your Sisters to write to me. Give my
                    love to M<hi rend="super">rs</hi> Hremer &amp; <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> and all of
                    my kind friends.</p>

                <p>And much love to you all</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Your True Friend </salute>
                    <signed>John N. Hull </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">Directions <abbr expan="Company">Comp</abbr> "D" 4<hi
                            rend="super">th</hi><abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr> Infantry Stone Wall
                        Brigade Ewell Corps 1<hi rend="super">st</hi> Division <del hand="h1"
                        >A.N.V.</del>
                    </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
