<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0572"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A0572">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: John H. Cochran to His Mother,
                    December 11, 1860</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county john h cochran to his mother, december 11 1860</title>
        <author>Cochran, John H. </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Murrell </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/personal.html </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <idno type="VCDH">A0572</idno>
                <date value="1997">1997</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501869</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: John H. Cochran to His Mother, December 11, 1860</title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county john h cochran to his mother, december 11 1860</title>
            <author>John H. Cochran </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source Copy Consulted: Cochran Family Letters, 1860-1861, (MS 92-032),
                            Civil War Collections, Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic
                            Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Virginia. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1860-12-11">1860-12-11 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, National Government, State Government</term>
                    <term>Regiment: Wise Legion </term>
                    <term>Company: A </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp> </resp>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees </name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="A0572T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Cochran talks about the growing anxiety and uncertainty surrounding South
                    Carolina's threat of secession and evaluates the South's readiness for a war.
                </p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Mother</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1860-12-11"><abbr expan="December">Decr.</abbr> 11<hi
                                rend="super">th</hi> 60 </date>
                        <name type="place">Richmond </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Mother </salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Your letter is received and contents noted. I will come up sometime after <orig
                        reg="Christmas">Christmass</orig> what time I cannot now say but as soon as
                    circumstances will permit. </p>

                <p>The country is now in a fearful state of agitation. So much so that thinking men
                    believe that a war between the sections is <orig reg="imminent">iminent</orig>.
                    Should things continue as they are I do not think that any one will venture into
                    the tobacco business at least until near spring. We contemplate holding off
                    until then as we expect that by that time things will have been settled or taken
                    such a turn as to indicate whether the business will be safe or not. Ours <del
                        hand="h1">business</del> being a credit business and being carried on almost
                    exclusively through agencies in the northern states would be the first and
                    longest sufferer from civil war.</p>

                <p>As you have seen by the papers your own glorious native state has at last
                    determined to throw off the <orig reg="shackles">shackels</orig> of a government
                    which it would be <hi rend="underline">disgrace</hi> for any southern man to
                    submit to. Glorious South Carolina how I wish I also could claim it for my
                    native country. In this city the friends of Southern rights are not idle though
                    we are not making any fuss or parade of our <orig reg="strength"
                    >streangth</orig>. We could muster<pb n="2"/> with a days notice five hundred
                    good men and true who are determined to maintain our rights. Even though we have
                    to fight in the language of the infamous traitor Douglass "with halters around
                    our necks," Blue cockades are not uncommon here. I have been wearing one for
                    nearly two months and so help me God I intend if necessary to make the
                    declaration implied by it good even with my hearts blood.</p>

                <p>As to the gun. Trades in guns and horses are proverbally uncertain. Frank when
                    down here saw a gun that he liked as well as mine. And Paul who is very anxious
                    to possess <del hand="h1">my</del> mine has purchased that one with the hope of
                    trading with him. It is as good as mine but Paul like myself has falled in love
                    with mine. He made Frank an offer while down here which pleased him. If you do
                    not object <abbr expan="Paul">P.</abbr> and myself have determined to send his
                    and the boot agreed upon between him and Frank in place of mine. I hope this
                    arrangement will be satisfactory to you and Frank as <abbr expan="Paul"
                    >P.</abbr> is very anxious to have my gun. It would not do at this time to send
                    a gun by a negro even with an order as it would get him into trouble. The
                    arrangement for paying suits me as well as any other.</p>

                <p>I am glad to hear that the baby is better and hope<pb n="3"/> he will continue to
                    improve. I could not get your bill <orig reg="today">to day</orig> but as Paul
                    is anxious for a reply to my <orig reg="proposition">propposition</orig> I
                    determined to write <orig reg="today">to day</orig> so that I could get your
                    reply as soon as possible. I will get your Bill as soon as possible and send it
                    to you in my next. Paul sends his respects and says times are worse and worse.</p>

                <p>Give my respects to all and believe me your affectionate son</p>


                <closer>
                    <salute> </salute>
                    <signed><abbr expan="John">J.</abbr> H. Cochran </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">P.S. Enclosed I send you some <orig reg="speeches"
                            >speaches</orig> delivered in the Senate which will give you some idea
                        of the feeling existing there. </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
