<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0583"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A0583">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: M. T. Norman to Nancy Norman, August
                    9, 1864</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county m t norman to nancy norman, august 9 1864</title>
        <author>Norman, M. T. </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Sarah Richardson and Amy Voorhees </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">14</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">A0583</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2 </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501880</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: M. T. Norman to Nancy Norman, August 9, 1864 </title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county m t norman to nancy norman, august 9 1864</title>
            <author> </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source Copy Consulted: M.T. Norman Letter, MS87-015, Civil War
                            Collections, Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and
                            State University, Blacksburg, Virginia.</p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Virginia.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-08-09">1864-08-09 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Troop Movement, Battle Description, Home Front</term>
                    <term>Regiment: none </term>
                    <term>Company: none </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp> </resp>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees </name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="A0583T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>M.T. Norman writes to his wife of his battalion's movements in the valley and
                    includes an account of the burning of Chambersburg. </p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Nancy Norman</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-08-09">Aug 9th 1864 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Mount Jackson</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Wife, </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I embrace the present opportunity of dropping you a few lines which <del
                        hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> I truly hope these lines will reach you <del hand="h1"
                        /><unclear> home you and family well</unclear> and doing well.</p>

                <p>Nancy it is impossible for me to give you a full history of my hard ship and ups
                    and downs since I left home I reached my command the 24 of July I Started from
                        <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> the 7 day and never <orig reg="stopped">stoped</orig> but
                        <orig reg="two">too</orig> days <orig reg="until">untill</orig> I got to my
                        <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <unclear>Cal Dim</unclear> was in command of the Battalion was very glad to see
                    me I found 20 of my boys well mounted had just <orig reg="returned"
                    >retured</orig> from <orig reg="Maryland">Mariland</orig> They was on the bank
                    of the Potomac River <orig reg="above">a bove</orig>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> barge I taken down the distance and the <orig reg="different"
                        >differente</orig> places as past them I was three hundred and 25 miles from
                    home I struck the valley of Va at Salem and went clear through it the <orig
                        reg="most beautiful">beautifuls</orig> country I ever saw just as <orig
                        reg="level">leval</orig> as you please and any amount of wheat but awful dry
                        <orig reg="everywhere">all whare</orig> I have <orig reg="been">bin</orig>,
                    well I will <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>, with a little more of my trip the next day after I
                    got to my command we struck the line of march in to Mariland crossed the Potomac
                    River the 29<hi rend="super">th</hi> of July went through a large portion of
                        <abbr expan="Maryland">Ma</abbr> then in to <orig reg="Pennsylvania"
                        >Pensylvany</orig> Marching night and day almost we reached the city of
                        <orig reg="Chambersberg">Chambersburge</orig> General
                    <unclear>Meeauslin</unclear> was in command of <orig reg="two">too</orig>
                    <orig reg="Brigades">Brigads</orig> and cavalry he demanded one thousand dollars
                    in <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> from the town or he would burn it they refused to pay it and
                    he set fire to the whole Town our Battalion was ordered to do the <orig
                        reg="firing">fireing</orig> and was permitted to take <orig reg="anything"
                        >any thing</orig> we wanted in the Town <orig reg="stores">Stors</orig> or
                    private Houses but I was so displeased with the <unclear>apporation</unclear> I
                    never touched a thing I never witnessed <orig reg="such">sutch</orig> a <orig
                        reg="sight">site </orig>in all my life - <pb n="2"/></p>

                <p>Nancy the poor women and children and <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> gray
                    <unclear>headed</unclear> men was running in every direction with a little <del
                        hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> under there were crying and <orig reg="screaming">skreaming</orig>
                    <orig reg="scarcely">skarsly</orig> any of them had time to remove any of <orig
                        reg="their">ther</orig> property I was ordered to set fire to <orig
                        reg="houses">hauses</orig> time and again and take <orig reg="anything">any
                        thing</orig> I wanted but I never set fire nor took <orig reg="anything">any
                        thing</orig>. I saw three hundred <orig reg="houses">hauses</orig> on fire
                    at once I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> uphold no <orig reg="such">sutch</orig>
                    for all though our poor <orig reg="women">wimmen</orig> and children has
                    suffered a great deal by the <orig reg="yankees">yankes</orig> but I don't <orig
                        reg="believe">beleave</orig> in burning <orig reg="our">ar</orig> own side
                    the worst of all they <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> one woman and <orig reg="two">too</orig>
                    children that unable to be <orig reg="moved">mooved</orig> the woman had just
                    got to heal from the birth of a child, well we moved in from <orig reg="there"
                        >thare</orig> and attacked several places and they was too hard for us and
                    we would turn back aiming to cross the River in to Va but one place that we
                    could cross <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <unclear>Avrel</unclear> pursuing us all the time we would have to turn and
                    fight him back and then march on we got to the River and was attacked by a
                    regiment of <orig reg="yankees">yankes </orig>but we soon <orig reg="whipped"
                        >whiped</orig> them and crossed we came to new creek Depot in the Baltimore
                    and Ohio Rail <orig reg="Road">Rode</orig> and <orig reg="fought">faught</orig>
                    them a while but never taken the place we fell back 40 miles to <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> stay a day or so and the <orig reg="yankees">yankes</orig>
                    remain on us with double the number we had a <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> day and was laying
                    in camp a <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> and they was <orig reg="firing">fireing</orig> at us
                    before we knew <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig> about them and all of the
                    Stampedes ever was we had it we run about five miles over rivers, <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>, ditches in every direction they was in fifty yards of me
                    several times, <orig reg="hollering">hallawing</orig> halt halt but it was no
                    use <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> was going on old town they shooting for life I made my
                    escape thank God lost <orig reg="two">too</orig> men out of my Co John Phillips
                    and <unclear>Hughander</unclear> Sparks, from <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <abbr expan="County">Cty</abbr> he joined my Co as I came on they <orig
                        reg="are">ar </orig>killed <orig reg="are">ar</orig> taken<pb n="3"
                    />prisoners I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know which <orig reg="prisoners"
                        >prisners</orig> though I think we lost 4 <orig reg="pieces">pecies</orig>
                    of <orig reg="our">ar</orig> artillery and <orig reg="about">a bout</orig> one
                    thousand men and <orig reg="about">a baut</orig> the same of horses, we marched
                    50 miles that day and night through the mountains to get away <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> the command of his regiment they got all the Generals
                        <unclear>staff</unclear> and the <orig reg="adjutant">adjutent</orig> Gen So
                    we <orig reg="are">ar</orig> now in camp in the valley <orig reg="where"
                    >whare</orig> I went down I came by <orig reg="where">whare</orig> the way I was
                    with the crippled horses and brought all the bays only Harrison Norman I tell
                    you we have seen hard times I have <orig reg="been">bin</orig> under the fire of
                    the enemy five times since I left home I tell you we have to fight <orig
                        reg="here">hear</orig>. <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> Parson and Ashby Isaacks is well
                    and good soldiers they was in all the fights them and Jack fired deliberately at
                    a party <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> but they have to stand to it (you <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> who
                    I mean) Aaron parson is down with the measles and <unclear>G.H.
                    Thompson</unclear> is back with the horses his mare has broke down and his
                            <unclear><del rend="none" hand="h1"/> so bad he <orig reg="couldn't">couldent</orig>
                        walk and he <orig reg="hadn't">hadent</orig>
                        <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                        <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> they had him drafted from the road if he would come up now
                        I can get him in again but if he dont <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                        <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                        <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> is you. I am <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                        <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> &amp; am for him I hope he will come soon for I <orig
                            reg="don't">dont </orig>want to <orig reg="lose">loos</orig> him I <orig
                            reg="don't">dont</orig> know whare he is now or I would send him <del
                            hand="h1"/></unclear></p>


                <p>Nancy I would love to hear from you I havent heard since I left home you must
                    write soon and let me know how you are coming on wether you ar <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> hear I fear you ar <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>, <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> Nancy I forgot I heard last night <del
                        hand="h1"/> was <orig reg="elected">ealected</orig> Governer <orig
                        reg="hooray">who raw</orig> for him I would love to hear a full account of
                    the election I never can hear from <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> I fear he is dead<pb n="4"/></p>


                <p>Nancy <orig reg="be sure">beshure</orig> and write if you know <orig
                        reg="anything">any thing</orig> of Lacy I am uneasy <orig reg="about">a
                    baut</orig> him write all <orig reg="about">a baut</orig> your <orig
                        reg="affairs">effars</orig> write what <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> is doing and <orig
                        reg="whether">wether</orig> you have got my horses at home or not and what
                    they have done with my mules get the horses home in a <orig reg="pasture">paster</orig>
                    <orig reg="somewhere">some whare</orig> and sell them if you can and keep my
                    mules if you can I can get my money if I can send it home if I <orig reg="can't"
                        >cant</orig> send it I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> want to draw it tell
                    Jack if he can get me a hay stack to do so and if he <orig reg="sells"
                    >sels</orig> any corn or <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> I want it I will send you <orig
                        reg="some">som</orig> money the first chance. If I <orig reg="can't"
                    >cant</orig> send it no other way I will send <orig reg="some">som</orig> in a
                    letter.</p>

                <p>Nancy excuse my long and <orig reg="wearisome">wearisom</orig> letter for I could
                        <orig reg="sit">set</orig> here and write all day Nancy it has nearly killed
                    some <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>, <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> elected they <orig reg="swore">sware</orig> they <orig
                        reg="wouldn't">wouldant</orig> vote for Lacy <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> he was a <del
                        hand="h1"/> man I would love <unclear>to hear how he <orig reg="came"
                        >cam</orig> out </unclear></p>

                <p><orig reg="give">gave</orig> all the children my love and your pap and <orig
                        reg="family">fammaly</orig> I send my respects to them all</p>

                <p>Nancy I got no <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> to eat <orig reg="here">hear</orig> I wish I was at home and
                    little Elizabeth could get me some I often think of the dinner she got for me
                    while I was at home I have got her a <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> if I could send them to her I would be so glad I will try and
                    quit for this time by asking you to write to me Direct to <orig reg="Staunton"
                        >Stanton</orig> Va<lb/>37 Batt Calvary<lb/>Johnson Brigade</p>


                <closer>
                    <salute>I am your devoted Husband <orig reg="until">untill</orig> death </salute>
                    <signed>M.T. Norman </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">how does <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                        <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> bless his little heart how I want to <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> them
                        all <name type="recipient">Nancy Norman </name>
                    </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
