<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0584"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A0584">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Edward P. Walton to Mary Baylor, October 1, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county edward p walton to mary baylor, october 1 1862</title>
        <author>Walton, Edward P.</author>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Sarah Richardson </name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
        <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
        <idno type="VCDH">A0584 </idno>
        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The University of Virginia.
      All rights reserved. </p>
     <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2 </p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1998">1998 </date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501881</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note> </note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Edward P. Walton to Mary Baylor, October 1, 1862 </title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county edward p walton to mary baylor, october 1 1862</title>
            <author>Edward P. Walton</author>
            <respStmt>
              <resp> </resp>
              <name> </name>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher> </publisher>
            <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
            <date value=""/>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p>Source Copy Consulted: William Smith Hanger Baylor Correspondence (MS 85- 002), Civil War
       Collection, Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University,
       Blacksburg, Virginia.</p>
          </seriesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-10-01">1862-10-01 </date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Death/Casualties, Patriotism, Church/Religious Activity, Military Authority </term>
          <term>Regiment: 5th Va. Inf. </term>
          <term>Company: none </term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp> </resp>
          <name>Amy Voorhees </name>
        </respStmt>
        <item> Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text id="A0584T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Walton reports on Colonel Baylor's death and describes Baylor's religious conversion before
     he died.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>
  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Mrs. Baylor</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-10-01">Octo. 1st, 1862. </date>
      <name type="place">Staunton, Va.</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My dear friend, </salute>
    </opener>
    <p>Having just returned from my imprisonment in Washington I hasten to offer my deepest sympathy
     in the sad bereavement which has fallen upon us in the death of yr. noble Husband. On the fatal
     day of his immolation upon the altar of Patriotism, I was guarded by hireling Yankees, in full
     view of our forces; compelled to witness their heroic sufferings, without being able to offer
     aid or consolation to my wounded and dying companions.</p>

    <p>Late Saturday evening a prisoner was brought into our crowd, who informed us that Col. Baylor
     had fallen, mortally wounded, that day; while lifting the Colors of his his Regiment from the
     ground where they had fallen <abbr expan="when">wh.</abbr> the gallant color-bearer of the 5<hi
      rend="super">th</hi>.</p>
    <pb n="2"/>

    <p>I can not describe my emotions on receiving this intelligence. I felt as if my own brother
     had been stricken from my side. I <unclear>rebelled</unclear> at the Providence that denied me
     the privilege of being by his side and following his remains to their final resting place. I
     recalled the hours wherein we had <unclear>communed</unclear> together upon our beds; and
     remembered the deep anxiety which he always expressed in the success of my efforts to awaken a
     religious interest, in the regiment; how he cheered up, as I would tell him of one and another
     of his men, who had come to converse <abbr expan="with">wh.</abbr> me, on the subject of
     religion; and said <abbr expan="with">wh.</abbr> earnest emphasis "I would rather a revival of
     religion in my Regiment than to realize any temporal advantage whatever" This solicitude for
     the conversion of souls, manifested by word and acts, is one of the most satisfactory evidences
     of a change of heart. It is the first impulse of a renewed heart to long for<pb n="3"/>the
     conversion of others.</p>

    <p>Another characteristic struck me as very indicative of a saving change. I never knew a man
     addicted to swearing that could refrain from profanity when provoked, without Divine
     assistance: and yet I have seen Col. Baylor under the most harrassing provocations, without
     yielding to the promptings of his old habit. He had completely mastered, at least, that habit.</p>

    <p>Before I had indulged the hope of his conversion, I was frequently astonished at his
     discriminating views on the subject of experimental piety. He seemed to delight in spending
     hours, after others were asleep, in analyzing the emotions of his own heart and repeatedly said
     that he would make a profession of religion; but for his fears of being <del hand="h1"
     >again</del> ensnared by the world. He also expressed a preference for the Ministry as a
     profession above all others.</p>

    <p>But his conversation during the last day<pb n="4"/> we were together (Tuesday before his
     death) furnished the strongest proof of his concern on the subject of religion and his faith
     the power of <hi rend="underline">Prayer</hi>. He asked not less than half a dozen times,
     during the day, an interest in my prayers, in view of the impending conflict, and the last
     words that he spoke to me were "Walton, I do hope that Christians are praying for us, at home."</p>

    <p>He frequently conversed with Gen. Jackson on religious subjects. It is well known that the
     General indulged the warmest feeling of esteem and affection for your Husband. On one occasion,
     when he thought that Col. Baylor was absent from his command and a severe engagement was going
     on he expressed fears that the Brigade would not maintain its reputation; but when he was told
     that your Husband was at his post, he replied "all is right, they will prove worthy of their
     commander."</p>

    <p>Our whole Brigade mourns with you his irreparable loss. I have sent a short obituary to the
     Religious Herald and will forward a copy to you.</p>

    <p>Now dear Gawsey, Harken to this solemn call, learn its fearful teachings and cease more
     entirely from earth &amp; the joys of earth, that you may obtain a firmer hold upon those
     joys that are eternal. Love from Jeanette &amp; self to all your Mother's family.</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Yrs, warmly </salute>
     <signed>Edwd. P. Walton </signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
