<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0747"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A0747">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jacob Kent Langhorne to his sister, September 1,
     1862</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jacob kent langhorne to his sister, september 1 1862</title>
        <author>Langhorne, Jacob Kent</author>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Sally Henninger</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
        <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va.</pubPlace>
        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The University of Virginia.
      All rights reserved.</p>
     <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/personal.html </p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1997">1997</date>
        <idno type="VCDH">A0747</idno>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501884</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note> </note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jacob Kent Langhorne to his sister, September 1, 1862</title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jacob kent langhorne to his sister, september 1 1862</title>
            <author>Jacob Kent Langhorne</author>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p>Source Copy Consulted: Jacob Kent Langhorne Papers, Manuscript #361, Virginia Military
       Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia. Also available online at
       http://www.vmi.edu/~archtml/ms361.html</p>
          </seriesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-09-01">1862-09-01</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Church/Religious Activity, Family, Home Front</term>
          <term>Regiment: 2nd Va. Cav. </term>
          <term>Company: C </term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Amy Voorhees </name>
        </respStmt>
        <item> Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text id="A0747T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Langhorne describes his first few days at VMI and mentions the people he has met there. </p>
   </div1>
  </front>
  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Sister</name>
    </head>
    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-09-01">Sept 1, 1862</date>
      <name type="place">
       <abbr expan="Virginia Military Institute">VMI.</abbr>
      </name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Sister</salute>
    </opener>
    <p>According to <orig reg="promise">promice</orig> I sit down to write you. I wrote to Mama the
     day after I arrived here. The <orig reg="second">2</orig> evening I had been here I was invited
     to the Misses Baxters to Tea <orig reg="and">an</orig> was <orig reg="treated">treeted</orig>
     so kindly that I began to feel some what like I was at home. Sister no one can like this place
     at first but I will soon become <orig reg="used">use</orig> to it I reckon. I met Risk Hutter
     at Buchannan and he gave me a letter of introduction to Breedlove the Adjutant of the Corps. I
     expect he is a very nice fellow without knowing whether he is or not. </p>
    <p>I have not commenced studying yet on account of the examination but will <orig reg="commence"
      >comence</orig> studying tomorrow I hope. I have made <orig reg="several">severall</orig> very
     pleasant <orig reg="acquaintances">acuaintances</orig> since I have been here. Burton one of my
      <orig reg="roommates">roomates</orig> is a very good fellow but I do not consider any of them
     my equals. Ruffin from Salem is here. I have had one report against me for not
      <unclear>doudling</unclear> in ranks <unclear>
      <orig reg="properly">property</orig>
     </unclear> but Major Ship let me off with the report. <orig reg="Anyone">Any one</orig> can get
     off with all reports &amp; demerits that they get <orig reg="until">untill</orig> they have
     been here a month. </p>
    <p>I made the <orig reg="acquaintance">acuaintance</orig> of a Mrs Myers <orig reg="coming"
      >comeing</orig> over here, a very nice old lady and she invited me very kindly to come and see
     her. The old cadets have <orig reg="given">give</orig> me 2 or 3 buckings every day since I
     have been here. They hurt at first like the mischief but I am getting tough now and it <orig
      reg="doesn't">dont</orig> hurt so bad. </p>
    <p>Sept 2</p>
    <p>Dear Sister <lb/> I will <orig reg="commence">comence</orig> again but have nothing of
     interest to write. Tell Ma that I have read my bible every day since I have been here. We <orig
      reg="also">allso</orig> have prayers every night among the cadets and tell her that I have
     been every night and expect to keep it up as long as I stay here. I have looked for the last
      <orig reg="two">too</orig> days for a letter from home if you all knew how much I want to hear
     from home you would <orig reg="certainly">sertainly</orig> write. Sister I have been thinking
     all day about the nice grapes and peaches you all are having and how much I would like to be
      <orig reg="there">their</orig>. </p>
    <p>Sister when you write let me know how Uncle Archer is getting along with the
      <unclear>copperas</unclear>
     <orig reg="business">buisnes</orig> and tell him he must write to me. In fact I must hear from
     home once or twice a week any how. How are all at aunt Sarahs and <unclear>tell</unclear>. I
     hope the future days of her life may be spent more happily than the past. Tell Aunt Nanny
     Brother Jim Maurice and Jim Armistad to write to me and to let me know whether Cousin Nanny is
     with you. Give my love to all of the above named and kiss dear Aunt Nanny a dozen times for the
     nice ring she gave me. Tell dear Papa &amp; Mama that I am going to do all I can for my own
      <unclear>interest</unclear> as well as for theirs. What a gods blessing it is to have two such
     dear parents as they are.</p>

    <p>Kiss Ma and tell her that I hope god may bless her and all the rest of you. Tell Papa that I
     will try and do all I can. <sic corr="Kiss">Kis</sic>
     <unclear>
      <orig reg="May">May</orig>
     </unclear> and Mary and my love to John. <orig reg="Goodbye">Good by</orig> dear sister with
     love to all </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your <sic corr="affectionate">affctionate</sic>
      <abbr expan="Brother">Bro</abbr>
     </salute>
     <signed>Kent </signed>
     <seg type="postscript">Write soon. </seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
