<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0748"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A0748">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jacob Kent Langhorne to his father,
                    September 13, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jacob kent langhorne to his father, september 13 1862</title>
        <author>Langhorne, Jacob Kent </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Sally Henninger </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/personal.html </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <idno type="VCDH">A0748</idno>
                <date value="1997">1997</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501885</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War. </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jacob Kent Langhorne to his father, September 13,
                            1862</title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jacob kent langhorne to his father, september 13 1862</title>
            <author>Jacob Kent Langhorne </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source Copy Consulted: Jacob Kent Langhorne Papers, Manuscript #361,
                            Virginia Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia. Also
                            available online at http://www.vmi.edu/~archtml/ms361.html </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-09-13">1862-09-13 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Desertion/Leave, Home Front</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 2nd Va. Cav. </term>
                    <term>Company: C </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp> </resp>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees </name>
                </respStmt>
                <item> Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="A0748T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Langhorne describes the difficulties of life at VMI and asks about war, local,
                    and family news.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Father</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-09-13"><abbr expan="September">Sept</abbr> 13, 1862</date>
                        <name type="place"><abbr expan="Virginia Military 
                            Institute">VMI</abbr>,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Papa </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have been intending to write to you for several days but thought I would wait a
                    day or two so that if I wanted anything from home I could write for them and
                    very well I did as I want you to send me the books with the following names:
                    Bolmar's Levizack's French Grammar, &amp; Penney &amp; Badois Practical
                    french grammar &amp; Dictionary, Modern and Ancient geography &amp;
                    atlas, Smiths &amp; Dukes Arithmetic as it will be a great help to me in
                        <orig reg="studying">studdying</orig> Algebra. They have <orig reg="allways"
                        >allways</orig> had books here <orig reg="until">untill</orig> this year and
                    I don't <orig reg="know">no</orig> why they have not gotten them this year. Tell
                    Ma to send me my gray Roundybout as we will not get our uniform for a month yet
                    and perhaps more.</p>

                <p>I reckon you think I spend half my time writing but I think so much of home and
                    the dear ones there that I cannot help writing. I would give so much to see you
                    all <orig reg="today">to day</orig>. Tell Brother Jim and sister that they must
                    not give out their trip to Natural Bridge this fall as it would disappoint me
                    very much. </p>

                <p>I am rooming now with Rough Griffin son of Dr. G of Salem and like him very much.
                    About one half of the boys here are very nice boys the other half are perfect
                        <orig reg="rowdies">roudies</orig>. When you write let me know how you are
                    getting along on the farm and <orig reg="whether">wheather</orig> uncle Archer
                    has heard from his horse and write me how Nanny looks. <orig reg="Please"
                    >Pleas</orig> dont let <orig reg="anyone">any one</orig> hack her about. </p>

                <p>We are not regularly started with our studies yet will get straight by next week.
                    I received Sisters letter last week the other day and was delighted to hear from
                    home &amp; to hear that Grandpapa &amp; Uncle M had improved so much.
                    Give my best love to uncle M. &amp; Aunt Liz when you see them and tell them
                    that I regretted not seeing them very much. What horse will Jimmy Armistead get.</p>

                <p>Tell Sister I have been on guard twice once on police and once on fatigue. I
                        <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> mind police guard much as I <orig reg="don't"
                        >dont</orig> have to stand long at a time but fatigue guard is very hard
                    duty. You have to stand 2 hours at a time and then you are off 4 and <unclear>
                        <orig reg="on">on</orig>
                    </unclear> 2. You are put on guard one morning at 6 and come off the next at 6
                    but that exempts you from drill or any other Military duty and from your studies
                    also but I will not have to go on that kind of guard for a month yet. The other
                    kind of guard does not exempt you from any duty whatever.</p>

                <p><orig reg="Please">Pleas</orig> send me the papers when you send the books as I
                    have only heard that there was a battle at Manassas and one in Kentucky and that
                    is all I know about it. I have made on Algebra this week 10 1/2 3 being the
                    highest mark and I missed one day the day I was on fatigue guard. I consider the
                    mark very good as I never <orig reg="studied">studdied</orig> algebra before and
                    don't understand how to work by letters. I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know
                    what I got on my other <orig reg="studies">studdies</orig> as our marks were not
                    read out to us in French and geography but I hope and trust that they are good.
                    I would like to do well here as it is such a great thing for one to do well
                    here. </p>

                <p>They say no one can get furlough here unless they have been here 6 months. 6
                    months sounds longer to me now than 12 years did before. It is a sad thought to
                    me to think of 6 months. Write me all the news when you write as I <orig
                        reg="don't">dont</orig> hear a word now. Tell uncle Archer to write to me
                    and let me know how much copperas he is making a day. Write me how everything is
                    going on the farm. Tell brother Jim I will write to him next but he must not
                        <unclear>want</unclear> to receive one before he writes. Is he gaining his
                    strength rapidly or not. <orig reg="Tell">Tel</orig> him that the Bridge will
                    pay <orig reg="anyone">any one</orig> for coming to see it. I <orig reg="didn't"
                        >didnt</orig> have time to look at it well I only stopped long enough to get
                    my breakfast.</p>

                <p>I feel very sick at my stomach every morning getting up so soon and drilling an
                        <orig reg="hour">our</orig> before breakfast. We get up at five and go down
                    to roll call having from 3 to 5 minutes to dress and roll up and strap our beds.
                    We go to tattoo at half past 9 and the roll is called again then we have half an
                        <orig reg="hour">our</orig> to fix down our beds and undress. Tell Ma I
                        <orig reg="always">all ways</orig> take time in that half <orig reg="hour"
                        >our</orig> to read my bible. Then the lights are tapped out and if there be
                    light burning after the drum <orig reg="quits">qits</orig>
                    <orig reg="beating">beeting</orig> the orderly of the room gets 5 or 10 demerits
                    for it &amp; one of the boys in the room are made orderly every week and is
                    responsible for any noise made in it and if any <orig reg="noise">nois</orig>
                    should be made in the room during study hours the orderly is reported for it and
                    gets from 3 to 5 demerits for it or if any thing in the room should be out of
                    order or out of place the orderly is reported for it. The inspectors of rooms
                    visits 3 to 6 times a day.</p>

                <p>Give my love to all at Cousin H<unclear>
                        <orig reg="Hues">Hues</orig>
                    </unclear> > and at aunt Sarahs. You all must write often. Give my best love to
                    all at home.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>I remain as ever your attached son, </salute>
                    <signed>Kent. </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
