<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0753"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A0753">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jacob Kent Langhorne to His Brother,
                    November 10, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jacob kent langhorne to his brother, november 10 1862</title>
        <author>Langhorne, Jacob Kent </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Sally Henninger </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/personal.html </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997</date>
                <idno type="VCDH">A0753</idno>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501890</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jacob Kent Langhorne to His Brother, November 10,
                            1862</title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jacob kent langhorne to his brother, november 10 1862</title>
            <author>Jacob Kent Langhorne </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source Copy Consulted: Jacob Kent Langhorne Papers, Manuscript #361,
                            Virginia Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia. Also
                            available online at http://www.vmi.edu/~archtml/ms361.html </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-11-10">1862-11-10</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Military Authority, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 2nd Va. Cav. </term>
                    <term>Company: C </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees </name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="A0753T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Langhorne talks about the sending home of a dead student's corpse. He also
                    mentions getting help with algebra and tells about the celebration of VMI's
                    Anniversary.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Brother</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-11-10"><abbr expan="November">Nov</abbr>the 10th 1862</date>
                        <name type="place">Virginia Military Institute </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear <abbr expan="Brother">Bro</abbr>
                    </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I received your letter some week or 10 days ago and would have answered it sooner
                    time ago but have been waiting to hear from home. I have not heard a word from
                    home for 2 weeks. I have not a word of news to write you. I suppose I wrote you
                    about the death of young Fleming, he died a week ago yesterday. Whilst his dead
                    body was in the House we had no duty to attend to Academic or Military. The
                    Corps was turned out on Tuesday to bury him but his <abbr expan="Brother"
                    >Bro</abbr> came from Staunton on the Stage and carried his body home. The Corps
                    marched a mile after the hearse, then we were halted &amp; Major Ship
                    detailed on 4 Pall bearers &amp; sent them on to Staunton with his corpse.</p>

                <p>As we only had 3 more days that week to attend to duty &amp; 3 being the
                    highest mark I was the maximum &amp; I only made <unclear>5...</unclear> the
                    worst mark on math I have made since I have been here. I went to the board this
                    morning had this example given me. The hour &amp; minute hands of a watch
                    show the time of day to be 24 minutes past 3 <orig reg="o'clock">oclock</orig>,
                    at what time will they come together. You are only allowed 1 minute to
                    demonstrate. I <orig reg="couldn't">couldnt</orig> work it and then I asked him
                        <abbr expan="Professor">Pro</abbr> Miller to work it out and explain it and
                    took him minutes to work it and I told him he ought not to mark me on an example
                    that I only had a minute as I knew he had been 5 and he said he would not mark
                    me on it but told me to come round to his room that night &amp; he would
                    show me how to work it. Tis night now and time for me to go. </p>

                <p>Tomorrow is the 23rd anniversary of the <abbr
                        expan="Virginia Military  
 Institute">VMI</abbr> and by the way I have a
                    good piece of news to tell you. The Beef <orig reg="Sargeant">Sergeant</orig>
                    has bought 40 odd turkeys for dinner tomorrow and we have for dessert Pies. They
                    generally fire a salute with cannon but the powder is so scarce that they will
                    not fire one but <orig reg="there">their</orig> is a piece of bad news with it,
                    the old cadets are going to buck every Rat in Barracks tomorrow. They have had
                    regular committees taking down all their names &amp; my name came under that
                    head. <abbr expan="Brother">Bro</abbr> Jim I have been <orig reg="scuffling"
                        >scufling</orig> and my hand trembles so that cannot write and so much
                    excited that you must excuse all mistakes.</p>

                <p>I wrote to Papa some time ago about some shoes and he never wrote me a <orig
                        reg="word">
                        <unclear>work</unclear>
                    </orig> about them &amp; General Smith says he cannot and will not furnish
                    us shoes and I am nearly barefooted and If Ma has not sent me the box <orig
                        reg="please">pleas</orig> send me a pair in it. <orig reg="Please"
                    >Pleas</orig> excuse this <orig reg="poorly">porly</orig> written letter. I will
                    try and do better next time. Love to All at Edgehill &amp; Cousin Hues. Kiss
                    Mama and the two children, love to all.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>I remain as ever your attached <abbr expan="Brother">Bro</abbr>
                    </salute>
                    <signed>Kent </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
