<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0752"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A0752">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jacob Kent Langhorne to His Mother,
                    November 2, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jacob kent langhorne to his mother, november 2 1862</title>
        <author>Langhorne, Jacob Kent </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Sally Henninger</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/personal.html</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997</date>
                <idno type="VCDH">A0752</idno>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501889</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jacob Kent Langhorne to His Mother, November 2, 1862</title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jacob kent langhorne to his mother, november 2 1862</title>
            <author>Jacob Kent Langhorne </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source Copy Consulted: Jacob Kent Langhorne Papers, Manuscript #361,
                            Virginia Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia. Also
                            available online at http://www.vmi.edu/~archtml/ms361.html </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-11-02">1862-11-02</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Desertion/Leave, Family, Medicine/Hospitals</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 2nd Va. Cav. </term>
                    <term>Company: C </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="A0752T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Langhorne describes his recovery and tells about students' demands for a
                    cessation of classes following the death of a fellow student.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Mother</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-11-02">November the 2nd 1862 </date>
                        <name type="place">Virginia Military Institute </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My own Darling Mother </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have been intending writing you ever since I came out of the Hospital but I
                    have had as much as I could do ever since. I have been so weak that I have not
                    attended to any military duty yet and <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> think I will
                    be strong enough for a week yet. I am still <orig reg="taking">takeing</orig>
                    medicine. I could get a furlough at any time but I would <orig reg="lose"
                    >loose</orig> so much time from my class that I thought I had better stay here
                    but if I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> gain my strength more rapidly I will
                    apply for a furlough and come Home and stay for a week or 10 days. You have no
                    idea dear Mama how much I want to see you all at home. It makes me <orig
                        reg="almost">all most</orig> cry to think about Home and the dear ones <orig
                        reg="there">their</orig>. Some of the boys seem perfectly satisfied here but
                    I will <orig reg="always">all ways</orig> want to see home. </p>

                <p>I have been attending to my academic duties since Tuesday and the lessons are
                    very hard to me indeed. I <orig reg="don't">dont </orig>know what I made on my
                    studies last week but I expect I made very poor ones as I lost so much time
                    whilst I was in the Hospital. I will have to study very hard to keep up with my
                    class. I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know when I will stand head in my class
                    again. I mean to devote most of my time to my Mathematics as that is the main
                    study here. I hope you have written to sister that I was well enough to attend
                    to my studies again. Tell brother Jim I will answer his letter the first chance
                    I have. Tell Pa that I will write to him shortly. I forgot last time I wrote to
                    Maurice and directed it to Papa.</p>

                <p>Ma I want you to be sure to send me a box by the cars to Lynchburg and from there
                    by packet. Write to Uncle D when you send it and he will have it put on the
                    packet and then I will be sure to get it. The cloth has come for our uniforms at
                    last and I hope we will get them soon. Sister spoke of my wearing the Jacket
                    that Aunt Sarah gave me, the reason was that it was so narrow across the breast
                    that I got reported <abbr expan="too">2</abbr> for not holding my shoulders back
                    and I quit wearing it. The Jacket and overcoat you sent me have been quite a
                    treat to me as it has been very cold since you sent it. You said the jacket was
                    not nice enough there are any quantity that are 60 times worse than mine.</p>

                <p>There is a young Fleming in the hospital that may die at any minute. If he dies
                    here it will be the <orig reg="4th">4</orig> cadet that has died here in 21
                    years. I think that very few. I hope and trust that this poor fellow may live
                    yet but he is just as low as he can be to live. Every body has gone to church
                    and I feel very lonesome and home sick. The sick are not allowed to go out of
                    Barracks and to the Hospital morning &amp; evening.</p>

                <p>Give my love to all at Edgehill &amp; Cousin Hues. Kiss May and Mary for me
                    and let me know whether the <unclear>
                        <orig reg="instructions">instuctions</orig>
                    </unclear> has come or not. </p>

                <p>This is the <orig reg="November 3rd">3</orig>. <lb/> That poor fellow that I
                    spoke of being so sick in the Hospital died yesterday evening about 5 <orig
                        reg="o'clock">oclock</orig>. He is laid out in one of the Society Halls.
                    Just to think a week ago that Dr. Madison thought that I was the sickest one in
                    the Hospital and he poor Fellow is gone and I am yet spared. It makes the cold
                    chills run over me to think of it.</p>

                <p>Tell Uncle Archer that the Druggist says he will take some copperas and said he
                    would let me know to day how much he would take. I will write to him as soon as
                    I hear how much to send. Ma this is all the Ink I have or I would not write with
                    it. I wish you all would write oftener from home.</p>

                <p>The Corps Has just been called out and all Military and Academic duty suspended
                    for today and I reckon tomorrow as he will be <orig reg="buried">burried</orig>
                    tomorrow. In fact we had some little difficulty this morning about some of the
                    academic duties. The First Classmen held a meeting and refused to recite and
                    then all of the classes refused and they appointed a committee to visit the
                    Superintendent and he suspended all duty for the day. </p>

                <p>I will answer Brother Jim's letter in a day or two if I have time. Write me how
                        <orig reg="everything">every thing</orig> is going on on the place and how
                    the lame horses are getting along. Write me how the carriage horses look and how
                    Nannie and Annie look. I would like to see how every thing is going on the farm
                    now. What kind of speculation did Maurice make on his chestnuts and what does
                    John do with himself now does he do any thing or not.</p>

                <p> </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute> </salute>
                    <signed> </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
