<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0755"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A0755">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jacob Kent Langhorne to His Father,
                    November 23, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jacob kent langhorne to his father, november 23 1862</title>
        <author>Langhorne, Jacob Kent </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Sally Henninger </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 8</num> kilobytes </extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/personal.html </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997</date>
                <idno type="VCDH">A0755</idno>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501892</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jacob Kent Langhorne to His Father, November 23, 1862</title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jacob kent langhorne to his father, november 23 1862</title>
            <author>Jacob Kent Langhorne </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Editor </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source Copy Consulted: Jacob Kent Langhorne Papers, Manuscript #361,
                            Virginia Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia. Also
                            available online at http://www.vmi.edu/~archtml/ms361.html </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-11-23">1862-11-23</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Military Authority</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 2nd Va. Cav.</term>
                    <term>Company: C</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees </name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="A0755T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Langhorne reports on his difficulties with math and complains about guard duty
                    and demerits. </p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Father</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-11-23"><abbr expan="November">Nov</abbr> the 23 1862</date>
                        <name type="place"><abbr expan="Virginia Military">VM</abbr> Institute </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Papa </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I had to write to you today as I have been put in a lower section in Math. I
                    commenced this letter yesterday and my heart was touched to the very core to
                    think of telling you that I had been put in a lower section &amp; As
                    Professor Miller did not do me justice about it I went to see him about it and
                    he looked at my marks before I went in the Hospital and found that I stood 3 in
                    the section on Marks &amp; I told him that I had not had time to get the
                    rules that the boys had gone over whilst I was in the Hospital and that If I
                        <orig reg="knew">new</orig> the rules I could keep up. He gave me a lesson
                    in the rules &amp; I hope now to take a higher position in my section than I
                    ever have held yet.</p>

                <p>Tuesday the 11th was the 23 anniversary of Institute &amp; All duties were
                    suspended &amp; the day commenced as follows. The old Cadets hung &amp;
                    bucked every new cadet or rather Rats as they call us in Barracks. They got up
                        <orig reg="between">betwen</orig> 4 &amp; 5 and tried to catch us in bed
                    but we <orig reg="knew">new</orig> something was out and we were up as soon as
                    they. We had turkies Ham &amp; Rice for dinner. The Beef <orig
                        reg="Sergeant">Sargeant</orig> bought 40 odd turkeys for dinner &amp;
                    there is not more than 225 boys here and we ate them all up &amp; every
                    thing else in proportion.</p>

                <p>Tell Uncle Archer I saw Mell yesterday. She says she wants 2 Winter dresses, says
                    someone stole the only thick dress she had, says the Captain of the boat says he
                    wants her next year, says he can get the money for her hire now if he wishes.
                    She told me this yesterday and asked me to write to him. </p>

                <p>I am getting rather tired of guard duty as I have to go on 1 every week &amp;
                    stand 3 hours guard at night 1/2 or 3/4 in the day besides having to march on
                    &amp; off. I have gotten 27 demerits but have only 3 Academic reports, some
                    of the others are incorrect and a good many that I can get <orig reg="off"
                    >of</orig> with by writing excuses. One of the reports that I got 11 demerits
                    for nearly half of which I have gotten was giving notice that the inspector was
                    visiting which I think I can get off with it as the sentinals on post had <orig
                        reg="always">all ways</orig> given notice to us that the inspector was
                    visiting and it was 2 or 3 time I was on post and I thought it was my duty to
                    give them notice. I haven't time to write more as I have to get ready for
                    church. <orig reg="Goodbye">Good by</orig>, love to all both white &amp;
                    black, </p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>remain your Attached son, </salute>
                    <signed>Kent </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">PS love to all at Edgehill. Mell told me yesterday that
                        Emily told her that Will H was wounded is it so or not, love to cousin Milly
                        &amp; Hues, K. </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
