<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0809"?>
<?dlps page-images="color" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;


<!ENTITY garb9a SYSTEM "uva-lib:503034" NDATA uvaHighRes>
<!ENTITY garb9b SYSTEM "uva-lib:503035" NDATA uvaHighRes>
<!ENTITY garb9c SYSTEM "uva-lib:503036" NDATA uvaHighRes>
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A0809">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Thomas Garber to Albert Garber, September 25,
     1862</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county thomas garber to albert garber, september 25 1862</title>
        <author>Garber, Thomas</author>
        <editor> </editor>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Alice Carter</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Murrell</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A0809</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>copyright 1998, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1998 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1998">1998</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:503033</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>


      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Thomas Garber to Albert Garber, September 25, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county thomas garber to albert garber, september 25 1862</title>
            <author>Thomas Garber</author>
            <editor> </editor>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p> </p>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>3 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher> </publisher>
            <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Garber Family Letters, Augusta County Historical
       Society, Staunton, Virginia </idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>The upper left corner of page two is missing.</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Augusta County Historical Society, Staunton, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-09-25">1862-09-25</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Battle Description, Family, Military Strategy, Prisons/Prisoners, Troop Movement</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A0809T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Thomas Garber describes the activities of his regiment since leaving the Valley.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>
  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <opener>
     <pb n="1" entity="garb9a" pid="uva-lib:503034"/>
    

     <name type="recipient">Albert Garber</name>

     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-09-25">Sept 25<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1862</date>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Father</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>In the last few weeks I have received several letters from Addie complaining that I did not
     write home <orig reg="at all">atall</orig> but she is mistaken for I have written you one
     letter I have sent one to Kate and have written 3 o 4 times to Addie Addie <orig reg="also"
      >allso</orig> complained that you know nothing about me at home when we were at Harrisonburg I
     wrote <orig reg="home">hom</orig> that I had <orig reg="joined">join</orig> Co. I. Capt C
     Ferralls Company and that Regiment was the 12<hi rend="super">th</hi> V<hi rend="super">a</hi>
     and now I will try to give you an account of <orig reg="myself">my self</orig> since we left
     the Valley. The Col. has just given orders to saddle up I will finish this the first
     opportunity (Sept. 26) We passed through Charlestown yesterday &amp; have encamped 4 or 5
     miles of that place. We left <orig reg="Harrisonburg">Harrison burg</orig> on the 1<hi
      rend="super">st</hi> day of August and after a march of 20 or 25 miles we encamped near John
     Lewis and on the next night we stayed at Michums River <orig reg="where">were</orig> we laid
     over Sunday cousin <orig reg="Jenny">Jenney</orig> brought the Col a box which did a <orig
      reg="heap">heep </orig> of good on the next night <del hand="h1">last we</del> we stayed <del
      hand="h1">on</del> 7 miles <orig reg="from">form</orig>
     <orig reg="Charlottesville">Charloatesville</orig> we laid over there to await orders from Gen
     Jackson we were encamped near <unclear>Cobhan</unclear> Depot I rode out to <orig reg="see"
     >se</orig> if I could hear <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig> of Mr. Lewis I found his
     Father and Told Nicky had gone to Halifax to finish his education and was there arrested as a
     conscript put in the guard house and sent to Richmond where he got an appointment in the Q.M.
     Office. We left that neighborhood on the next day and every <pb n="2" entity="garb9b" pid="uva-lib:503035"/>
      * <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> has <orig reg="almost">allmost</orig>
     <orig reg="passed">past</orig> like a dream since that <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> had a good deal of hard
      <orig reg="marching">marcing</orig>
     <orig reg="both">booth</orig> day and night. We laid around while they were fighting <orig
      reg="until">untill</orig>
     <orig reg="Saturday">Satherday</orig> when the whole Brigade started out full gallop for about
     2 miles when our Regiments &amp; the 7<hi rend="super">th</hi> and the 2<hi rend="super"
     >nd</hi> and 6<hi rend="super">th</hi> went on before as fast as they could gallop. I did not
     know <orig reg="what ">wat</orig> is <orig reg="meant">ment</orig> when old Stuart came and
     ordered Col Harman up with his Regiment and we galloped a quarter of a mile and met the 2<hi
      rend="super">nd</hi>
     <orig reg="running">runing</orig>
     <orig reg="away">a way</orig> we <orig reg="passed">past</orig> on through them to where I
     thought the 7<hi rend="super">th</hi> was drawn up line when we got in 50 yards of them I found
     out my mistake for I could see the stars &amp; stripes plainly then the Col ordered a
     charge I made right for the flag and shot at it once but lost sight of it &amp; then <del
      hand="h1">met up</del>
     <orig reg="cought">cought</orig> up to a yankee <orig reg="running">runing</orig> like blazes I
     shot him through the back and <orig reg="tried">tryed</orig> to get him but he fell <orig
      reg="off">of</orig> of his horse and I went on to where the Col was he had halted near Bull
     run and <orig reg="tried">tryed</orig> to form the Regt on the top of the hill the other side
     of the Run there was 25 or 30 Yanks Capt Ford <orig reg="passed">past</orig> on &amp; told
     me to come on with the flag I passed on in the creek and the whole line fired at me but did not
     hurt <orig reg="anyone">any one</orig> but came all around us we charged up the hill and broke
     the line and then Capt Ford myself and two other men galloped off to left and captured 34
     yankees 8 horses &amp; two ambulances which were brought in to camp <pb n="3" entity="garb9c" pid="uva-lib:503036"/>
     8 of the men we <orig reg="brought">brout</orig> in I captured myself
     12 of them and the Ambulances I and one of the took together. In the first part of the fight I
     lost my old black hat and the first yankee I met I told him to give me his hat which he did the
     next one I met had a <orig reg="brand">bran</orig> new one so I traded with him Dear Father
      <unclear>Bunch</unclear> is about starting I can not write any more I do not think because I
     do not write often it is because I do not want to or that I do not <orig reg="wish"
     >whish</orig> to hear from you for the true reason of my not writing <del hand="h1">when I have
      time I two am tired when time do not think I am busy all the for often we do not see the
      wagons for 5 or 6 days</del> we are <orig reg="moving">moveing</orig> around all the time and
     we are very seldom with the wagons Give my love to Ma, Addie, Kate and sister Ellen and tell
     them all to write to me and write soon your self to your</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Affectionate son</salute>
     <signed>Tho M Garber</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
