<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A1102"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A1102">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: A. J. Gilkeson to Gilkeson's brother
                    (probably Hugh Gilkeson), October 6, 1862</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county a j gilkeson to gilkesons brother probably hugh gilkeson , october 6 1862</title>
        <author>A. J. Gilkeson</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A1102</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501905</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: A. J. Gilkeson to Gilkeson's brother (probably Hugh
                            Gilkeson), October 6, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county a j gilkeson to gilkesons brother probably hugh gilkeson , october 6 1862</title>
            <author>A. J. Gilkeson</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Hugh W. Gilkeson Collection,
                            SHC-052, Northwest Georgia Document Preservation Project, Shorter
                            College, Rome, Georgia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Northwest Georgia Document Preservation Project, Shorter College, Rome, Georgia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-10-06">1862-10-06</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Enlistment, Family, Home Front, Military Authority, National Government,
                        Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005">Summer 2005</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Douglas Michael O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A1102T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Gilkeson updates his brother on the health of his family and remarks upon the
                    excitement of the times. He then devotes considerable space to discussing
                    conscription and the reasons that he believes his brother should employ a
                    substitute (he emphasizes the need to stay home as a father).</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-10-06">Oct. 6<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1862</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Brother</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>David, a few days since, gave me yours of the 17 <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> and at the same
                    time, requested me to answer it, which I promised to do. I have neither written
                    to nor received a letter from you for a long time. I suppose your excuse and
                    mine for neglecting each other for so long a period are one and the same;
                        <unclear>viz</unclear>, we hear from each other through David. I have often
                    thought I would write, but really in the times of such excitement I am almost
                    unfit for <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig>. I often feel, particularly
                    after the occurrence of a battle or of a series of battles, that it will be
                    impossible for me to bear up against the excitement. But I at all times, feel so
                    restless and unsettled that I can scarcely compose myself to write at all.</p>
                <p>We are all in our usual health, as are<pb n="2"/> David and his family. Father
                    has been more troubled of late with the inflammation in his face than usual; but
                    I think it has not been near so bad as it was frequently in <orig reg="bygone"
                        >by-gone</orig> years. We have just gotten through with a very interesting
                    meeting of the <unclear>Synod</unclear> of Virginia. It assembled here on last
                    Wednesday evening and adjourned on Saturday evening. The subject of the
                    chaplaincy in the army and furnishing aid and comfort to our soldiers in various
                    ways occupied the greater part of their time. There were some very able and
                    interesting speeches made on the subject: some detailing their experience as
                    chaplains heretofore, and others, who have been within the enemy's lines, giving
                    a detailed account of the sufferings and indignities inflicted on our people by
                    the Yankees. But you will doubtless see an account of the proceedings of Synod
                    in the Central Presbyterian.</p>
                <p>You ask if the conscript law has been enforced in Virginia, and what are<pb n="3"
                    /> our plans when all between the ages of 35 &amp; 45 may be conscripted. I
                    think the first conscript bill has been pretty generally <orig reg="enforced"
                        >inforced</orig> here. And now all between the ages of 35 &amp; 45 are
                    liable to be called into service at any time. David employed a substitute, a
                    week or two since, for whom he paid One Thousand Dollars. I have not as yet, and
                    I think I will not; as I am satisfied that no surgeon will pronounce me fit for
                    duty in the field, and if not I <unclear>hear</unclear> from our Representation
                        (<abbr expan="Colonel">Col</abbr> Baldwin) that they cannot require any
                    other service of me. And in reference to your case I do no think you ought
                        <unclear>indicate</unclear> the circumstances, to think of going into
                    service. You must know that it is all important that you should remain at home
                    on account of your children <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> and your brother-in-law being in
                    the service, you having the control of his business, you will be, very likely,
                    exempted. But if you should not be exempted I think you ought not to hesitate<pb
                        n="4"/> to get a substitute. That is my decided conviction, and David and
                    Father unite with me in urging you to get one. I am satisfied that you cannot
                    stand the service; and if you attended it, your life will almost certainly be
                    the forfeit, although you may never be in a battle. Now a man must be governed
                    by the circumstances of the case: if he may be satisfied that he cannot stand
                    the service, and his family and friends require his presence at home, then by
                    all means let him employ a substitute. Now you may feel that you are not able to
                    pay for one: but reflect that you can much better afford to employ a substitue,
                    than your children can afford to be fatherless at this tender age. In addition
                    to that is the fact, that your presence at home, during the times that war will
                    probably last, will save you more than your have to pay for a substitue. Now
                    cannot you make us a visit this fall, or winter. I would be so glad to see you.
                    I am now a housekeeper, and will have so much more satisfaction with you now
                    than when you were here before. And then it would be such a gratification to
                    Father to see you once more. Make an effort to come, <orig reg="won't"
                    >wont</orig> you? Do write me immediately on <orig reg="receiving"
                    >recieving</orig> this, &amp; tell what you think of my suggestions.
                        <unclear>Sam</unclear> joins in much love to you and joins me in urging you
                    to pay us a visit. Give my love to your dear little <unclear>Amy</unclear>. Do
                    write at once.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours affectionately</salute>
                    <signed>A. <unclear>J</unclear>. Gilkeson</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
