<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A1117"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A1117">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: R. Buchanan to Buchanan's roommates,
                    February 12, 1867</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county r buchanan to buchanans roommates, february 12 1867</title>
        <author>Buchanan, R.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">13</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A1117</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501920</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: R. Buchanan to Buchanan's roommates, February 12,
                            1867</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county r buchanan to buchanans roommates, february 12 1867</title>
            <author>R. Buchanan</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Smiley Family Papers, Accession
                            #1807, Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library,
                            Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1867-02-12">1867-02-12</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>African Americans, Arts/Leisure, Family, Medicine/Hospitals, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005">Summer 2005</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A1117T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Buchanan describes a recent party, delivers generally lighthearted news about
                    acquaintances, and accuses an African-American woman of careless treatment of a
                    child.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1867-02-12">Feb 12<hi rend="super"><hi rend="underline">th</hi></hi>/67</date>
                        <name type="place">Home Lensdagene</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My dear Roommates</salute>
                </opener>

                <p> I <hi rend="underline">seat</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">myself</hi> this evening to hold a short conversation with
                    you all. How are you "one and all" getting along in the <hi rend="underline">old</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">Maidens</hi> establishment, suppose Miss Baldwin is
                    pleasant as ever. Does she ever get <hi rend="underline">Spotty</hi> on her back
                    now? I hope not. I suppose she looked very <unclear>
                        <hi rend="underline">disconsolable</hi>
                    </unclear> after I left-I <orig reg="haven't">hav'nt</orig> a doubt but my
                    departure cast a <hi rend="underline">gloom</hi> over the house. Well I must
                    stop this &amp; tell you about the party, now Lucie Tish Annie and Mary all
                    get round the stove with you "little feet on it as to be comfortable and put a
                        <unclear>book</unclear> on the arm &amp; then set" the lamp on it, and I
                    will begin about the party (all ready). Well we arrived at uncle James's about
                    five and intended coming on home that night but Charlie and Annie's Billie came
                    down to the road and said we should stay all night and go to the party. Father
                    at last consented, and we drove up and spent the night. In the first place we
                    had <orig reg="hardly">harly</orig> stopped till Billie asked how his <hi
                        rend="underline">little</hi> Annie was <hi rend="underline">getting</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">along</hi>, when I went in the house, there sat two or
                    three <orig reg="gentlemen">gentleman</orig>, you may know I was considerably
                    frustrated but how some ever I stood the trial of being introduced to them After
                    sitting awhile another gentleman came in. I felt very much agitated at being
                    among so many (<hi rend="underline">males</hi>). As the evening advanced, supper
                    was announced, need I tell an elegant one aunt R never has an<del hand="h1"
                    >n</del>y other kind. And then about "7<hi rend="super">o</hi>clock" we started
                    to the party. I was mounted behind Billie__"<pb n="2"/> Cousin Hannah behind Mr
                    Dunlap one of the Brownsburg students who came home with Charlie that evening.
                    You can fancy us riding across a cornfield with <unclear>cornstocks</unclear>
                    higher than your he<add hand="h1" place="inline">a</add>d. I forgot to tell you
                    how the rest of our party went. Charlie Mr Clemman (<unclear>Lew</unclear>) Mr
                    Martin went in an old sleigh to break the road, we went up the <hi
                        rend="underline">steepest</hi> hill you ever saw, <unclear>sow</unclear>
                    dreadful deep. I was afraid I would pull Billie's shirt, drawers, and <orig
                        reg="everything">every <hi rend="underline">thing</hi></orig>
                    <hi rend="underline">else</hi> off before we got up the hill. But we got up at
                    last, and arrived at the party without accidents happening. When we went in they
                    were sitting all around the room, I was completely surprised to see so many
                    there, when Cousin Hannah and me went in the parlor I got with Mary Smiley the
                    first person. We had not been in but a few <del hand="h1">days</del> minutes
                    when they commenced playing some kind of a thing, that you seized the boys by
                    the arms and dragged them across the <hi rend="underline">rooms</hi>. The boys
                    began to come around on our side, and <hi rend="underline">asking</hi> the <hi
                        rend="underline">gals</hi> to promenade the floor <hi rend="underline"
                        >wid</hi>-<hi rend="underline">em</hi>. I told Mary I thought we had better
                    take a promenade on the porch (I told Mary out there about the cat fainting)
                        <orig reg="stayed">staid</orig> a few minutes went in and sad
                        <unclear>stower</unclear>, and lo! and behold! a feller asked me to take his
                    arms. I was terribly excited and if it had not been for the support of his arm I
                        <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know what I might have done. I tell you he was
                    a mighty nice little fellow. There was about <hi rend="underline">28</hi> or <hi
                        rend="underline">30</hi> there - just enough to enjoy themselves they were
                    all very sociable. I tell you I never was at a party where I enjoyed myself like
                    I did there, (we had good things to eat too) We played all kinds of kissing
                    plays, I always got around the kissing part as <hi rend="underline">quickly</hi>
                    as <hi rend="underline">possible</hi>, managed to kiss my Cousins, I <orig
                        reg="know">now</orig> you all are tired reading this awful<pb n="3"/> letter
                    - especially this description of the party. But please bear with me a little
                    longer. I want to tell you about <hi rend="underline">little</hi> Thompson
                    Brower, Ok! Tish he <unclear>pintedly</unclear> cut around Marty that night, you
                    ought to have seen him jumping over the floor <del hand="h1">he</del> cutting
                    some kind of a step. I had a mind to ask him if it was what they call the <hi
                        rend="underline">Grecian</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">bend</hi> I was dreadfully afraid he would slip and split
                    himself up from the <orig reg="center">centre</orig> of <hi rend="underline"
                        >gravity</hi>, you all know where that is, Annie does I know. I will tell
                    you one more incident of the party &amp; close on the subject as I went to
                    get on when we started I mounted the <unclear>stile</unclear> a plank broke
                    which occassioned considerable laughter - I tried again and the <hi
                        rend="underline">abominable</hi> old plank broke again I will have you all
                    to comment on my misfortune; we got home <unclear>or</unclear> to <orig
                        reg="uncle's">uncles</orig> half past 2 in the morning. The next morning
                    when we were ready to start (we were all in aunts' room) Cousin Hannah came to
                    the door &amp; called me out, I went out and there stood aunt killing
                    herself laughing said one of the <unclear>oreges</unclear> women was going to
                    have a little one, said she had just taken sick, while we were talking (<hi
                        rend="underline">babie</hi>) <unclear>hollored</unclear>
                    <hi rend="underline">recken it was hurtin</hi> / Uncle James, Father Mr Dunlap,
                    Billie &amp; Charlie were in the room just over her. Cousin Hanna came and
                    called Uncle James to take them out of that room so they went out pretty quick,
                    cousin Hannah said the <hi rend="underline">nigger</hi> woman had the thing
                    sitting on the floor, what do you think of that. I will try and stop on this
                    subject and write something else. I want you all to decide about an offer which
                    a gentleman sent me a few days ago. He sent me word in the first place he would
                    give me $10.00<pb n="4"/> in Confederate <orig reg="money">monie</orig> for a
                    composition told him <unclear>or</unclear> sent him word it would have to be <hi
                        rend="underline">greenbacks</hi>. He returned the answer he did not have the
                        <hi rend="underline">change</hi> but would give himself for one, the
                    question is will <add hand="h1" place="inline">I</add> accept the offer I want
                        <hi rend="underline">your</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">alls</hi> advice on the subject, of course I expect it to
                    be <hi rend="underline">confidential</hi>. I have not been to <hi
                        rend="underline">meeting</hi> since I came home, weather has been too
                    inclement &amp; I am so <hi rend="underline">
                        <unclear>skeary</unclear>
                    </hi> about the house. <unclear>Mathi</unclear> said she was going to send the
                        <orig reg="wagon">waggon</orig> around to take Sue &amp; me to preaching
                    wish she would if <hi rend="underline">her</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">brother</hi> would drive. Well Lucie I might as well tell
                    you that I lost that note you gave me for your Ma it was in my cloak pocket
                    &amp; I suppose it dropped out I looked <orig reg="everywhere">every
                    where</orig> for it. I am very sorry but I will cut a cuff out and take to your
                    Ma next Sunday I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> think you put <orig
                        reg="anything">any thing</orig> in the note except that. I will tell your Ma
                    how you wanted it made. I hope you <orig reg="won't">wont</orig> think hard of
                    it I could not help it. Lucie I know you will like to hear about Robert Morrison
                    &amp; James M<hi rend="super">c</hi>nutt, they are in Brownsburg studying
                        <hi rend="underline">medicine</hi>, so it is no longer Jim M<hi rend="super"
                        >c</hi>nutt &amp; Bob Morrison but <abbr expan="Doctor">Dr</abbr> M<hi
                        rend="super">c</hi>Nutt &amp; <abbr expan="Doctor">Dr</abbr> Morrison;
                    wonder where they will practice? I am afraid Bob's <hi rend="underline">health</hi>
                    <orig reg="won't">wont</orig> stand it; you know he is delicate. Lucie you
                    remember I told you I would transfer my correspondents to you a gentleman
                    offered himself to write to you he asked me to let him write to you, He is the
                    one that I used to get letters from every Thursday, you <orig reg="don't"
                    >dont</orig> know what <hi rend="underline">pretty</hi> things he said about you
                    I told him I would transfer to you any correspondence. I must stop as it is
                    bedtime please all excuse this miserable letter write so I will get a letter
                    next Wednesday, my love to you all Mary, Annie, Tish, and Lucie <orig
                        reg="don't">dont</orig> let <orig reg="anyone">any one</orig> but the girls
                    in your room [continued at top of first page] Give my best love to the girls in
                        <orig reg="Nelie's">Nelies</orig> room and to Lucie &amp; Ella. And last
                    but not least give my love to my dear Lizzie tell her I will write to her next
                    week, hope she passed her examination, If you all let <orig reg="anyone">any
                    one</orig> see this I never will write to you again</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>I remain your <hi rend="underline">friend</hi>
                        <hi rend="underline">till</hi>
                        <hi rend="underline">death</hi></salute>
                    <signed>R Buchanan</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
