<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A1122"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A1122">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Mary A. Smiley to Unknown, October
                    4, 1865</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county mary a smiley to unknown, october 4 1865</title>
        <author>Smiley, Mary A.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A1122</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501925</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Mary A. Smiley to Unknown, October 4, 1865</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county mary a smiley to unknown, october 4 1865</title>
            <author>Mary A. Smiley</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Smiley Family Papers, Accession
                            #1807, Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library,
                            Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1865-10-04">1865-10-04</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Arts/Leisure, Church/Religious Activity</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005">Summer 2005</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A1122T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Smiley ponders the concept and meaning of beauty.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>

                <p> The science which treats of the beautiful is called aesthetics. To define what
                    the beautiful is, is a question hard to answer properly. It does not consist
                    merely in perfect figure or colors for we consider many things beautiful that
                    have neither. There are various opinions as to what our ideas of the beautiful
                    are to be <hi rend="underline">
                        <orig reg="referred">refered</orig>
                    </hi>. Some make it a feeling or sensation others <del hand="h1">to</del><add
                        hand="h1" place="inline">an</add> association &amp; again others <del
                        hand="h1">to</del> expression. These all lie within or in the mind. Then
                    again there are those who refer it entirely to the external, to novelty,
                    utility, unity and order or proportion. Still we know from our own mind that it
                    does not consist altogether in any of these, as for instance novelty does not
                    always please at first sight and <add hand="h1" place="inline">to</add> again
                        <add hand="h1" place="inline">with</add> its opposite. So also it may be
                    proved of the other theories. The true meaning does not lie in any one of these
                    different theories but rather in a combination. The question is asked is beauty
                    something objective or subjective. Is the beautiful merely an emotion? We know
                    it excites a pleasant emotion within us, but the beauty does not consist in
                    this. If it did then the beauty would be in us and not in the object. To speak
                    and think of the beauty of objects is the most natural and sensible view of the
                    question. There are objects which when viewed call forth these emotions of
                    beauty in all. The child who has never before viewed a certain <add hand="h1"
                        place="inline">beautiful</add> object has as lively emotions of its beauty
                    as those who are familiar with it. So it cannot be association merely that makes
                        <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig> beautiful. The ideas of the beautiful
                    are not alike in all. There is a difference in thought, education, custom
                    &amp;c which makes the effect produced by a beautiful object very different
                    in differnt individuals. There is by no means a perfect uniformity in the efect
                    produced on the mind by the same object. If the beauty of an object <del
                        hand="h1">co</del>exists in the mind of the beholder only, it follows then
                    that there would be no beauty were there no observers<pb n="2"/> There is an
                    intimate connection between the emotions produced on the mind and the objects
                    themselves. There is another theory mentioned, called the spiritual, which makes
                    beauty consist not in matter as such, nor in any mere arrangement of it in stuff
                    considered, but in the manifestation or expression under these forms of the
                    higher, the hidden spiritual nature or element, appealing thus to our own
                    spiritual nature which is thereby awakened to sympathy. It argues there is
                    something in the different kinds of matter that expresses to us the higher and
                    spiritual principle which is the life and soul of <unclear>thing</unclear> The
                    perfection of beauty is not to be found in any of the different scales of matter
                    but is found in God alone. There are considerations in favor of the spiritual
                    theory In nature and art the beautiful expresses something and in this lies much
                    of their beauty. God speaks to us through them, silently but <orig
                        reg="nonetheless">none the less</orig> doesn't come from Him. The
                    impressions of beauty are perceived by the senses and through them conveyed is
                    the mind. The power of judging of and selecting the beautiful is called taste.
                    Here again there has been a variety of opinions in reference to the exact
                    definition of taste. The definition given is, the power of judging and
                    discriminating objects whether beautiful or sublime in nature or art. All
                    nations possess taste of some kind though often not good taste. Good taste
                    depends very much on cultivation by education and exercise.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed>Mary A Smiley</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript"/>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1865-10-04">
                            <hi rend="underline">Oct 4<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1865</hi>
                        </date>
                    </dateline>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
