<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A1405"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A1405">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta: D. C. Snyder to Rachel Snyder, January 16,
                    1865</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta d c snyder to rachel snyder, january 16 1865</title>
        <author>Snyder, D. C.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Unknown</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Kid W.</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes </extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A1405</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501944</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: D. C. Snyder to Rachel Snyder, January 16, 1865</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta d c snyder to rachel snyder, january 16 1865</title>
            <author>D. C. Snyder</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Unknown pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: D. C. Snyder Letters, Source collection unknown</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note><p>Originally cited as coming from James Madison Univeristy holdings</p></note>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
          <p><!--Used with permission from James Madison University--></p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1865-01-16">1865-01-16</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Death/Casualties, Military Authority, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005">Summer 2005</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A1405T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Snyder describes the burning of a local's barn. Citing the cause as accidental,
                    he notes the family's losses. He passes along news of a Confederate raid on a
                    Union garrison.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1865-01-16">Monday Morning, <abbr expan="January">Jan.</abbr>
                            16, 1865</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>

                <p>Not having an opportunity to send my Letter off I have concluded to add a few
                    lines at my leisure this morning as I think I can send off today. I intended
                    writing you yesterday, dear Rachel, but circumstances did not suit. After
                    getting through with breakfast I proposed to Marcus Irwin to go to church and we
                    did so and had an excellent sermon too. After church I became interested in a
                    book and read until dark. Jimmy, Marcus, Mr. Hawse and myself then concluded we
                    would go over to a house near camp and sit a few moments in order to return
                    thanks for kindness received from the family (as they had sent us a pie, milk
                    and apples). We had scarcely taken our seats until in came his daughter
                    screaming that their barn was on fire. And so it was and we ran to it but too
                    late to save the poor horses. Four of them consumed and all of his hay, straw,
                    corn, wheat, farming tools, wagons and harness, carriage and harness, and
                    everything useful about a farm. It was the greatest difficulty that we saved his
                    house.</p>

                <p>Poor family. I feel so sorry for them and oh the distressed look of some of its
                    members last night still are fresh in my mind. It was the result of carelessness
                    on the part of someone smoking or else the work of an incendiary. It was a pity
                    indeed to see the destruction of property and suffering of the poor horses.</p>

                <p>I learn that Rosser reports by courier this morning the success of his
                    expedition, having taken the Garrison at Beverly consisting of over 500 Yankees,
                    a large quantity of stores of different kinds, etc. They will return today. He
                    lost 5 men killed and 15 wounded. None from this <abbr expan="Regiment"
                    >Reg't</abbr>.</p>

                <p>I am glad to inform you that I <abbr expan="received">rec'd</abbr> a Letter
                    yesterday from John and he is once more at work in his office with the prospect
                    of remaining. He will not be called out until in the Spring, if at all. I am
                    truly glad to know it and trust if the necessity arises for your going to <abbr
                        expan="Richmond">R.</abbr> it may tend to render your visit more pleasant.</p>

                <p>I think in my next letter I can give you some positive idea of what you can
                    depend on, and then if you think best to go to <abbr expan="Richmond">R.</abbr>
                    you can do so. I will know, I suppose, if <abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> H.
                    is going off and what I can depend on.</p>

                <p>If you go out take my suit and the other coat, too, that you made the 1st year of
                    the war. I will need it next winter. I will close again and hope to send out and
                    if not will add more.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Love to the children and all and believe me as ever Your Aff. Husband,</salute>
                    <signed>D.C.S.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
