<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2005"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A2005">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: William B. Gallaher to E. C. Gallaher, [undated]</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county william b gallaher to e c gallaher, undated</title>
        <author>Gallaher, William B.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Susanna Michele Lee</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Susanna Michele Lee</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A2005</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501978</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>
          <p>This letter was transcribed from another transcribed copy, and William B. Gallaher's
      mother's name was taken from the census.</p>
        </note>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: William B. Gallaher to E. C. Gallaher, [undated]</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county william b gallaher to e c gallaher, undated</title>
            <author>William B. Gallaher</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>1 page</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William B. Gallaher Letters, Waynesboro Public
       Library Collection, Waynesboro, Virginia.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Waynesboro Public Library Collection, Waynesboro, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value=""/>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Camp Life, Family, Medicine/Hospitals, Troop Movement, Women, Church/Religious Activity</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A2005T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>William B. Gallaher writes to his mother about his father's visit, his new commission, the
     food in camp, his good behavior, his religious readings, getting his washing done, and
     interactions with old acquaintances. He assures his mother that with the provisions sent from
     home and gifts from the "country people" the soldiers "live very well."</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">E. C. Gallaher</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <name type="place">Camp Clover Berkely Co VA at Hainsville</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Ma</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>Pa got here day before yesterday. I was very glad to see him. I did not look for him so soon.
     I am very glad to hear that you are all well &amp; getting on so well. Ma I will get a
     commission as soon as Pa goes home &amp; can send it to me. I will have no difficulty in
     getting it. Capt Patrick gave him the certificate. I am so much pleased at getting it &amp;
     will try &amp; do my duty. I will have a very good time &amp; will get $70 or 80
     dollars per month. The Capt told Pa that he wanted me to stay with him in his tent. I am very
     much obliged to you &amp; Sallie for the provisions shirt you sent me &amp; am happy to
     know that my mother don't forget her big boy as you sometimes call me. I read the tract you
     sent me &amp; will read a portion of my Bible &amp; the book Sallie put in my trunk
     everyday. I am very well &amp; am as well satisfied as I could be under the circumstances.
     Of course I would like to be with you all &amp; hope if spared by Providence to be at some
     future day I may get up in August to see you all. Cousin Joe Rawlins his wife Mollie &amp;
     his little girl came down day before yesterday to see me &amp; the Shepherdstown troop.
     They brought me a large basket of pies pound cake &amp; rusks &amp; said I must be sure
     &amp; come up to see them. Mrs Rawlins says she would like to see you &amp; Sallie. Mr
     Rawlins talked of taking Mrs Rawlins &amp; Mollie up to see you. I told them to be sure and
     go especially if there was any danger here. I was introduced to Capt Morgan of Shepherdstown
     &amp; Dr Ganns who is a Lieut in the same company. He said he would have never known that I
     was Billy Gallaher. I know a good many of the Shepherdstown Company. I was introduced to Oliver
     Sherman. I suppose you know him he is with Capt Morgan's Company. It seems almost like home to
     me. I see so many acquaintances here. There was Augusta Foot Companies came here yesterday. It
     is said the whole Augusta Regt. will be here today commanded by Col Hanger. Ned Waddell
     &amp; John Lipscomb will be with them. Dr King has not arrived yet he stopped at the Ferry
     will be up in a day or two. There is some talk of us going to Shepherdstown soon but I don't
     know that it is so. We are all anxious to go there. Pa seems at home here he knows just near
     every person about here. He will leave tomorrow for Martinsburgh stay a day there &amp;
     then go to Shepherdstown. He will stay two or three days &amp; then go to the Ferry
     &amp; from there home. I have as many clothes as I need this summer. I am glad to hear
     Clinton &amp; Chas are doing so well. I think Clinton will make a business man if he will
     be attentive. We <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> get much news here. We get the mail from the
     Ferry everyday or two it is brought up by our men on horseback. I get my washing done here at
     Hainsville. There is a daughter of Polly Millers near Darffields here. She is married. I dont
     know her husbands name but I think it is Kearney. She washes my clothes 5 cents for a shirt the
     same for drawers &amp; she says she knows you well that she used to nurse me. I have no
     difficulty getting the washing done. James Irvine, Elliott Fishburne Virginia guys Norman
     Hanger Chas L Patterson &amp; myself are in the same tent &amp; I suppose Dr King will
     come in with us. We have the best behaved boys in the camps in our tent. Elliott is looking as
     well as ever. I will not have much use for my white pants they get dirty so soon but will keep
     them to wear when I call on the ladies. I got the other box of provisions &amp; enjoyed
     them very much. The boys were wondering how my pies kept from moulding &amp; I told them it
     was putting greased paper on them. We live very well. When we get in the country we go to the
     farm houses &amp; get as much as we can eat. Some of the boys had strawberries given them
     by the country people. I will get some the next time I go out if I can. Ma you must excuse bad
     writing my paper is not ruled very well. I will write often to you. Write soon. Give my love to
     all kiss the little folks for me. Give my respect to all. God Bless you all.</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your affect son</salute>
     <signed>W B Gallaher</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
