<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2001"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A2001">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: William B. Gallaher to E. C. Gallaher, May 15,
     1861</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county william b gallaher to e c gallaher, may 15 1861</title>
        <author>Gallaher, William B.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Susanna Michele Lee</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Susanna Michele Lee</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A2001</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501974</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>
          <p>This letter was transcribed from another transcribed copy. William B. Gallaher's mother's
      name was taken from the 1860 population census.</p>
        </note>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: William B. Gallaher to E.C. Gallaher, May 15, 1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county william b gallaher to e c gallaher, may 15 1861</title>
            <author>William B. Gallaher</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>1 page</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William B. Gallaher Letters, Waynesboro Public
       Library Collection, Waynesboro, Virginia.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Waynesboro Public Library Collection, Waynesboro, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1861-05-15">1861-05-15</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Camp Life, Enlistment, Family, Home front, Troop Movement</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A2001T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>William B. Gallaher describes his satisfaction with camp life and his anticipation of troop
     movement. He cautions his mother to "keep a sharp look out" on the farm yard and stable.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">E.C. Gallaher</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1861-05-15">May 15, 1861</date>
      <name type="place">Harpers Ferry</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Ma</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I got here today and found all well &amp; very glad to see me and got my office. Capt
     Patrick seemed glad to see me he said he intended writing to Pa but had been very busy. I was
     about leaving for Shepherdstown when we got orders to get ready to leave at once but after we
     were told to march at 8 oclock tomorrow morning. I expect we will go to Shepherdstown. Everyone
     is talking about the way they were treated at Shepherdstown &amp; are anxious to go there
     again they were so well treated. I will have no difficulty in getting along. I went down to see
     Eddie Waddell. He was glad to see me &amp; said he wished he was in our company. Saw also
     Lipscomb. Both are looking well. Camp life seems to agree with them. I left Clinton at
     Stroudsburgh &amp; gave him money to pay his way home. I wish he could have come to the
     Ferry. There is about 11000 men here now. You can see tents &amp; soldiers all over the
     place. We are in camp in a large brick house in the upper part of Bolivar. It is only a few
     hundred yards to Capt Baylors company. There is a regiment of 1100 men just left here for
     Shepherdstown or Martinsburg. I will write you from where I am to go. I think to Shepheredstown
     I will go &amp; see the folks. Tell Pa I will write to him next &amp; will write to you
     all the first chance I have. The Capt myself &amp; the officers all sleep in the same room.
     I will sleep with Irvine. I am very well pleased with camp life. Give my love to all. Excuse
     this short &amp; badly written letter as I am very busy fixing things. I am very glad you
     put so many little articles in my trunk. Write soon. I got Charley letter with no trouble and a
     piece of the Dispatch. I will read it and take good care of myself. You need have no fears of
     me keeping bad company or anything of that kind.</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>From your affectionate son</salute>
     <signed>W B Gallaher</signed>
     <seg type="postscript">Kiss the little folks for me. My horse stood the travel very well. I had
      her put on the cart at Winchester &amp; brought down. It did not cost me much. Give my
      respect to all. Write soon.<lb/> Your son<lb/>William <lb/> Tell Pa to keep a sharp look out
      in the farm yard &amp; at the stable. I have never seen anything wrong but if they are so
      inclined they have a very good chance. The reason Guy wrote to me to come he could not enlist
      as a substitute unless he would enlist for 12 months &amp; he said he did not want me to
      lose my place. He is going home Monday &amp; will be back in a week &amp; join our
      company or get an appointment as he is trying very hard to get the adjutants place in the
      Regiment. I will get Capt Patrick to sign the certificate for my horse &amp; send to you
      next week.<lb/>
      <lb/>Your son<lb/>William <lb/> Love to all. Tell Mr. Evans to make me a pair shoes like the
      ones he made me &amp; send down with Ed Waddells. They are too narrow at the toes. I can
      get along with the boots.</seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
