<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2504"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A2504">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, July
     18, 1861</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, july 18 1861</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A2504</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501993</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, July 18, 1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, july 18 1861</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>2 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D.C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1861-07-18">1861-07-18</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Prisons/Prisoners, Military Authority, National Government, Family, Church/Religious
      Activity, Troop Movement, Women, Home Front, Slavery, African Americans</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A2504T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss describes the return of paroled prisoners captured in a recent battle. He also
     gives his wife instructions concerning items he wishes sent to him.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Sara A. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1861-07-18">July 18<hi rend="super">th </hi> 1861</date>
      <name type="place">Monterey, Va.</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Dear Wife:</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>Mrs. Allen &amp; Bishop Glossbrenner &amp; Mr. Arnold passed through here today on
     their way to the Cavalry came 4 miles beyond at <unclear>Hevaner's</unclear> Store and said
     they were going back tomorrow &amp; I must write by them -- so I will write a little,
     though I wrote only a day or so ago. We are getting quite rested and are feeling very well now,
     though sorry that so many of our brave boys were taken prisoners, though they will all get
     home, I suppose without any doubt for <orig reg="McClellan">McLelland</orig> sent a messenger
     here to say that he would send back our prisoners if we would send ten wagons &amp; meet
     the ten he would send half way --there are some 700 of our men prisoners -- they would be glad
     to get home, though it will be mortifying to them to leave their companies &amp; go home
     excluded from aiding in the defence of their homes &amp; country. We are very anxious to
     get some of our officers back &amp; are petitioning the President to exchange some of the
     prisoners we have for our own men who will be released on <orig reg="parole">porol</orig>. I
     want you to get me out some 20 sheets of my drawing paper, wrap it up in one of the large brown
     sheets you will find at the same place, that is in the middle case of the lower part of the
     book case -- You may send me a half dozen of my shirt collars -- do not send the new ones -- I
     got a good overcoat today from the public stores -- have a plenty of socks -- you may get some
     calico -- good strong, dark figure -- long in the tails, collar of the same sewed on the shirt
     &amp; make me two shirts - - I have got two <abbr expan="handkerchiefs">hdkfs</abbr> -- You
     may send me my horn protractor &amp; the case the flat one in which I keep amy instruments
     -- I shall send to Staunton and get some pencils -- direct -- I can get them sooner, than any
     other way. I was today made acting Adjutant of the Regiment, but I do not desire to hold that
     office -- and I expect when Gen. Lee comes, and that will be as soon as Sunday, I shall be
     attached to his staff as Topographer. I regretted the loss of my sweet little Testament, the
     gift of Mr. Gilbert at the time of our marriage, as much as of anything I left behind, and next
     the loss of my fine Barometer and then of my old blue cloak -- I could almost cry at the loss
     of such an old &amp; faithful friend -- one that has been my constant companion for 14
     years -- has shielded myself, my bosom friend &amp; my children from the storm &amp;
     comforted over many a weary mile -- But I intend to have it back -- we took the road back today
     -- the Georgia Regiment leading at noon -- <pb n="2"/> I suppose the rest of us will follow as
     soon as Lee comes on -- One man got back today from the flight -- a Mr. Burwell, a lawyer of
     Richmond -- he exchanged clothes with a mountaineer -- got an old hat, red shirt, patched pants
     &amp;c -- just such a suit as you can see any Pendleton wagoner have on and passed himself
     for a man going to <unclear>salt</unclear> sheep -- cutting off his mustache -- his friends
      <orig reg="did">died</orig> not know him so complete was the metamorphosis -- he passed
     through the midst of the enemy -- It was unfortunate that Gen. Garnett did not get correct
     information from us in time or we would have all gotten together and safely moved off --
     Garnett's men are coming towards us slowly, the officers <unclear>have</unclear> come on in
     advance and are here now -- We expect Garnett's body tomorrow and the men the enemy took. The
     scouts of the enemy now come to within some 25 miles of us, but I do not think they will get
     any nearer. </p>
    <p> If a good chance offers you may send me a little butter &amp; cake and some pickles from
     home &amp; a few good potatoes -- we have good bread rice, coffee, sugar &amp; many
     things that are sent to our camp -- no special lack of any thing and all are becoming well
     supplied. I am glad you soon got some of my letters -- it almost broke my heart to read the one
     when you thought me lost -- do not despond -- I trust we shall soon conquer a piece &amp;
     all return to our homes and enjoy the real pleasures of quiet &amp; rest they only offer
     &amp; I trust in the God of justice to vindicate our cause. Be cheerful &amp; do not
     despond, my dear, all will yet be well -- train on our darlings as I know you do &amp; make
     them good, obedient and loveable -- O! I would like to spend one day with you. I forgot to tell
     Nelson I stuck to my gun, flask &amp; ammunition &amp; should have used it fatally if
     our path had been impeded. I want to write to Allie &amp; will soon I hope she will write
     to me -- I have but little leisure I want to write too to my excellent friend Harvey Bear
     &amp; the good fellows Henry Sieg &amp; C. Bear -- &amp; Mr. Stover &amp; all
     -- and <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> be jealous how is Miss Kate &amp;c &amp;c. I may
     write more in the morning -- How fares the Sunday School -- I am tired, have been busy all day
     &amp; must now retire -- By the way send me a blacking brush -- there are a plenty of them
     about home, one with a handle. If I go on, as I hope to tell Nelson, I shall want William to go
     along as a cook for a mess. Nearly all the servants in the camp got back safely &amp; they
     were permitted by McL to go where they pleased. Write soon -- Good bye God bless you -- </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Truly,</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
     <seg type="postscript">I have not <abbr expan="received">recd.</abbr> what you sent to me --
      please say by whom -- and the rest by some one that will bring direct to me --</seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
