<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2518"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A2518">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, March
     21, 1862</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, march 21 1862</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A2518</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502007</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, March 21, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, march 21 1862</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>2 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D.C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-03-21">1862-03-21</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Slavery, African Americans, Family, Military Authority, Enlistment, Desertion/Leave, Camp
      Life</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A2518T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss describes the army's current encampment, the weather, and the mustering in of
     militia units.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Sara A. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-03-21">March 21<hi rend="super">st</hi> 1862</date>
      <name type="place">Gen. <unclear>Mecin's</unclear> -- near Mt. Jackson Va. Shenandoah
       Co.</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Dear Wife --</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>We have now been a day &amp; a half here at the Old <orig reg="Steenberger's"
      >Steenbergers</orig> place, the most magnificent farm in Va - - some 1100 acres of level
     meadowland, the house a fine stone one in the 1<hi rend="super">st </hi> terrace above the
     level &amp; a mile back from the turnpike. Mrs. <unclear>Mecin</unclear> is a sister of
     Mason Jordan -- they sent their servants to Lynchburg but 9 ran away the day before they were
     to leave. Mason has gone home to see about his sisters. We had 2 days of fine weather to come
     here in &amp; 1 bad. We stayed the 2<hi rend="super">nd</hi> night at Harrisonburg, at the
     Mill there -- I went to <unclear>Frick's</unclear> with Col. Sproul -- we had <orig reg="a"
      >&amp;</orig> nice time, the next night we were two miles from New Market at Dr.
     Williamson's &amp; the next day came here. I have been very busy &amp; have had to
     write a great deal -- but expect to get through tomorrow, when I shall be a private I suppose
     as there are not men enough for a <abbr expan="Regiment">Regt</abbr> &amp; so the Col. does
     not command, but he has offered me the Adjutancy of the <abbr expan="Regiment">Regt</abbr> when
     made up -- But Baylor says Gen. Jackson will have me detailed on <abbr expan="Engineer"
     >Eng.</abbr> Duty -- The Militia were partly mustered in today, by Col. Baylor -- they are put
     into companies of 100. Some of the men that ran away from home were caught by Ashby's Cavalry
     and brought here to jail -- Gen. Jackson has been falling back but today he moved forward. It
     is reported that the enemy has fallen back, owing to a rebellion in Maryland, but there's no
     finding <pb n="2"/> out what the truth is.</p>

    <p>22<hi rend="super">nd</hi>
     <unclear>this</unclear> morning some improvement in the weather, yesterday was very bad, the
     mud is deep, but we are very well cared for, as we have houses to say in, though crowded. There
     are about <unclear>12</unclear> of us that sleep in one room, with all sorts of sleeping
     fixings &amp; some with no sleeping fixings. Gen. Jackson called up to see us yesterday, he
     looks care worn, though he is a very pleasant man. I went down to see him the day we got here
     he is very busy -- (pen again). I called at Mr. Ruffner's the morning we left Harrisonburg, for
     a few minutes -- he gave me a very nice pocket compass -- &amp; letters to some of his
     friends here -- He wants my Johnston's Physical Atlas &amp; if he sends for it do it u p
     very carefully &amp; send it. See that the Martin boys return my Marlborough &amp;
     Alison if they go away. Tell them I have not yet seen their father, or the Hardy Militia. I
     hope you are well yet - - I am in much suspense about you all &amp; do not know when I
     shall hear from you -- the mails are so deranged -- half of the time the mail bags are not
     brought Write to me by private hands if you hear of any one coming here -- They are falling
     every day -- the arresting of some starts the others. They have taken the Bank away from
     Harrisonburg -- God bless you all -- kiss the dear children for Pa -- </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your <abbr expan="affectionate">aff.</abbr> husband</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
     <seg type="postscript">I am very well indeed -- write if by mail to care of Lt. Col.
       <unclear>W. S. H.</unclear> Baylor Mt. Jackson</seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
