<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2546"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A2546">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, July
     18, 1862</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, july 18 1862</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A2546</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502035</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, July 18, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, july 18 1862</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>2 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D.C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-07-18">1862-07-18</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Church/Religious Activity, Military Authority, Prisons/Prisoners, Troop Movement,
      Military Strategy</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A2546T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss describes his trip from Staunton to Gordonsville, conditions in the camp there, and
     the possibilities for future battles.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Sara A. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-07-18">Friday July 18<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1862</date>
      <name type="place">Gordonsville Va.</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My <abbr expan="Dear">Dr</abbr> Wife:</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>We got here today, through the mud and rain &amp; have pitched our tent and are trying to
     get dry, though it is doubtful, if the rain continues, for the ground is very wet We came to
     Mechum's River the day we left Staunton, slept there in an empty house, soundly, after our long
     and weary ride in the hot sun, I think I never felt the sun as hot as it was coming up the Blue
     Ridge, when it caused a violent pain in my head, which I was afraid would be sunstroke, but we
     stopped at the Mountain House and <orig reg="stayed">staid</orig> several hours, got dinner,
     and then went to sleep, after <abbr expan="which">wh.</abbr> I felt better, and we went on
     through a heavy thunder shower that came up -- we rode some 30 miles. Thursday we came on
     through Charlottesville, across the S.W. Mts. on <abbr expan="which">wh.</abbr> Monticello is
     situated and then on nearly along the line of the Va. C.R.R. and spent the night with the Rev.
     Mr. Boyden, next neighbor to <abbr expan="William">Wm</abbr> C. Rives -- we were very kindly
     treated by him -- he is pastor of an episcopal church nearby; a beautiful <pb n="2"/> stone
     edifice, one of the neatest I ever saw -- We heard in the night that the Yankees were near
     Gordonsville, but find today that they are still some distance away, though threatening this
     direction -- Our cavalry brought in fourteen of them today, that they took. Gen. Jackson has
     not yet arrived, though I supposed he soon will -- The troops are coming in and some of them
     have gone out on the Orange and Alexandria Road -- the Cars went up to Staunton today, the
     first time for several days, so I suppose you will get the papers again now -- We are on the
     hard fodder line now -- some of the troops have not been fed for 24 hours as they were brought
     up on the cars and their supplies came by wagon -- or rather their wagons had to come up to
     them over the common roads. I saw young Blair, James today, some one of the boys had stolen his
     boots and he was barefooted -- so I found a pair of old shoes and gave them to him --</p>
    <p> I do not know what is to be done --There are all sorts of extravagant stories in circulation
     -- some say that Jackson is to have 80000 men and go to Pennsylvania by the way of Harrisburg
     -- and some that he is to go to Washington &amp;c &amp;c. But I do not presume to know
     anything about it as yet -- though I doubt not he will be allowed to have his own way -- You
     will see all the news there is, in the papers. I will write to you often, and you can write to
     me through Major H.M. Bell who is now the chief <abbr expan="Quarter  
 Master">Q.M.</abbr> at
     Staunton. You can keep my clothes until I write to you where to sent them. My Love to all God
     bless you and keep you safely -- </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your <abbr expan="Affectionate">Aff</abbr> husband</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
     <seg type="postscript">I wrote to you from Staunton -- and left the pitcher and letter at Dr.
      Young's</seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
