<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2549"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A2549">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, August
     3, 1862</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, august 3 1862</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A2549</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502038</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, August 3, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, august 3 1862</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>2 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D.C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-08-03">1862-08-03</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Family, Troop Movement, Home Front, Battle Description, Women, Enlistment, Military
      Authority, Medicine/Hospitals, Agriculture</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A2549T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss describes the Confederate camp at Mechanicsville, especially the surrounding
     countryside and the availability of supplies. He relates news of a skirmish, and reports that
     the Confederate forces are expanding in numbers.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     Mrs. Sara A. Hotchkiss<lb/> Churchville <lb/> Augusta Co <lb/> Va.<lb/> Maj. Bell will please
     forward &amp; oblige <lb/>J.H. <lb/> Aug. 3 1862
     <name type="recipient">Sara A. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-08-03">Sunday Morning, Aug. 3<hi rend="super">rd</hi> 1862</date>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My <abbr expan="Dear">Dr.</abbr> Wife:</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>In the quiet of this lovely sabbath morning my thoughts revert to my home and the loved ones
     there, and I can not refrain from writing you a few lines more, though all things invite to
     rest after the fatigue of a week, in which I have closely kept my tent, hard at work, all the
     time, preparing maps for future use -- if not immediate. We moved last Tuesday, from our camp 4
     miles N.E. of Gordonsville, on the road towards Orange <abbr expan="Court House">C.H.</abbr> to
     a camp at Mechanicsville 6 miles S.W. of Gordonsville, where we are now. This is a very
     pleasant region, sparsely settled, but having some very fine farms in it, and one from which we
     can draw some supplies, though at extravagant rates -- potatoes $5, onions $4. Butter $1. Eggs
     $1 &amp;c, war prices sure enough, but then we must live, and nothing is as good for the
     fatigues of a soldier's life as a hearty diet, nothing so good to keep off disease. We are in
     the grove of an old church, (the new one only a few steps off), under the shade of venerable
     trees and not far from good water -- the enemy is about 12 miles from us, and we enjoy
     comparative quiet, though there was a skirmish of Cavalry at Orange <abbr expan="Court House"
      >C.H.</abbr> yesterday, in which we had two killed and several taken prisoners, and also
     killed and took several of the enemy, driving and being driven in turn through Orange <abbr
      expan="Court  
 House">C.H.</abbr> I <abbr expan="received">recd.</abbr> your last letter, the
     one of last Sunday, in good time, and have thought, daily, of writing, but, as I <abbr
      expan="said">sd.</abbr> before, have been more than usually busy. I am very sorry your old
     complaint has come on you, but hope it will not continue, be very careful and do not exert
     yourself in the hot sun, as that aggravates it. We are all very much incensed at Pope's
     atrocious orders, and hope the day of retribution may soon come to him &amp; his vile crew.
     Our ranks are filling up with conscripts from the Carolinas, <abbr expan="Georgia">Ga.</abbr>
     &amp;c, and we have some reinforcements, so we are safe from any force that may be sent
     against us, and may take the offensive if the powers that be shall so ordain. I wish you would
     put up, carefully, in a small box, my bottle of Blue Ink and send it to me through Maj. Bell.
     Fix it up so it will not break, for it is very precious -- no more to be had. If the bottle is
     half full keep some of it in another bottle. Pope will <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> are tired of that game.
      <pb n="2"/> Our forces are augmenting and I suppose a blow will be struck somewhere -- Morgan
     telegraphed to Gen. A. P. Hill, here, a day or two ago, that he took 10000 stand of arms and
     destroyed 15 millions worth of property in his late raid, and that he went to within 4 miles of
      <orig reg="Cincinnati">Cincinnatti</orig> -- a pity he had not gone there and burnt the
     accursed hole up --</p>
    <p> The doctors are a hard crew generally, but it was thought the Staunton hospital was very
     well managed -- many of the men at Staunton have been brought away, and our sick in
     Charlottesville have been removed to Lynchburg. I will buy you the things you speak of if I can
     find them -- you will have to send to Staunton &amp; buy Sugar there, for it is just as
     dear elsewhere -- if I find any cheaper I will buy some -- Much love to all -- I am feeling
     very well indeed -- I shall look for my barrel of things soon -- Kisses for the wee things --
     Goodbye &amp; may God bless you all </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your <abbr expan="affectionate">aff.</abbr> husband</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
