<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2551"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A2551">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, August
     16, 1862</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, august 16 1862</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">11</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A2551</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502040</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, August 16, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, august 16 1862</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D.C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-08-16">1862-08-16</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Military Authority, Death/Casualties, Battle Description, Medicine/Hospitals, Patriotism,
      Desertion/Leave, Church/Religious Activity, Slavery, African Americans</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A2551T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss relates the results of the Battle of Cedar Run, including killed, wounded,
     prisoners and arms taken. He also describes the Federal efforts to find and bury their
    dead.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     Mrs. Sara A. Hotchkiss <lb/> Churchville <lb/> Augusta Co <lb/> Va -- <lb/> Maj Bell will
     please forward oblige -- <lb/> J.H. --
     <name type="recipient">Sara A. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-08-16">Saturday -- Aug. 16<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1862</date>
      <name type="place">Near Orange <abbr expan="Court House">C.H.</abbr></name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My <abbr expan="Dear">Dr.</abbr> Wife:</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>We are now again on the move -- Gen Lee is with us &amp; Gen. Longstreet &amp; a host
     of men &amp; I suppose we shall make a big move now -- I have been working very hard
     &amp; until quite late, as I have not been able to write you a long letter, as I intended
     -- but now while we are lying by the road side, waiting for the army to move on, I will write
     you from under a tree My barrel came, but, poor me, the bottom fell out of the pitcher
     &amp; the butter all melted &amp; greased the potatoes before they were cooked
     &amp; they have since taken the rot and all gone to corruption -- The bread was excellent
     -- I gave a loaf of it to the Gen -- who is very fond of light bread. The onions go finely
     &amp; I carry them, while on a march to quench thirst they do it admirably. I wrote to you
     the day after the battle of Cedar Run -- there was no fighting on Sunday -- we held the Battle
     field, gathered up our wounded, buried the dead, collected arms &amp; watched the movements
     of the enemy -- we had about 900 men killed &amp; wounded &amp; I see by the late
     northern papers that they admit a loss of 1500 killed &amp; wounded. It was a very hard
     fought battle and I felt very thankful that I escaped unhurt. Monday morning the surgeons of
     the enemy came out under a white flag to carry off their wounded -- who were still on the field
     -- &amp; just after they got them a large cavalry force was seen advancing -- Gen. J. E. B.
     Stuart (Cavalry Maj. Gen. -- the noted one) who was in our front -- sent word to them that if
     they advanced any further he would seize their ambulances -- and -- "Either <pb n="2"/> respect
     your flag &amp; go back, or come on -- It makes no difference which" They said --
      (<unclear>Bugard</unclear>, the Yank <abbr expan="Cavalry">Cav.</abbr> Gen. in command) that
     they would go back until they could see Gen. Pope &amp; they then asked for a truce until 2
     P.M. which was granted, &amp; they came &amp; gathered up their dead &amp; wounded
     while we kept gathering arms upon the same field. When they first came on, one of Siegle's
     staff began to gather arms too &amp; one of our officers told him that was contrary to the
     rules of a truce &amp; he got mad at it, when an officer of his own army came up &amp;
     wanted to know what he was doing &amp; by whose order -- he <abbr expan="said">sd</abbr> he
     was one of Gen. Siegle's men &amp; was gathering up those arms by his order -- he <orig
      reg="then">the</orig> cursed him &amp; told him Siegle had better send some one there that
     was not a d-d fool --. The fellow succumbed &amp; went off -- Many Yankee officers came to
     the field &amp; they &amp; our men conversed freely -- Many of them were quite sick of
     the war -- They asked to have the truce extended to 5 P.M. -- which we granted -- We then sent
     back our baggage train &amp; came back that night, unmolested, to near our old camp. Since
     the battle a good many deserters have come in from the enemy -- 12 at one time -- from Western
     Va -- they say that many of them intend to desert -- even whole Regiments -- Gen. Jackson
     paroled these men &amp; let them go home. One of the 5<hi rend="super">th</hi>
     <abbr expan="Regiment">Regt</abbr> in the fight was met by 3 Yankees -- he had lost his bayonet
     &amp; had no cap in his gun -- he clubbed his gun &amp; knocked one of them down (here
     he stopped --) &amp; what of the other two, said the Adjutant -- Why I ran away from them
     as fast as I could -- There was quite a scene at the preaching which Gen. Jackson ordered day
     before yesterday: he had been to <pb n="3"/> the 5<hi rend="super">th</hi>
     <abbr expan="Regiment">Regt</abbr> to preaching &amp; was coming back, passing by the
     Brigade of Gen. Taliaferro where Mr. Ewing was preaching -- Gen. T -- says, in the midst of a
     splendid <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> -- but at sight of the old Gray Cap coming down the road the men all
     broke &amp; rushed to the road side to cheer the Gen. as he passed -- leaving Mr. Ewing in
     amazement in the height of his eloquence. Gen. Taliaferro says he intends to have Gen. Jackson
     arrested for disturbing a religious meeting &amp; a Presbyterian one at that! We took 19
     wagon loads &amp; one car load of arms from the battle -- Gen. J. says that is the best way
     to get arms -- to go &amp; take them. Capt Lilley behaved gallantly in the action -- he
     seized to colors of the wavering regiment waving it in advance of them rallied them &amp;
     hurried them on to the fight -- Andrew Newman behaved well too &amp; was wounded in the leg
     -- Esq. Gamble lost his right arm &amp; one of the Korncofe's of North River his leg --
     Grady, son-in-law of <orig reg="Humphrey's">
      <unclear>Humpheys</unclear>
     </orig> was taken prisoner it is said -- There is quite a commotion in the 1<hi rend="super"
     >st</hi> Brigade as to who shall command it now that poor Winder is no more -- the officers
     some time ago united in a recommendation of <abbr expan="William">Wm</abbr> Harman, at the
     earnest solicitation of his brother, for a Brig. Generalship -- from mere charity they say, of
     course not expecting him to command them -- but as soon as he hears of Winder's death they (His
     friends) press his case at Richmond &amp; produce this recommendation as evidence that the
      1<hi rend="super">st</hi> Brigade wants him -- thus caught, the officers back out &amp;
     send a counter petition that they do not want him -- &amp; ask to have Baylor made
     Brigadier &amp; so it goes -- My bottle of ink came safely -- &amp; says the welcome
     word on it that you are well -- It will be of no use to send any more provisions till you hear
     from me, but write through Maj. Bell &amp; I shall get it -- I will write as often as I can
      <pb n="4"/> There is no telling where we shall go to, but our faces are Northward &amp; we
     are moving -- I have money but do not see any way to send it -- so get the check cashed that I
     gave you if you need any before I send to you -- I will send the first opportunity -- Any of
     the men around you will cash the check --</p>
    <p> May God bless &amp; keep you all -- I hope to come home, if spared after this move --
     Tell the children to be good &amp; remember their Pa -- Tell Allen I hope he will be a good
     boy &amp; do what is right -- </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Good bye -- Your <abbr expan="affectionate">aff</abbr> -- husband</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
