<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2578"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
 <TEI.2 id="A2578">  
 <teiHeader type="migrated">  
  
    <fileDesc>  
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: M. W. Pollard to Cousin James, May 6, 1863</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county m w pollard to cousin james, may 6 1863</title>
        <author>Pollard, M.W.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>  
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>  
          <name>Amy Rider</name>  
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>  
          <name>Amy Rider</name>  
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>  
  
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>  
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>  
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>  
  
        <idno type="VCDH">A2578</idno>  
  
        <!--
 <availability>  
 <p>Publicly accessible </p>  
 <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>  
 <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the  
 University of Virginia</p>  
 </availability>
-->  
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>  
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502067</idno>
      </publicationStmt>  
      <seriesStmt> 
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil  
 War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>  
      <notesStmt>
        <note>
          <p>The date 1863 written in brackets in another hand on top of  
 letter; letter consists of 4 physical pages, with "pages" 5-7 written crosswise  
 on the first three.</p>
        </note>
      </notesStmt>  
  
      <sourceDesc>  
        <biblFull>  
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: M. W. Pollard to Cousin James, May 6, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county m w pollard to cousin james, may 6 1863</title>
            <author>M.W. Pollard</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>  
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>  
          <extent>4 pages</extent>  
          <publicationStmt>  
            <publisher/>  
            <pubPlace/>  
            <date value=""/> 
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel  
 4, Manuscripts Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D.C.</idno>  
          </publicationStmt>  
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>  
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>  
        </biblFull>  
      </sourceDesc>  
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>  
  
    <profileDesc>  
      <creation>
        <date value="1863-05-06">1863-05-06</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>  
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>  
        <keywords>  
          <term>Home Front, Women, Family, Military Authority, Arts/Leisure</term>  
          <term>American Civil War</term> 
        </keywords>  
      </textClass>  
    </profileDesc>  
  
    <revisionDesc>  
      <change>  
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>  
        <item/>  
      </change>  
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>  
 </teiHeader>  
  
 <text id="A2578T"> 
 <front id="d2"> 
 <div1 type="summary" id="d3"> 
 <p>M. W. Pollard writes to her cousin James, telling him of her life at school,  
 her studies, her teachers, and the people she has met.  Also, she relates news  
 of family members.</p>  
 </div1>   
 </front>  
  
 <body id="d4"> 
 <div1 type="letter" id="d5"> 
 <head> 
 <name type="recipient">James</name>  
 </head> 
  
 <opener> 
 <dateline> 
 <date value="1863-05-06">May 6th</date>  
  <name type="place">Montgomery</name>  
 </dateline>  
 <salute>My Dear Cousin</salute>  
 </opener>  
  
 <p>Some time has elapsed since I received your last letter my excuse for this  
 summary negligence must be that I have been very busily engaged at school.  We  
 are preparing for another examination.  What I would give if you could only be  
 here to attend.  This term has been what my teacher calls a "picking up term".   
 That is we have been reviewing the lower branches, such as Grammar, Mental  
 arithmetic &amp; Geography but which are in fact what I consider the foundation  
 of a good education.  Do you not agree <pb n="2"/> with me?  Miss Kellogg my dear  
 good teacher has convinced me that I can be just such a lady as I wish to be and  
 I am aiming to become a <hi rend="underline">brilliant</hi> and accomplished  
 young lady, although it is quite far off to anticipate <unclear>this</unclear>.   
 Do not think me egotistical when I say that I shall be really <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> at the  
 end of this term to think how much I have accomplished in nine months.  There  
 are fine girls in my class in Mathematics at the end of the term we will have  
 finished Practical armithmetic, Mental arthimetic,  Algebra &amp; one Book on  
 Geometry, and be examined publicly on all of them.  Miss Kellogg says she <pb n="3"/> is very proud of us.  I have <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> attended a series of very  
 interesting lectures delivered by Rev. Dr. Leyburn on the Holy Land every one  
 acknowledes him as very gifted and talented.  I am perfectly charmed with him he  
 has a kind and pleasant word for every one.  Dr Petrie's health is very feeble.   
 <hi rend="underline">Miss Essie</hi> is quite well she asks about you very  
 frequently.  I see very little of Aunt <orig reg="Jennie's">Jennies</orig>  
 family I am so constantly employed at school (very frequently we are compelled  
 to attend school on Saturday) that there is little time left for visiting.  I do  
 not think they realize that dear cousin Joe is dead at times they seem very <pb n="4"/> distressed while at other times they seem to forget.  It is indeed a sad  
 thought that we never shall see Cousin Joe on <hi  
 rend="underline">earth</hi> again, but we have the hope of seeing him in  
 Heaven a brighter and happier home that his world of sorrow and temptation.   
 Friday is my birthday.  I shall be fourteen years of age, four years more to go  
 to school and then we shall have to make a tour of travels through Europe.  It  
 would be <hi rend="underline">so</hi> pleasant for you and "<hi  
 rend="underline">Cousin Sophia</hi>" to join our party.  Father has concluded  
 not to sell our place he has had an offer of ninety thousand dollars, but he  
 declined this.  Cousin James I wish to seek a favor of you  <pb n="5"/> Will you  
 be so kind as to get me Gen. <orig reg="Jackson's">Jacksons</orig> <hi  
 rend="underline">autograph</hi>  I have commenced making an <hi  
 rend="underline">antiquarian</hi> book.  A gunboat is to be launched tomorrow.   
 I am afraid we cannot attend as our teacher forbids unless we have finished  
 every lesson by noon.  We have a very difficult lesson for tomorrow, so I shall  
 have to content my self with staying in school, I have much more to tell you but  
 time does not permit.  Do please write me a long letter soon, and tell me all  
 about "<hi rend="underline">Cousin Sophia</hi>"   If it was not so very late  
 I could write a very long letter.  I never felt so much in the humor of writing  
 Good Night Dear cousin and accept the prayers and best wishes of your devoted  
 cousin</p>  
 				<p>	M. W. Pollard</p> 
 <lb/> 
 <p><pb n="6"/> Cousin Katie and all of our little household join me in love to  
 you.  As it is not quite time to go to school I will write a little more.  Mrs.  
 Gen Johnsons is now in the city attended by <hi  
 rend="underline"><unclear>ten</unclear> men and sixteen horses</hi>.  three or  
 four of the General's staff are with her every one called them Mrs. Johnson's  
 staff.  I became acquainted with two of them  Lieuts Hampton and Washington.  I  
 saw them out at a picnic.  It has been quite gay here this Spring since people  
 have made themselves foolish about "Mrs Gen. Johnson and her staff" There are  
 two charming young ladies residing in Montgomery who were originally from  
 <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> they are twin sisters it is very difficult to distinguish one from  
 the other.  they always dress alike they are the Misses Smith.  I wish you could  
 know <pb n="7"/> them.  Well I suppose you are weary reading this unentertaining  
 letter so I will close although I do so with reluctance.  Again, I ask you  
 please write very soon and you will greatly oblige 
 </p> 
  
 <closer> 
 <salute>Yours affectionately</salute>  
 <signed>M.W.P.</signed>   
 </closer>  
 </div1>  
 </body>  
 </text>  
 </TEI.2> 
 