<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2591"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A2591">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Nelson H. Hotchkiss,
     October 25, 1863</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to nelson h hotchkiss, october 25 1863</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A2591</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502080</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Nelson H. Hotchkiss, October 25, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to nelson h hotchkiss, october 25 1863</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>1 page</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D.C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>The only original is a typed copy.</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1863-10-25">1863-10-25</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Troop Movement, Military Authority, Battle Description, Home Front, Women</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A2591T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss describes recent troop movements, Stuart's cavalry skirmishes, and possible winter
     quarters for the Confederate army. He also discusses matters at home.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Nelson H. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1863-10-25">October 25th., 1863</date>
      <name type="place">"Berry Hill" <abbr expan="Head Quarters">Hd. Qrs.</abbr> 2nd Corps <abbr
       expan="Army of Northern Virginia">A.N.Va.</abbr></name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My dear Brother:-</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I wrote to you from Bristoe station while we were on the march just before we started back. I
     have not heard from you but not considering that I avail myself of the quiet of the early
     candle lighting of this Sunday night to speak a few words by pen as I would by mouth if I were
     near enough.</p>
    <p> We did not succeed in heading off Meade; his conscripts are too fleetfooted and we have no
     "Old Jack" with the "foot Cavalry to beat him in a long race, so we only had a fight with his
     rear guard in which a portion of A.P. Hill's corps got the worst of it for a short time and the
     enemy fled before we could join a general battle, so we could only turn around and come back as
     our rations for man and beast had run out and there was absolutely nothing <orig reg="where"
      >were</orig> we were but ruined houses and a waste and howling wilderness and no enemy to
     fight except in the fortifications of Alexandria and Washington.</p>
    <p> Stuart remained there several days subsisting his men on nothing and his horses on the
     commons and had several fights with the Yankee Cavalry in most of which he got the better of
     them: in fact all the glory of this movement, if there is any, belongs of the cavalry. They
     fought elegantly, charging the enemy on all occasions and carrying everthing before them,
     capturing hundreds of Yankees. Our infantry witnessed the charges of the cavalry and cheered
     them on. As we came back we tore up and burnt the ties and bent the rails of the railroad back
     to the Rappahannock, destroying it completely and we are now hauling away the rails of that
     portion of the railway that is nearest to us.</p>
    <p> The enemy pickets some 5 miles beyond the river and we <pb n="2"/> have a skirmish with them
     every now and then but there is no prospect of a fight and we may spend the winter here for all
     I know, judging from all appearances. We are at a deserted house and I have very comfortable
     quarters in a large upper room with fireplace. This was an old place; a fine family mansion
     well furnished, but when the Yanks were here last they broke up the furniture, tore up and
     carried off the books, smashed the books and made a general desolation.</p>
    <p> I suppose Allie may have written to you of Sterritt's health and his disinclination to marry
     now. I hope he has gotten better and come to reason. If not I must believe he is insincere and
     has trifled with the affections of one of the most loving and confident of her sex. If so shame
     to him. I hope it may not prove so but have my fears and though Allie has pride enough to bear
     up outwardly it will be a crushing blow to her spirits which she can illy endure in the present
     state of her health. I hope to soon hear more of the matter and in the mean time hope and pray
     for the best. </p>
    <p> I saw McCue when I was home and spoke to him about the Hogsett matter. He said it was no
     matter about it but did not tell me what wrote. I am thankful it is thus disposed of and I will
     pay it up as soon as I can.</p>
    <p> I was so unfortunate as to have my horse taken the night after I got back for camp and but
     for the kindness of Mr. Harnsberger, one of my former pupils, I would be on foot. I hardly know
     what to do with existing prices staring me in the face for I cannot save enough from current
     expenses from self and family under the most rigid economy to buy another but some way will be
     provided. As General Ewell says: "I will fall on my feet, fall as I may". <pb n="3"/></p>
    <p> Can you find the potatoes for me. I shall come to see you when the prospects will admit of
     it. My love to all. Write to me soon. May Heaven help you all. </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your <abbr expan="affectionate">aff.</abbr> brother,</salute>
     <signed>Jed.</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
