<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2917"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A2917">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Phebe Ann McCormick to Enos Ott,
                    December 9, 1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county phebe ann mccormick to enos ott, december 9 1864</title>
        <author>Annie</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A2917</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502102</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Phebe Ann McCormick to Enos Ott, December 9, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county phebe ann mccormick to enos ott, december 9 1864</title>
            <author>Annie</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Enos Ott Papers, Private
                            Collection of Gail Ott</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from private collection</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-12-09">1864-12-09</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Desertion/Leave, Home Front, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A2917T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In this letter to her brother-in-law, Phebe discusses the recent harsh weather,
                    local troop movements, Henry's detail to some public works, and their attempts
                    to round up her father's apples.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Mr Enos Ott<lb/>Camp Lee<lb/>Richmond<lb/>Virginia<lb/>Care of Rev Henry
                    Brown
                    <name type="recipient">Mr Enos Ott</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-12-09">December 9, 1864</date>
                        <name type="place">Home</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Brother</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>It is now nearly the middle of the day and I have had my paper, pen, &amp;
                    ink all morning to write to you, but we had company last night, and they have
                    not all got away yet, and several more come in so you see I have just <add
                        hand="h1" place="inline">to</add> slip off from them and write. I am up
                    stairs in our room with little fire &amp; so cold that I <abbr
                        expan="cannot">cant</abbr> write with a pen so you must excuse pencil. It is
                    one of the coldest days we have had this winter. I received your kind letter
                    several weeks ago (or rather it came here for me) as I was at Moore's at the
                    time I spent two weeks (wanting two days) <pb n="2"/> there. They nearly all had
                    diptheria very badly. Marie had it so badly that we did not think she could live
                    at all, but they are all well of it now. So you see my brother you will have to
                    take off the two weeks I was there waiting on the sick folks. When I came home I
                        <orig reg="spoke">spok</orig> of writing and Ma said for me to wait until Pa
                    would start your apples to you, so you could be on the "look out" for them but I
                    have waited, and waited, long enough for that, so I have concluded to write now
                    as there is no probability of getting your apples off for a few days. Harry is
                    away working on some public works, will not be home before next week, if then.
                    We can't haul away any thing until he <pb n="3"/>comes to drive the wagon I hope
                    you will excuse your "little Sis" for not writing <orig reg="sooner"
                    >soone</orig> as you will see I had to battle with circumstances, but enough of
                    this. Ginnie and Charlotte were over at <abbr expan="Old Providence">O.P.</abbr>
                    last Sabbath They are all well there. Ginnie has been over there a good while,
                    and will remain until about Christmas, then she will come over and stay with us
                    awhile. Henry is at home now, came home on a Twenty-day furlough, to attend to
                    his <orig reg="business">buisness</orig>. I wish you could meet with such luck
                    as that, only to get a longer one and come home to stay. Gordons &amp;
                    Pegrams Divisions were ordered to Richmond a few days ago, and Brother <pb n="4"
                    />was seen in Staunton on his way down. I feel very uneasy about him. He has
                    never been home since he left the 18<hi rend="super">th</hi> of <abbr
                        expan="October">Oct</abbr>. If you can we would like for you to ascertain
                    something about where he is &amp;c and if any thing should happen him to let
                    us know. We know not what a day nor an hour may bring forth. We will try
                    &amp; send you a barrel as soon as we possibly can. I was truly glad to hear
                    that you were so fortunate as to get in with <abbr expan="Lieutenant">Lt.</abbr>
                    H. and did not have to go the field of a action hope you will remain there.
                    Write soon and let us hear from you, and if you know any thing about Davis.
                    Sarah Margaret and <hi rend="underline">all</hi> send their love to you. Please
                    excuse this horridly written letter as I am in a great hurry, and am cold. May
                    the blessings of our Heavenly Father ever be with you is the prayer of your
                    sister</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed>Phebe A</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript"><pb n="1"/>You must not think that it was through neglect
                        that I did not write to you sooner for I had the inclination often I will
                        have to close as <abbr expan="Robert">Robt</abbr> is most ready to start
                        Your Sister Annie</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
