<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2914"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A2914">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Ginnie Ott to Enos Ott, December 1,
                    1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county ginnie ott to enos ott, december 1 1864</title>
        <author>Ott, Ginnie</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A2914</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502099</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Ginnie Ott to Enos Ott, December 1, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county ginnie ott to enos ott, december 1 1864</title>
            <author>Ginnie Ott</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Enos Ott Papers, Private
                            Collection of Gail Ott</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from private collection</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-12-01">1864-12-01</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>African Americans, Church/Religious Activity, Home Front</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A2914T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In this letter to her husband, Ginnie discusses the numerous weddings that
                    recetnly occurred, the movement of provisions for troops, and how two black
                    women joined New Providence Church.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Moffett's Creek Va<lb/>Dec 2<hi rend="super">nd</hi><lb/>Mr Enos Ott<lb/>Camp
                    Lee<lb/>Richmond<lb/>Virginia<lb/>Care of<lb/>Rev Henry Brown
                    <name type="recipient">Mr Enos Ott</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-12-01">Dec 1<hi rend="super">st</hi> 1864</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Husband</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Yours of the 22<hi rend="super">d</hi> came to hand Tuesday and I had just set
                    down to answer it when Estaline came from the office with the one that was
                    written the 26<hi rend="super">th</hi>. I was glad to <orig reg="hear"
                    >heare</orig> from you and know that you were well and I hope when this comes to
                    hand <orig reg="you">yuo</orig> may still be enjoying the same great blessing. I
                    am glad you have such a good situation, as you cannot be at home for I think it
                    is a better place than down the Valley. Mag received a letter from Henry today
                    he is well and Davis also. he took down a load of provision he said they were
                    all very glad to see him he thinks it is probable that he will get home soon to
                    attend to putting up his corn and attend to some other things I wrote to you
                    last Thursday and sent the letter to Staunton with your box but I hope you have
                    got them before this time we did not write to Tyler as Henry thought it was not
                        <orig reg="necessary">nessessary</orig>, as the box was directed to you in
                    care of Tyler &amp; Son. Your cat has deserted the mill he did <add
                        hand="h1" place="inline">not</add> like staying about there alone he went up
                    to Mr. Blacks and Alex brought him down and took him to the mill again but he
                    would not stay there; he is a great pet he gets up on my lap any time, and you
                    know it is something new for me to nurse a cat, but they all say if was any
                    other cat than yours I would nurse it. There is no one at home today except
                    Hannah and myself. Mag and Charlotte went up to Mr Blacks on a visit Charlotte
                    said to tell <add hand="h1" place="inline">you</add> that her and Cal are
                    getting along finely and you need <add hand="h1" place="inline">not</add> be
                    surprised to hear of a wedding some day. <abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> Yates
                    oldest daughter was married the 10<hi rend="super">th</hi> day this month to
                    Charlie Cameron they had quite a jolly time. <pb n="2"/>I heard one of the young
                    ladies say she got tipsy going up to the <unclear>infare</unclear> There has
                    been a good many marriages in the neighborhood of Fairfield I do not remember
                    any but Mr James Shirey &amp; Miss Eliza McCormick he said he had waited
                    long enough on the war to close and would not wait any longer. We have had a
                    great deal of trouble with the army agents They are here nearly every day after
                    something there was five wagons here of <abbr expan="Captain">Capt</abbr> Oden's
                    tuesday to be loaded with hay, but when two of them were loaded <abbr
                        expan="Captain">Capt</abbr> Harris came and ordered them away. Mrs Hupp is
                    talking of breaking up housekeeping and going down to Rockingham to live with
                    her Sister but her sister thinks she had better stay up here as she has nearly
                    every thing laid in for winter she is down at Mrs Cile's now went down to try to
                    get Mr. Hupp's body, I guess if she goes down there she will find it very hard
                        <orig reg="living">liveing</orig> as the yankees have been through there and
                    destroyed nearly every thing. David Black &amp; Thomas Christ &amp;
                    Jacob Hanger got hom last week Mr Black and some of the rest of the family did
                    not know Davie when he came home he has long whiskers &amp; mustache and is
                    very much sunburnt. James Smith has been home for several weeks. There was
                    sacrament at New Providence last Sabbath Mr Junkin had no one to assist him I
                    believe there was no one joined except two black women and one of them old Dr
                    Hamilton's. Mag says she sent a sample of Hannah's cloak in the last letter, and
                    if that piece you spoke of being $95.00 yards is no lighter than that is and all
                    wool it will do very well. Mag says she thinks that she thinks looked in the
                    very place you told her and Alex was with her he took a stick and hunted about
                    but could not find it, she thinks some one else has found it, but she will try
                    it again tomorrow. Phebe was over last Thursday when I wrote and told me to give
                    her love to you and tell you she would write soon. I believe I have no news to
                    write, we are all well. it is now bed time and I must close Nothing more at
                    present but remain your affectionate Wife until death.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed>Ginnie Ott</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
