<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2955"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A2955">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta: Amanda C. Armentrout to William F. Brand,
                    July 29, 1866</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta amanda c armentrout to william f brand, july 29 1866</title>
        <author>Armentrout, Amanda C.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">15</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A2955</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502125</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: Amanda C. Armentrout to William F. Brand, July 29, 1866</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta amanda c armentrout to william f brand, july 29 1866</title>
            <author>Amanda C. Armentrout</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William F. Brand Papers</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1866-07-29">1866-07-29</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Home Front, Church/Religious Activity, Family</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A2955T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Kate, blaming herself for their estrangement, apologizes to Willie and pleads
                    with him to forgive her and find his way back to God.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1866-07-29">July 29th 66</date>
                        <name type="place">Rose Dale</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My dear friend</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>This is a beautiful <orig reg="Sabbath">Sabbeth</orig> morn &amp; all nature
                    seems to be sending up its praises to the great &amp; good God yes I say
                        <add hand="h1" place="inline">good</add> (good when he gives supremely good
                    nor less when he <orig reg="denies">dinies</orig>) &amp; it is Him who
                    deserves the <orig reg="praise">prais</orig> for he does all things well. Willie
                    I was not well this morning nor have not been for a week &amp; could not go
                    to church so I thought I would respond to your dear <orig reg="missive"
                    >messive</orig> that I <abbr expan="received">Recd</abbr> last Thursday Oh you
                    know not how I felt when I got it I feared to open it my hand trembled when I
                    grasped it &amp; saw it was from you; but you will say what caused the fear
                    now do not <orig reg="censure">centure</orig> me for my weakness, I feared it
                    would be cold &amp; <orig reg="indifferent">indiferent</orig> &amp;
                    perhaps bid me <orig reg="never">neve</orig> to <orig reg="write">right</orig>
                    again but when I saw dear Kate it <orig reg="cheered">cheared</orig> me up yes I
                        <orig reg="felt">filt</orig> strong again &amp; thought perhaps <orig
                        reg="there">ther</orig> were some hope &amp; now I am replying with you
                    last request (<hi rend="underline">write soon</hi>) yes I will try &amp;
                    comply with <orig reg="every">evry</orig> request that you make though I have
                    been denied of <orig reg="every">evry</orig> one I have made. I will try
                    &amp; return good for <orig reg="evil">evel</orig>, I am resigned to my
                    fate. <pb n="2"/>but I must hasten to respond to your dear sweet letter. you say
                    mine caused your sensitive nature to mourn over the past my dear friend I am
                    sorry that I caused you to <orig reg="mourn">morn</orig> over the past for it is
                    wicked for me to mourn over it let alone being the cause of another one to be
                    sad forgive me for making you thus. God in his goodness has some wise <orig
                        reg="device">devise</orig> for doing this so I am willing to <orig
                        reg="bear">bare</orig> though the <orig reg="chastening">chastning</orig>
                    rod has been <orig reg="severe">sever</orig> it has brought me nearer <hi
                        rend="underline">him</hi> &amp; <orig reg="made">maid</orig> a better
                    girl of me &amp; I hope ere long dear brother that you will <orig
                        reg="exclaim">exclame</orig> God is good &amp; does all things well.
                    Willie you wish a <orig reg="release">relies</orig> you have loved me I do not
                    doubt that but your affections have changed &amp; you soon wish to be free
                    again &amp; can I hold thy pure &amp; noble heart bind it to me that is
                    so impure as mine for I have been the cause of you being unhappy &amp; I
                    know not but what I am the cause of you <orig reg="losing">loosing</orig> your
                    religion though I hope not so Willie I am not worthy of you. I love you
                    &amp; can not help it but Willie I will never harm you love works no ill to
                    any one I never expect to love another nor do not wish to no could I trust
                    another could I ask my dear Father to <orig reg="change">chang</orig> that which
                    I asked him to do but with in my <orig reg="bossom">bosom</orig> no never, but
                    can I claim you when you are <orig reg="changed">chainged</orig>; Oh my Heavenly
                    Father forbid no no Willie I care not what may be my fate I can not hold thee to
                    me if you do not wish it nor can I spurn you no Willie I blame myself in part
                    for it yes the letter that I wrote last winter just after Christmas I blame for
                    it yes dear Willie I will take half of the blame or all of it if it will make
                    you happy for I have bore the blame &amp; <orig reg="censure">centure</orig>
                    of the people for it &amp; swore then it yes Willie I have bore the burden
                    in the heat of the day I caused &amp; cast it all <orig reg="upon"
                    >uppon</orig> thee now but will <orig reg="bear">bare</orig> half of it with
                    you. I will tell you some things that has (come) been said to me Kate you look
                    sad you kicked Billie thinking you could do better &amp; I dont <orig
                        reg="pity">pitty</orig> you one bit what could I say I <orig reg="denied"
                        >dened</orig> the charge but it is <orig reg="generally">generly</orig>
                    believed that I did kick you yes I am blamed with your drinking which I <orig
                        reg="never">neve</orig> did believe you did though you thought I did no
                    Willie I could not believe it I would see you laying dead drunk in the mud I
                    would (not) think it was not you there oh you said the next to the last time you
                    were down <orig reg="here">her</orig> if I ever kicked you that you would get to
                    drinking but Willie here is the hardest thing I had to endure that I had kicked
                    you &amp; you got to drinking on the account of it &amp; that now I had
                    lost my mind on the account of it Oh Willie is it not a <pb n="3"/>wonder that I
                    have not lost my mind as be <orig reg="blamed">blaimed</orig> with so much that
                    I hope I am <orig reg="innocent">inosent</orig> of &amp; yet I <orig
                        reg="believe">bilieve</orig> it is all for my own good "all work together
                    for good to those that love God yes dear Willie God in all his ways is just
                    &amp; merciful &amp; if we <orig reg="really">rely</orig> trust him
                    though we pass through fire it will not harm us.</p>

                <p>Willie do not think that I wrote this to make you sad no no dear one I would do
                    anything in my power to make you happy; you say you would like to see me why do
                    you think then it is best for us not to meet; I <orig reg="sort of"
                    >sorter</orig> believe you are a <orig reg="little">lettle</orig> contrary ha ha
                    &amp; what do you think of that no Willie but why is it do you think I can
                    not <orig reg="bear">bare</orig> to meet you I have taught or rather God has
                    taught me to <orig reg="bear">bare</orig> much I think I could meet you as
                    cheerful as ever I met you in my life. you say my cup has been bitter it has
                    been bitter Oh far worse than you have any <orig reg="idea">idie</orig> of but
                    dear Willie there was some sweets with it at times; you say blame you with it
                    not all dear one can I blame you no no you could not help it for I think that
                    the wicked one has done it not your good heart dictated but you were not happy
                    &amp; he wished to claim you for one of his <orig reg="servants"
                    >servents</orig> &amp; persuaded you that you did not love me yes Willie he
                    knew that I was trying to win you back to God &amp; that he would get you to
                    dismiss me at once but my dear Father ordered other wise he bid me noy to give
                    thee up Willie dear I believe he has directed me how to <orig reg="write"
                    >wright</orig> every letter that I have written to you since you were here
                    &amp; Oh I pray that my dear <orig reg="Savior">Savier</orig> may make them
                    the instrument of bringing you back to God Oh dear one you say you are willing
                    to bear my malice if it but make me happpy my malice Willie no Malice if I have
                    any in my heart I pray to my dear <orig reg="Savior">Savier</orig> (to) to pluck
                    it out Willie come to see me &amp; I will tell you what will make me happy
                    Willie I will treat you as a fond sister would a brother <orig reg="mistreat"
                        >misstreat</orig> you no never &amp; as for the rest of the family <orig
                        reg="mistreating">misstreating</orig> you there are no danger of that I
                        <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> think none but Susie knows how you have
                    treated me I think that she <orig reg="pitied">pittied</orig> you now as for Pa
                    &amp; Ma Willie I do not think they will ever <orig reg="mistreat"
                    >misstreat</orig> you for they see my perfect <orig reg="indifference"
                        >indifferents</orig> to every other man so Willie I <orig reg="don't"
                    >dont</orig> think you need to fear at all S was not at the Barbecue nor none of
                    our family nor I do not regret that I was not there I think Willie there is more
                        <pb n="4"/>harm done at such places than good they had a <orig reg="picnic"
                        >picknick</orig> at Mint Spring &amp; danced in the church Oh that these
                    dances were turned to prayer <orig reg="meetings">metings</orig> how much sooner
                    could we expect the blessings of God <orig reg="upon">uppon</orig> our country.
                    Willie All have <orig reg="gone">gon</orig> to <orig reg="Sabbath"
                    >Sabbeth</orig> school this eve but Pa Ma &amp; myself &amp; I feel very
                    lonely Alone yes Alone shall it always be thus Oh my Father forsaken &amp;
                        <orig reg="forgotten">forgoten</orig> no one to care for me how long Oh how
                    long but enough thy will <add hand="h1" place="inline">be done</add> The health
                    of the neighborhood is very good &amp; our family is all well with the <orig
                        reg="exception">excep</orig> of myself I have not been ill but am not well
                    though I hope it is nothing serious I <orig reg="have been">been</orig> taking
                        <orig reg="medicine">medisson</orig> but it has had but <orig reg="little"
                        >lettle</orig>
                    <orig reg="effect">affect</orig> I <orig reg="hope">hopefly</orig> I will be
                    well by next <orig reg="Sabbath">Sabbeth</orig> (I will) be well as there are
                    camp <orig reg="meeting">metning</orig> at <orig reg="Bethel">Bethle</orig>
                    &amp; I want to go Willie do come down &amp; go with me Sis Lizzie
                    &amp; both Jimmie are going to be taken in on <orig reg="certificate"
                        >sertificate</orig> do come brother &amp; commune with (me) us come
                    &amp; stay down a week &amp; go to the pines with
                    <unclear>Aleberryine</unclear> we are expecting a nice dance there is talk of a
                    crowd going Tuesday a week I expect we will join the crowd if it goes Willie
                        <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> deny me this time but do come. I suppose you
                    heard that Frank McFarland was <orig reg="buried">burried</orig> last Monday.
                    Dear Willie I have some very bad news to relate to you cousin Bell Rubush has
                    lost her mind Oh Willie is it not sad indeed to think such a good woman should
                    be afflicted thus I <orig reg="pity">pitty</orig> her so much we know not what
                    one day may bring forth yes we we may sink beneath the <unclear>rod</unclear>
                    Willie my dear dear brother ought we not then to strive more &amp; more
                        <orig reg="every">evry</orig> day to meet our God than to spurn his
                    pleadings who are so indifferent to our dear <orig reg="Savior's">Saviers</orig>
                    pleadings has he not said no to is the accepted time brother I am try<add
                        hand="h1" place="inline">ing</add> to make my bible my companion <add
                        hand="h1" place="inline">and guardian</add> through life as I have nothing
                    to care for in this world but why have I nothing to care for does not Willie
                    call me dear Kate once more &amp; will he not return I can only hope. Oh
                    Willie I have <orig reg="never">neve</orig> told you about my little pet Ida
                    Lizzie little babe she is the sweetest little thing that I ever saw Sis brings
                    her up <orig reg="every">evry</orig>
                    <orig reg="Sunday">sunday</orig> did not come today I do not know why will be
                    here next if nothing happens she leaves her here when she goes to church I know
                    you will love her Willie do come down next Saturday evening you can get some one
                    to stay in the mill that long I will look for you <orig reg="don't">dont</orig>
                    let me be disappointed where ever there is a will there is a way but enough Well
                    I must close this disinteresting note now Willie let nothing in this hurt your
                    feelings or cause you to be sad but be cheerful &amp; happy &amp; come
                    to see me &amp; you will find me a true sister please excuse all
                    imperfections. Willie if it is impolitic for you to come write soon but I want
                    to see you your own dear self</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>your ever true &amp; fond friend</salute>
                    <signed>Midie</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">Willie read the 7 Chap from the 8<hi rend="super">th</hi>
                        to the 12<hi rend="super">th</hi> verses &amp; the 6<hi rend="super"
                        >th</hi> of Second Corinthians <orig reg="they">the</orig> express my
                        sentiments to thee my eyes are getting very weak or I would write more but
                            <unclear>tears at</unclear> I will worry you with this <orig reg="yours"
                            >your</orig> as ever Midie</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
