<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2959"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A2959">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta: Robert B. Spillman to Amanda C. Armentrout,
                    October 13, 1866</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta robert b spillman to amanda c armentrout, october 13 1866</title>
        <author>Spillman, Robert B.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A2959</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502129</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: Robert B. Spillman to Amanda C. Armentrout, October 13, 1866</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta robert b spillman to amanda c armentrout, october 13 1866</title>
            <author>Robert B. Spillman</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William F. Brand Letters</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1866-10-13">1866-10-13</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Home Front, Family, Church/Religious Activity</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A2959T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Robert writes to Kate assuring her of his interest in another girl and his
                    absolute devotion to Kate as a friend only. He also mentions his religious
                    thoughts.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1866-10-13">Oct 13<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1866</date>
                        <name type="place">Seeds farm Westd Co Va</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Sister</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Yours of the 19 of Aug &amp; 26 of Sept have been recieved. Oh I cannot find
                    words to express my joy at the receipt of your letter of the 19 August twas
                    after I had waited so long &amp; anxiously for a letter from you that I had
                    concluded that something had happened &amp; then wrote that my letter might
                    be opened by your Pa in order that I might get some information of you. meantime
                    your dear letter came on in other words an Angel's visit. I seized the dear
                    letters messenger &amp; with anxious eyes &amp; heart full of joy
                    unspeakable I perused its contents with <orig reg="unparalleled">un
                    parralelled</orig> interest &amp; pleasure the relief of my anxiety was so
                    forcibly impressive that I could but (umanly or childish as it was) press the
                    dear sheet to my lips &amp; cover your name with numerous kisses. I really
                    was never more delighted at the receipt of a letter all my life. One would have
                    supposed from <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> emotions, that I was much in love with <del
                        hand="h1"/> than that of friendship. Sweet <pb n="2"/>dearest Kate you know
                    I <add hand="h1" place="inline">have</add> long since defined my position fully,
                    I have claimed to love you only as a friend &amp; as a proof of the fact
                    have openly told you of my fond relations with another a friend of early life
                    whose constancy &amp; devotion I can <hi rend="underline">scarce doubt</hi>.
                        <orig reg="Our">our</orig> attachment was formed in early life. <orig
                        reg="Long">long</orig> separations during the protracted perils of war
                    &amp; blood Shed, my reduction (by the same) to <orig reg="comparative"
                        >comparitive</orig> poverty has made no change in the dearest objects of my
                        <hi rend="underline">undivided affection</hi> like you my dear <hi
                        rend="underline">Sister</hi> who has proven to be a devoted friend. She too
                    has proven to be all that one could be, who holds the place she does, in my
                    hearts dearest affections and nothing prevents the consumation of what has been
                    vowed between us but my limited means &amp; the depressed condition of the
                    Country.</p>

                <p>But my dear friend I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> think there is a <orig
                        reg="friend">freind</orig> on Earth that I love more as a pure &amp;
                    constant <orig reg="friend">freind</orig> than my fond &amp; affectionate
                    Sister Kate she <add hand="h1" place="inline">is</add> truly <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <unclear>short</unclear> a <orig reg="friend">freind</orig> can be on whom I
                    hold very dear in <orig reg="friendship">freindship</orig> love &amp;
                    confidence.</p>

                <p>Now my dear <orig reg="friend">freind</orig> I will with <orig reg="painful"
                        >painfull</orig> emotions communicate to <add hand="h1" place="inline"
                    >you</add> news that is sad to me, the death of a young man, a warmly attached
                    &amp; well loved <orig reg="friend">freind</orig> of mine. <orig reg="He"
                    >he</orig> was <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <pb n="3"/>Brother of my dear Lou, he was an associate from his early Boyhood
                    when he <add hand="h1" place="inline">was</add> quite a small boy I engaged with
                    his Father to conduct a <orig reg="mercantile">merchantile</orig> business for
                    him which I did till the commencement of the war. My constant association with
                    the family &amp; their marked kindness draw out my warmest attachment for
                    them all, particularly this dear Boy Calvin, he was always so particularly fond
                    of me that I had really <orig reg="learned">learnd</orig> to love him almost as
                    a brother. <orig reg="He">he</orig> was 18 or 19 years old when he died <orig
                        reg="entered">Entered</orig> the Army the last year of the war. <orig
                        reg="He">he</orig> was sick about six weeks with a Billious Typhoid <orig
                        reg="affliction">affiction</orig> &amp; fell a victim to the disease the
                    17th of <orig reg="August">august</orig>. I visited him constantly during his
                    illness watched with <orig reg="painful">pain-full</orig> anxiety the last
                    breathings of his <orig reg="existence">existance</orig> while around his dying
                    bed stood the almost heart broken family his dear parents &amp; fond sisters
                    Oh dear friend how deep the unspeakable grief and anguish of all amid this scene
                    of death. <orig reg="He">he</orig> was a lively &amp; very <orig
                        reg="cheerful">cheerfull</orig> young lad &amp; very thoughtless of here
                    after but during his long illness he was visited by Christian <orig
                        reg="friends">freinds</orig> prayed for by the Church &amp; before he
                    died gave some hopeful evidence of his fitness for a home beyond the grave. Well
                    my dear sister <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> the scene of death &amp; change <pb n="4"
                    />the subject for a season I was truly sorry to hear of your illness &amp;
                    troubles truly hope ere this you are fully restored to health &amp;
                    happiness I thank you for your kind invitation to visit you I am very sorry that
                    we are so far separated I have a great anxiety to see you but situated as I am
                    at this time it almost impossible for me to leave home for any length of time I
                    hope it will not always be the case. <orig reg="Remember">remember</orig> me
                    ever in you prayers remember kindly to your Pa &amp; Ma Bro &amp;
                    Sisters I have a great vision to meet with you all. Take care of your-self dear
                    sister. <orig reg="Accept">accept</orig> my warmest wishes for your <orig
                        reg="welfare">wellfare</orig> &amp; happiness with my lasting love</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>write soon to your constant friend &amp; affectionate Brother</salute>
                    <signed>Robt B Spillman</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">PS please excuse bad writing &amp; mistakes I have
                        very bad pen<lb/>Yr Bro Robt</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
