<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2961"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A2961">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta: Amanda C. Armentrout to William F. Brand,
                    September 1, 1867</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta amanda c armentrout to william f brand, september 1 1867</title>
        <author>Armentrout, Amanda C.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A2961</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502131</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: Amanda C. Armentrout to William F. Brand, September 1, 1867</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta amanda c armentrout to william f brand, september 1 1867</title>
            <author>Amanda C. Armentrout</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William F. Brand Papers</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1867-09-01">1867-09-01</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Home Front, Women, Family</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A2961T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>With their marriage pending, Amanda writes to Willie about her plans for their
                    wedding.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1867-09-01">Sept 1<hi rend="super">st</hi> 67</date>
                        <name type="place">Rose Dale</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My dearest friend</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I have just returned from my friend Rachel's &amp; thought I would write you
                    a short note my health is very good better than usual I think &amp; I am
                    trying to be very cheerful though I get the blues very bad some times. Pa has at
                    last consented for to have some <orig reg="waiters">waters</orig> &amp; get
                    married at home so I have chosen six girls though I expected to have 7 but I
                    want the privlege of inviting one gent <add hand="h1" place="inline">as <orig
                            reg="waiter">water</orig></add> &amp; will give you the same <orig
                        reg="privilege">privlege</orig> you can invite a lady to wait as I have but
                    (on) six chosen but wish to know immediately what lady you wish. I have my two
                        <orig reg="sisses">sises</orig> R.C.E. Shuey, Kate Shields &amp; cousin
                    Josie of course I will expect you to have Mr. Linzy as a <orig reg="waiter"
                        >water</orig> to make the 6th I do not know how to spell the name; Oh how I
                    wish you were here that we could make the <orig reg="arrangement"
                    >arangement</orig> you are so slow <orig reg="about">a bout</orig> writing I
                    think you are so careless <orig reg="about">a bout</orig> writing Willie dear
                    will you always be so it has a bad tendency <add hand="h1" place="inline"
                    >now</add> you can not <orig reg="imagine">imagin</orig> my feelings when I
                    think <orig reg="about">a bout</orig> it but then I think it will not be long
                    that I will be from you &amp; that you <pb n="2"/>will strive to make me
                    happy. Alas how long long did I await to hear these words <add hand="h1"
                        place="inline">the other night</add> Kate I am striving to live a better
                    life to become a good Christian my dear one are you trying to do this Oh I do
                    hope you are you cannot imagine the joy those few words would create within in
                    my bosom I think the <orig reg="trials">tryals</orig> that I have <orig
                        reg="daily">dayly</orig> would be nothing if I but knew that all that you
                    can do is being done; if I allow myself to think for one moment that you are not
                    doing that I almost shrink from the situation or position I have taken but I
                    feel that you are trying for I know you will not have me <orig reg="break"
                    >brake</orig> that <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> no I know you want to make me happy
                    &amp; that will make us both happy dearest remember me in your <orig
                        reg="daily">dayly</orig>
                    <orig reg="prayers">prayrs</orig> but enough.</p>

                <p>Willie the company all that I have talked to wish to go to the <add hand="h1"
                        place="inline">Natural</add> bridges what do you say about it I for my part
                    would rather take the trip over the mountain though I am in for what ever suits
                    you the best if it suits you the best to go to the bridges I want to go there I
                    would like to have the crowd together <pb n="3"/>longer as they are so anxious
                    but we <orig reg="can't">cant</orig> take both trips though it may suit you
                    better to take the trip to the bridge as you would not <orig reg="lose"
                    >loose</orig> so much time but I suppose your friends will look for you
                    &amp; I should not like to disappoint but I will leave it <orig
                        reg="entirely">intirely</orig> to you your will is my pleasure you know what
                    I would rather do but I want you <orig reg="decide">deside</orig> if you prefer
                    going to the bridge let us know immediately so we can make arrangements to that
                        <orig reg="affect">affet</orig> I leave it all for you to <orig reg="decide"
                        >deside</orig> I do not know your friends but have a desire to see them I
                    know I will love them do not forget the lady of your choice I wish you were here
                    for I am not half through but must close as it is getting late write as soon as
                    you get this you will come Friday or Saturday a week excuse all imperfections as
                    this is my birth day</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your ever true</salute>
                    <signed>Kate</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">My love to Lizzie &amp; Mr Linzy &amp; much for
                        your self be a good boy dearest &amp; strive to be happy &amp;
                        useful do write soon your Midie <pb n="4"/>Tell Mr. Linzy that he must not
                        be so bashful when he comes to old <abbr expan="Augusta">Aug</abbr> the next
                        time I will try &amp; have some lady here that will please him yours
                        Kate</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
