<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2960"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A2960">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta: Angus to Amanda C. Armentrout, November 22,
                    1866</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta angus to amanda c armentrout, november 22 1866</title>
        <author>Angus</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">6</num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A2960</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502130</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: Angus to Amanda C. Armentrout, November 22, 1866</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta angus to amanda c armentrout, november 22 1866</title>
            <author>Angus</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William F. Brand Papers</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1866-11-22">1866-11-22</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Home Front, Family, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A2960T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Angus, a teacher, writes to his friend Kate about her prospects at marriage and
                    his musings on life.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1866-11-22">Nov 22nd 1866</date>
                        <name type="place">Arbor Hill<lb/>Augusta Co. Va</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Midie</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I received your very dear missive not long since - by whom sent, I know not was
                    handed on by one of my school girls, Matter Speck. but nevertheless, not knowing
                    its route to destination, was none the less, interesting. You certainly have
                    been having a gay time this winter, in entertaining company, &amp; most
                    assuredly, after so much fatigue from setting up, was a kind act in you to write
                    me so kind &amp; dear sweet missive; I say so because I believe you are a
                    true friend of mine, although your heart is Billie's. Dreamed last night of
                    seeing Billie; do not think I saw you, but I interpret that he has been down to
                    see you - did you make your lovely appearance? Make a wedding &amp; invite
                    me, I will wait on you with the greatest felicity. Am still in the study of
                    human nature, &amp; the more I study of it, the less confidence I have in
                    myself, &amp; in such conclusion, the analogy may be, that there is little
                    confidence to be placed in any one, beyond open, social relations. But I presume
                    the best way to find out the disposition of any one, is by timely association,
                    but I do not know how your disposition can be found out, <pb n="2"/>or why you
                    wish to know, as you have concluded to live the miserable, sinful, disgraceful
                    life of an old maid.</p>

                <p>If you were like me, could not get any one, why it would be unavoidable then; but
                    your fastidious notion may leave you an old maid, companionless, as so many
                    offers have been rejected, hoping still for better. ha!ha!</p>

                <p>How does a person feel from having <add hand="h1" place="inline">wrongly</add>
                    placed their affections? would like to know; was very near once, but got bluffed
                    just in the nick of time.</p>

                <p>Have been very unwell this week; have no school; will resume on Monday next. Have
                    been afflicted with whooping cough for some time back; do you know what is good?
                    ask Mrs. A. tell her, she certainly would have to laugh to hear me barking. You
                    all had your examination &amp; never said turkey; &amp; then ask me why
                    I did not go over? well, well!! I knew of your exhibition but thought it
                    imprudent to out in the night air.</p>
                <p>Want to go to your singing on the last day, if I can be informed of the time
                    where &amp;c. Why is it that Jno Wright attends your singings so regularly?
                    Because he is so smitten with Midie; am alarmed - afraid the fellow might
                    wrongly accuse me for something; but my innocence will be manifested by the
                    loving display of Midie's affections in return for his. Is Annie's peach still
                    on <orig reg="hand">hands</orig>? Wish her much success, although she is
                    displeased with me for what I did not. Curl your hair, hang your ribbons
                    &amp; try again, is my advice; I know you are not too old. As I can think of
                    nothing worth writing, will close, by forgiving &amp; asking to be forgiven.
                    Love to all (bear up.)</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>truly yours</salute>
                    <signed>Angus</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
