<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2978"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]> 


<TEI.2 id="A2978">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta: William F. Brand to Amanda C. Armentrout,
                    February 6, 1863</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta william f brand to amanda c armentrout, february 6 1863</title>
        <author>Brand, William F.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Mary Elizabeth McCaskill</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A2978</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502148</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: William F. Brand to Amanda C. Armentrout, February 6, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta william f brand to amanda c armentrout, february 6 1863</title>
            <author>William F. Brand</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William F. Brand Papers</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-02-06">1863-02-06</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Death/Casualties, Church/Religious Activities, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A2978T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>William writes to Kate of the wounded in his camp, camp life including
                    sleighriding and the beginning of Bible class, and general news about army
                    commanders.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Miss Kate Armentrout<lb/>Lexington<lb/>Virginia
                    <name type="recipient">Miss Kate Armentrout</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-02-06">February 6th 1863<lb/>Nine oclock PM</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Winder Carolina Co Va</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Friend</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>As the most of the boys have retired to <orig reg="their">thare</orig> bed of
                    poles I have concluded to drop you a <orig reg="few">fiew</orig> lines, My
                    health is very good &amp; hope <orig reg="these">theese</orig>
                    <orig reg="few">fiew</orig> lines may find you enjoying the same blessing. <orig
                        reg="There">Thare</orig> is no news of importance to write, we <orig
                        reg="have to">hafto</orig> go on picket tomorrow morning I suppose we will
                    get a peep at our <orig reg="enemies">enimies</orig> I hope we may have a <orig
                        reg="pleasant">plesent</orig> time while we are on picket, <orig reg="There"
                        >Thare</orig> has been a <orig reg="great">grate</orig> deal of snow
                    &amp; rain in the last two <orig reg="weeks">week</orig> I hope we may have
                    some more clear weather now The <orig reg="roads">road</orig> are almost a bed
                    of mud. <pb n="2"/>It is almost <orig reg="impossible">imposible</orig> to get
                        <orig reg="provisions">provitions</orig> from the <orig reg="depot"
                    >debot</orig> to our camp I suppose <orig reg="there">thare</orig> is plenty of
                    snow in <orig reg="Augusta">augusta</orig> now for sleighing if so I hope you
                    may have some <orig reg="pleasant">plesent</orig>
                    <orig reg="sleigh rides">sleighrides</orig> we take our fun in snowballing. We
                    have formed a Bible class &amp; meet on <orig reg="Sunday">sundy</orig>
                    &amp; <orig reg="Wednesday">Wednsday</orig> nights to recite our <orig
                        reg="lessons">lessings</orig> I hope it may be carried on and that some good
                    may come <orig reg="of">ove</orig> it we have a grand theatre in the Regt,
                    carried on by Capt Brown of the Marion Rifles he is a very good performer he is
                    a noble singer. Capt Newton started home this morning on furlough he is very
                    lucky in getting home though I do not envy him his good fortune I would have
                    written by the Capt if I had have had notice <pb n="3"/>in time. As it is I will
                        <orig reg="have to">hafto</orig> risk another by mail hoping it may soon
                    reach your hand Well Kate did your cous, Lizzie make you acquainted with all her
                        <orig reg="secrets">secreets</orig> if so do you know who she is engaged to
                    I will tell you my reasons for asking you this question in my next letter if you
                    answer it I am a thousand times obliged to you for the cheese you sent to me I
                    assure you it was something I never look for I would like to be in a mess with
                    your brother but the boys would think hard of me for leaving my old mess I may
                    say we are almost one mess for whenever one mess gets a box the other is <orig
                        reg="invited">envited</orig> to share its contents but if Lieut Dempster
                    joines the officers mess I <orig reg="expect">exspect</orig> to change well Kate
                    I <orig reg="wasn't">wasent</orig> aware that I had <pb n="4"/>shown so many
                        <orig reg="signs">sines</orig> of my weakness on leaving Greenville it goes
                    to show the feebleness of mans nature I was very sorry to hear of the <orig
                        reg="bereavements">perevements</orig> of the Harris <orig reg="families"
                        >famlies</orig> I hope the <orig reg="all-wise">alwise</orig> God may do
                    unto them as he did unto <orig reg="Job">jobe</orig> of old bless <orig
                        reg="their">thare</orig> future years you said you wished you could take our
                    places down <orig reg="here">hear</orig> do you think you could stand out on
                        <orig reg="guard">gard</orig> one of <orig reg="these">theese</orig> cold
                    nights and if you could <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> you <orig reg="think"
                    >thin</orig> we would be as unhappy if all the Ladies <orig reg="were">ware</orig>
                    <orig reg="here">hear</orig> and we <orig reg="were">ware</orig> at home you
                    wrote as if you had been trying to get me to change my love for you but <orig
                        reg="alas">alass</orig> how could I you are constantly in my thoughts by day
                    and my dreams by night &amp; God forbid that I should ever love another
                    woman I have often thought dear Kate that you never loved me as I did you but
                    found the keys of my heart and took pity on me. It seemes to me that man is one
                    of Gods weakest instruments well Kate I have not entirely quit chewing tobacco
                    yet I have used one plug since I came back to the company I used to chew two a
                    week I hope I may entirely quit before long; uncle John was wounded at the <orig
                        reg="Sharpsburg">sharpsburg</orig> fight in the arm, I <orig reg="expect"
                        >exspect</orig> he is in <orig reg="Buckingham">buckingham</orig>. Bro John
                    had a letter for me from Sister when I came down She was well and going to
                    school I would like very much to see her Jake is well and looks <orig
                        reg="hardy">harty</orig> cous, Jimmie is enjoying the same blessing I must
                    bring my letter to a close as it is <orig reg="after">afto</orig> twelve oclock
                    Abe stayed up and bothered me <orig reg="until">untill</orig> eleven trying to
                    find out who I was going to write to my respects to all; the family write soon
                    as I am always glad to hear from you let no one see this</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>I remain your much attached friend</salute>
                    <signed>W.F.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
