<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2986"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A2986">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta: William F. Brand to Amanda C. Armentrout,
                    May 16, 1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta william f brand to amanda c armentrout, may 16 1864</title>
        <author>Brand, William F.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Mary Elizabeth McCaskill</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">12</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A2986</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502156</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: William F. Brand to Amanda C. Armentrout, May 16, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta william f brand to amanda c armentrout, may 16 1864</title>
            <author>William F. Brand</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>10 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William F. Brand Papers</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-05-16">1864-05-16</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties, Family, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A2986T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>William writes to Kate about his desire that the army be more Christian, troop
                    movements, his fears of their estrangement, and the health of his comrades in
                    the army.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Miss Kate Armentrout<lb/>Lexington<lb/>Virginia
                    <name type="recipient">Miss Kate Armentrout</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-05-16">May 16th 1864</date>
                        <name type="place">Greenville Va</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Friend</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>In all probability you think that I am dead or forgotten you as I have kept
                    silent for so long. I <orig reg="received">recieved</orig> your letter on the
                    eve before the battle of the fifth while we <orig reg="were">ware</orig> cooking
                    rations I was truly glad to hear from you. I was wounded on last <orig
                        reg="Thursday">thirsday</orig> the 12th a flesh wound in the right arm near
                    the <orig reg="shoulder">sholder</orig> I have no doubt but you will expect me
                    to give you a full account of the casualties of our company on that day but I am
                        <orig reg="sorry">soray</orig> I can not I was wounded about nine oclock
                    &amp; went <pb n="2"/>back to the field hospital &amp; got my wound
                    dressed &amp; stayed <orig reg="there">thare</orig>
                    <orig reg="until">untill</orig> twelve oclock; when all that was able to walk
                        <orig reg="were">ware</orig> ordered back to some other hospital &amp;
                        <orig reg="there">thare</orig> was none nearer than <orig reg="Louisa"
                        >Loeusa</orig> C.H. I <orig reg="begged">beged</orig> them to let me stay
                        <orig reg="until">untill</orig> the fight was over but they said I could be
                    of no use &amp; would just be in the way Capt Dempster advised me to go on
                    to some hospital Sam A Lightner Mays &amp; Hight, <orig reg="were"
                    >ware</orig> wounded &amp; came home with me all slight wounds; Lightner
                    wounded in the right hand Mays in the left side &amp; Hight on the right
                        <orig reg="shoulder">sholder</orig> Jake was safe when I left him he was
                    with me after we fell back from our breastworks &amp; I <orig reg="don't"
                        >dount</orig> think our <orig reg="Brigade">Brigde</orig> went in any more
                    that day I have not the least doubt but many of our <pb n="3"/>boys ware taken
                    prisoners; The <orig reg="enemy">enimy</orig>
                    <orig reg="amassed">massed</orig>
                    <orig reg="their">thare</orig> troops in front of the second Brigade &amp;
                    at daylight charged the second &amp; drove them from <orig reg="their"
                    >thare</orig> breastworks &amp; following them <orig reg="closely"
                    >closly</orig> captured many. By having that gap open thay soon attacked our
                    Brigade in front flank &amp; in the rear. The front line was <orig
                        reg="dispersed">deperesed</orig> &amp; a <orig reg="great">grate</orig>
                    many of our boys jumped over the breastworks &amp; took after the Yanks
                    capturing <orig reg="one">on</orig> of <orig reg="their">thare</orig>
                    <orig reg="colors">coulars</orig> Colonel Funk then told us if we did not get
                    out of <orig reg="there">thare</orig> we would be all captured. Then we
                    commenced retreating to our second line of works &amp; while I was crossing
                    the field I was wounded I am very <orig reg="thankful">thankfull</orig> to the
                    great &amp; good God that I came out so well the air seemed filled with the
                        <orig reg="leaden">laden</orig>
                    <orig reg="messengers">mesangers</orig> of death I do not know <orig
                        reg="whether">whethar</orig>
                    <pb n="4"/>Brother John came out safe or not he was on the skirmish line
                    &amp; when the <orig reg="enemy">enimy</orig> advanced he fell back on the
                    left of the Regt. Abe came out safe I heard from him friday I hope to get the
                    all <orig reg="particulars">perticulars</orig> of the battle tomorrow. Jim
                    Vines, Kelley &amp; Sayton was take <orig reg="prisoners">prisaners</orig>
                    last thursday week the 9th. I was very sorry for him but hope he may be well
                    treated Cicero Bare was <orig reg="mortally">mortly</orig> wounded since died
                    John Pilson has lost a leg <add hand="h1" place="inline">amputated</add> above
                    the knee. Jim Trusler was killed dead Willie Gardner was killed a <orig
                        reg="great">grate</orig> many wounded from <orig reg="different"
                    >diferent</orig> parts of Augusta The Yanks have fought with more <orig
                        reg="desperation">desperration</orig> than they ever fought before Sometimes
                    I can but cry. oh Lord, what demon has taken <orig reg="possession"
                    >posession</orig> of the people that they are so thirsty for blood. Lord ease
                        <orig reg="their">thare</orig>
                    <orig reg="appetites">apatites</orig>
                    <pb n="5"/>I suppose you have <orig reg="heard">hurd</orig>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> who all <orig reg="were">ware</orig> wounded in our <abbr
                        expan="Company">Comp</abbr> the first days fight, all my mess have been
                    wounded but Crist, Rubush Abny was wounded in the ear Shot a round hole the size
                    of a <orig reg="Minie">meny</orig> ball in the left ear he will always be <orig
                        reg="known">nown</orig> as cross eared Abny Trotter <orig reg="received"
                        >recieved</orig> a flesh wound in the left thigh &amp; Grieaver was
                    wounded in the foot I suppose his wound is very <orig reg="painful"
                    >painfull</orig>. Since the commencement of the fighting our <abbr
                        expan="Company">Comp</abbr> has had fifteen wounded &amp; one has died
                    Tom Shannon Campell he was <orig reg="mortally">mortly</orig> wounded last <orig
                        reg="Tuesday">teusday</orig>
                    <orig reg="morning">moroning</orig> &amp; died that <orig reg="evening"
                        >eavning</orig> poor fellow I went and talked to him &amp; <orig
                        reg="tried">tryed</orig> to cheer him, He said oh Bill I can not be <pb
                        n="6"/><orig reg="cheeful">cheerfull</orig> my wound is <orig reg="too">to</orig>
                    <orig reg="painful">painfull</orig> he was soon moved <orig reg="off">of</orig>
                    &amp; I <orig reg="couldn't">coulnt</orig> get to say much to him. Our
                    division has lost heavily in prisoners &amp; wounded. When we commenced
                    fighting we had four Brigadeer Generals &amp; one Maj Gen. now we have none
                    able to command. Johnson &amp; Stuart captured; Stafford &amp; Jones
                        <orig reg="were">ware</orig> killed. Walker badly wounded in the arm. All
                    our Regimental field officers came out safe Cousin William Koiner was badly
                    wounded last thursday. The night before we started from our old camp Capt
                    Lampster Jim Vines &amp; George Valentine came out to enquire the way of
                    salvation oh how I wish our army would become an army of <orig reg="Christians"
                        >Christains</orig> then I am sure <pb n="7"/>we would be invincible our God
                    would smile upon us &amp; we would seen be a free &amp; happy people I
                    saw your Father today. he was well &amp; said all <orig reg="were"
                    >ware</orig> well at home Rachel C came up to see me to inquire after her
                    brother he was well the day before the great Battle I was glad to hear you <orig
                        reg="were">ware</orig> well pleased in Rockbridge &amp; was happy try
                    &amp; make your older sister <orig reg="cheerful">cheerfull</orig> &amp;
                    happy in her new home with a kind husband by her side to console her <orig
                        reg="every">evry</orig> want dear Kate you asked me whether I had any
                    objections to you sending your friend your picture What objections could I have
                    I am sure I am not your master or lawgiver I would advise you <pb n="8"/>to do
                    as you think best I hope you have not delayed sending it to him on account of my
                    delaying writing so long Abney had all my paper &amp; <orig reg="envelopes"
                        >envellopes</orig> in his portfolio &amp; took it with him when he was
                    wounded &amp; we <orig reg="were">ware</orig> almost constantly in the
                    ditches waiting for the <orig reg="enemy">enimy</orig> to advance. You asked me
                    my reasons for telling your cousin about our <orig reg="estrangement"
                        >enstrangment</orig>. She guessed as much by my not going down to see you
                    She asked me <orig reg="wasn't">wasnt</orig> she right &amp; I could not
                    deny it; She seemed sorry &amp; hoped it would all be made up &amp; for
                        <add hand="h1" place="inline">my</add> saying you mistreated me I deny it.
                    dear Kate I <orig reg="feel">fell</orig> sad this <orig reg="evening"
                    >eavning</orig> I often think I would be happier if I was taken out of this
                    world &amp; could be with a kind Mother in heaven My prospect for worldly
                        <orig reg="happiness">hapiness</orig> is dark forgive my <orig
                        reg="weakness">wekness</orig> in thus writing. My heart seems filled to over
                    flooding this <orig reg="evening">eavning</orig>. <pb n="9"/>We recieved news
                    this <orig reg="evening">eavning</orig> from camp <orig reg="there">thare</orig>
                    has been <orig reg="fifteen">fiften</orig> wounded &amp; twenty three
                    missing Jake is still safe so is Brother John &amp; all the <orig
                        reg="Ruebushes">Ruebushis</orig> if I had <orig reg="their">thare</orig>
                    names <orig reg="here">hear</orig> I would send you a list but I know but part
                    &amp; I will not send any I hope this may find you well My health is very
                    good I <orig reg="have">hav</orig><pb n="10"/>fallen <orig reg="off">of</orig>
                    some ten or fifteen lbs since I was wounded my arm is getting tired I will stop
                    Ever <orig reg="believe">pelieve</orig> me to be your true friend &amp;
                    please write soon as I shall look for an answer in a few days</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Now may a great &amp; Good God protect you is the prayer of</salute>
                    <signed>William</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
