<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2984"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A2984">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta: William F. Brand to Amanda C. Armentrout,
                    April 10, 1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta william f brand to amanda c armentrout, april 10 1864</title>
        <author>Brand, William F.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Mary Elizabeth McCaskill</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A2984</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502154</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: William F. Brand to Amanda C. Armentrout, April 10, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta william f brand to amanda c armentrout, april 10 1864</title>
            <author>William F. Brand</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William F. Brand Papers</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-04-10">1864-04-10</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Church/Religious Activity, Troop Movement, Military Authority, Family, </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A2984T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>William writes to Kate of camp religious life, his belief that he won't have a
                    furlough unless he becomes sick or the Yankees get him, and his continued love
                    for her.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Miss Kate Armentrout<lb/>Greenville<lb/>Augusta County<lb/>Virginia
                    <name type="recipient">Miss Kate Armentrout</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-04-10">April 10th</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Randolph</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Friend</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I <orig reg="received">recieved</orig> yours of the 21st on the sixth; I failed
                    in <orig reg="receiving">recieving</orig> your letter in time to write to you
                    before you would leave home, Thought it best to wait a day or two then direct to
                    Lexington; <orig reg="There">Thare</orig> never was a letter <orig
                        reg="received">recieved</orig> with more pleasure, or perused with more
                    interest; When Abe returned to camp we <orig reg="were">ware</orig> on picket
                    &amp; <orig reg="didn't">didnt</orig> get to camp <orig reg="until"
                    >untill</orig> the 4th; I believe my letter was enclosed in one of <orig
                        reg="packs">packes</orig> he gave it to me on the 6th I hope you will not be
                    low spirited when this reaches you for I do not feel as if I could interest you
                    this <orig reg="evening">eavening</orig>. I spent part of the <orig
                        reg="forenoon">four noon</orig> of this blessed day at our little <orig
                        reg="chapel">chaple</orig>; <orig reg="there">Thare</orig> was a large
                    congregation all seemed <pb n="2"/>to <orig reg="pay">pa</orig> strict attention
                    to the word of life; oh how I do wish all our soldiers would become pious men I
                    am sure then our armies would be invincible I sometimes think your brother is
                    trying to be a better boy. I pray I may be right for I hope to see him a true
                    christian I <orig reg="need">nead</orig> not ask you to make him a special
                    object in your <orig reg="secret">secreet</orig> communings for I am sure you
                    do; <orig reg="There">Thare</orig> is no news in camp worth your attention.
                        <orig reg="Everything">Evrything</orig> is quiet as far as I know The <orig
                        reg="weather">wether</orig> has been very <orig reg="inclement"
                    >inclemment</orig> for the last two weeks; first snow then rain my darling Kate
                    you said your face could not <orig reg="wear">ware</orig> a joyous smile, <orig
                        reg="until">untill</orig> you could behold my face, Cheer up my ever <orig
                        reg="faithful">faithfull</orig> one I hope the time will soon hasten round
                    when we may meet, But I pray <orig reg="thee">the</orig> not to put off smiling
                        <orig reg="until">untill</orig> I come, but rather try &amp; be <orig
                        reg="cheerful">cheerfull</orig> &amp; <orig reg="happy">hapy</orig>
                    darling I am sorry that my last letter brought with it sorrow to thy <pb n="3"
                    />noble heart; God knows I would not <orig reg="purposely">purposly</orig> give
                        <orig reg="thee">the</orig> trouble. Would that I <orig reg="were"
                    >ware</orig> so situated that I could say to the <orig reg="idol">idle</orig> of
                    my heart lean upon my <del hand="h1">heart</del> arm <orig reg="and">an</orig> I
                    will support <orig reg="thee">the</orig> through life with a willingness that
                    would <orig reg="know">now</orig> no end. That dream of yours oh that it was a
                    reality <orig reg="I'm">I'me</orig> my <orig reg="happiness">hapine<add
                            hand="h1" place="inline">ss</add></orig> would be <orig reg="complete"
                        >compleat</orig>, Often in my nightly slumber you are by my side &amp; I
                    wake finding my arms around my friend Trot -- oh! Dear Kate I fear you have some
                    clue that will be injurious to your kind sisters <orig reg="happiness"
                    >hapiness</orig> in the future I would be sorry if anything should <orig
                        reg="occur">accur</orig> to cause her to be sorry for her change in life. I
                    have heard <orig reg="rumors">rumers</orig> but I hope thay are <orig reg="all"
                        >al</orig> false My wish is that she may be <orig reg="happy">hapy</orig>
                    throughout her days, You need not look for me this summer without sickness or
                    the Yanks give me a furlough. The detail I was at home on counted as a furlough
                    I would be <orig reg="satisfied">sadisfied</orig> if I was sure you <orig
                        reg="were">ware</orig>
                    <orig reg="happy">hapy</orig>, Abe told me you desired me to direct your letter
                    in the care of your friend Rachel I think we had better continue <pb n="4"/>to
                    direct as we have in the past for if your parents <orig reg="should"
                    >shuld</orig> ever find out you were <orig reg=" corresponding"
                    >corissponding</orig> with me in a <orig reg="secret">secreet</orig> way <orig
                        reg="their">thare</orig> anger would be increased against both of us while
                    they do not <orig reg="positively">positivly</orig> object we had best write
                    openly dear Kate what can I do to alleviate your troubles, I love you yes
                    passionately &amp; if you think you have ever treated me <orig reg="wrong"
                        >rong</orig> I forgive thee, &amp; will if you will permit love and
                    cherish <orig reg="thee">
                        <add hand="h1" place="inline">the</add>
                    </orig> more than I ever did, I believe my own coldness brought on our troubles
                    about but I believe they will <add hand="h1" place="inline">be</add> a <orig
                        reg="blessing">blesing</orig> to us both I am sure it has drawn thee nearer
                    to me, I can only say speed on sweet day when I may meet thee. I must soon close
                    My health is very good &amp; I hope this may find you enjoying the same with
                        <orig reg="cheerful">ceerfull</orig> spirits. Give my love to you sister
                    &amp; write soon It is getting so dark that I can hardly see how to write I
                    have not <orig reg="heard">hurd</orig> from Bro. Charles only by your letter
                    Sister is well She desires to know your name I will give it to her in my next
                    letter, Now may the blessing of a great &amp; good God be with you</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>from your true friend</salute>
                    <signed>Willie</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
