<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A3026"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A3026">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Tony Pastor to Annie Harris, July
                    25, 1861</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county tony pastor to annie harris, july 25 1861</title>
        <author>Pastor, Tony</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A3026</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502186</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Tony Pastor to Annie Harris, July 25, 1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county tony pastor to annie harris, july 25 1861</title>
            <author>Tony Pastor</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Tony Pastor to Annie Harris, July
                            25, 1861, Nellie Harris private collection</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from private collection</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-07-25">1861-07-25</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Battle Description, Camp Life, Church/Religious Activity,
                        Death/Casualties, Military Authority, Military Strategy, Patriotism,
                        Prisons/Prisoners, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A3026T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Pastor begins by describing a very hard march to a position in the Piedmont, then
                    describes the Battle of Bull Run in some detail. He expresses patriotic
                    sentiment in the early part of the letter but describes horror at reviewing the
                    wounded and dead on the field after the battle. He also refers to the Union
                    troops as rebels.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-07-25">July 25<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1861</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Pickens</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Annie,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p> I seat myself this morning for the purpose of writing you a short epistle. That
                    you may acertain my whereabouts. We are stationed at the above named place,
                    which is about 4 <abbr expan="miles">Mi.</abbr> from "Manasses Junction" where
                    we arrrived on friday last, which was the 18<hi rend="super">
                        <hi rend="underline">th</hi>
                    </hi>. We left Winchester on Thursday about 12 Oclock, <orig reg="traveled"
                        >travailed</orig> 23 miles to a little town named Parris. where we arrived
                    at 1 Oclock in the night. I tell you this was the severest march we have had
                    except one. We were so completely exhausted, that we just fell down on the
                    ground, &amp; in a few moments we were fast asleep. We resumed our march the
                    next morning at day break, &amp; arrived at "Piedmont" where we took the
                        <unclear>cars</unclear> for this point. The rest you <orig reg="know"
                    >Kno</orig> up to our arrival here, We took on a little something to eat.
                    &amp; in a few moments we were on the tramp again. We took off in the<pb
                        n="2"/> direction of Alexandria &amp; <orig reg="traveled"
                    >travailed</orig> about 4 miles on the lookout for the enemy. night soon
                    overtook us, &amp; then what a time we did have, nothing to sleep on,
                    nothing to eat, &amp; worse than all, we could get no water that was fit to
                    drink. But we put up with it all without a murmer, Knowing our country's welfare
                    was at stake. we got no sleep that night again, only what little we could get
                    between <hi rend="underline">halts</hi>, shifting our position. every hour or
                    two the whole night this was the case the next day, which was saturday. That
                    night however we fared pretty well - slept all the time. The next morning which
                    was <orig reg="Sabbath">Sabath</orig>, we were called to arms, to prepare for
                    the battle, which you doubtless have heard of ere this.</p>
                <p>It was about five Oclock in the morning when the first cannon was fired by the
                    enemy. This they kept up for several hours, doubtless with the
                    <unclear>view</unclear> of drawing out troops to<pb n="3"/> that point. Whilst
                    at the same time they were <orig reg="trying">tryin</orig> to flank us on the
                    left. But I am happy to say they were defeated in their design they were met by
                    the Georgians &amp; South <unclear>Carolinans</unclear> who held them for
                    near two hours, but the enemy being too strong in numbers, they had to fall
                    back, In the mean time our batteries were playing upon them beautifully General
                        <orig reg="Beauregard">Buragard</orig> came up with a strong reinforcement,
                    accompanied by <abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr>
                    <orig reg="Stuart's">Stuarts</orig> Cavalry, &amp; in a very short time we
                    routed the rebels completely. They dropped Guns, Knapsacks, Overcoats, Blankets,
                    swords, &amp; in fact every thing that would impede their progress in
                    retreating, Our men being in full posession of the battle ground. But Oh; what a
                    spectacle presented itself then, to see the killed &amp; wounded laying on
                    the field by hundreds &amp; thousands, was a horrid sight. But so it was<pb
                        n="4"/> I saw those with <orig reg="whom">whoome</orig> I had long been
                    acquainted, laying crying for help &amp; for some one to take them away when
                    it was impossible for me to <add hand="h1" place="inline">do</add> anything for
                    them. I helped to carry poor Charley <unclear>Bell</unclear> off he had his arm
                    &amp; point of his shoulder torn off with a cannon Ball. Baxter
                    <unclear>Ott</unclear> &amp; him were killed with the same ball. I <orig
                        reg="can't">cant</orig> take time to enumerate <add hand="h1" place="inline"
                        >the names of</add> all that I saw laying dead &amp; wounded of our men,
                    neither do I want to call it <add hand="h1" place="inline">to</add> mind again
                    for it heart rendering indeed to think of it. Our loss is variously estimated at
                    from 5 to 1500 killed &amp; wounded. Whilst that of the enemy is supposed to
                    be from 5 to 12,000. This is awful, to think of so many men being called into
                    eternity in a few short hours. We took about 1000 Prisoners, they are sent to
                    Richmond to be put into custody. We also got some 60 pieces of artillery
                    &amp; a great many horses &amp; wagons, also 2000 Guns <unclear>etc.
                    etc</unclear>. Suffice it to say that it was a glorious victory we achieved on
                    last <orig reg="sabbath">sabath</orig>. I must close, please write as soon as
                    you can &amp; let me hear from you all I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know
                    how long we will stay here, perhaps a good while &amp; perhaps not more than
                    a day. its hard to tell I must close by saying that I am well &amp; hope
                    there may find you enjoying the same blessing. May God bless &amp; preserve
                    you from all danger, is the prayer of your devoted friend</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed>Tony Pastor</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">[written at top of first page] <orig reg="Don't"
                        >Dont</orig> show this to <orig reg="anyone">any one</orig> if you please as
                        it is so badly written &amp; put together I am in such a hurry I <orig
                            reg="can't">cant</orig> do any thing <hi rend="underline">
                            <unclear>right</unclear>
                        </hi></seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
