<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A4027"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A4027">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, March
     15, 1863</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, march 15 1863</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Lara Diefenderfer</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">11</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A4027</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502226</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, March 15, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, march 15 1863</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1863-03-15">1863-03-15</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Troop Movement, Church/Religious Activity, Agriculture, Military Authority, African
      Americans, Slavery</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A4027T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss writes about the horrible destruction of war, the bad weather in camp, and the
     environment around the camp. He comments on the farm and affairs back home, and a possible
     commission for himself.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Sara A. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1863-03-15">Sunday Night March 15<hi rend="underline">
        <hi rend="super">th</hi>
      </hi> 1863</date>
      <name type="place">Moss Neck, Caroline Co. Va.</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Own Dear Wife:</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I wrote you a few lines the other day when I received your welcome letter, but promised that
     should not be a bar to my writing agian today, as usual, so I am now prompt to fulfill my
     agreement, and you must credit me largely for doing just what you desire. I suppose I write to
     you today for the last time from this place, for orders are out for us to move, at dawn
     tomorrow, to a new camp, just in the rear of the last battlefield, 8 miles up the river from
     here, and we shall go unless this storm, that has opened upon us today, with thunder and
     lightning, rain, hail and sleet; shall continue with too much fury. We have been here just
     three months, a long time, but how speedily it has gone, inaction has made it seem short, not
     like the month, yea year long weeks of the busy summer that preceded this long rest, now, alas!
     again to be broken by a repetition of the same sufferings, privations and bloody battles that
     marked the previous Spring, Summer &amp; Fall, I was going to add, Winter; for the last
     battle was almost mid-December. Activity must soon succeed to this quiet and the storm, the
     tempest &amp; the hurricane of war <pb n="2"/>begin to rage again -- O when will it cease,
     when shall the plowshare of death give way to that of life &amp; the land enjoy its now
     desecrated Sabbaths once more. God grant to shorten these days before we all perish -- You ask
     me what I think of the signs of the times -- Speaking from the outward &amp; human
     appearance they are gloomy and portentious enough, to us: the whole sky is blackend by the
     prodigies War has conjured up, with aid of its sister furies Pestilence &amp; Famine, and
     only evil seems to threaten us, but it was even so one year ago, the same gloom palled our land
     and the same spirits of evil were everywhere brooding over it, but we bowed humbly before our
     God &amp; confessed our sins as a nation, we girded up ourselves as men, and lo they all
     passed away and "the winter of our discontent" became a glorious summer of rejoicing, crowned
     by a plenteous harvest time of farms and blessings -- so may it be again, yea I am confident it
     so will be --</p>
    <p> "Indulge not the Lord by feeble sins</p>
    <p> But trust him for his grace</p>
    <p> Behind a frowning Providence</p>
    <p> He hides a smiling face."<lb/> I have always found Him "a <hi rend="underline">very</hi>
     present help in time of need &amp; so I trust he will continue to be to our land and nation
     as he has been to it in times gone by -- but not remote.</p>
    <p> So let us take courage and be of good cheer for the <hi rend="underline">Lord</hi> of Hosts
     is our helper &amp; we will not fear what <unclear>waits us</unclear> can do <pb n="3"/>How
     the storm is raging! the hail and rain are pouring down on my <orig reg="canvas">canvass</orig>
     roof and a chilly dampness attests the penetrating effect of this moistened atmosphere -- all
     seems gloomy &amp; cheerless, dark and disagreeable, but tomorrow morning <hi
      rend="underline">may</hi> and likely <hi rend="underline">will</hi>, find the sun streaming
     thorugh the dissipating vapors &amp; cheering us with a spring morning -- thus, ever, it
     happens with human things -- as you wrote me, in halcyon days of the now long ago that "every
     cloud has its silver lining", so let us reflect that "joy cometh in the morning" and "fear no
     danger", trusting to Him that is mightier than the mightiest.</p>

    <p>We have had a very good place here, the climate has been mild, though damp, and we have had a
     good degree of health and comfort here and I can but think Providence wisely ordered that
     McClellan should leave the Valley &amp; we follow him and find our winter quarters nearer
     the sea &amp; in a milder climate. Things have changed much since we came here, one large
     forest covered the crest of the chain of hills running along from one to two miles from the
     river, and stretched back for nearly a mile and in the edge of this forest, peeping out towards
     the river, were the baronial, almost, mansions of the old F.F.V<hi rend="underline">s</hi> of
     "The Northern Neck", but we have had our camps along these hilltops, and the trees have
     disappeared &amp; houses that never looked at each other in the almost century they have
     been standing stare each other impudently <pb n="4"/>in the face -- having barely the trees
     that surround them left to tell of the lordly race from whose destructions they are spared --
     so it is here -- but across the river they too are gone and whatever new generation shall live
     in that land they cannot say they sit under the trees their fathers planted -- We pay nearly
     One Hundred thousand Dollars for damages to the farms on which we have encamped &amp; from
     that you may form some idea of the "abomination of desolation" an army produces -- Boswell has
     sent after a servant and when it comes I shall try and send William up to help make garden
     &amp; he will make Allen help him &amp; so push it along -- I hope Nelson has found
     some one to buy the farm -- if I could only get away for some two weeks I think I might find a
     purchaser, but it of no use to ask now -- for the days of activity are coming <orig reg="on"
      >one</orig> and we must work -- besides I do not wish to do anything that might lead to a loss
     of my place with Gen. <abbr expan="Jackson">J.</abbr> for then I should be compelled to join
     some company and serve there, or only be detailed on a private's pay -- Gen. Jackson wants me
     commissioned &amp; I may get so by the application I have made, but so many appointments
     have been made from Va -- that it is next to impossible to get any one appointed from that
     state -- as it is I am here by Gen. Lee's orders &amp; so far all is right, but the
     officers at Richmond are doing all they can to get every one into the ranks that is not
     commissioned -- but I do not fear -- my services are needed here -- they are appreciated by
     those I am with and I have <orig reg="too">to</orig> well committed the lesson "Learn to labor
     and to wait" to forget it at this time -- so I may not absent myself much as I desire to close
     my business matters, but I shall press them up as much as I can - - Be of good cheer my love
     &amp; pray for a shortening of these days of separation &amp; may God bless you in all
     blessings -- Write very soon -- we have no news -- Love for you all -- </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your <abbr expan="Affectionate">Aff.</abbr> husband</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
     <seg type="postscript">I will write to Nelly after we move. We are to go at dawn tomorrow
     --</seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
