<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A4033"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A4033">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, April
     24, 1863</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, april 24 1863</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Lara Diefenderfer</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A4033</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502232</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, April 24, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, april 24 1863</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>2 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1863-04-24">1863-04-24</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>African Americans, Slavery, Home Front, Women, Military Authority, Church/Religious
      Activity, Camp Life, Family</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A4033T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss discusses the food items he sent home, and the visit of General Lee's wife to the
     camp.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Sara A. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1863-04-24">April 24<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1863</date>
      <name type="place"><abbr expan="Head Quarters">Hd. Qrs.</abbr> 2<hi rend="super">
       <hi rend="underline">nd</hi>
      </hi> Corps <abbr expan="Army of Northern Virginia">A. N. Va.</abbr>
      </name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Ever Dear One:</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I have been delaying to write to you, owing to a press of business and a mishap that <orig
      reg="befell">befel</orig> me in the running off of my horse, compelling me to look three days
     for him, hard riding, in the rain, and it was only this P. M. that I found him, so I have not
     been in any mood for writing, you may well imagine.</p>
    <p> William got back Monday, all safe, everything right &amp; nothing broken, a few beans
     and apples mixed, but they were soon sorted &amp; he had faithfully attended to every
     errand I sent by him -- he gives glowing accounts of the beauty of your yard, the condition of
     your wood pile and the air of "Comfort" that pervades all things "at home" &amp; almost
     made me homesick with the recital Many thanks for your numerous favors -- I enjoyed a <hi
      rend="underline">full</hi> meal much, being prepared to appreciate it from a continued
     abstinence of sundry days. I am very sorry the jars got broken, thought the blanket would keep
     them tight -- you did not say whether the molasses and sugar came safely -- they will aid in
     eking out your store of sweets -- I fear you denied yourselves to send me butter, in your noble
     self denying for my benefit -- I hope you did not, for I <orig reg="can">cand</orig> do without
     better than you can -- I bought me a new pair of pants today from the <abbr
      expan="Quarter 
 Master">Q. M.</abbr> for $7.50 -- so I am supplied &amp; can let William
     have my old blue ones &amp; he will be provided for. We are having very hard rains and the
     roads are very muddy, so there is not much prospect of any movements soon -- A few of the enemy
     came across at Port Royal a day or two ago, but they <pb n="2"/>soon went back. The General's
     wife came up Monday and she and "Miss" Julia Laura (the lately arrived one) are now at Mr.
     Yerby's -- a mile below here -- the General goes down about dark and comes back to breakfast
     and prayers at 7 A. M. -- so is up by daylight, you see, a pattern for all good soldiers -- but
     one which many of them would be slow to imitate under like circumstances, I imagine. Mr Lacy
     baptized the "Baby" yesterday -- the Gen. says it is "very <hi rend="underline">fine</hi>, very
     fine." I have been so busy looking for my horse that I have not my respects to Madam as yet,
      <orig reg="though">tho'</orig> most of the Staff have done so -- I may go tomorrow and will
     tell you about her as, of course, there is much importance pertaining to the "Lieutenant
     Generaless," as Smith calls her - - The soldiers cheered them when they saw him help her out of
     the cars -- You did not say what you thought of Lindsey's place after I wrote you the price --
     I can easily borrow the money on long time and at a monderate rate of interest, but I shall be
     governed in the matter entirely by your views in regard to it. Nelson writes to me that Mrs.
     Opie is unwilling for her girl to go over the Mt. so he will send her to you &amp; you will
     then be relieved from much drudgery you have had to undergo, and you can make such disposition
     of Allen's time as you see proper &amp; make as much out of him as you can -- I will send
     you more money in a few days. You may give those <abbr expan="accounts">a/cts</abbr> of Dr.
     Butcher's to James Bear (Harvey's son) and tell him to get them receipted and I will pay them.
     I am very sorry for Mr. C. Bear &amp; family &amp; can but mourn with them. Pardon my
     short letter, My Dear, I am so weary after my long ride today -- Write to me often -- I have no
     fears of the enemy's coming to Augusta -- I still consider it safe, but admire your spirit
     under impending evils -- Love &amp; kisses for you all -- &amp; may the Lord's belssing
     be with you -- </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your true husband</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
