<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A4050"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A4050">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, August
     21, 1863</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, august 21 1863</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Lara Diefenderfer</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A4050</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502249</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, August 21, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, august 21 1863</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1863-08-21">1863-08-21</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Church/Religious Activity, Military Authority, Women, Patriotism, Desertion/Leave,
      Family, Home Front</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A4050T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss writes of a Sunday in camp, commenting on the sermon at length. He hopes to get
     leave to go home soon.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Sara A. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1863-08-21">August 21<hi rend="underline">
        <hi rend="super">st</hi>
      </hi> 1863</date>
      <name type="place"><abbr expan="Head Quarters">Hd. Qrs.</abbr> 2<hi rend="underline">
       <hi rend="super">nd</hi>
      </hi> Corps -- Orange <abbr expan="Court House">C.H.</abbr> Va.</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Dear Wife and Children:</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I have a little leisure in the cool of this evening &amp; I will write you a few lines --
     a little conversation, <orig reg="though">tho'</orig> far away over the Blue Mountains -- We
     have had an "appointed day of fasting &amp; prayer", and it has been well observed -- a
     Sabbath stillness has prevailed &amp; every one seems to have been impressed with a proper
     sense of the importance of humbling ourselves before God, confessing our sins &amp;
     imploring his aid in the time of our extremity. Mr Lacy preached at our <abbr
      expan="Head Quarters">Hd. Qrs.</abbr> at 11 A. M. to some 1500 -- among them Gens. Lee,
     Johnson, Rodes &amp;c, &amp; quite a group of ladies &amp; children, on the nice
     lawn in front of the house where we are encamped -- his text was from 2<hi rend="underline">
      <hi rend="super">nd</hi>
     </hi> Kings 6<hi rend="super">th</hi>-16<pb n="2"/> and he gave us a capital discourse in the
     estimation of all that heard it. He said though we had suffered a few reverses they were only
     needed to check our pride -- and in the only way it could be checked -- David had 3
     alternatives offered to him for the punishment of his pride &amp; he chose to fall into the
     hands of God - -we had vainly thought we could do anything by our might and had arrogated the
     glory to ourselves, but God had restrained us &amp; it might prove our salvation -- He
     called upon each one to make himself what <hi rend="underline">he</hi> ought to be before God,
     and then all would become good and a blessing could not be denied us. He argued that we had
     been favored of God, that we had sought to acknowledge him by our acts, while our enemy had
     ignored him &amp; vainly boasted of starving us and such inhuman things which God could
     not, from his nature, approve, &amp; so he must be against them -- .<pb n="3"/> He
     administered a proper rebuke to frivolity "the mingling of blood &amp; festivity", and gave
     to each one his portion. There is quite a religious feeling in some of the Brigades &amp;
     many have been converted - five ministers of our church reported to Mr. Lacy this week, two
     from Louisiana, one from Alabama &amp;c - Mr. See is down here for a time - Dr. Ben Smith's
     son is here for a day or so with Lt. Smith - he is a fine young man --. I thought while Mr.
     Lacy was preaching, of the admirable notions you often have in your letters of the demands of
     the times &amp; the merging of self in the public claims of the notion - I must commend you
     for your enlarged views of rights &amp; duties.</p>
    <p> I am very busy on the reconnaisance I wrote to you about, but hope to soon finish, when I
     intend to ask to come home for a joyous week with you &amp; my sweet babes - and if all
     things are quiet<pb n="4"/>Gen. Lee will grant it to me -- <orig reg="Won't">Wont</orig> it be
     delightful to come for a whole week just to visit &amp; feel free to visit -- I will not
     dwell on it, only hope it may be so -- I do not often allude to my coming, only come whenever I
     can, so I do not raise any expectations which I cannot fulfill -- I had rather surprise you by
     coming unexpected than disappoint you by not coming when I had said I would come, so do not
     look for me my Deary, but pray that all may be favorable to my coming I was pleased to see
     Allen doing so well when I was home &amp; hope he will continue to do well &amp; I will
     reward him -- I hope to be able to soon get him a pair of shoes will as soon as I can -- I hope
     my little daughters are well -- and it comforts my long absence &amp; deprivations of their
     sweet &amp; pleasant words &amp; looks to know that they are kind &amp; gentle
     &amp; pleasant to one another and to their Mother and that they are growing up like "Olive
     plants around my table" -- that they thank God for all his mercies, that they learn the lessons
     of His Holy Book and are trying to be like the Holy Child that went about doing &amp;
     saying good --. I have no news to write, My Beloved, but I know she wants to hear from <del
      hand="h1"/> &amp; I have written as I thought -- Write soon my ever loved one &amp;
     may God bless you -- </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your <abbr expan="affectionate">aff</abbr> husband</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
     <seg type="postscript">We get corn &amp; tomates &amp; potatoes now &amp; are doing
      very well indeed -- How has Mr. Bear gotten -- I gave one large pear to Gen. Ewell &amp;
      one to his wife &amp; they enjoyed them much -- </seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
