<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A4059"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A4059">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss,
     November 11, 1863</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, november 11 1863</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Lara Diefenderfer</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A4059</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502258</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, November 11, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, november 11 1863</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>2 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1863-11-11">1863-11-11</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Women, Home Front, Slavery, African Americans, Church/Religious Activity, Military
      Authority, Military Strategy</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A4059T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss comments on news from home, and speculates about the army's future activities.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     Mrs. Sara A. Hotchkiss Churchville Augusta Co. Va.
     <name type="recipient">Sara A. Hotchkiss</name>
     <name type="place"><abbr expan="Head Quarters">Hd. Qrs.</abbr> 2<hi rend="super">nd</hi>
     Corps</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1863-11-11">Nov. 11<hi rend="underline">
        <hi rend="super">th</hi>
       </hi> 1863</date>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Dear Wife:</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I wrote you briefly the day we got here, to Morton Hall &amp; have heard form you twice
     since, so I must write a few lines again, <orig reg="though">tho'</orig> but 3 days since I
     wrote. You have heard before this that my butter came safely to hand &amp; very soon - I do
     not think it could hve stopped at Gordonsville Mr. R. must have been mistaken - we enjoy the
     butter much &amp; I hope Mr. R. will continue his good offices in our behalf &amp; get
     us some more for you to keep till this is gone, also some nice dried apples or peaches -- Up to
     the 7<hi rend="underline">
      <hi rend="super">th</hi>
     </hi> you do not speak of getting the $40. I sent you by Mrs. Wise. I am very fearful your
     exhaustive labors have been too much for you -- I was in hopes you would have had Richard to
     aid you by this time -- I did not think <orig reg="your">you</orig> company would stay so long
     -- I am glad Allie has got a good place in Staunton, but am sorry, truly sorry, her fond dream
     of happiness has been dashed to the ground -- but perhaps it is all for the best God grant it
     may be. I hope she will be benefitted by the surgeon of the Blind <abbr expan="Institution"
      >Instn.</abbr> -- She must not task her eyes to teach -- if she finds her eyes too weak she
     must not teach -- I do not wish her to --. Do not try to do so much My Dear -- I shall get you
     a woman at Christmas -- I hope Richard intends to come up - it is about the time when he would
     come up to see you. Does Mr. Walker go to the army this winter? Lt. Smith intends to become a
     chaplain next year -- he intends to leave us about the 1<hi rend="underline">
      <hi rend="super">st</hi>
     </hi> of Dec. I suppose we shall have another fight here -- Gen. Lee is full of it, to wipe out
     the advantage Meade has gained &amp; teach <pb n="2"/>him a lesson -- O that we may gain a
     substantial victory here yet this year -- I hope the forces sent may check Averill -- of course
     they will do all they can to make diversions in favor of Meade -- but I think we have force
     enough for any emergency that may occur. I thought I would have a chance before this to send
     you some more money -- &amp; I shall soon find a chance then you can pay James Henry the
     Butcher claims -- &amp;c &amp;c -- I want to pay up as many of his claims as I can --
     &amp; get square with my account. It has turned quite cold - and threatens snow -- We are
     in a house &amp; do very well, but it sets quite hard on the soldiers. I cannot spare Lt.
     Koemer any heavy paper as I want what I have -- I think - if I have any to spare when I come at
     Christmas he shall have it. Get my pants made if you can - - I shall need them when winter sets
     in. I am truly grateful to our neighbors for their kindness to you &amp; hope I may have it
     in my power to repay them -- the enemy is on one side of the Rapidan &amp; we on the other
     -- most of them are encamped near Brandy - Good night -- my love to all &amp; kisses
     &amp; may our Heavenly Father bless &amp; keep you is the prayer of </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>your devoted husband</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
