<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A4061"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A4061">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss,
     November 22, 1863</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, november 22 1863</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Lara Diefenderfer</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A4061</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502260</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, November 22, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, november 22 1863</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1863-11-22">1863-11-22</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Women, Family, Death/Casualties, National Government, Military Authority, Camp Life,
      Church/Religious Activity, Prisons/Prisoners, Arts/Leisure, Home Front</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A4061T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss relates news from camp, concerning officers, preaching, and camp life. He comments
     on family news, and on various other topics.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Sara A. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1863-11-22">Nov. 22<hi rend="underline">
        <hi rend="super">nd</hi>
      </hi> 1863</date>
      <name type="place">Hd. Qrs. 2<hi rend="super">nd</hi> Corps</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Dear Wife:</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>It has been some days since I wrote to you a letter of any length, as the letter I sent by
     Capt. Carroll enclosing $100--, had only a few lines in it as he was on the point of starting
     when I heard he was going. Nelly's letter came a few days ago also, &amp; I was very glad
     to hear from you all through her, very glad she wrote to me &amp; I will write to her
     before many days, but I was sorry you are still unwell, tired out by your many cares -- I hope
     Richard has been up to see you or will come soon &amp; look after those wearisome things
     that take away your strength and do not invigorate you. I do hope the Lord will let us end this
     war before many months, that we may return to our homes &amp; look after our households
     &amp; cheer up our wives &amp; children -- We are quietly resting here, with no signs
     of an advance, <orig reg="though">tho'</orig> the enemy may come any day, if they intend any
     movement this year. I suppose the Yankees have got the cars running to Culpeper <abbr
      expan="Court House">C.H.</abbr> as they have finished the bridge &amp;c. They are encamped
     near Culpeper <abbr expan="Court House">C. H</abbr>, &amp; from there back to Brandy -- The
     President came up yesterday &amp; is to review<pb n="2"/>our corps in a few days -- it is
     said the President is in fine health &amp; looking better than he has for a long time. Col.
     Pendleton went up to Orange <abbr expan="Court House">C.H.</abbr> to church today &amp;
     says the Pres. &amp; Gen. Lee were both there--. Gen Ewell &amp; family went to
     Charlottesville last week, as his leg is not very well -- though we hear he is better &amp;
     will be back in a few days. Gen. Early commands the Corps in his absence &amp; is here at
     our <abbr expan="Head Quarters">Hd. Qrs.</abbr> I am very glad we are so well situated, and I
     am making good use of time to get my work advanced, hoping to get off early in Dec. &amp;
     be home some 3 weeks at Christmas -- if I am not disappointed -- which I do hope may not be the
     case. I suppose Gen. Ewell will bring his family back, though all are much opposed to having
     women in camp, as officers neglect their duties to attend to their wives &amp; when any
     movement takes place instead of seeing their commands off -- Mrs. E. seemed to think all were
     glad to see her go, for she had to make that remark as she bade us good bye. Hon. Jere Morton's
     family is here in part of the house, having left their house on the bank of the river, fearing
     that if the Yankees attempt to cross, a fight may take place near the house and they do not
     wish to be in the midst of it. Mrs. Morton is one of your<pb n="3"/> trim, smart, busy bodies
     -- at the same time one of the most perfect ladies I have ever met with -- <orig reg="though"
      >tho'</orig> we see very little of her since Mr. Morton went away a few days ago &amp;
     she, good wife that she is, keeps her room, disconsolate I suppose, until her nice old man
     returns. We had a good rain all day uesterday, but it cleared off this morning &amp; we
     have had an elegant day - warm &amp; sunshiny -- I went down with Mr. Lacy to the guard
     house this morning with Mr. Lacy &amp; he preached to the prisoners, -- a very good sermon
     &amp; then I have read some &amp; talked some &amp; thus the day has passed --
     There is quite a crowd in my ranks, Smith, complaining, lying in the corner, Mr. Lacy stretched
     out on my pallet &amp; saying good things, Dr. McGuire in the corner &amp; Pendleton
     near <orig reg="by">bye</orig> -- &amp; Capt. Milbourn of the Signal Corps has just come in
     -- says there are 3 Corps of the Yankees on this side of the river, &amp; two Corps on the
     other ridge -- My Company keeps up a running fire of wit &amp; humor, so my letter has but
     little connection, <orig reg="though">tho</orig> it will be a message -- I am enjoying
     excellent health &amp; get along nicely -- my butter is lasting well and they are now
     issuing Sweet Potatoes as rations to all the army I wish you had some of them --<pb n="4"/> I
     spend my nights copying letters from Gen. Jackson's Letter Book -- collecting materials Dr.
     Dabney has also some of them copied - The life of Gen. Jackson by McCabe is a pretty good one
     -- This is the first Sunday that it has been quiet for a month -- it seems almost strange to
     have a day of rest. Last Sunday we had just finished breakfast when they opened artillery at
     Raccoon ford &amp; we thought they were coming over --- so we hurried up &amp; packed
     &amp; flew round &amp; started the wagons off, &amp; the troops went to the front
     &amp; there was a general stir - but it all amounted to nothing -- only a cavalry
     demonstration -- so we got back to our old quarters &amp; got dinner about 8 P.M. -- .
     Nelly says Allie went off in good spirits -- do you think she is reconciled to what has
     happened? &amp; how is Sterret getting on -- ? Do you want any more money just now, if so
     please let me know -- . How are you getting along my lone Dove -- I fear you have many
     troubles. Can I write to any one to do anything for you. Kiss Anne &amp; Nelly for me - -
     Pa sends them his blessings &amp; hopes they are always good &amp; kind &amp;
     trying to be good -- Do not overwork yourself my Dear, try to get along by doing as little work
     as possible &amp; I hope I may be able to fix you better at Christmas -- Write often My
     Dear -- I long to see you -- May God's blessing attend you -- </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your loving husband</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
