<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A4082"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A4082">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, June
     19, 1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, june 19 1864</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Lara Diefenderfer</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A4082</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502277</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, June 19, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, june 19 1864</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>There is a notation on the letter in another hand, stating that the date should be July,
        not June 19th.</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1864-06-19">1864-06-19</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Troop Movement, Battle Description, Military Authority, Death/Casualties</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A4082T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss writes to his wife, telling her of skirmishes with the enemy -- in particular
     attacks on some wagons. He lists some items he sent his wife in a package.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Sara A. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1864-06-19">June 19<hi rend="underline">
        <hi rend="super">th</hi>
      </hi> 1864</date>
      <name type="place"><abbr expan="Head Quarters Valley District">Hd. Qrs. V. D.</abbr> near
       Berryville Va.</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Dear Sara:</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I wrote you a few days ago from near Leesburg -- after we had crossed back to Virginia --
     Sunday we came on across the Blue Ridge -- there was not flour enough in Loudoun Co. to supply
     our wants, but Clarke &amp; Jefferson have an abundance in them -- our commissary having
     100000 bushels of wheat at his command -- The Yankee cavalry found a portion of our train
     exposed to attack as we came across the Blue Ridge &amp; they fell on it &amp; captured
     &amp; destroyed some 30 or 40 wagons -- but our infantry got up &amp; punished them,
     capturing in turn a piece of artillery from the Yankees -- the wagons captured all belonged to
     the cavalry -- <orig reg="Imboden's">Imbodens</orig> were nearly all captured -- Maj. McCue <pb
      n="2"/>lost his goods in one of Imbodens wagons -- I am sorry -- for he had a great deal of
     trouble to get them I sent my bundle up to Staunton by Maj. Braithwaite -- directed to myself
     care of Maj. Bell &amp; I will write to Maj. Bell to send it to you -- I hope to be able to
     get other things before the season is over -- a great many got nothing as the people of
     Frederick purchased immunity by paying $200000, &amp; only sold if they pleased &amp;
     they required "greenbacks" -- &amp; they were hard to get -- we were not in any other place
     where there was any thing -- I will repeat the contents of my bundle so you may know if all of
     it comes -- to hand -- I enclosed it in some linen &amp; sewed it up &amp; then put it
     in a bag -- There is an overcoat along - a very nice one - which Robinson captured at Harpers
     Ferry -- take care of it -- then 7 yds. of grey cloth, for a coat &amp; pants for myself --
     1/2 doz. <abbr expan="Handkerchiefs">Hdkfs</abbr> -- (2 kinds)<pb n="3"/>2 <abbr expan="pairs"
      >prs</abbr> shoes -- 40 yds. dark calico 20 yds <orig reg="bleached">bleched</orig> cotton --
     a piece of some 8 or 10 yds -- 6 yds. of bonnet Ribbon, 1 small cravat -- 2 undershirts, 1
      <abbr expan="pair">pr</abbr> drawers, 1 bottle of brandy -- (a present to me from Maj. Hawks,
     which I send for your use) some <unclear>gents</unclear> socks -- that is all I believe --
     sorry it is no more but will hope for another opportunity. </p>
    <p> Yesterday, after we thought we were fixed for a rest in camp the Yankees came on across the
     Mt. &amp; attempted to cross the Shenandoah River -- in fact they did cross, but Gen. Rodes
     fell on them &amp; compelled them to go back with considerable loss -- we had quite a hard
     fight &amp; lost quite a number of men -- The fight was at Rock's ford some 6 miles <abbr
      expan="North East">N. E.</abbr> of Berryville -- Today the enemy has been demonstrating
     towards Winchester<pb n="4"/>trying to induce us to go away from here -- I do not know how well
     they may succeed -- they have quite a large force -- the 19<hi rend="super">th</hi> Corps that
     has been in La. has been brought up -- the 6<hi rend="super">th</hi> Corps from Grant's Army --
     then all Hunter's &amp; Siegel's forces -- some 25000 men perhaps -- but I think if we can
     induce them to fight, by God's blessing we can whip them -- It is very dry here -- the grass
     completely <orig reg="scorched">scrorched</orig> -- I sent my watch up by Maj. McCue -- get it
     if you have a chance -- I have sent my horses home by <abbr expan="George">Geo.</abbr> Horger
     to go to Mr. Geedings -- say to him I hope he will do the best he can for them in the way of
     pastures -- I am riding over this county mapping it -- am very busy &amp; tired at night --
     so do excuse this -- Love &amp; kisses &amp; blessings for you all -- Write often -- I
     just got yours of June 12<hi rend="underline">
      <hi rend="super">th</hi>
     </hi> -- Hunter filled it up -- Good bye my sweet one </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your <abbr expan="Affectionate">Aff.</abbr> husband --</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
