<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A5039"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A5039">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Martha L. Roadcap to John B.
                    McGuffin, July 19, 1861</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county martha l roadcap to john b mcguffin, july 19 1861</title>
        <author>Roadcap, Martha L.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A5039</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502323</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Martha L. Roadcap to John B. McGuffin, July 19, 1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county martha l roadcap to john b mcguffin, july 19 1861</title>
            <author>Martha L. Roadcap</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: McGuffin Family Papers, Accession
                            #6732, Special Collections Department, University of Virginia,
                            Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-07-19">1861-07-19</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Home Front, Enlistment, Agriculture, Death/Casualties, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A5039T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Martha Roadcap's letter tells of the problems completing the harvest because all
                    men aged 18 to 45 have been drafted. She thanks her son for his prompt letter
                    because reports have become unreliable, and writes him about an accidental
                    shooting in Lexington that killed a Colonel and a 14 year old boy.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Goshen Bridge Va, July 19th, Paid 5<lb/>John Berry McGuffin, 5th Regt. Va Volun,
                    Winchester, Va.<lb/>Care of Capt. Waters, West Augusta Guards
                    <name type="recipient">John Berry McGuffin</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-07-19">Friday July 19th 1861</date>
                        <name type="place">At Home</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Son</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Your letter of the 15th <unclear>which</unclear> I <orig reg="received"
                    >recd</orig> last night and am truly thankful that you are so prompt and mindful
                    of your Mother. I was very anxious to hear from you from the fact that it was
                    reported <orig reg="here">hear</orig> that an engagement was begun on Tuesday
                    last, and that it was still going on, at Winchester which I see by your letter
                    is not the case. But it is no use believing any reports now. We are all well
                    here at home, but in great trouble. Every person between the age of 18 &amp;
                    45 have been drafted and now I am <hi rend="underline">alone</hi> with a house
                    full of children. All your friends about here will start for Staunton on
                    Saturday morning next. What their destination is when they get here, is unknown,
                    some say Strasburg and others say out West, to support our troops near Beverly -
                    the last report is that the Enemy has fallen back on Beverly. We are very near
                    the Enemy now. Joseph I. Ruff goes as captain of the Militia from here. I am
                    sorry to hear of your sickness and hope if you are not able to join your <abbr
                        expan="company">Co.</abbr> soon, that you will get a <hi rend="underline"
                        >furlough</hi> &amp; come and see me. It is impossible to tell you the
                    distress of mind I am in. It is hoped they will send the Militia back as soon as
                    the states quota is obtained. There is not much news stirring all is preparation
                    for war.</p>

                <p><pb n="2"/>Many of our people are unable to get up their grain oats &amp; hay
                    so sudden in the draft. If the powers that be had put it off in these hills for
                    2 weeks our people would have been better prepared to leave and would have left
                    in better spirits, but as it we must bear it but the Urgency of the measure
                    possibly would not admit of it. Crops are all of the very best. Corn is growing
                    finely. Let me hear from you &amp; Charles as often as you can spare the
                    time to write, tell that lady you were staying with that my prayers shall ever
                    be raised to heaven for her, in response to the care bestowed upon you. And if
                    she should ever visit this part of our state, no one would welcome her with more
                    gladness than myself. May providence shield her in these
                    <unclear>tremblous</unclear> times and from all harm. Pa and the children all
                    send their love to you, and your friends Every where. Sallie B. is still slowly
                    improving. </p>

                <p><abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> Cameron was accidently shot yesterday in
                    Lexington, he was shot dead. A passenger was getting out of the stage, with a
                    Minnie Rifle and the hammer struck upon the side of the door, and caused it to
                    explode, it struck the <abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> in the upper part of
                    the Breast where the Neck is joined to the body, passing entirely through his
                    body. It struck Dr. McClung's son <abbr expan="William">Wm.</abbr> age 14 years
                    on the side of the head penetrating the skull &amp; passing through, wounded
                    a Gentleman in the arm - this is all that I have learned of the sad Casualty,
                    the little boy died shortly after. So much for the careful use of Fire arms.</p>

                <p><pb n="3"/>Well, I have written up all my paper I will close hoping to hear from
                    you soon as it is my greatest consolation. Tell Charles to write when you see
                    him. My love to him and yourself</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>and may God protect you both in the prayers of your Affectionate Mother</salute>
                    <signed>
                        <hi rend="underline">M L Roadcap</hi>
                    </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
