<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A5065"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="A5065">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: S. E. Zimmerman to Mary C. Baylor,
                    November 18, 186x</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county s e zimmerman to mary c baylor, november 18 186x</title>
        <author>Zimmerman, S. E.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">6</num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A5065</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502349</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: S. E. Zimmerman to Mary C. Baylor, November 18, 186x</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county s e zimmerman to mary c baylor, november 18 186x</title>
            <author>S. E. Zimmerman</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>1 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: McGuffin Family Papers, Accession
                            #6732, Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library,
                            Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="-11-18">186x-11-18</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Home Front, Family, Women, Death/Casualties</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2002-11">November 2002</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A5065T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Mary Baylor's friend, S. E. Zimmerman writes about the death of her young
                    daughter Florence, and mentions the death of Emma, the young daughter of Mary's
                    brother Charles. Zimmerman also writes about her desire to return to Augusta
                    county if the war doesn't escalate.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="-11-18">Nov 18th</date>
                        <name type="place">Wytheville Va</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Mary</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I have received both of your letters and was very glad to hear from you all but
                    was very sorry they were written under such painful circumstances. when I
                    received your first letter I was in hopes that Florence would recover, but the
                    Lord seen fit to take her from this world of sorrow and trouble and therefore we
                    ought not grumble or complain she has escaped all trouble and suffering that is
                    to come on us yet if the war <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> soon end. There is no
                    sign of it ending very soon, oh that it would end before every body is ruined,
                    it is much better for little Florence to die and have her Ma and Pa than for
                    them to have to leave her, for there is no one like a Mother to her babe, no one
                    has lost a dearer babe than I it is a hard trial to know that she is gone from
                    me forever, but I can go to her and therefore I am <orig reg="reconciled"
                        >reconsiled</orig>, and know that she is better off. Mary I have no news of
                    importance to write to you to night I am looking for Sue Perkins this week give
                    my love to your Ma Pa and all the family Tell Lizzie I will write to her soon I
                    wrote to Mother <orig reg="today">to day</orig> George is not well yet but is
                    getting better every day <unclear>sis</unclear> is as fat as ever they both
                    kissed me for you before they went to bed give my love to your brothers wife and
                    tell her I sympathise with very much I was very sorry to hear of her little
                    girls death. I am so lonesome to night Will has gone to the Saltworks I would
                    like to spend another winter in old Augusta, Will talks very strong of coming
                    down in the spring to live if nothing happens, you must excuse this badly
                    written and uninteresting letter write often and with all the news.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your aff friend</salute>
                    <signed>S E Zimmerman</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
