<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A5500"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="A5500">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Nelly
                    Hotchkiss, December 17, 1862</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to nelly hotchkiss, december 17 1862</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amanda Mushal</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Amanda Mushal</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A5500</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502351</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Nelly Hotchkiss, December 17,
                            1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to nelly hotchkiss, december 17 1862</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Nelly
                            Hotchkiss, 17 December 1862, Jedediah Hotchkiss Papers, Accession Number
                            2822, Special Collections, Alderman Library, University of
                        Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-12-17">1862-12-17</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Battle Description, Family, Camp Life, Death/Casualties, Education,
                        Patriotism</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A5500T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Jedediah Hotchkiss describes for his daughter Nelly the Battle of Fredericksburg,
                    tents for soldiers, local technique of "wattle" fencemaking, and a local
                    graveyard.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-12-17">Dec. 17<hi rend="super">th</hi>, 1862</date>
                        <name type="place">Moss Neck, Caroline Co., <abbr expan="Virginia"
                            >Va.</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Little Nelly</salute>
                </opener>

                <p> I promised to write you a letter, when I was at home, so I will take a few
                    minutes this evening and <del hand="h1">comply with</del> make my promise good.
                    I left home Sunday, you know, and went to New Hope that day, the next day I went
                    across the Blue Ridge Mountain and the next day went on to Orange <orig
                        reg="Courthouse">Court House</orig> and then travelled nearly all day
                    through the woods, and where the road is sandy, and then got to where the army
                    was the next day, on the <orig reg="Mattaponi">Mattapony</orig> River. If you
                    look in the large Atlas, in Virginia, you will find four rivers, the Mat, the
                    Ta, the Po and the <orig reg="Ni">Ny</orig> and they all come together and make
                    the <orig reg="Mat-ta-po-ni">Mat-ta-po-ny</orig>
                    <orig reg="River">river</orig>, near which we had our camp, among the
                    long-leaved pine trees, the evergreen holly bushes, with prickles on the edges
                    of the leaves; and the Sweet Juni trees that look as though they were winged, or
                    rather the little limbs look so, for the bark projects on each side and
                        causes<pb n="2"/>the winged appearance I spoke of. We had a cold snow storm
                    while we were at Guinea Station near the <orig reg="Mattaponi">Mattapony</orig>
                    river, but our cloth houses were very comfortable, for we had a stove, with the
                    pipe sticking out of the door, or the slit in the side<del hand="h1">s</del> of
                    the tent, that serves for a door. Not far from our tent runs a pretty stream of
                    water, with a bottom of white sand and white and yellow quartz pebbles, that
                    look very prettily through the clear water. You never saw such fences as they
                    have here, they call them wattled fences -- they throw up a ridge of dirt,
                    leaving a ditch on one side, then they drive a row of stakes, nearly six inches
                    apart, along the top of the ridge, and then they get long, slender cedar limbs
                    and weave them in among the stakes, like the splints of a basket, and so make a
                    tight fence 3 or 4 feet high. Nearly all the fences here are wattled ones -- and
                    then they have cedar trees growing up by the sides of the fences, and we
                    sometimes go a long ways through two rows of pretty <hi rend="underline"
                    >ever</hi>-green trees. The country here is very flat with a good many swamps,
                    but no very high hills, and a great many pine forests -- where the trees are all
                    pines, and very thick. I saw a very pretty <orig reg="graveyard">grave
                    yard</orig> the other day, made by planting<pb n="3"/>cedar trees in a ring and
                    they had grown up thick &amp; had come together at the top and the limbs had
                    been kept cut off on the inside, and there was a place where you could go in,
                    and when in it was like a green house, shaped like half an egg, and the ground
                    on the inside was thickly covered with myrtle, and there were several graves
                    with nice marble slabs -- on the outside it looked like one big tree. I must now
                    tell you about a battle we had last Saturday, the 13<hi rend="super">th</hi> of
                        <abbr expan="December">Dec.</abbr>, and I will make a little map for you to
                    look at and see how the armies were located when they fought. Look at the map I
                    have made for you. The roads are put down in red lines, our troops in black
                    lines and the Yankees in blue ones.</p>
                <p>[Jedediah Hotchkiss sketched a somewhat detailed map]</p>
                <pb n="4"/>
                <p>Our army was on the hills in front of the Mine and Telegraph Roads, mostly in the
                    woods, and we had cannons where you see a black line with a dot on each side.
                    The enemy came across the river on pontoon, or boat bridges, made so -- [drawing
                    of a pontoon bridge] of boats fastened in the stream<del hand="h1">s</del> with
                    planks laid across them, at Fredericksburg and at the mouth of Deep Run, and
                    they came up into the flat where the short blue lines are &amp; they had
                    cannons where I have made short blue lines with dots beside them -- when they
                    came up towards the woods where our men were we fired a great many thousand guns
                    at them and they fired at us, and so we did for a long time, and we at last
                    drove them back, having killed a large number of them and wounded many more --
                    We had a good many killed and wounded too, but not as many as they did, for we
                    were protected by the woods -- Now they have gone away across the river, and we
                    must thank the good Lord that he enabled us to whip them and drive them away,
                    for they would come and destroy us and our country if they could.</p>

                <p>We are now on a neck of land in a big bend of the river, called Moss Neck --
                    there is a great deal of pretty moss growing here. </p>

                <p>I am glad you say so many good lessons, as your Ma tells me -- be a good girl and
                    learn all you can -- help your Ma and be kind to <orig reg="everybody">every
                        body</orig> and always good-natured and be sure to love God and do right.
                    Kiss your sister Anna for Pa--</p>

                <p>So good night, my daughter--</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>From Your Pa--</salute>
                    <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
