<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6003"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A6003">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Henry H. Dedrick to Mary E. A. Dedrick, November
     23, 1861</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county henry h dedrick to mary e a dedrick, november 23 1861</title>
        <author>Dedrick, Henry H.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Diane B. Jacob, Virginia Military Institute</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Alice McShane </name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6003</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502366</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Henry H. Dedrick to Mary E. A. Dedrick, November 23, 1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county henry h dedrick to mary e a dedrick, november 23 1861</title>
            <author>Henry H. Dedrick</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>1 page</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Henry H. Dedrick Papers, Manuscript #0332, Virginia
       Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1861-11-23">1861-11-23</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Camp Life, Family, Home Front, Women</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2001-07">July 2001</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Amy Murrell</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Tagging checked; final corrections made.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6003T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Dedrick writes about cold weather, winter quarters, and the fact that he is sending money.
     The reverse of the letter is one from his wife about the food she tried to send.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Mary E.A. Dedrick</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1861-11-23">November the 23 1861</date>
      <name type="place">Pocahontas County VA</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Wife</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I have an opportunity this morning to send you a few lines by Walter Lewis to let you know
     that I am well at this time and I hope when these few lines comes to hand they may find you all
     are well and doing well. Bill O. is well he is agetting breakfast. The rest of the creek boys
     is all well with the exception of Rice and <unclear>Bridge</unclear>. They aint very well at
     this time. We have had some hard times here. We have had some snow here, it is a snowing here
     now. We have rain or snow every two or three days and it is most impossible to get provisions
     here for all the soldiers.</p>
    <p>We have moved in our cabin and we have very good times now. We can do almost as well here as
     we can at home. All of the soldiers have left Greenbrier River. They come up here yesterday.
     Some of them will stay here with us and some of them will go to Staunton. I am on guard. I have
     stood one tour and I tell you it is cold. </p>
    <p>I wrote this above before daylight this morning. I heard while I was on my post that our
     regiment and four other regiments was to stay on Alleghany this winter. I saw Jeremy Falls last
     night. He was well. Give my love to all my friends. Lissa we drawed our money yesterday and I
     will send you fifteen dollars in this letter. I will send you five more in this which will make
     twenty dollars in this letter and I will send you seven dollars by Lewis, that will make twenty
     seven dollars. I want you to take care of it for me. If you need any you must take as much of
     it as you want. I drawed $63.85. I paid $6.50 for my coat and $6.00 for a pair of boots that I
     got from Smith, and I paid Lewis $20.00 and <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> 35 cents. I wrote you a letter
     some time ago and I have not got any answer from it yet. I want you to write soon and let me
     know how you are agetting along. If you have anything to send me if you have a chance you may
     send it and if you don't have any chance it don't make any difference. I have more to write but
     I have not got time to write. Write soon. So nothing more but remain your affectionate husband
     until death. So fare you well my Dear. H. H. Dedrick to his Dear wife. Lissa, I don't want you
     to lend out one cent of it to nobody on occasion at all.</p>
    <p>Mary E. A. Dedrick to Henry</p>
    <p>Nov. [?] 1861</p>
    <p>Dear Henry- I packed up a good many things, preserves and one thing and another and took them
     over to Grasses and he told me he would take them and I went over there the next day after he
     started and he hadn't took them, and this letter was in the satchel, the reason you didn't get
     it sooner. We are well. It is agetting late and I must go to the office yet. May my kind
     saviour protect you. Yours truly, M.E.A.D.</p>

    <closer>
     <salute/>
     <signed/>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
