<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6009"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A6009">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Henry H. Dedrick to Mary E. A. Dedrick, April 7,
     1862</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county henry h dedrick to mary e a dedrick, april 7 1862</title>
        <author>Dedrick, Henry H.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Diane B. Jacob, Virginia Military Institute</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Alice McShane</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6009</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502372</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Henry H. Dedrick to Mary E. A. Dedrick, April 7, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county henry h dedrick to mary e a dedrick, april 7 1862</title>
            <author>Henry H. Dedrick</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>1 page</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Henry H. Dedrick Papers, Manuscript #0332, Virginia
       Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-04-07">1862-04-07</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Camp Life, Death/Casualties, Family, Home Front, Troop Movement, Women</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2001-07">July 2001</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Amy Murrell</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Tagging checked; final corrections made.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6009T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Dedrick writes about his regiment's movement toward Staunton. He also complains about the
     cold and snow.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Mary E.A. Dedrick</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-04-07">April the 7 1862 </date>
      <name type="place">Camp Shenandoah, Augusta Co., Virginia</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Dear Wife-</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I received your kind letter yesterday. I was glad to hear from you and I was sorry to hear
     that you had the mumps, but if you take good care of your self you will soon get well. I was
     glad to hear that Willie was so <unclear>pert</unclear> and so lively. I am well at present and
     I do hope when these lines comes to hand they may find you all well.</p>
    <p>Uncle Will is not very well. He has been very sick. We have left Alleghany. We left last
     Wednesday and come to Monterey and the next day we come to McDowell and then we stayed there
     one day, and on Saturday we marched within a half of a mile of Rodgerses, which is on
     Shenandoah Mountain. We are now within 24 1/2 miles of Staunton and 14/12 miles from Buffalo
     Gap, but I can't tell you how long we will stay here, but if we stay here long I would like
     your pap to come out here to see me.</p>
    <p>I would like to see you all very much, but if I can't get to see you before my time is out I
     think I can stay three months and a half yet if I have my health. All of the creek boys is
     well. William Diddle is sitting in his tent blowing his fife.</p>
    <p>Dear Lissa I was up on the top of a ridge yesterday and I could see the Blue Ridge. I could
     see the laurel and Spring Hollow and I said to my self now if I was up in that hollow how soon
     I could get home. Well Dear Lissa I will now finish my letter. It is now 3 o'clock and it is
     very cold and snowy. We all just have to do the best we can. We are nearly froze. All the
     balance of my mess is lying down in the tent wrapped up in there blankets. I wish you could see
     us, then you would say that we had hard times out here.</p>
    <p>Lissa you wanted to know how much I had to pay a year on that lot and how much I had to pay
     in all. I have to pay $38.75cts a year and there is four payments back yet that will make $155.
     Yet if you do pay any on it you must take in my note.</p>
    <p>Uncle Will, Will Diddle, and Hiram Coyner and James Padgett and Ephriam Sillings all sends
     their best regards to you and Amanda and Aunt Rebecca and your mother and your Pap, and you
     will please give my love to all inquiring friends if there be any, and you must accept a great
     portion for your self. You said in your letter that I had better kept one of them ladies that I
     sent you. I had no use for them as they could not cook nor wash nor do anthing else. I would
     rather have you here by a long ways before I would have them. I must close as I am so cold I
     can't write. I was glad to get some of your hair. It is very pretty. May god bless you all.
     Nothing more but remain your affectionate husband until death.</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>H.H. Dedrick to his dear wife.</salute>
     <signed/>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
