<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6012"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A6012">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Henry H. Dedrick to Mary E. A. Dedrick, May 10,
     1863</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county henry h dedrick to mary e a dedrick, may 10 1863</title>
        <author>Dedrick, Henry H.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Diane B. Jacob, Virginia Military Institute</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Alice McShane</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6012</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502375</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Henry H. Dedrick to Mary E. A. Dedrick, May 10, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county henry h dedrick to mary e a dedrick, may 10 1863</title>
            <author>Henry H. Dedrick</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>1 page</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Henry H. Dedrick Papers, Manusript #0332, Virginia
       Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1863-05-10">1863-05-10</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Battle Description, Camp Life, Death/Casualties, Desertion/Leave, Home Front, Family,
      Military Authority</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2001-07">July 2001</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Amy Murrell</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Tagging checked; final corrections made.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6012T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Dedrick describes the battle of Chancellorsville, the wounding and death of General Jackson,
     and the shortages plaguing his regiment, i.e. food and paper.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Mary E.A. Dedrick</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1863-05-10">May 10th 1863</date>
      <name type="place">Spotsylvania Co. Virginia. Camp near Hamilton's Crossing</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Father-</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I take this opportunity to drop you a few to answer your few lines that I received from you
     this evening. I was glad to hear from you all and to hear that youw as well. I am well at
     present and hope when these few lines comes to hand they may find you all enjoying the same
     blessing of god a resting upon you.</p>
    <p>You said that you heard that Gen. Jackson had a fight. It was not only him it was all of the
     troops. We had one of the hardest fights that we ever had since the war begun. General Jackson
     has lost one of his arms and <unclear>has</unclear> now got the pneumonia. He is not expected
     to live. He was shot by our own pickets. He got out side of our pickets after night and he come
     up in a gallop and they fired on him and wounded him and all of his guard but one. Our loss is
     said to be twenty thousand killed wounded and missing. I don't know what the
     <unclear>loss,</unclear> of the enemy was but it must be terrible. I have just heard that
     General Jackson was dead. If he is it is a great loss to the Southern confederacy.</p>
    <p>You said that there was a petition wrote and sent to me or my officers. I have not heard
      <orig reg="nothing">nothinig</orig> from it. I don't think I will need but you can get it and
     send it to me, for if the officers gets it it won't do me any good. William Offlighter and
     Hiram Coyner is in Richmond from what I can find out. They left the last day of April and I
     have not heard from them since.</p>
    <p>If we stay here I wish you would come down and bring me something to eat for we don't get
     half enough and I can't stand it. If you do come you can bring something along and make more
     off of it <unclear>than</unclear> you can make any other way. You can get from 50 to 75 cents
     for a pie, and tobacco is very high. You can sell most anything at all, potatoes 50 cents per
     quart. Thread is very high and I have two overcoats and a good blanket I would like to send
     home. If I had them at home I wouldn't take less than 60 dollars for them. If you come and if
     we are at the <orig reg="same">ame</orig> place you can come to Hamilton's Crossing, that is in
     two miles of our camp.</p>
    <p>Joshua <unclear>Robison</unclear> and Adam Pannell sends their best respects to you all. I
     must close for this time. You will please excuse me for this. May god bless you all. Write
     soon.</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Henry H. Dedrick to Elijah Balsley</salute>
     <signed/>
     <seg type="postscript">May 11th 1863<lb/><lb/> Dear Wife-<lb/> I take this <orig
       reg="privilege">priviledge</orig> this morning to drop you a few more lines. I received your
      kind letter yesterday after I had written home one to you. It found me well except the
      toothache it all but set me crazy. I commenced while I was writing to you and I had to quit
      writing for awhile but it has quit aching now. Give father and mother and Betty my love and
      tell him I would have written him a letter but I have not got the paper. Tell him to write to
      me. I must close. May god be with you all. I remain your affectionate husband until death
      separates us</seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
