<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6028"?>
<?dlps page-images="color" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;

<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">

  
 <!ENTITY Smiley1 SYSTEM "uva-lib:503075" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 <!ENTITY Smiley1b SYSTEM "uva-lib:503076" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 <!ENTITY Smiley1c SYSTEM "uva-lib:503077" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 <!ENTITY Smiley1d SYSTEM "uva-lib:503078" NDATA uvaHighRes> 

 ]>  
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A6028">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Thomas M. Smiley to His Sister, January 10, 1862</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county thomas m smiley to his sister, january 10 1862</title>
        <author>Smiley, Thomas M.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Alice McShane</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6028</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:503074</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Thomas M. Smiley to His Sister, January 10, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county thomas m smiley to his sister, january 10 1862</title>
            <author>Thomas M. Smiley</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>1 page</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Smiley Family Papers Accession #1807 Special
       Collections Department, University of Virginia Library, Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>An archivist or family member noted "Crossroads-Jan 10" in the margin of the letter.</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-01-10">1862-01-10</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Camp Life, Death/Casualties, Enlistment, Military Authority, National Government, Troop
      Movement</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2001">Summer 2001</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6028T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Thomas M. Smiley describes troop movements in the mountains of Morgan County during bad
     weather and a brief confrontation with Yankees at the county seat, Bath. They are moving
     towards winter quarters.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">sister</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
    
     <pb n="1" entity="Smiley1" pid="uva-lib:503075"/>
   
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-01-10">[1862 Jan 10] Jany 10<hi rend="super">th</hi></date>
      <name type="place">Camp near crossroads Morgan Co</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Sister</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>As it has been almost three weeks since I wrote to you I will try and write a few lines to
     you this <unclear>morning</unclear> to let you know that I am well and getting along pretty
     well considering the hardships we have had to go through with since the commencement of the
     present year We left camp Stephenson on New year's day and since that we have been almost
     constantly on the march and when night came we had to lay down without our tents in the snow
     and rain We marched to Bath the County seat of morgan and was five days in getting there. The
     first snow we have seen this winter fell on us the third night while we were laying on the side
     of one of Morgans Numerous mountains<pb n="2" entity="Smiley1b" pid="uva-lib:503076"/>
    And after that we marched on a solid sheet of ice the wagons <orig
      reg="running"> runing</orig> on <orig reg="the road">theroad</orig> packed down the snow and
     it got so icy a person could hardly stand on his feet the horses falling down wagons sliding
     off the road and breaking to pieces there was several men slipped down and broke their legs and
     arms there was a great many horses killed and crippled not so many in our brigade but in those
     that came from Western Virginia they are weak and poor and can not stand much hardship we drove
     the enemy out of Bath took 24 prisoners killed and wounded 8 or ten took their <orig
      reg="commissary">comissary</orig> stores &amp;c we got about 6-or 8000 dollars worth of
     property our success would have been much greater had it not<pb n="3" entity="Smiley1c" pid="uva-lib:503077"/>
     been for some militia we had along with us 2 regiments of them run
     from some 25 Yankees and their general in the first place disobeyed orders throwing the whole
     plan wrong he has <del hand="h1">been</del> been placed under arrest by Gen Jackson. If the
     Militia had done right we would have captured the whole <del hand="h1">plac</del> force baggage
     and every thing they had and made a complete disaster to the enemy We are camped at the cross
     roads where we can go to four different places we do not know where we are going to some thinks
     we are going to romney and some to Martinsburg-while others suppose we are going to Winchester
     we will probably take winter quarters when we get back if the weather is very rough<pb n="4" entity="Smiley1d" pid="uva-lib:503078"/>
     you say to let you know whether I want a pair of over socks I do
     not know that I want them as I have not wore the other ones any yet my boots are most too tight
     with them on Tell pa that he need not be uneasy about my enlisting for the war as I have not
     had any idea of it yet there is a bill up in Congress now for the purpose of keeping the twelve
     month volunteers in service during the whole war but I do not know whether it has passed or not
     our regiment are all wanting to go home when their term expires as they do not like their
     officers but I must close as my paper is out Write soon</p>


    <closer>
     <salute>nothing more at present but remain your brother</salute>
     <signed>T M Smily</signed>
     <seg type="postscript">Crossroads Jan 10th</seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
