<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6045"?>
<?dlps page-images="color" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;

<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">

 
 <!ENTITY Smiley17 SYSTEM "uva-lib:503132" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 <!ENTITY Smiley17b SYSTEM "uva-lib:503133" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 <!ENTITY Smiley17c SYSTEM "uva-lib:503134" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 <!ENTITY Smiley17d SYSTEM "uva-lib:503135" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
  
 ]>  
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A6045">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Hannah M. Berry to Thomas M. Smiley, [1861]</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county hannah m berry to thomas m smiley, 1861</title>
        <author>Berry, Hannah M.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Alice McShane</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Alice McShane</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6045</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:503131</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Hannah M. Berry to Thomas M. Smiley, [1861]</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county hannah m berry to thomas m smiley, 1861</title>
            <author>Hannah M. Berry</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>1 page</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Smiley Family Papers Accession 1807 Special
       Collections Department, University of Virginia Library, Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>Letter undated. The year 1861 added later by a family member or archivist</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1861">1861</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Desertion/Leave, Home Front, Patriotism, Troop Movement, Women</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2001">Summer 2001</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6045T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Discusses news from the home front including attending a partriotic rally and sewing
     secession flags. She also comments on unionists in the area.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Thomas M. Smiley</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     
      <pb n="1" entity="Smiley17" pid="uva-lib:503132"/>
     
     <dateline>
      <date value="1861">Wednesday Eve</date>
      <name type="place">Moffetts Creek</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>
      <hi rend="underline">Dear Cousin Thomas</hi>
     </salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I suppose you will be much surprised to <orig reg="receive">recieve</orig> a letter from me,
     but I have waited so long to hear from you &amp; have as yet waited in vain <del hand="h1"
      >and</del> I concluded I would write first I intended writing to you last week but it was
     reported here that the Southern Guards had left the Ferry so I concluded to wait awhile yet.
     Charlie &amp; Annie <orig reg="received">recieved</orig> letters from Harpers Ferry by Mr
      <unclear>Ceaig</unclear> but I did not. it was a sad disappointment to me. <hi
      rend="underline">but the renewal of Hope gave me Consolation</hi> We are all very well also
     the neighbors are well I saw your people all at church Sunday they were all well. Your Aunts
     &amp; Uncle are all well<pb n="2" entity="Smiley17b" pid="uva-lib:503133"/>
      your Uncle has not been at church this spring yet but he was so
     well last Sunday that Cousins Annie &amp; Ellen were both at church</p>
    <p>There seems to be nothing new or uncommon occurring in the neighborhood &amp; <orig
      reg="don't">dont</orig> have much excitement about war now we have not become <unclear/> to so
     many of our men leaving &amp; <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> think we can as our loss has
     been great in comparison with the losses other neighborhoods have met with. Cousin Tom I must
     tell you of the Secession Flag that was hoisted in the important place of New Port. We had a
     delightful time had a nice crowd of <unclear>geats</unclear> all the way to two or three
     Lincolnites (as we call the Union men) but the Speeches delivered were by far more entertaining
     than <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig> else. When I tell you the Speaker or speakers you
     certainly will laugh. Mr Echard the self important man was the first had his written down
     &amp; read it <orig reg="off">of</orig>. I could not help laughing. Mr Jim Callison made a
     short speech it was<pb n="3" entity="Smiley17c" pid="uva-lib:503134"/>
     very good and a very appropriate one</p>
    <p>Mr Echard is not married yet but is still flying around with the ladies but goes to other
     parts when he wishes to wait on them. I believe he is afraid of the girls around here. I
     suppose you have heard that Bill Anderson started away with the troop and went as far as
     Staunton and was taken sick. I expect he wanted some excuse to get back home <orig reg="anyhow"
      >any how</orig>. I tell you I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> believe in cowardice. (in time of
     war no way.) and we have <orig reg="too">to</orig> much of that great evil about here. If I
     were a man I would have gone long before this and would now be serving my country. I would like
     to visit you all &amp; see how you are getting along I suppose you have a nice time when
     cooking time comes. If you all ever return I have no doubt but you will be considered great
     &amp; learned men I guess every girl would fight for a Soldier &amp; me with the rest
     as I think they would be useful at all times</p>
    <p>I heard the other day that John Beard was<pb n="4"  entity="Smiley17d" pid="uva-lib:503135"/>
      walking along and saw a pretty girl &amp; made a misstep and
     rolled down on the bank of the River thats a fine <orig reg="fate">late</orig> but I am glad
     you all have some pretty girls to look at. Where do you all stay now in a house or where I hope
     you will have your Tents in a few days more. We all sewed in New Port last weeks for several
     days in order to get them done we made four there and five or six in Middlebrook but they
      <unclear>had</unclear> sewing <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> and we <orig reg="didn't">didnt</orig> there is
     a great quantity of sewing in them your female friends would do <orig reg="everything">every
      thing</orig> in the world for you could it afford you the least pleasure or comfort in the
     world. I suppose you all <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> care about coming home on furlow. We
     would all be very glad to see any of you. &amp; nothing gives me more pleasure than to
      <orig reg="receive">recieve</orig> a letter from any of you Soldiers. Ma &amp; Pa came
     home from NewPort a few moments ago &amp; told us Mr Grove &amp; <abbr expan="Captain"
      >Capt</abbr> Hite were going to start with your Tents tomorrow &amp; we concluded to write
     and send our letters with him &amp; you would be sure to <orig reg="receive">recieve</orig>
     them. I asked John M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Kerry to speak to you &amp; some more of my
     acquaintances to have their Likenesses taken together with their uniforms for me. If you have
     them taken I will be under many obligations to you. Did you <orig reg="receive">recieve</orig>
     the Secession Badge I sent you if I could have had time I would have made more but <abbr
      expan="Lieutenant">Lieut</abbr> M<hi rend="super">c</hi> did not say anything about it until a
     day or so before he left &amp; we had to go to church that day Has <abbr expan="Lieutenant"
      >Lieut</abbr> M<hi rend="super">c</hi> been in any better spirits since he went back. I
     thought he looked badly and<pb n="1" entity="Smiley17" pid="uva-lib:503132"/>
      looked very badly but I did not wonder at it when he seen his Men
     looking so badly &amp; so much distressed about them his situation is certainly a
     deplorable one Cousin Tom we have some great times here with the Union Men. we were raising
     money for our flag &amp; asked Mr Billie Beard but he would not give us one cent you I
     suppose are aware of the fact that he is a strong <hi rend="underline">Unionist</hi>. I must
     stop writing as it is late. Give my best love to all my acquaintances Ma Annie &amp; all
     the rest of the family send much love to you. Please excuse bad writing <orig reg="etc."
      >&amp;c</orig>
     <orig reg="etc.">&amp;c</orig> as I have been in a hurry. </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Please write soon &amp; believe me as ever your true cousin</salute>
     <signed>Hannah M Berry</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
