<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6042"?>
<?dlps page-images="color" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;

<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">

 
 <!ENTITY Smiley14 SYSTEM "uva-lib:503123" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 <!ENTITY Smiley14b SYSTEM "uva-lib:503124" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 <!ENTITY Smiley14c SYSTEM "uva-lib:503125" NDATA uvaHighRes> 

 ]>  
  
  
 <TEI.2 id="A6042">  
 <teiHeader type="migrated">  
  
    <fileDesc>  
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Thomas M. Smiley to His Aunt, November 12, 1862</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county thomas m smiley to his aunt, november 12 1862</title>
        <author>Smiley, Thomas M.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>  
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>  
          <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>  
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>  
          <name>Alice McShane</name>  
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>  
  
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">6</num>kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>  
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>  
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>  
  
        <idno type="VCDH">A6042</idno>  
  
        <!--
 <availability>  
 <p>Publicly accessible </p>  
 <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>  
 <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the 
 University of Virginia</p>  
 </availability>
-->  
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>  
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:503122</idno>
      </publicationStmt>  
      <seriesStmt> 
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American 
 Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>  
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>  
  
      <sourceDesc>  
        <biblFull>  
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Thomas M. Smiley to His Aunt, November 12, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county thomas m smiley to his aunt, november 12 1862</title>
            <author>Thomas M. Smiley</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>  
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>  
          <extent>1 page</extent>  
          <publicationStmt>  
            <publisher/>  
            <pubPlace/>  
            <date value=""/> 
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Smiley Family Papers Special 
 Collections Department, University of Virginia Library, Charlottesville, 
 Virginia</idno> 
          </publicationStmt>  
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>  
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>  
        </biblFull>  
      </sourceDesc>  
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>  
  
    <profileDesc>  
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-11-12">1862-11-12</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>  
      <textClass>  
        <keywords>  
          <term>Battle Description, Camp Life, Death/Casualties, Home Front, 
 Military Authority, Prisons/Prisoners, Troop Movement </term>  
          <term>American Civil War</term> 
        </keywords>  
      </textClass>  
    </profileDesc>  
  
    <revisionDesc>  
      <change>  
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>  
        <item/>  
      </change>  
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>  
 </teiHeader>  
  
 <text id="A6042T"> 
 <front id="d2"> 
 <div1 type="summary" id="d3"> 
 <p>Thomas M. Smiley winter camp on Valley Turnpike near Winchester.  It is snowing and they are waiting for their tents.  He asks about a rumored wedding back home.</p>  
 </div1>  
 </front>  
  
 <body id="d4"> 
 <div1 type="letter" id="d5"> 
 <head> 
 <name type="recipient">aunt</name>  
 </head> 
  
 <opener> 
 <pb n="1" entity="Smiley14" pid="uva-lib:503123"/>
 <dateline> 
 <date value="1862-11-12">Nov 12<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1862</date>
  <name type="place">Camp Stephenson </name>  
 </dateline>  
 <salute>Dear Aunt</salute>  
 </opener>  
  
 <p>I will endeavor this morning to write you a few lines to let you know 
 that I am well &amp; hope these few lines may find you enjoying the same 
 blessing.  We are now camped at the same place we were at this time last 
 year four miles below Winchester on the Valley turnpike We came here on 
 Monday.  We received orders to move above Winchester on sunday but on 
 Monday morning we got orders to go below Winchester four miles and take up 
  Winter quarters so we are now in our quarters for the winter<pb n="2" entity="Smiley14b" pid="uva-lib:503124"/> 
 
 unless the enemy chase us away.  We have no tents although we expect them 
 shortly I do not know how we would get along without tents as winter has 
 already set in with us there was a considerable Snow here last friday and 
 it is now cloudy and looks as if it would snow <orig reg="tonight">to 
 night</orig>.  There has been considerable fighting along the mountain 
 lately.  D H Hill had a skirmish with the enemy last week at Castlemans 
 Ferry in which the enemys loss was forty killed, and one hundred wounded; 
 and not a single man on our side injured.  We also took several hundred 
 prisoners, at Harpers Ferry lately, they are now in Winchester under a 
 strong guard.  It has been reported here that One division of the enemy; 
 numbering ten, or fifteen, thousand men threw down their arms and refused 
  to come on confederate soil to fight; but said that if we<pb n="3" entity="Smiley14c" pid="uva-lib:503125"/>  
 
 would go to invade them they would do their best fighting.  I would not 
 care much if they were all like this division refuse to invade us.  I 
 heard a few days ago that there has been a wedding close to you, John 
 M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Kenny, &amp; Hannah Berry  Lieutenant 
 Carson got a letter last week in which it was that they were married and 
 on a bridal trip to Giles County.  Tell Mary that I think it is pretty 
 near time she was writing as I have not got any word from home since I 
 started away three weeks ago.  I must now draw my note to a close by 
 asking you to excuse all mistakes bad writing <orig 
 reg="etc.">&amp;c</orig></p> 
  
 <closer> 
 <salute>Give my love to Aunt Ann, Uncles Jamess family and all other 
 enquiring friends also receive a due share yourself from your affectionate 
 nephew</salute>  
 <signed>Thomas. M. Smiley</signed>   
 </closer>  
 </div1>  
 </body>  
 </text>  
 </TEI.2> 