<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6044"?>
<?dlps page-images="color" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;

<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">

 
 <!ENTITY Smiley16 SYSTEM "uva-lib:503127" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 <!ENTITY Smiley16b SYSTEM "uva-lib:503128" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 <!ENTITY Smiley16c SYSTEM "uva-lib:503129" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 <!ENTITY Smiley16d SYSTEM "uva-lib:503130" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
  
 ]>  
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A6044">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Hannah M. Berry to Thomas M. Smiley, [1861]</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county hannah m berry to thomas m smiley, 1861</title>
        <author>Berry, Hannah M.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Alice McShane</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Alice McShane</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6044</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:503126</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Hannah M. Berry to Thomas M. Smiley, [1861]</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county hannah m berry to thomas m smiley, 1861</title>
            <author>Hannah M. Berry</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>1 page</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Smiley Family Papers Accession #1807 Special
       Collections Department, University of Virginia Library, Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>Letter was undated, the year 1861 was added later by family member or archivist</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1861">1861</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Camp Life, Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties, Desertion/Leave, Patriotism </term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2001">Summer 2001</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6044T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Discusses home front news including church news and individuals home on leave.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Thomas M. Smiley </name>
    </head>

    <opener>
    
      <pb n="1" entity="Smiley16" pid="uva-lib:503127"/>

     <dateline>
      <date value="1861">Saturday</date>
      <name type="place">Moffets Creek</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Cousin</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I will make one more attempt to answer the welcome epistle I <orig reg="received"
     >recieved</orig> from you several months ago I am ashamed that it has been so long neglected
     but as this is my third attempt I hope you will forgive me this time and <orig reg="I'll"
     >Ill</orig> endeavor to be more punctual <orig reg="hereafter">here after</orig>. How have you
     been standing Camp Life since your visit at home wish you could have stayed longer we all feel
     so lonesome since so many of you have been at home and gone we have <abbr expan="Captain"
     >Capt</abbr> M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Kerry to visit now. Annie and I spent the evening with him
     Thursday<pb n="2" entity="Smiley16b" pid="uva-lib:503128"/>
      did not find him in very good spirits looks badly was not
     suffering much from his wound but he certainly has suffered from the appearance of his wound
     now it looks very badly indeed he says he never has felt weak until after he was moved home but
     stood the trip home very well I think if Annie Buck would come down it would raise his spirits
     very much <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> think he will be able to go up soon for he has only
     set-up a few minute since he came home has no use of his leg at all think he is <orig
      reg="discouraged">discourag</orig> about that <orig reg="which">whisch</orig> is the source of
     his being so low spirited</p>
    <p>I have not spoken to Billie Fulton since he came home got sight of him at church last Sunday
     but that was all I was surprised to know that he would come<pb n="3" entity="Smiley16c" pid="uva-lib:503129"/>
     home under such circumstances I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know
     whether the <orig reg="wealthy">woathy</orig> Mr Echard is at home now or not he never calls
     here. &amp; I know very little about him I understood you all elected a <abbr
      expan="Lieutenant">Lieut</abbr> but did not hold his office long suppose he felt a little
     cheap when he had to give his office up but I imagine he would have had you all under arrest
     before this time from what I have heard if he had <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> been your <abbr
      expan="Lieutenant">Lieut</abbr> yet. How is Cousin Jimmie M<hi rend="super">c</hi> getting
     along heard from <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> some of your <abbr expan="Company">Co</abbr> this week that
     he had been writing letters for six days and as I have <orig reg="received">recieved</orig>
     none from him I imagine he intends slighting me as usual. I have heard from several of the boys
     this week all speak of having a Chaplain and preaching<pb n="4" entity="Smiley16d" pid="uva-lib:503130"/>
      or prayer meeting every night <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> think
      <orig reg="worthwhile">worth while</orig> to tell his name where he is from what denomination
     he is of or anything about him these questions have been asked me by several persons but have
     so far been unable to answer any of them how has Mr John Beard been getting along <orig
      reg="since">sinc</orig> he returned to camp suppose he has written to his <hi rend="underline"
      >Dear</hi>
     <unclear>
      <hi rend="underline">Denizen</hi>
     </unclear> several times since he left guess he must have taken it very hard as I know he had
     been crying all the way from there down here but <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> blame him. You
     must all come home to Presbytery the 4th of <abbr expan="September">Sept</abbr> and bring
     Cousin Lane <unclear>Caerose</unclear> with you think he might afford to come home to see his
     old man(as he calls <abbr expan="Captain">Capt</abbr> M<hi rend="super">c</hi>) then if not
     before that time Mr Junkin preaches in Newport tomorrow week hope Mr Harris will not be there
     as I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> want to hear him preach <orig reg="anymore">any more</orig>
     for I know he is a real Yankee</p>
    <pb n="1" entity="Smiley16" pid="uva-lib:503127"/>
    <p> We have no Bible Class tomorrow as Mr Junkin expects to be absent
     and I am glad for we have an unmerciful hard and long lesson think we ought to have two weeks
     at it I must bring this epistle to a close as it is <orig reg="out">hout</orig> of news my best
     love to Cousins Jimmie Buck Samuel Carson and all any other <orig reg="acquaintances"
      >acquantances</orig> receiving a large share for yourself I bid you <orig reg="adieu"
     >adeiu</orig> hoping you will write Soon &amp; I will follow your <orig reg="example"
     >examp</orig></p>

    <closer>
     <salute>I remain as ever your true friend and <orig reg="Cousin">Cous</orig></salute>
     <signed>Hannah<pb n="4" entity="Smiley16d" pid="uva-lib:503130"/></signed>
     <seg type="postscript">Please excuse mistakes bad writing
      &amp;c all send much love to you all</seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
