<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6144"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
 <TEI.2 id="A6144">  
 <teiHeader type="migrated">  
  
    <fileDesc>  
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jesse Rolston, Jr., to Mary Rolston, March 11, 1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jesse rolston, jr to mary rolston march 11 1864</title>
        <author>Rolston, Jr., Jesse</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>  
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>  
          <name>Julie Beagle</name>  
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>  
          <name>Julie Beagle</name>  
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>  
  
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>  
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>  
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>  
  
        <idno type="VCDH">A6144</idno>  
  
        <!--
 <availability>  
 <p>Publicly accessible </p>  
 <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>  
 <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the 
 University of Virginia</p>  
 </availability>
-->  
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>  
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502414</idno>
      </publicationStmt>  
      <seriesStmt> 
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American 
 Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>  
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>  
  
      <sourceDesc>  
        <biblFull>  
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jesse Rolston, Jr., to Mary Rolston, March 11, 
 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jesse rolston, jr to mary rolston march 11 1864</title>
            <author/>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>  
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>  
          <extent/>  
          <publicationStmt>  
            <publisher/>  
            <pubPlace/>  
            <date value=""/> 
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Joyce DeBolt Miller, ed., 
 "Until Seperated by Death": Lives and Civil War Letters of Jesse Rolston, 
 Jr., and Mary Catharine Cromer (Bridgewater, Va.: Good Printers, Inc., 
 1994), pp. 67-68.</idno> 
          </publicationStmt>  
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>  
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>We would like to thank Joyce DeBolt Miller for giving us 
 permission to print these letters and Barbara Rolston for bringing this 
 collection to our attention.</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>  
        </biblFull>  
      </sourceDesc>  
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Published Source</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>  
  
    <profileDesc>  
      <creation>
        <date value="1864-03-11">1864-03-11</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>  
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>  
        <keywords>  
          <term>Enlistment, Agriculture, Family</term>  
          <term>American Civil War</term> 
        </keywords>  
      </textClass>  
    </profileDesc>  
  
    <revisionDesc>  
      <change>  
        <date value="2001">Summer 2001</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Jaime 
 Henshaw</name>
        </respStmt>  
        <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>  
      </change>  
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>  
 </teiHeader>  
  
 <text id="A6144T"> 
 <front id="d2"> 
 <div1 type="summary" id="d3"> 
 <p>Rolston discusses options for enlistment and the price paid by his 
 family for having another son go to war.</p>  
 </div1>  
 </front>  
  
 <body id="d4"> 
 <div1 type="letter" id="d5"> 
 <opener> 
 <dateline> 
 <date value="1864-03-11">March 11 1864</date>  
  <name type="place">Orange County <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> 
   Sumerville Ford, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> <lb/> Camp 52 
   Infantry</name> 
 </dateline>  
 <salute>Dear and affectionate wife,</salute>  
 </opener>  
  
 <p>I seat myself this morning to try and answer your welcome letter that I 
 just received a few minutes ago.  I had been looking for it some day past, 
 but it did not come to hand until this morning.  It found me in good 
 health and I was glad to hear from you and all was receiving the same 
 blessing of health but I feel somewhat vexed since I read your letter to 
 think of some things that is about reenlisting.  I have not reenlisted nor 
 do I ever intend to under the present circumstances.  If I have to stay in 
 service you can mark Jesse one that has not re-enlisted if you believe 
 what I write unless my mind changes very much from what it is now and what 
 it has been for some time past.  Accordance with the late law that has 
 been <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> for some time-between the<pb n="2"/> ages of 18 and 45 
 will have to be in service for the war.  It makes no difference whether I 
 want to or not unless they can get a detail of some kind <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> any 
 honorable detail that I can get, for I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> think 
 that duty would be any harder than it was on me.  So if you have a chance 
 you need not be uneasy but what I will except of it <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> so I hope 
 that you may <orig reg="meet">meat</orig> with success in what you have 
 undertaken and I hope that this will satisfy you about re-enlisting and it 
 may give you comfort and happiness to you, it <orig 
 reg="don't">dont</orig> do for a person to believe all they <orig 
 reg="hear">heare</orig> <orig reg="nowadays">now a days</orig>. 
 Furloughing is still a going on.  There is <orig reg="two">to</orig> ahead 
 of mine yet so I am still in hopes of getting one before long, we can have 
 the pleasure of talking in place of writing it.  it would give me so much 
 more <orig reg="comfort">comforty</orig>.  I have not heard anything about 
 giving up in Virginia.  It may be so, but I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> 
 believe that they are going to do it, for I think if they give up Virginia 
 this <orig reg="cruel">crewell</orig> war will be over soon.  I <orig 
 reg="don't">dint</orig> know what will be best for to do if John leaves. 
 If you can [get] <orig reg="someone">some one</orig> to crop it would be 
 less trouble to you and if I should be so lucky as to get off-I would 
 rather do it myself, so i leave that with you to decide.  I judge there is 
 no chance of hiring <orig reg="anyone">any one</orig> to work with any 
 certainty.  As they take what little you do raise - it <orig 
 reg="won't">wont</orig> pay you for to pay a big price for hiring.  How 
 old is John and how long can he stay before he would have to go in 
 service?  Does he want to go?  There is some boys that goes in service 
 sooner than they <orig reg="need">nead</orig>, but I don't know how it is 
 with him.  If you have a chance and can if you would move some of your 
 corn out of the crib someplace else.  They would not bother you so much. 
 It is right in the way.  it shows too plain.  Try to keep enough to do 
 you.  If you can hide it.  <orig reg="Don't">Dont</orig> think it will be 
 any harm in doing so.  So must come to a close -</p> 
  
 <closer> 
 <salute>remaining your husband until <orig 
 reg="separated">seperated</orig> by death.</salute>  
 <signed>Jesse Rolston</signed>  
 <seg type="postscript">
 <name type="recipient">Mary C Rolston</name>
 </seg>  
 </closer>  
 </div1>  
 </body>  
 </text>  
 </TEI.2> 