<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6216"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A6216">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Mary Anna Sibert to David H. Evans,
                    May 13, 1868</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county mary anna sibert to david h evans, may 13 1868</title>
        <author>Sibert, Mary Anna</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A6216</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502457</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Mary Anna Sibert to David H. Evans, May 13, 1868</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county mary anna sibert to david h evans, may 13 1868</title>
            <author>Mary Anna Sibert</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Mary Anna Sibert to David H.
                            Evans, May 13, 1868, Evans-Sibert Family Papers, Accession 27770,
                            Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1868-05-13">1868-05-13</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Women, Family</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A6216T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Sibert discusses family news and her longing for a visit from Evans.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1868-05-13">May 13, 1868.</date>
                        <name type="place">Mt. Solon Va</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear David,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I will now answer your dear &amp; welcome letter of Tuesday &amp; have it
                    mailed if the rain is falling but I hope not enough to raise the rivers. I wish
                    as usual for the first &amp; last wish of every day that I could see you.
                    Ella &amp; her dear children arrived safely Monday Evening &amp; found
                    us all gald to see them again. Ella says she knows you will take care of her
                    dear Magnus &amp; stay with him at night &amp; keep the robbers from
                    killing him, but don't you let them kill you. Ella talks so often &amp; so
                    much about you all that <pb n="2"/>is good. I love to hear her speak of you. she
                    knows it. dear Ella is a true, &amp; faithful firend of yours from the very
                    sincerity of her heart. so is Magnus. I will tell you something Ella told me he
                    said to his sister Bettsey about you when you come then you will know that he
                    does certainly esteem you very highly. it makes me love Magnus more <orig
                        reg="than">then</orig> I ever did. I wish you were only here this gloomy
                    evening I would then forget the sun was not shining &amp; the rain was
                    falling it would be so bright within the house that I would not feel the want of
                    sunshine <orig reg="outdoors">out doors</orig>. but you are not &amp; cannot
                    be here now. I can love you, think of you, &amp; write to you, pleasures I
                    thank God for giving me <pb n="3"/>when you are absent. I have been thinking so
                    much about you that I love to think of nothing else all the day long. Ella is
                    anxious for me to spend some time with her this Summer if we should live I told
                    her the same I wrote to you last week, but if Ada returns I can go &amp;
                    stay a long time &amp; be near you who I love to be with always &amp;
                    never get tired of seeing your dear face. I do get very tired now of waiting
                    until I can see you two long dreary weeks Oh how long &amp; slow the days
                    are to me before you come I often think I can't wait there is nothing in this
                    life harder to bear <orig reg="than">then</orig> to wait patiently for what our
                    hearts wants to be now, to have <pb n="4"/>now, but can't &amp; must wait
                    longer <orig reg="than">then</orig> now for what we so fondly desire to make the
                    heart happy &amp; satisfied I try to wait, &amp; not complain for I know
                    it cannot be helped. It seems that I would give <orig reg="anything">any
                    thing</orig> in this world if I could only see you every day. I am sorry you
                    can't get here earlier, so we could be with <orig reg="each other"
                    >eachother</orig> as long as possible your short visits seem like dreams to me
                        <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> they are dear &amp; sweet to me if short just so I can
                    be with you I am happy &amp; contented &amp; now to think you will soon
                    be here makes my heart very light &amp; glad. I can scarcely wait for the
                    two days to pass so anxious am I to see you again. come if you live my love I
                    hope God will safely guide you to me as in days past. I love to have you with me
                    always I love you with the same unchanging devotion of heart &amp; soul.
                    nothing can ever take my love from you &amp; to love you is a very dear
                    pleasure to my heart. I ask only for you to love me, &amp; only for me to
                    love you of all the living on Earth. Yes I love you &amp; God knows how
                    deeply, &amp; how devotedly. All send love. I send love &amp; a loving
                    kiss to you. Come Saturday my heart says come. God bless you</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours</salute>
                    <signed>Mollie Sibert</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
