<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6214"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A6214">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Mary Anna Sibert to David H. Evans,
                    April 31, 1868</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county mary anna sibert to david h evans, april 31 1868</title>
        <author>Sibert, Mary Anna</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A6214</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502455</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Mary Anna Sibert to David H. Evans, April 31, 1868</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county mary anna sibert to david h evans, april 31 1868</title>
            <author>Mary Anna Sibert</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Mary Anna Sibert to David H.
                            Evans, April 31, 1868, Evans-Sibert Family Papers, Accession 27770,
                            Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1868-04-30">1868-04-31</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Women, Family, Arts/Leisure, Church/Religious Activity</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A6214T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Sibert details the ways in which Evans makes her happy, reaffirms her love for
                    him, and urges him to come visit. She also reports on recent successes enjoyed
                    by her father's steel business, and discusses other family news.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1868-04-30"><sic>April 31, 1868</sic></date>
                        <name type="place">Mt Solon, Va.</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear David,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Your dear letter of the 28 has been <abbr expan="received">rc'd</abbr>, &amp;
                    read with thankful heart many times. You can, &amp; do make me very happy
                    when you look bright &amp; happy <orig reg="yourself">your self</orig>, when
                    you stay with me, &amp; love me, when you write me long &amp;
                    affectionate letters, &amp; when I think you will ask God to bless you with
                    a new heart. Do you think I demand a great deal to make me <hi rend="underline"
                        >very</hi> happy? &amp; that it is too much to give? I feel sure the
                    answer of both your heart, &amp; lips will be no! How delighted I am to know
                    that you do not, &amp; have not regretted giving me <pb n="2"/>your love.
                    &amp; may it be my only &amp; greatest desire while we both live never
                    to give you a cause to regret having given to me the first devotion of your
                    early manhood. May I ever love, &amp; dearly prize the sweet gift of your
                    heart its truth &amp; love. You <hi rend="underline">are</hi> &amp;
                    always will be worthy of my love, &amp; deepest devotion. You are all I
                    could wish you to be but a christian &amp; in that particular I have placed
                    you my love in the hands of a merciful God who will in due time answer my daily
                    &amp; earnest prayers for you who I love so well. My dear papa is very
                    joyful <orig reg="today">to day</orig> over his steel success. he <abbr
                        expan="received">rec'd</abbr> a letter from <abbr expan="General"
                    >Gen'l</abbr> Imboden, saying the analysis of the metal made by the great
                    chemist of <pb n="3"/>Baltimore had been sent to him &amp; that it was not
                    an alloy but pure steel of the best quality ever made. The chemist has been
                    almost 2 months giving the metal a fair &amp; perfect test by the best
                    chemicals which he sent to the City of New York for just to try papa's own metal
                    with. <abbr expan="General">Gen'l</abbr> Imboden also wrote that the tires sent
                    to Mr. Whitcomb at Richmond would be tried the first of May. I never saw pa in
                    such a glee as he is <orig reg="today">to day</orig>, did not know what to do
                    with himself. I told him to thank God for his success. Maj. M'Cue invited him
                    over to his home this evening where he is now. I was interrupted while ago by
                    some ladies calling to see the stereoscope. it took them some time to view
                    Washington City Rennie is coming up tomorrow if <pb n="4"/>she lives to remain
                    with us until Sunday. So brother David wrote to pa. We will not get down to see
                    them if she comes Got a letter from Ada she is anxious to come home now. I wish
                    you were here this lovely Spring evening we would enjoy a long walk &amp;
                    gather flowers without <hi rend="underline">thorns</hi> for each other. I long
                    to see your dear face can't hardly wait until Saturday comes &amp; brings
                    you with it. Come if you live, my heart is <orig reg="anxious">anxius</orig>
                    &amp; impatient to have you here again. be happy &amp; I shall be so.
                    let nothing cloud the joy of our meeting but let us be very glad &amp; truly
                    thankful that God has so kindly granted us the blessing of being with each other
                    again. I love you Oh! so devotedly &amp; entirely that to be with you is
                    happiness indeed. &amp; I ask no other joy only to have you ever with me.
                    May God let you come to one who loves you with all her heart &amp; soul. All
                    send love, I send love &amp; a loving kiss to you. God bless you my love.
                    Come Saturday I long to see you.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours</salute>
                    <signed>Mollie Sibert</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
