<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6226"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A6226">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Mary Anna Sibert to David H. Evans,
                    August 27, 1868</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county mary anna sibert to david h evans, august 27 1868</title>
        <author>Sibert, Mary Anna</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">6</num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A6226</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502467</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: </title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county</title>
            <author>Mary Anna Sibert</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Mary Anna Sibert to David H.
                            Evans, August 27, 1868, Evans-Sibert Family Papers, Accession 27770,
                            Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1868-08-27">1868-08-27</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Women, Family, Arts/Leisure</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A6226T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Sibert Writes Evans and discusses family news, her desire to see Evans, and her
                    love for him.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1868-08-27">Aug 27, 1868</date>
                        <name type="place">Mt. Solon Va.</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear David</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Your dear &amp; truely welcome letter of Tuesday came safely, &amp; now I
                    will answer it having completed my domestic duties for the present hour. I find
                    it a much sweeter duty to write to you <orig reg="than">then</orig> any other
                    when not with you. You don't know how much I was disappointed last Sabbath when
                    Magnus came without you. I told him I was not glad to see him as you could not
                    come. The day seemed long &amp; lonely to me without you my love. I scarcely
                    knew <pb n="2"/>what to do with myself all day it was so lonely. I am so
                    delighted to feel sure of your coming this Saturday I want to see your dear face
                    more <orig reg="than">then</orig> I can tell. Ma &amp; Pa went to Buffalo
                    &amp; will not return if they live until tomorrow evening. Hattie came home
                    this morning. I am glad she is with us once more. The home circle was not
                    complete while our Hattie was absent You can't imagine how Macon has improved
                    since his two weeks sojourn with us. he does not look like the frail delicate
                        <pb n="3"/>flower brought here two weeks past. I agree with you in advising
                    Magnus to let Ella remain here until the last of September, but Ella says she
                    cannot stay. I do wish she could I love to have her with us. Magnus did not tell
                    me how he had disappointed you last Sabbath. I think he reproached himself when
                    he saw how much I was disappointed by you not coming. he told me that you would
                    come if you could get a horse, but said he felt sure you could not hire one as
                    so many had been hired before you. I hope with all my heart that <pb n="4"
                    />nothing will prevent you from coming this Saturday. I am so anxious to see you
                    to be with one I love more <orig reg="than">then</orig> all on Earth. I do
                    indeed think you are <orig reg="becoming">be coming</orig> quite fond of gay
                    society. I was pleased to hear you enjoyed the Masquerade it was something novel
                    to you &amp; you could not fail to be interested. I should have loved to be
                    with you but not there. You are in all my thoughts <orig reg="wherever">where
                        ever</orig> you may be, I love you only &amp; at all times with fervent
                    &amp; unchanging devotion of my heart &amp; Soul. in my heart there is
                    no change toward you it is filled with love &amp; devotion only for you
                    while I live. I do regret that you can't come sooner Saturday. I love to have
                    you with me as long as possible. May God let you come I long to see your dear
                    face again all send love. I send a loving kiss, &amp; all the love of my
                    heart. God bless you my love.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours</salute>
                    <signed>Mollie Sibert</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
