<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6239"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A6239">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Mary Anna Sibert to David H. Evans,
                    November 18, 1868</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county mary anna sibert to david h evans, november 18 1868</title>
        <author>Sibert, Mary Anna</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A6239</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502480</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Mary Anna Sibert to David H. Evans, November 18, 1868</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county mary anna sibert to david h evans, november 18 1868</title>
            <author>Mary Anna Sibert</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Mary Anna Sibert to David H.
                            Evans, November 18, 1868, Evans-Sibert Family Papers, Accession 27770,
                            Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1868-11-18">1868-11-18</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Women, Family, Arts/Leisure</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A6239T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Sibert writes Evans and discusses her reaction to his quiet mood, family news,
                    and prospects for future visits.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1868-11-18">Nov. 18, /'68.<lb/>I wrote this letter Wednesday</date>
                        <name type="place">Buffalo, Va.</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear David</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Hamie brought your last dear &amp; welcome letter safely. It contained the
                    same news of God's Mercy in guiding you on your way home without accident for
                    which I am not forgetful, but I know that My heart is too much filled with
                    thoughts of you to be true to My Father in Heaven. May God moderate My deep
                    affection for you My love is the daily prayer of my life. I am truly <del
                        hand="h1"/>y that I gave way to my feelings before you last Saturday night I
                        <pb n="2"/>could not help it then forgive me my love I did not know what to
                    think of your manner towards me I wished while I sit &amp; looked at you
                    that I could read your heart &amp; see love there for me without letting you
                    know that I was grieved at the time. I did not doubt you my love I have said
                    that I would not. I did not &amp; will not doubt your affection for me I
                    felt disappointed &amp; deeply grieved that after an absence of a long week
                    that you who I love more <orig reg="than">then</orig> my own soul should seem so
                        <unclear>indifferent toward</unclear> me, but I will not forget in the
                    future that you have much to think <pb n="3"/>over &amp; make you silent
                    regarding business affairs it is so with all gentlemen. I shall not forget that
                    you have your business cares to occupy your time &amp; thoughts. I am
                    selfish to suppose that you have nothing to think of but me. I know that you are
                    my first thought in all things, &amp; at all times. I will yet learn to see
                    &amp; do my duty to you my love at all times when you are silent &amp;
                    thoughtful I love you then as devotedly as if you were gay. It gives me pain to
                    see you troubled &amp; I don't know <unclear>what</unclear>
                    <unclear>makes</unclear> you so. Ma was not angry when she reached home about
                    Hamie going down with you she <pb n="4"/>was glad to get home again. she told me
                    how handsome you looked Monday night I wish I could have seen you. did your
                    Sister <orig reg="in law">inlaw</orig> think you were dressed fanciful. I have
                    given up the hope of spending any time in Staunton this Winter it has been my
                    earnest wish to do so <unclear>that</unclear> I might be near you My love but I
                    am I see doomed to be disappointed in that wish of my heart I may get there
                    after Christmas &amp; spend a week or two I do hope so then I can see you
                    every day. I wish you were here <orig reg="today">to day</orig> I do want to see
                    your dear face more <orig reg="than">then</orig> I can tell. I hope you can come
                    up Saturday I do want you to come Magnus expects to come, we are expecting dear
                    papa Saturday. he may come before then. I hope so I love you with all the
                    unchanging devotion of my heart &amp; soul &amp; ever shall while I
                    live. You are the dearest to me of all on Earth <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> the devotion of my heart &amp; all my thoughts are of you.
                    Come, May God bless you my love. All send love I send a loving kiss Write to me
                    soon I love you only</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours Lovingly</salute>
                    <signed>Mollie Sibert</signed>
                    <pb n="1"/>
                    <seg type="postscript">Do you think I am selfish for wanting you to come every
                        Saturday? I love to be <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>th you &amp; I do want you to
                        come every <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>ek, forgive me if you think me selfish. I love
                        you</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
