<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6243"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A6243">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Mary Anna Sibert to David H. Evans,
                    December 10, 1868</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county mary anna sibert to david h evans, december 10 1868</title>
        <author>Sibert, Mary Anna</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A6243</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502484</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Mary Anna Sibert to David H. Evans, December 10, 1868</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county mary anna sibert to david h evans, december 10 1868</title>
            <author>Mary Anna Sibert</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Mary Anna Sibert to David H.
                            Evans, December 10, 1868, Evans-Sibert Family Papers, Accession 27770,
                            Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1868-12-10">1868-12-10</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Women, Family</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A6243T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Sibert writes Evans and discusses family news, her desire to move from Buffalo,
                    and her wish that Evans spend Christmas with her family.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1868-12-10">Dec 10,/'68</date>
                        <name type="place">Buffalo Va,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear David</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I have your welcome &amp; dear letter of Tuesday which I have read with
                    thankful happines. I missed you so much last Sabbath my love. I expect Ada
                    &amp; John Noon thought me unsociable I felt lonely in heart &amp; Soul
                    &amp; could not talk much to them. The day <orig reg="though">tho</orig> a
                    holy one seemed long to me without you who I love to be with. Yes my dear pa has
                    been called away again &amp; left us alone in the Mountains <pb n="2"/> for
                    how long I know not We are doubly lonely when he is absent. he wanted me to go
                    with him as far as Gordonsville, but I thought of you my love &amp; Ma was
                    not willing for me to leave home.</p>

                <p>Cousin Gordon Beale wrote that he was coming over to spend his Christmas with us
                    if he comes I have thought of going home with him after the holidays I would
                    rather be at home Christmas &amp; have you here <orig reg="than">then</orig>
                    <orig reg="anywhere">any where </orig> on Earth. I want you to come my love
                    &amp; stay all week then you can hunt with Ham &amp; cousin Gordon. You
                    must come I am going to remain at home just to have the dear pleasure of being
                        <pb n="3"/> with you who I love more <orig reg="than">then</orig> all
                    others. papa will be at home if he lives &amp; we shall have a happy time.
                    You will come will you not my love I am so anxious for you to spend your
                    Christmas with us if you live I shall be very happy with you here &amp; do
                    all I can to make you happy. My love you do not know how anxious I am for papa
                    to move from this lonely place. I suppose we shall know where we will locate
                    when he returns from Baltimore I hope he will go to Staunton. Pa expects to send
                    Hamie to school very soon it may be to New York. Ada writes that she is not
                    going to <pb n="4"/> wait any longer <orig reg="than">then</orig> Spring before
                    she is married. Tell her I am surprised to hear it as I did not know she was
                    really loving <orig reg="anyone">any one</orig> at this time. I wish I could see
                    you my love it seems long since you were here last. I am sorry you
                        <unclear>cannot</unclear> come Saturday evening it will be so long until
                    Sunday Morning &amp; then you will have such a little while to stay <orig
                        reg="can't">cant</orig> you stay with us Sunday night? I wish you could my
                    love &amp; I do hope from my heart that we will soon live near so I can see
                    you often. I love to be with you who I love with all the deep devotion of my
                    heart &amp; soul. I love you more &amp; more every day of my life
                    &amp; ever shall while I live with faithful devotion. You are dearer to my
                    heart &amp; memory <orig reg="than">then</orig> all on Earth. Yes I do
                    indeed love you only &amp; love to think of you when absent &amp; read
                    your dear welcome letters. Come Sunday my heart says come I want to see you more
                        <orig reg="than">then</orig> I can tell &amp; love you more <orig
                        reg="than">then</orig> I can ever express in words. All send love. I send a
                    loving kiss to you. God bless you &amp; let you come my only love.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours Lovingly</salute>
                    <signed>Mollie Sibert</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
