<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6519"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A6519">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Clinton Hatcher to Mary Anna Sibert, September
     24, 1861</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county clinton hatcher to mary anna sibert, september 24 1861</title>
        <author>Hatcher, Clinton</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Susanna Michele Lee</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Susanna Michele Lee</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">12</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6519</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502530</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Clinton Hatcher to Mary Anna Sibert, September 24, 1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county clinton hatcher to mary anna sibert, september 24 1861</title>
            <author>Clinton Hatcher</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Evans-Sibert Family Papers, 1849-1900, Accession
       27770, Personal Papers Collection, Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond,
      Virginia</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1861-09-24">1861-09-24</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Battle Description, Camp Life, Medicine/Hospitals, Women</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2005-02-01">February 1, 2005</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Andre Fleche</name>
        </respStmt>

        <item>Proofread against original; changes made.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6519T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Clinton Hatcher names one exception to the rule of female inconstancy and reveals his
     feelings for Mary Sibert. He also comments on camp life, mentions a skirmish with the Yankees,
     and criticizes prominent Unionist John Minor Botts.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1861-09-24">Sept 24<hi rend="super">
        <hi rend="underline">th</hi>
      </hi> 1861</date>
      <name type="place">Camp Johnson</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Miss Mary:</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>Your <hi rend="underline">very</hi> long and interesting letter arrived yesterday evening and
     was perused with the greatest pleasure. I have several correspondents but no other, who can
     spare the time rather or has the inclination to write me such long and interesting epistles.
     You need not fear that I ever <hi rend="underline">can</hi> become wearied with a
     correspondence which gives me <hi rend="underline">so</hi>
     <hi rend="underline">much</hi> pleasure without being the slightest inconvenience, for I do not
     consider it a trouble to write to <hi rend="underline">you</hi> no matter how often a letter
     may be due you. My actions also prove this for I think I always answer your letters at the
     earliest possible moment after receiving them.</p>

    <p>Camp is rather duller than usual this week. Last friday night the pickets brought in the
     report that several hundred Yanks had crossed the river and were encamped within about eight
     miles of this place; we were arroused about two O'clock and two hundred of us marched off in
     search of them. We walked about eighteen miles; half of it in the rain and saw not a trace of
     the federals. We have orders now to have our knapsacks packed and be ready to march at a
     moment's warning; but I think it quite probable that we will be left to protect Loudon for some
     time yet.</p>

    <p>I hope we will not be left behind when the attack is made on Washington, for I would not miss
     marching in there for anything in the world, but I had rather remain here until they are ready
     to commence fighting at once. My cousin and I went on a pear-stealing expedition yesterday
     evening and managed to get about half a bushel, so green that you can hardly keep from
     whistling <pb n="2"/> after eating one or two. But anything is good in camp.</p>

    <p>Oh! How <hi rend="underline">I</hi> wish you could have wings if you would favour the 8<hi
      rend="super">th</hi> Regiment with a visit, of all my <hi rend="underline">dear</hi> friends
     there is none, I would welcome with such pure, heartfelt joy, none in whose company the hours
     would pass so delightfully, as a fair inhabitant of Mount Solon. I would give so much to be in
     your company now even for a short time; to see you and freely tell <hi rend="underline"
     >all</hi> I think and <hi rend="underline">feel</hi>. I fear to write <hi rend="underline"
     >all</hi>; to tell you how the image of one seen but three times, has lingered round my waking
     fancies, added sweetness to my dreams, and driven away the gloom which would inevitably have
     hung round one leading a life so indolent, and seemingly employed to so little purpose. But I
      <hi rend="underline">must</hi> not proceed. I am almost <hi rend="underline">certain</hi> that
     I posses your friendship and I fear to lose even it, which I <orig reg="prize">prise</orig>
     <hi rend="underline">so</hi> much by straining for more. I think I am already tolerably well
     acquainted with you; you posses a depth of feeling and comprehensiveness of thought of which
      <hi rend="underline">many</hi> persons can form no conception and fortunate, doubly fortunate
     is he, whose love shall wake a responsive echo in <hi rend="underline">your</hi> heart. You
     misunderstood my letter if you thought I doubted your friendship. I believe that the human race
     is naturally inconstant and the female portion especially so, but there are many high and noble
     exceptions to this general rule and I am firmly convinced that you are one. My heart is not so
     invulnerable, as you think, to Cupid's darts. I like the "free and sociable" way in which you
     write and although our acquaintance has been short I think we are far from being strangers. But
     to answer your question: Candidly, I do not think you are a flirt, I <hi rend="underline"
     >hope</hi> you are not. I may have "misconstrued your sentiments," but have never thought you
     capable of "hypocrisy": what I most fear is that I may have misconstrued them in the vain <hi
      rend="underline">hope</hi> that you cared more for me than you really do. How I would enjoy
     the realization of your <pb n="3"/>picture of the sail on the lake. It would be the happiest
     moment of my life, to hear the secrets of <hi rend="underline">your</hi>
     <hi rend="underline">heart</hi>, all of them. I would bid you love one did I not fear you would
     think I commanded impossibilities; one who would be willing to devote his life to securing your
     happiness, and consecrate every physical and mental energy to the accomplishment of your
     wishes. Indeed I can never become "disgusted with your sentimental strains." I could never tire
     with reading such letters as yours. <unclear>Yora</unclear> or Forrer, one misunderstood my
     message in his last; your note or rather sentence, in the corner of his letter admitted two
     constructions and I preferred construing it differently from the way you explained and only
     asked if I might. There was nothing in it to give offence in any way.</p>

    <p>I have heard nothing of Hon. John M. Botts for a long time. He is a man I never admired much.
     I always feard his devotion to the interests of the South was very small. I heard when I was in
     Augusta of the <orig reg="bouquet">boquet</orig> which you presented him and wondered how you
     would like the principles, which he was then advocating. The letter which he wrote to President
     Lincoln was unworthy of a Southerner. I was <hi rend="underline">very</hi> sorry to hear of the
     loss of our North Carolina forts, they were especially valuable to us as a refuge for our
     privateers, but in the end it may be an advantage to our cause, for it is arousing the brave
     sons of the old tar state and she will send thousands of volunteers into service now who would
     otherwise have remained idly at home, thinking the seat of war too far removed for them to
     offer their services. <orig reg="Did">Dide</orig> you learn the name of that College friend of
     mine with whom your brother met? I have a great many collegemates in the army and some very <pb
      n="4"/> dear friends. I wish paper was not so scarce and I would write to some of them, but it
     is a precious article in the army. One of our companies went down to the river yesterday and
     exchanged about a dozen rounds with the enemy. None of our men were hurt and they hope they did
     some execution among the federals as they were within musket range.</p>

    <p>I would not mind having a slight wound if I could only be taken to the Mossy Creek hospital.
     I am sure I should never think of pain if I could have your kind and tender attentions. I envy
     those soldiers who will be near you and hear your sweet voice speak words of comfort. But I am
     afraid I shall weary you this time for although I do not write so many pages as you, my mamoth
     sheet almost makes up the difference, and then my style, interrupted as I am every minute by
     some of our numerous visitors, is <hi rend="underline">so</hi> much more tiresome than your
     free and natural manner of writing. But I know that <hi rend="underline">you</hi> will overlook
     all my defects. Otherwise my letter should be committed at once to the flames. I have not heard
     from Chum now for some time, I hope I shall receive another letter soon. Please write me
     another of your long and interesting letters very soon. I ask no more interesting than your
     last. Is Miss Bettie Forrer at home now? She is a very nice young lady.</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>I remain as ever, most <hi rend="underline">devotedly</hi> and <hi rend="underline"
       >unchangingly</hi><lb/> Your <hi rend="underline">true</hi> friend</salute>
     <signed>Clinton</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
