<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6520"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A6520">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Clinton Hatcher to Mary Anna Sibert, October 8,
     1861</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county clinton hatcher to mary anna sibert, october 8 1861</title>
        <author>Hatcher, Clinton</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Susanna Michele Lee</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Susanna Michele Lee</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">11</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6520</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502531</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Clinton Hatcher to Mary Anna Sibert, October 8, 1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county clinton hatcher to mary anna sibert, october 8 1861</title>
            <author>Clinton Hatcher</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Evans-Sibert Family Papers, 1849-1900, Accession
       27770, Personal Papers Collection, Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond,
      Virginia</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>Included in the Library of Virginia with this letter is a newspaper clipping entitled "Our
        Leesburg Victory," which notes the death of Clinton Hatcher of Loudoun County, and a small
        bouquet of flowers tied with a string.</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1861-10-08">1861-10-08</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Military Strategy, Women</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2005-02-04">February 4, 2005</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Andre Fleche</name>
        </respStmt>

        <item>Proofread against original; changes made.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6520T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Clinton Hatcher discusses changes in his regiment, including its possible incorporation into
     Longstreet's Brigade. Hatcher also asks Mary Sibert whether she could possibly love him.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Miss Mary A Sibert<lb/> Mt. Solon<lb/>Augusta County<lb/>Virginia</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1861-10-08">October 8<hi rend="super">
        <hi rend="underline">th</hi>
      </hi> 1861</date>
      <name type="place">Camp Johnson</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Miss Mary:</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>Your <hi rend="underline">very</hi> welcome letter was received from the courier yesterday
     and although he may have borne despatches of more importance to the Southern Confederacy, yet I
     am certain that none contained half so much to interest the recipients as did that fair
     missive. I was afraid at first that you would finally grow weary of writing such long letters
     to one who could offer so poor a return for them and it rejoices me exceedingly every time I
     receive another practical assurance that such is not, yet at least, the case.</p>

    <p>It is currently reported here that we are soon to be attached to Longstreet's Brigade, which
     you know is in the very vanguard of our army. They have been down nearly to Alexandria and are
     still the advanced Brigade. If I was certain that a battle would take place very soon I would
     like very much for the "eigth" to be placed under Longstreet as he is a brave man and will be
     one of the first to commence fighting, but if we are only to be wearied out with marchings and
     pickett duty I had much rather remain here in Loudon until we cross into Maryland. The news
     from Jno. is glorious and if we could only get over into Maryland, Beauregard might soon
     dictate his terms of peace with his cannons leveled at Philadephia. For my part I should like
     Boston once to hear the roar of our artillery, it would tame the firey spirits of some
     fanatical leaders. But I am tired of writing on a subject which I hear discussed so incessantly
     therefore I will change the current to a theme which interests <hi rend="underline">me</hi>
     infinitely more than <hi rend="underline">all</hi> else on earth your own <hi rend="underline"
      >dear</hi> (pardon me) self <pb n="2"/> You bid me write all I feel, yet I can not summon
     courage to tell what I have never told before. I fear--every thing. Yet I have already told you
     in effect all I would say; my last letter must have conveyed <hi rend="underline">all</hi> to
     your mind; Can you bid me hope? I know I have no right to infer any thing from what you have
     said previous to this; it is true you have expressed friendship for me but friendship is cold
     and formal, and I fear you can give nothing more. Oh! If I could only hold your hand and look
     into those eyes which have lit the darkest hours of our separation you could then no longer
     doubt with what feelings I regard <hi rend="underline">you</hi>, you would then know how much I
      <hi rend="underline">love</hi>. I confess I have dared to hope, from the free and confiding
     style of your letters that perhaps you could reciprocate my affections, but if I have
     misconstrued your manner and from false premises formed wrong conclusions please do not blame
     me, my wishes may have biased my judgement, but if so I deserve sympathy rather than censure. I
     shall in that event <hi rend="underline">try</hi> to love you more as a sister, and be a friend
     to the one, who more fortunate than myself, shall gain your hand and priceless love. So far
     life has been to me a happy dream my wishes have been realised, I have succeeded in my
     undertakings and fortune has smiled upon me. In school and college I never thought of failing
     and thought the highest rank only worthy my exertions, but every one must learn to bear
     disappointments, and if I must endure this, although the sorest of my life, I will try to nerve
     myself for the sad task. Being alone in the world, having no sister in whom to confide and upon
     whom to lavish the <pb n="3"/> tender affections of my nature, and no brother whose helping
     hand could smooth the path of life, I have always longed for some one to <hi rend="underline"
      >love</hi>, to trust with every secret of my heart one who would seem almost a part of my
     existence. Although not usually considered sentimental, I do not think love to be a fairy
     legend of the Poet's brain, but a powerful, enduring passion which binds the heart to that of
     another, firmly and forever. Such is the <hi rend="underline">love</hi>
     <hi rend="underline">I</hi> would offer. Can <hi rend="underline">you</hi> receive and requite
     it? You ask who it is I would <unclear>bide</unclear> you love and encourage me with the
     assurance that you "could not be so cruel as to deny him all the deep devotion of your fond
     heart." But you have just said the one you love must be "embelished with the charms of
     refinement nobleness and goodness." Oh! that the one of whom I spoke could pass that hard
     ordeal, then it is I, I would bid you love but I feel that the aspirant for that greatest of
      <hi rend="underline">all</hi>
     <hi rend="underline">earthly</hi> prizes if weighed in the <orig reg="balance">ballance</orig>
     would be found wanting. I am certain you have long ago become weary of the subject about which
     I have been writing, and which my inexperienced pen has rendered so uninteresting. It is indeed
     a novel undertaking with me to describe the secret attractions and impulses of my heart,
     feelings never before experienced. But I know you will make sufficient apologies to your own
     mind for a letter which is from the heart and not the intellect. Please do not neglect to
     answer all these things in your next for you have no idea how eagerly and impatiently <pb n="4"
     /> I shall <orig reg="await">awaite</orig> an answer. You need not fear of wearying me no
     matter how much you may write on <hi rend="underline">that</hi> subject or indeed on any other.
     The greatest pleasure of my life is in the free and unrestrained communion with kindred
     spirits, and thoughts and feelings are always more welcome, whose sympathising emotions are
      <orig reg="far">fare</orig> dearer than all on earth besides.</p>

    <p>Oh! If I could only be free once more and go to the spot, to which my thoughts ever tend, I
     could be supremely happy, now I cannot help like Moore's lover sighing for the placid
     "Lake,<lb/> And the light canoe of my dear".<lb/> To be your companion in those boat rides and
     mountain strolls, to be your escort when you ride and sit beside you when no one else is near
     and tell you <hi rend="underline">all</hi> I feel, all the depth of my affection for <hi
      rend="underline">you</hi>, that would be the ultimatum of happiness, my imagination can paint
     nothing which nearer realises my idea of the "Sunum bonum", the greatest good of all on earth.</p>

    <p>But I must close, I have already wearied you I fear and must not try your patience too far.
     Please write to me <hi rend="underline">at</hi>
     <hi rend="underline">once</hi> a long, confiding letter; tell me all, even the worst. I shall
      <orig reg="wait">waite</orig>
     <hi rend="underline">so</hi> impatiently for your next letter, but I know you will be punctual,
     you always are.</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Please think sometimes of one who always remembers you, and most truly <hi
       rend="underline">your</hi>
      <hi rend="underline">devoted</hi>,</salute>
     <signed>Clinton</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
