<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A7102"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A7102"> 
<teiHeader type="migrated"> 

    <fileDesc> 
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: John Scott to Samuel Hunt, December 18, 1865</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county john scott to samuel hunt, december 18 1865</title>
        <author>Scott, John</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt> 
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp> 
          <name>Bart Elmore</name> 
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp> 
          <name>Bart Elmore</name> 
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt> 

      <extent>ca. 6.475 kilobytes </extent> 
      <publicationStmt> 
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher> 
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace> 

        <idno type="VCDH">A7102</idno> 

        <!--
<availability> 
<p>Publicly accessible </p> 
<p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p> 
<p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p> 
</availability>
--> 
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2002">2002</date> 
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500218</idno>
      </publicationStmt> 
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt> 
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt> 

      <sourceDesc> 
        <biblFull> 
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: John Scott to Samuel Hunt, December 18, 1865</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county john scott to samuel hunt, december 18 1865</title>
            <author>John Scott</author>
          </titleStmt> 
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt> 
          <extent>4 pages</extent> 
          <publicationStmt> 
            <publisher/> 
            <pubPlace/> 
            <date value=""/> 
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: John Scott to Samuel Hunt, December 18, 1865, American Missionary Association Archives Collection, Microfilm 72, Alderman Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville</idno>
          </publicationStmt> 
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt> 
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt> 
        </biblFull> 
      </sourceDesc> 
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Alderman Library, University of Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc> 

    <profileDesc> 
      <creation>
        <date value="1865-12-18">1865-12-18</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass> 
        <keywords> 
          <term>African Americans, Education, Arts/Leisure, Economy</term> 
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords> 
      </textClass> 
    </profileDesc> 


    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader> 

<text id="A7102T">
<front id="d2">
<div1 type="summary" id="d3">
<p>In a typical report to Samuel Hunt, Scott focuses on the recent acquisition of a "Rebel Camp stove" which has helped to provide heat in his classroom.  He comments on the beauty of the "'Alleghany' Mts" and mentions a "young man" who has been buying "condemned property" in the Valley and assisting the AMA in Staunton.</p> 
</div1> 

</front> 

<body id="d4">
<div1 type="letter" id="d5">
<head>
<name type="recipient">Rev S Hunt</name> 
<name type="place">Staunton Va.</name> 
</head>

<opener>
<dateline>
    <date value="1865-12-18">Dec 18<hi rend="super">th</hi>/65</date> 
</dateline> 
<salute>Dear Sir</salute> 
</opener> 

<p>Yours of the 16<hi rend="super">th</hi> inst. came to hand this eve acknowledging the "receipt of the Monthly Report of schools in" Staunton, and inquiring if we have received "Blanks and Registers"
</p>

<p>In reply I would say that we have not received them.  Your letter breathes of sympathy that is cheering.</p>

<p>The boxes containing the books and lamps are expected tonight and nothing can be more welcome than the latter.  I have taken up a contribution for lights<pb n="2"/> and fuel and established the practice as weekly.  Dec 19<hi rend="super">th</hi></p>

<p>The boxes have arrived, and although I have not opened them, yet I expect to, and must put up the lamps ready for night school.
</p>

<p>I have had the pleasure of teaching by a fire today for the first time as we had no stove for my room and I have suffered heretofore.
</p>

<p>I rode out, Saturday last and procured an old Rebel Camp stove which now warms <unclear>us</unclear> and is in better business than it ever was before.  The appearance of the country is desolate but the desolation is not departed glory, for it never had any, but gives evidence of a most consummate lazy people, as its former owners.
</p>

<p>I came in sight<pb n="3"/> of the grand old "Alleghany" Mts.  They look wild and majestic, I saw a wild deer this morning which was shot yesterday, out in those mountains.  We are overworked and could not carry on the schools were it not for the aid we get from a soldier and a young man who is staying in town a few days to buy condemned property, and <unclear>reffuse</unclear> stuff to send north.
</p>

<p>I hope our other teacher will return from Lexington this week and relieve us, as we sent her up with Supt. Coan last week to start that school til other teachers could arrive.
</p>

<p>Mr Tukey has gone to Lexington, and as it is near the holidays he took Mr Johstone up to relieve Mr Coan immediately, as he wishes to go down the valley toward Winchester<pb n="4"/> and visit the schools that way before Christmas, And Mr Johnston can return to this place and thence to Harrisonburg during Christmas week, and with no more expense to the Association than if he went to direct to Harrisonburg, as Mr Tukey takes his own horse.
</p>

<p>It seems to be expected that next week is to be a continual holiday.  I object to that use of the most sacred day as one of commemoration ever <del hand="h1">engaged</del> celebrated by man (except that which reminds us of the resurrection of Christ) but suppose I shall have to yield and close school
</p>

<p>We think however of trying to aid in geting up a fair to help pay for a School House--These poor people<pb n="1"/> think that they can raise money enough to build a church in a short time, I do not discourage them but they have little idea of the value of property.</p>

<closer>
<salute></salute> 
<signed>John Scott</signed> 
 
<name type="place">New York</name> 
</closer> 
</div1> 
</body> 
</text> 
</TEI.2>