<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A7122"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A7122"> 
<teiHeader type="migrated"> 

    <fileDesc> 
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: John Scott to Samuel Hunt, June 2, 1866</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county john scott to samuel hunt, june 2 1866</title>
        <author>Scott, John</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt> 
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp> 
          <name>Bart Elmore</name> 
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp> 
          <name>Bart Elmore</name> 
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt> 

      <extent>ca. 10.382 kilobytes </extent> 
      <publicationStmt> 
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher> 
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace> 

        <idno type="VCDH">A7122</idno> 

        <!--
<availability> 
<p>Publicly accessible </p> 
<p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p> 
<p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p> 
</availability>
--> 
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2002">2002</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500238</idno>
      </publicationStmt> 
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt> 
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt> 

      <sourceDesc> 
        <biblFull> 
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: John Scott to Samuel Hunt, June 2, 1866</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county john scott to samuel hunt, june 2 1866</title>
            <author>John Scott</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt> 
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt> 
          <extent>4 pages</extent> 
          <publicationStmt> 
            <publisher/> 
            <pubPlace/> 
            <date value=""/> 
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: John Scott to Samuel Hunt, June 2, 1866, American Missionary Association Archives Collection, Microfilm 72, Alderman Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville</idno>
          </publicationStmt> 
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt> 
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt> 
        </biblFull> 
      </sourceDesc> 
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Alderman Library, University of Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc> 

    <profileDesc> 
      <creation>
        <date value="1866-06-02">1866-06-02</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage> 
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass> 
        <keywords> 
          <term>African Americans, Education, Church/Religious Activity, Women</term> 
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords> 
      </textClass> 
    </profileDesc> 

    <revisionDesc> 
      <change> 
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt> 
        <item/> 
      </change> 
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc> 
  </teiHeader> 

<text id="A7122T">
<front id="d2">
<div1 type="summary" id="d3">
<p>Scott announces the arrival of AMA teacher C. E. Dewey and comments on a native Virginian and "presiding Elder from the north" who "sympathizes with us in our work."  Scott contends that this Elder "advises me to write concerning the importance of your work in the valley above other places.  He says 'They have more energy and influence' in this valley than in any other part of Va. Even the whole South with which he is acquainted.'"  [Article attached to page 3 of letter reads:
For the "Valley Virginian." A Card of Thanks from the Colored People<lb/>
SIR:-- The members of the colored M. E. Church, through the columns of the Virginian would take occasion to thank the white citizens, of Staunton, for their valuable aid at a Fair recently held by them.<lb/>
	We would take occasion to inform the citizens of Staunton, that we have in our midst, one Emily Rodney, of Pennsylvania, of the Bethel Church, soliciting subscriptions under a false misrepresentation of facts, and would say, that if the white citizens feel disposed to further aid us in paying for our Church, they will please be careful who they pay money to, as we have been informed several gentlemen have contributed, thinking it was for the benefit of the M. E. Church, Colored, when it was intended for the Bethel Church.<lb/>  
	They regret to learn that an impression seems to exist among the citizens that the colored people wish to "draw out from among the whites," and in church and business matters, become independent of them; thus acknowledging little obligation to them.  We are sorry to hear that this doctrine is taught by some of our color from the North, who are endeavoring to form a sect, new to us, here, but so far as that is concerned we have no sympathy with them.  We do not desire this foolish independence, but are very thankful for sympathy and aid from the whites, and respectfully acknowledge our obligations.<lb/>
	Rev. E. Lawson, Pastor; James Scott, Local Preacher; Phillip Rosshell, Exhorter; Henry Davenport, Aaron Shoveler, Frances Overton, Phillip Ransome, Oscar Morris, Adison King, F. Parris, Thos. Campbell, William Benny, James Carter, John Harris, John Napper, Nelson Shelton and David Devenport.<lb/>
To Major A. M. Garber, Jr.,<lb/>
	Editor of the "Valley Virginian"} ]
</p> 
</div1> 
 
</front> 

<body id="d4">
<div1 type="letter" id="d5">
<head>
<name type="recipient">Rev Samuel Hunt</name> 
<name type="place">Staunton Va</name> 
</head>

<opener>
<dateline>
    <date value="1866-06-02">June 2<hi rend="super">nd</hi> 1866</date> 
</dateline> 
<salute>Dear Sir</salute> 
</opener> 

<p>Our work still goes on.  We have engaged a colored teacher to take Miss Deweys place.  She has attended my school thro the winter, is black, intelligent, a christian, and to my surprise governs well  I have thought of giving her a little over $2.00 per week as she boards herself  If I take some of the money received by the sale of books to pay her, will it be all right?</p>
	<p>There is a preacher and a presiding Elder here from the north (<del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>) from <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Conference, who sympathizes with us in our work.  The Elder is an old man, a native of Va well acquainted with the colored people in the Shenandoah Valley  He advises me to write concerning the importance of your work in the valley above other places.  He says "They have more <hi rend="underline">energy</hi> and influence" in this valley than in any other <unclear>part</unclear> of Va. Even the whole South with which he is acquainted"  They also have more refinement.  This arises from the fact that man of them have had better associations over those further South, and have not been over worked like some in the Cotton or sugar districts, besides<pb n="2"/> being better cared for by the Master, as they were <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> here for market south.  He says <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> this is the place to raise up colored teachers in the whole south.  He does not think the <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> can do as well this side of the Blue Ridge as they can east of it as the colored people here are all methodists</p>
	<p>The colored people have spoken to me about writing up a petition to you for us to return after vacation.  I am rather of the opinion that it will be best for all of us to go home, or away from here during vacation  There are a few of these poor heathen people who do not appreciate us or our work and it will be well to let them see what they can do without us and give those who do appreciate us a chance to practice and memorize our teachings, as well as to let white people see that our influence here has been good; as they will find none to keep order <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> street and elsewhere as we have done.</p>

<p>There is here a repres. Of the African Am E or the <hi rend="underline">Bethel</hi> church <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> makes us some trouble by dividing the people, and is said to prejudice her followers against our schools  She seems to have a sort of <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> for the whites.  Her influence here is not good <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> its relation to the interest of the freedmen as connected with the white citizens as will be seen from the following article clipped from a Staunton Newspaper</p><pb n="3"/>

<p>Whether this Mrs Rodney <hi rend="underline">intends</hi> any thing wrong or not I do not know but those who listen to her preaching are backward about coming to our Sunday School and even do not attend singing school but have formed one of the latter themselves  Poor Creatures!  They are the victims of <hi rend="underline">experiments</hi> and <hi rend="underline">different religious theories</hi> without number.  There are less than 5 preachers of the gospel here to a <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> of between 7 &amp;8 hundred; besides <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> white clergymen.  Our Sabbath school is now very like a northern one.  We have our book case containing a Library of 100 vol. Our Class, Books and <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Books and all the appertenances of a good Sunday School.  When I compare this condition to what it was when we came, and think of <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> confusedly trying to study an old spelling book as there I rejoice and thank God.</p>
	<p>We have received $66.67/100 by the sale of clothing, by the aid of which money the people have secured their Church and School-house<pb n="4"/> thus making a place for your future operation should you choose to continue to work here.  <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> is a very important step.  I paid the money <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> over by permission from Mr Whipple and you will please inform him what is the exact amount as he requested me to do.</p>
	<p>There must have been from $350 to $400 worth of clothing and the small amount which we sold did not prevent any of the needy from obtaining it as we only sold to those who were able to buy, and to prevent them taking it from the more needy as they would have tried to do had we given it all away.</p>
	<p>We have now on hand some 30 <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> dresses for girls well packed in tobacco for winter--to be left in care of the Office <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> the Bureau or mailed up and placed in the hands of the Colored Church to be kept [unclear] return, or delivered over to the "Colored Aid Scoeity" to be used at their discretion.</p>  
	<p>Have you anything to advise in the matter?  We shall sell no more.</p>
<p>Packages should now be addressed to<lb/> 
{Lt. Geo T. Cook Assistant Supt. Freedmens Bureau} as Mr Tukey is relieved</p>

<closer>
<salute>Very Respectfully</salute> 
<signed>John Scott</signed> 

<name type="place">61 John St</name> 
</closer> 
</div1> 
</body> 
</text> 
</TEI.2>