<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A7184"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]> 


<TEI.2 id="A7184"> 
<teiHeader type="migrated"> 

    <fileDesc> 
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Sarah H. Davison to E. P. Smith, March 1, 1869</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county sarah h davison to e p smith, march 1 1869</title>
        <author>Davison, Sarah H.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt> 
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp> 
          <name>Bart Elmore</name> 
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp> 
          <name>Bart Elmore</name> 
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt> 

      <extent>ca. 5.644 kilobytes </extent> 
      <publicationStmt> 
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher> 
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace> 

        <idno type="VCDH">A7184</idno> 

        <!--
<availability> 
<p>Publicly accessible </p> 
<p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p> 
<p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p> 
</availability>
--> 
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2002">2002</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500300</idno>
      </publicationStmt> 
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt> 
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt> 

      <sourceDesc> 
        <biblFull> 
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Sarah H. Davison to E. P. Smith, March 1, 1869</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county sarah h davison to e p smith, march 1 1869</title>
            <author>Sarah H. Davison</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt> 
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt> 
          <extent>3 pages</extent> 
          <publicationStmt> 
            <publisher/> 
            <pubPlace/> 
            <date value=""/> 
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Sarah H. Davison to E. P. Smith, March 1, 1869, American Missionary Association Archives Collection, Microfilm 72, Alderman Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville</idno>
          </publicationStmt> 
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt> 
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt> 
        </biblFull> 
      </sourceDesc> 
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Alderman Library, University of Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc> 

    <profileDesc> 
      <creation>
        <date value="1869-03-01">1869-03-01</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass> 
        <keywords> 
          <term>African Americans, Education, Women, Economy</term> 
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords> 
      </textClass> 
    </profileDesc> 

    <revisionDesc> 
      <change> 
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt> 
        <item/> 
      </change> 
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc> 
  </teiHeader> 

<text id="A7184T">
<front id="d2">
<div1 type="summary" id="d3">
<p>In her letter to E. P. Smith, Davison offers several poignant anecdotes about her students and their families, illuminating the bonds that connected AMA teachers to their students.</p> 
</div1> 
<div1 type="figure" id="d4">
<p>American Missionary Association letterhead</p> 
</div1> 

</front> 

<body id="d5">
<div1 type="letter" id="d6">
<head>
<name type="recipient">Rev E P Smith</name> 
<name type="place">Mission Home, Staunton Va</name> 
</head>

<opener>
<dateline>
    <date value="1869-03-01">Mar 1<hi rend="super">st</hi> , 1869</date> 
</dateline> 
<salute>Dear Sir</salute> 
</opener> 

<p>We have been much interested the past month in <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>wished</unclear>find out if there were any who did not attend my school.</p>
		<p>The people were much pleased to see us--One of my scholars, a little girl, was standing upon a hill near her house--We saw her before she saw us but as we drew near her she recognized us and we soon knew she did--She stood a minute looking at us--Then threw up her hands and shouted a welcome turned and ran off as fast as she could to tell her mother who were coming--Arriving at the house we found it to be one of the neatest we had seen among the<pb n="2"/> colored people--The Mother a most interesting colored person both in manner, and appearance so much like white that if she were seen north her color and skin would never be suspected.</p>
	<p>We made a visit to the home of a girl we had <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> from school--asking her why she had not been there she explained she had to keep her house for her father while her mother who is hired out was from home--She told us almost in tears she could not come to day school and her father would not allow her to attend night school--I have <unclear>a</unclear> five adult scholars which meet every afternoon at a neighbors house.  I asked her if she would like to meet with these and recite her lessons--She was much pleased with the plan and has not missed coming one day yet.</p><pb n="3"/>
	<p>Next we visited four houses in three of which were children who did not attend any school upon asking the mother the reason were told they could not afford to pay the ten cents per week for tuition we <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> them to send their children without pay--They thanked us--And the next week three of the children came.</p>
	<p>In another house we found the mother sick in bed--One of her boys attends our day school--but not always regular--The mother asked if we had not wondered why- we said we had--She informed us he sometimes did work for the store keepers in order to obtain money with which to pay the ten cents per week tuition; for his father had never given him a cent towards it.</p>


<closer>
<salute>Very Respectfully,</salute> 
<signed>S H Davison</signed> 

<name type="place">N. Y.</name> 
</closer> 
</div1> 
</body> 
</text> 
</TEI.2>