<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A7539"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A7539">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Mary Anna Sibert to David H. Evans,
                    November 28, 1867</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county mary anna sibert to david h evans, november 28 1867</title>
        <author>Sibert, Mary Anna</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Andrew Witmer</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andrew Witmer</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A7539</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502581</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Mary Anna Sibert to David H. Evans, November 28, 1867</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county mary anna sibert to david h evans, november 28 1867</title>
            <author>Mary Anna Sibert</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Mary Anna Sibert to David H.
                            Evans, November 28, 1867, Evans-Sibert Family Papers, Accession 27770,
                            Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1867-11-28">1867-11-28</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Women, Family</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2004-12-29">December 29, 2004.</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; changes made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A7539T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Sibert reports on some last-minute changes in her sister's wedding and declares
                    that Evans is the only man who will ever own her heart.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1867-11-28">November 28 / '67</date>
                        <name type="place">Mt. Solon, Va.</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Mr. D.H. Evans,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Your dear, &amp; twice welcome letter of Tuesday came safely. I was so
                    thankful to hear that you were well. If I had known last night that pa was going
                    to Staunton this morning I would have written to you by him. I thought of you so
                    often Sunday night during your lonely ride, &amp; did wish that I could have
                    been with you. I went off to myself just to think of you after you left. I love
                    to think of you always. How much I want to see you <orig reg="tonight">to
                    night</orig>. It will be such a long &amp; weary two weeks before you can
                    come again. I wish that important day was<pb n="2"/>already here so you could
                    come &amp; just to think I cannot see your dear face until 9 O'clock
                    &amp; then we must meet in the presence of others &amp; only shake hands
                    with no warmer greeting for two days I don't like to think of it. Ada &amp;
                    Hamie M'Fall are not going to wait on Rennie. she <abbr expan="received"
                    >rec'd</abbr> a letter from Cousin David <orig reg="today">to day</orig>. he
                    will bring a lady, &amp; gentleman with him you myself, &amp; those two
                    will be the only <orig reg="attendants">attendents</orig>. Pa objected to H.
                    M'Fall. I was sorry on Ada's account but it can't be helped now. I wrote to Ella
                    by pa this morning before D. Sibert's letter came &amp; told her Miss Link
                    was not coming so <hi rend="underline">brother</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">David</hi> wrote in his letter of Monday but now he writes
                    that he has asked another lady<pb n="3"/>&amp; so we can do nothing but let
                    them come. I objected to this last arrangement but it did no good for he had
                    already asked the lady. I only hope we all shall have a happy time. Cousin David
                    wants us all to spend Wednesday night in Bridgewater as their Minister will
                    preach that night a special sermon for the Groom, &amp; his attendants so he
                    wants us all to go to church can you stay? I hope you can if you do not, I will
                    come home with you, for I would not care to stay there without you were with me.
                    The two Miss <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> were married this morning. Several other lady
                    friends of mine are to be married in a few days. I hope they will all be very
                    happy &amp; so they can be if they <hi rend="underline">will</hi>. I wish I
                    was with you now<pb n="4"/>I would be happy too. Mr. Estell called in twice this
                    week but I was too busy to see him. you see he is still in Mt. Solon he has
                    heard that it is Rennie who is to be married, &amp; not Miss Mollie. I do
                    not care about seeing him any more Rennie sends thanks for the <orig
                        reg="buttons">buttens</orig>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> they were the kind she wanted. I enclose <unclear>25</unclear>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> It will be so long so long <unclear>befor</unclear> can come.
                    sometimes <unclear>I</unclear> feel like I can't wait. I love you so truly
                    &amp; so devotedly that I want to have you near me or I am not happy
                    &amp; contented my only &amp; greatest joy &amp; <orig
                        reg="pleasure">pleasur</orig> is to be with you who I love with all the
                    strength &amp; devotion of my heart &amp; entire nature. Yes I do indeed
                    love you &amp; only you. no man in all this world can ever take my heart
                    &amp; all of its deep &amp; fervent love from you. I have yours <del
                        hand="h1"/> they are truly yours my heart, &amp; its love shall never
                    belong to any but you while I have life, unless you yourself refuse to have them
                    &amp; even then I will still love you. Write to me soon I love to read your
                    dear true letters I read them over more <orig reg="than">then</orig>
                    <hi rend="underline">3 or 4 time</hi>s I read them Every day till hear from you
                    again, or see you. I do want to see your darling face so much God bless you my
                    heart's best, &amp; only love. Goodnight. I send love &amp; a kiss to
                    you. I love you with all my heart.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours,</salute>
                    <signed>Mollie Sibert</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">Ma, Rennie, &amp; all send love to you Write soon I
                        love you Oh! so truly</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
