<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A7532"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A7532">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Mary Anna Sibert to David H. Evans,
                    October 28, 1867</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county mary anna sibert to david h evans, october 28 1867</title>
        <author>Sibert, Mary Anna</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Andrew Witmer</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andrew Witmer</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A7532</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502574</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Mary Anna Sibert to David H. Evans, October 28, 1867</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county mary anna sibert to david h evans, october 28 1867</title>
            <author>Mary Anna Sibert</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Mary Anna Sibert to David H.
                            Evans, October 28, 1867, Evans-Sibert Family Papers, Accession 27770,
                            Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1867-10-28">1867-10-28</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Women, Church/Religious Activity</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2004-12-29">December 29, 2004.</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; changes made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A7532T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Sibert apologizes profusely for a misunderstanding between her and Evans which
                    has caused her a great deal of pain. She offers to provide a full explanation
                    when he next visits.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1867-10-28">October 28 1867</date>
                        <name type="place">Mt. Solon, Va.</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Mr D.H. Evans</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I have never <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> Good bye feeling as unhappy as I did yesterday
                    Evening because I know you were leaving <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> with wrong thoughts
                    against me regarding our proposed ride. If you could have read my heart,
                    &amp; known my disappointment you would only have been pleased, &amp;
                    not disappointed, nor would you have blamed me had I told you why I did not go
                    then. It was not that I thought people would say <orig reg="anything">any
                    thing</orig>, for what could they say about me riding with <hi rend="underline"
                        >you</hi> nothing at all &amp; who's business would it have been but
                    yours &amp; mine? I am one who does not care what the world says, or persons
                    think of what I do when I know I am right <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> I know it would have
                    been right for <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> horse back jaunt with <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> but the
                    holy Sabbath, but <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> reason I did not go. I will tell you <del
                        hand="h1"/> the truth why I did not, when you come Saturday a week,
                    &amp; nothing but the truth then you will say you did me wrong by thinking
                        as<pb n="2"/>you did I knew just what you would say about it that was why I
                    cried it grieved my very heart to have you misjudge me when I <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    it &amp; you will say so when I tell you <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> the world was
                    against you knowing <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> do it would not keep me from giving <del
                        hand="h1"/>, or from loving you, no I would only love you the more,
                    &amp; go with you the oftener if that was the case, but it is not, for all
                    speak highly of you who know you. I would neither Thank, nor respect the person
                    (if my own dear father) who would come to me, &amp; say one word of
                    unkindness against you, I could never esteem them again, nor would I have them
                    for a friend, that is my way of doing for those I love I don't like any one who
                    says any thing about them that is not just. If I could see your heart, &amp;
                    read there that you truly believe <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> was not what you said that
                    kept me <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> riding, it would lift such a heavy <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> my
                    heart. I would write you why I <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> but I would rather tell you so I
                    could <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> you, &amp; have your answer from your mouth you will
                    laugh &amp; call me <hi rend="underline">vain</hi>. Ma told me to tell you
                    that when you come she will tell you her self<pb n="3"/>&amp; so will I, it
                    will not make you angry for you will then know why I said it was for your own
                    dear sake that I did not <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> I loved you so truly. This <del
                        hand="h1"/> talk to you now but I will <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> go <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    when you arrive, &amp; will tell you <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> did not go to church
                    whilst <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> &amp; that was for your sake too, as you shall hear
                    I know you will not love me less but love me more <orig reg="than">then</orig>
                    Ever. bless Ma she has been talking about you all day, says, she is afraid you
                    are in your store with no fire to warm you this cold damp day. Oh! how much I
                    would love to be with you <orig reg="today">to day</orig> I feel so lonely,
                    &amp; unhappy. If I could see you now I would tell you all but I must wait
                    til you come which will seem ages to me two weeks Ma says you must come then, if
                    you don't come in a buggy just so you come, if you come in a conveyance of your
                    own we will if we <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> go to Mossy Creek church. I will not <del
                        hand="h1"/> then indeed I will not I love <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> you &amp; I
                    do not go with any gentlemen <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> not since I loved you. I would
                        <unclear>no</unclear><del rend="none" hand="h1"/> you <hi rend="underline">in</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">an</hi>y <hi rend="underline">thin</hi>g because I love you
                    too well for that &amp; some day if we live you will see &amp; know that
                    I have not. I could not rest for thinking of what<pb n="4"/>you said. I went off
                    to <orig reg="myself">my self</orig> to cry &amp; grieve after you left <del
                        hand="h1"/> not told you the truth when you <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> never do so
                    again but will <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> will understand &amp;
                        <unclear>no</unclear><del rend="none" hand="h1"/> I was so anxious to put <del hand="h1"
                    /> from you in the subject that <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> Friday's mail to <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <hi rend="underline">Eve</hi>ry <hi rend="underline">thin</hi>g for I am <hi
                        rend="underline">tru</hi>e you <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> f<hi rend="underline"
                    >ea</hi>r to love &amp; t<hi rend="underline">rus</hi>t me, so long as <del
                        hand="h1"/> God's help. I shall never <hi rend="underline">deceive</hi> you
                    who I love above all others, nor will I tell you an <hi rend="underline"
                    >untrut</hi>h any time, or about any thing I <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> you too devotedly
                    for that. Ma says the exercise you have been taking in your rides down here has
                    done a great deal to improve your health, &amp; appearance. I think so my
                    self. come often then I am so p<hi rend="underline">roud</hi> of you. Oh! how I
                    do <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> you. You are all all I want you to be but a true <del
                        hand="h1"/> &amp; I will be all you would wish me to be. I will not do
                    &amp; be what is not pleasant to you in my manners or dress. I have tried
                    your patience <unclear>long</unclear> enough in many ways. I could see that <del
                        hand="h1"/> so often have I done so, &amp; you <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    complained. I do think you are the best <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> the world, you
                    &amp; my dear papa <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> I will do so no more, but will be <del
                        hand="h1"/> &amp; love to see a true lady be in Every respect <del
                        hand="h1"/> you will write to me by tomorrow's mail I shall be so <del
                        hand="h1"/> said <unclear>if</unclear>
                    <unclear>you</unclear> do not. Oh! love me will you? my heart aches so painfully
                    when I think I have grieved you or done <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig>
                    you don't like. Ma, Rennie, &amp; Ada send love Write to me soon. C<hi
                        rend="underline">ome down</hi> Saturday if you live I will go with you <orig
                        reg="anywhere">any where</orig> in this world for I love you. I send a
                    loving kiss to you <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> bless you is the prayer of</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours</salute>
                    <signed>Mollie Sibert</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">Please do not <hi rend="underline">throw</hi> your <hi
                            rend="underline">head</hi>
                        <hi rend="underline">back</hi> when you read this letter-- for I have
                        written the truthful language of my heart I mean all I have said I am not
                        going to Rockbridge tell Ella, all send love <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> to her
                        &amp; children. I had <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> today</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
