<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A7549"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A7549">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Mary Anna Sibert to David H. Evans,
                    February 6, 1868</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county mary anna sibert to david h evans, february 6 1868</title>
        <author>Sibert, Mary Anna</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Andrew Witmer</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andrew Witmer</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A7549</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502591</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Mary Anna Sibert to David H. Evans, February 6, 1868</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county mary anna sibert to david h evans, february 6 1868</title>
            <author>Mary Anna Sibert</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Mary Anna Sibert to David H.
                            Evans, February 6, 1868, Evans-Sibert Family Papers, Accession 27770,
                            Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1868-02-06">1868-02-06</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Women, Family, Church/Religious Activity</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2004-12-30">December 30, 2004.</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; changes made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A7549T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Sibert reports on family matters and discusses the nature of her love for
                Evans.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1868-02-06">Feb. 6 1868</date>
                        <name type="place">Mt Solon, Va.</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear David</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Here I am all alone with the delightful pleasure of answering your dear &amp;
                    truly welcome letter of Tuesday I was so glad &amp; thankful to get it
                    &amp; to hear that you were well. Every line written by your dear hand is
                    sacred, &amp; valued I wish from my heart that you were here this Evening
                    for it has been such a long time since you were with me. I looked for you last
                    Saturday. I thought you would certainly come, &amp; stay all week I did want
                    you to come so much but your letter Explained it all why you could not come
                    then. I am so glad you are coming Saturday if you live I hope the day will be as
                    bright &amp; pleasant as this has been then you will have a nice ride. You
                    can't imagine how much pleasure it gave me to have you say you never doubted my
                    affection for you. it is such a relief to me to know that you safely trust
                    &amp; believe in my love, for I do so entirely give you my heart with all
                    its affection that were a<pb n="2"/>thought to enter my mind that you for one
                    moment doubted me I should be very unhappy. Then never think that I do not love
                    you, &amp; nothing but a wish from you can Ever change my devotion,
                    &amp; were you even to wish that I should cease to love or think of you I
                    could not obey you, but would love you to my dying day Even without hope. it is
                    far better suited to my nature to love &amp; remember <orig reg="than"
                    >then</orig> to hate, &amp; forget those once dear to me. You must never ask
                    me not to love you for I do firmly <orig reg="believe">beleive</orig> that if
                    you should cease to love me &amp; would not want my love that my heart would
                    break, &amp; I would not wish to live without your dear &amp; most
                    precious love for it is the brightest sweetest &amp; best beloved joy of my
                    life to feel sure of your undivided &amp; entire affection. I never want to
                    think that you have Ever loved <orig reg="anyone">any one</orig> but me nor that
                    you ever will love another while I live. it is my nature to be selfish in my
                    love I can't help it either. try as I may to be more generous I can't that is
                    just the truth. in very<pb n="3"/>truth I can't bear to think that <orig
                        reg="anyone">any one</orig> should fill your heart &amp; thoughts but
                        <orig reg="myself">my self</orig>. I know no one does for your word is law
                    to me I believe the slightest word you ever utter for I know that you are
                    sincere to me in all things you say or do, &amp; it would be both unkind
                    &amp; cruel of me to doubt, or not to believe you since you have always been
                    so truthful, &amp; frank.</p>

                <p>Ma, &amp; I <abbr expan="received">rec'd</abbr> letters from Rennie <orig
                        reg="today">to day</orig> she &amp; her husband were well. Rennie write
                    that she loves him more &amp; more every day of her life. says he is such a
                    good husband. I am truly thankful that they are so happy &amp; they can
                    always be so if they will. Ma got a letter from dear pa Tuesday. we are still
                    lonely without him Rennie wants to know when I am coming to stay with her. I
                    don't know indeed when I can go, bless her heart I must go some time before
                    long. Hamie has come in to intrude upon my quiet with his studies for tomorrow.
                    We had a great time at dinner he wanted to make me read Rennie's letter out to
                    him &amp; I wanted him to read it to himself. for awhile I refused<pb n="4"
                    />but at last I read it <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> rest Oh! I do want to see you. I can't
                    wait with any patience for <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> long days to pass away before you
                    can come. it is so long long since you bid me <orig reg="Goodbye">Goodby</orig>.
                    I shall be so glad, thankful &amp; happy to have you here again to look at
                    you, &amp; to hear you talk, to see you throw back your dear curly head
                    &amp; shake your foot, but I don't like to see you look grave, &amp;
                    unhappy, for then I think that I have done something to displease you, &amp;
                    that I don't want to do, for I do love to add to your happiness. I never wish to
                    give you one <orig reg="moment's">moments</orig> pain, or to displease you about
                        <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig>. I love you more &amp; more Every
                    day of my life with all my heart, strength, mind &amp; thoughts I <hi
                        rend="underline">lov</hi>e <hi rend="underline">you</hi> &amp; you only,
                    &amp; Ever shall It seems that I can't find words enough to tell you how
                    dearly I love you. Come Saturday if you live I long so much for you to come I
                    will show you then how happy I am to have you with me again. I hope God will let
                    you come to one He knows loves you more <orig reg="than">then</orig> her own
                    life. I do hope the fire will be burning brightly this time when you come. I
                    will see that it is warm &amp; sweet for you so you can feel happy &amp;
                    at home. All send love. I enclose love &amp; a kiss to you. God bless you
                    forever. come Saturday. I love you Oh! so fondly Goodnight </p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours</salute>
                    <signed>Mollie Sibert</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
