<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A7615"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A7615">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch to
                    Hester J. Nadenbousch, January 27, 1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county john quincy adams nadenbousch to hester j nadenbousch, january 27 1864</title>
        <author>Nadenbousch, John Quincy Adams</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A7615</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502616</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch to Hester J.
                            Nadenbousch, January 27, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county john quincy adams nadenbousch to hester j nadenbousch, january 27 1864</title>
            <author>John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch to
                            Hester J. Nadenbousch, January 27, 1864, J.Q.A. Nadenbousch Letters,
                            Eleanor S. Brockenbrough Library, The Museum of the Confederacy,
                            Richmond, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Museum of the Confederacy, Richmond Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-01-27">1864-01-27</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Home Front, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-06">June, 2005</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Kid W.</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A7615T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Nadenbousch assures his wife he is not crazy, and promises to stop requesting
                    anything besides the presence of his family. He reports that the hotel is open.
                    He also discusses financial issues and sends messages to his children.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-01-27"><abbr expan="January">Jan</abbr> 27/64</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Hester</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Having an <orig reg="opportunity">oppertunity</orig> I again write you but have
                    not much to say I am well in health but my afflictions bother me considerable,
                    but do as well as can expect</p>

                <p>I received your reply to my request to purchase some articles &amp;c but am
                    not in the condition you think (Crazy) but if should be so unfortunate I have
                    the Asylum close at hand and will try &amp; take advantage of its
                    convenience</p>

                <p>We have the house open at last. we have a fine sum of travelling customs house
                    full every night keep it in good order receipts $1000<hi rend="super">
                        <hi rend="underline">00</hi>
                    </hi> per day everything going on <orig reg="smooth">smoothe</orig>. We have all
                    things fixed in running order need some linnens blankets comforts &amp;
                    groceries such as coffee &amp; tea But I <orig reg="shall not">shant</orig>
                    ask you to send me anything more except a few articles I need at once viz a
                    young lady of about 36 years old slender light hair fair complexion &amp;
                    blue eyes &amp; 4 little <unclear>flax</unclear> head fellows one boy
                    &amp; three girls I desire these goods &amp; chattels sent through to me
                    at once with their clothes &amp; bedding</p>

                <p>If I had you all here with me I would be much better satisfied &amp; think
                    you would be too we get plenty of supplies but at quite high prices rates $15 pr
                    day <orig reg="Can't">Cant</orig> you manage some way to move out if it <del
                        hand="h1">the</del> be at the risk of our property no matter I think we can
                    make something here but if come bring all<pb n="2"/> kinds of clothing you may
                    need as it is scarce &amp; high just here I think I will be out of the
                    service between this &amp; spring &amp; can be with you constantly My
                    impression is that we will do a good business here now I am anxious to make some
                    money here as we have lost so much since the war Porters <orig
                        reg="brother-in-law">brother inlaw</orig> wants the Porter property. I think
                    I will let him have it it has not been paid for &amp; he can take it at
                        $900<hi rend="super">
                        <hi rend="underline">00</hi>
                    </hi> lift the notes &amp; pay you the ballance if I do conclude to let him
                    have it I will make deed <orig reg="here">he<add hand="h1" place="inline"
                        >re</add>ar</orig> &amp; you can acknowledge it there before Notary
                    public but do nothing in the matter unless I give him the papers.</p>

                <p>I have much to say to you but cannot say it on paper but hope soon to see you. I
                    have just got 2 Shirts 1 <abbr expan="per">pr</abbr> shoes 2 <abbr expan="per"
                        >pr</abbr> socks &amp; 1 <abbr expan="per">pr</abbr> drawers which will
                    be a great benefit to me now</p>

                <p>If I only could have gotten some collars I would have been glad. Do try &amp;
                    write me fully all about private matters I am so anxious to hear from you tell
                    me how the little fellows get along and all domestic matters. I learn the mill
                    has been released</p>

                <p>from what I learn John must be about frightened to death He seems quite anxious
                    about the property &amp;c just say to him he need not fear about any money I
                    may owe him. if all we have there is lost I hope still to have enough here to
                    pay him &amp; all I owe<pb n="3"/> any person &amp; then keep my family
                    well These chicken hearted people <orig reg="won't">won<hi rend="super">
                            <hi rend="underline">t</hi>
                        </hi></orig> do. These times persons must have nerve</p>

                <p>I hope that all these croakers will in the end be disappointed They seem to
                    deprecate my position losses risks &amp;c &amp;c but I hope to come out
                    right in the end You keep perfectly calm <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> grieve or
                    be concerned about property. This is but dross. My greatest ambition now is to
                    be with you all I have written to you so often on this subject that I have but
                    little else to add but hope it will not be long until we meet</p>

                <p>Do the best you can with the property whilst there &amp; if leave put it in
                    the hands of some good person</p>

                <p>Freddy I hope you are a good boy &amp; attending to businiess for <hi
                        rend="underline">ma</hi> going to school &amp; taking care of your
                    little sisters. <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> run about with bad boys nor ride
                    strange horses this is dangerous you keep close about home and be a good boy</p>

                <p>Sissy, Lila &amp; Jinnie you be good girls obey your <hi rend="underline"
                    >ma</hi> stay about home &amp; attend school help your ma all you can</p>

                <p>My love to Miss Jane Kiss her for me tell her I will pay her back when I see her</p>

                <p>Remember me to Moses, Henry, Mary H Aunt &amp; Uncle Aunt P- &amp; Lute
                    &amp; all others</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours ever</salute>
                    <signed/>
                    <seg type="postscript">write</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
