<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A7621"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A7621">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch to
                    Hester J. Nadenbousch, March 16, 1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county john quincy adams nadenbousch to hester j nadenbousch, march 16 1864</title>
        <author>Nadenbousch, John Quincy Adams</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A7621</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502622</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch to Hester J.
                            Nadenbousch, March 16, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county john quincy adams nadenbousch to hester j nadenbousch, march 16 1864</title>
            <author>John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch to
                            Hester J. Nadenbousch, March 16, 1864, J.Q.A. Nadenbousch Letters,
                            Eleanor S. Brockenbrough Library, The Museum of the Confederacy,
                            Richmond, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Museum of the Confederacy, Richmond Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-03-16">1864-03-16</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Home Front, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-06">June, 2005</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Kid W.</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A7621T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Nadenbousch writes his wife thanking her for the pictures of the family she sent.
                    He sends messages for all the children, and instructions on how to care for
                    them. He worries about his wife's "delicate" appearance, and complains of his
                    loneliness. He also discusses his pending resignation and news about friends and
                    family.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-03-16">March 16/64</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Hester</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>The pictures came to hand which done me almost as much good as if I had seen you
                    all <hi rend="underline">except you</hi> Some of the pictures are good some not
                    so good but they all suit me. I would have mine taken &amp; sent down if
                    could get it done, but there is no operator here now but may be again, when I
                    will attend to it</p>

                <p>I am glad to see you all look so well &amp; getting along so well. <hi
                        rend="underline">I had expected to see you much fleshier &amp; only to
                        get a half view picture</hi>. You state that Freddy is complaining. See the
                    teacher and request him not to keep him too closely confined to his book
                    &amp; you give him some recreation from school <hi rend="underline">see to
                        this</hi> as too close confinement to studies now might ruin his health for
                    life &amp; alike with remainder of the children See to them as much
                        depend<hi rend="super">s</hi> upon their early training Try &amp; keep
                    them from running the streets &amp; keep out of bad company talk mildly and
                    seriously to them often which will do much more good than correcting them How I
                    would like to have you all here with me, but if it <orig reg="can't">cant</orig>
                    be done now I will have to wait until it can, let the suffering be what it may.
                    I have just got some 4 shirts &amp; 6 collars which come in like a dram in
                    the morning I am now<pb n="2"/> quite well supplied in that way for some time to
                    come I am running short of drawers if I could get hold of 2 or 4 pair of nice
                    drilled cotton I would like it.</p>

                <p>My resignation is still unaccepted but I will no doubt get out of the field. the
                        <abbr expan="Secretary of War">Secty-war</abbr> has shown me great courtesy
                    in the matter <add hand="h1" place="inline">as</add> also all other officers
                    through whose hand<hi rend="super">s</hi> the papers have passed. I have seen a
                    number of our citizens recently &amp; hear from you generally I make it a
                    rule to write by almost every <orig reg="opportunity">oppertunity</orig> whether
                    it goes through or not I think you might write me often &amp; fully</p>

                <p>remember me kindly to all friends but I forgot Miss Jane &amp; the children.
                    kiss Miss Jane as usual for me &amp; tell her that she can pay me double
                    when she sees me I will try &amp; select her a nice beau. The people here
                    (residents) are kind of a scotch Irish population &amp; not desirable but
                    will make the best selection can kiss the children all round for me tell Freddy
                    he grows up a perfect little man and to act as he looks. be kind &amp;
                    corteous to all and to manage things right at home</p>

                <p>Sissy she getting to be quite an amiable little lady &amp; I learn unusualy
                    industrious &amp; does good service in the domestic circle Lily she grows up
                    as cute &amp;<pb n="3"/>
                    <unclear>cunning</unclear> as ever a perfect coquet eye and manner be a good
                    girl &amp; help Ma- and attend to Jinny Little Jinny grows up as fat as a
                    possom and looks as saucy as if fed on Crout &amp; <orig reg="hominy"
                    >homany</orig>. And as to yourself you look well in the face but form much more
                    delicate than I expected to see Come up &amp; see us and get some of our
                    good eatings &amp; I think you will improve (in short you all seem to be
                    doing quite well.) but I have a hard time here blundering along <add hand="h1"
                        place="inline">solitary</add> &amp; alone care for <orig reg="nobody">no
                        body</orig> &amp; no body caring for me but so wags the wide world</p>

                <p>Ask Cousin Mary if she thinks enough of me to write to me and if <orig
                        reg="don't">dont</orig> to say so but I suppose she is so strong union that
                    she could not flourish a pen to a Rebel but she will change &amp; think
                    better of that &amp; will marry one yet unless old B- Henrys up</p>

                <p>So my love to all good night</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours ever</salute>
                    <signed/>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
