<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A7635"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A7635">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch to
                    Hester J. Nadenbousch, August 10, 1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county john quincy adams nadenbousch to hester j nadenbousch, august 10 1864</title>
        <author>Nadenbousch, John Quincy Adams</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A7635</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502636</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch to Hester J.
                            Nadenbousch, August 10, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county john quincy adams nadenbousch to hester j nadenbousch, august 10 1864</title>
            <author>John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>6 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch to
                            Hester J. Nadenbousch, August 10, 1864, J.Q.A. Nadenbousch Letters,
                            Eleanor S. Brockenbrough Library, The Museum of the Confederacy,
                            Richmond, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Museum of the Confederacy, Richmond Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-08-10">1864-08-10</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>African Americans, Family, Home Front, Patriotsim, Slavery, Troop
                        Movement, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-06">June, 2005</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Kid W.</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A7635T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Nadenbousch writes his wife Hester who is despondent over being left alone and
                    without domestic help. He cannot come home and stay because he refuses to take
                    an oath of loyalty to the Federal government and fears arrest. Instead, he has
                    hired an Irish servant girl for Hester, and will send his slave Louise if that
                    does not work out. He discusses moving Hester and the family to Staunton as a
                    third option, even if it means loss of property to the Federals. He cannot get
                    out of Staunton to visit home because of the shifting battle lines. Nadenbousch
                    also discusses financial matters.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-08-10"><abbr expan="August">Aug</abbr> 10/64</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Wife</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I received your letter by M<hi rend="super">
                        <hi rend="underline">r</hi>
                    </hi> H- also the money you sent me. I notice all you say and am sorry to see
                    you in such a <orig reg="desponding">disponding</orig>
                    <orig reg="mood">moode</orig>, though <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> see how you
                    can be otherwise being left alone &amp; have no help &amp;c, but we must
                    hope for better times soon. I think the tables are about being turned and we may
                    be able to be constantly together.</p>

                <p>I have set several times to start down since I came back but it seems that about
                    the time I have all arranged to leave our forces fall back from Martinsburg and
                    when they advance again we <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> get the reliable word
                    until about the time they start back I had set tomorrow again to start<pb n="2"
                    /> down but <orig reg="can't">cant</orig> get a buggy until friday &amp;
                    again we learn that our Army have fallen back to Millcreek so I will have again
                    to put off starting until I can learn that the way is open, for if I <orig
                        reg="can't">can<hi rend="super">
                            <hi rend="underline">t</hi>
                        </hi></orig> get home I care nothing about being in that neighborhood but
                    from what we learn here I think the way will soon be open and kept clear for
                    sometime and <del hand="h1">get</del> give me a fair chance it is a hard tramp
                    to make &amp; to be foiled when most there it is too hard</p>

                <p>I have found a little <orig reg="Irish">irish</orig> girl who wants a home. she
                    was a chamber maid in this Hotel before we got it and bore a very good name the
                    proprietor kept her in his family she agrees to go and live with you and make
                    that her home. I pay<pb n="3"/> her fair down and pay her $5 <abbr expan="per"
                        >pr</abbr> month. I have told her what the work will be (house work) you
                    take her and put her to work at this bargain. you put her in a room to herself
                    to lodge on the porch or at the head of the stairs and not to room with you all.
                    I think she is honest &amp; trusty &amp; will suit you well <orig
                        reg="don't">dont</orig> hesitate to put her at anything you have to do, and
                        <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> make too free with her as it might spoil her
                        <add hand="h1" place="inline">she sews well</add> get some one to cut your
                    wood get M<hi rend="super">r</hi> Staub to get you some one <orig reg="don't"
                        >dont</orig> think of getting <add hand="h1" place="inline">along</add> the
                    way you have been doing try this girl &amp; if you <orig reg="can't"
                    >cant</orig> make her suit, I will send you Louise &amp; run the chances of
                    loosing her as you shall not be put <orig reg="to">too</orig> so much for
                    assistance</p>

                <p>Or if upon reflection you would <pb n="4"/> prefer coming out here just write me
                    at once &amp; I will have you brought out at once and let the property take
                    chances, as I would much prefer having you all here comfortable and loose the
                    property to having you grabbing your way along as you write me We are still
                    doing considerable business here I have been offering my interest here for sale
                    and rent we could sell now for about $175,000<hi rend="super">
                        <hi rend="underline">00</hi>
                    </hi> in <abbr expan="Confederate">Confed<hi rend="super">
                            <hi rend="underline">t</hi>
                        </hi></abbr> funds but then the query is what to do with the money now
                    &amp; this is not the worth of the property we are now asking $300,000<hi
                        rend="super">
                        <hi rend="underline">00</hi>
                    </hi> and think we can get 2 at most anytime but we must make this pay as much
                    as possible. I want at least to be even when this war is over &amp; wish to
                    be something ahead</p>

                <p>If I were to stay at home as you intimate I think that I would be arrested and
                    required to take the <hi rend="underline">Oath</hi> or be sent off and
                    imprisoned during the war. the <hi rend="underline">oath</hi> I <orig
                        reg="won't">wont</orig> take and and of course to be imprisoned would
                    seperate me from you and yet I would not have my liberties or any chance to make
                    something for you in future so of the two it is [section cut off]<pb n="5"/> me
                    to be here and make <orig reg="something">somthing</orig> for us. My inclination
                    of course it to be with you constantly as my course up to the beginning of the
                    war will show <add hand="h1" place="inline">scarcely</add> ever staying from
                    home over night &amp;c &amp;c-</p>

                <p>If you prefer coming out here <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> hesitate to say so
                    &amp; you shall come &amp; I will make you as comfortable as I possibly
                    can in Dixie</p>

                <p>I have got hold of $20 more green backs which I send you. apply it as you chose.
                    it is quite scarce here &amp; hard to get hold of, but I will still try
                    &amp; get some &amp; will send you and as you have the chance get us
                    such things as <del hand="h1">we</del> we may need</p>

                <p>I will come down as soon as I can learn positively the way is clear to
                    Martinsburg. I learn that Jacob Thomas has gone to the Yankees that is heavy
                    work I would rather cut my throat that to be so treacherous<pb n="6"/> and heap
                    up such a stigma on my family but these are strange times, hard to <orig
                        reg="fathom">fathem</orig> depths</p>

                <p>Tell moses I will try &amp; do the very best I can <del hand="h1">for</del>
                    with his &amp; Wilsons fund<hi rend="super">s</hi> but have not as yet
                    determine what is best to do with it.</p>

                <p>You try &amp; keep this girl &amp; if you come out &amp; she wishes
                    to come along bring her out also. I have no directions to give about our
                    business there as all seems to be conducted as well as I could direct it from
                    here</p>

                <p>Take good care of yourselves keep plenty of every thing on hand If smallpox there
                    is too dangerous there move from the house out to the mill with Henry</p>

                <p>I will be down as soon as can Write soon God bless you all</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours ever</salute>
                    <signed><abbr expan="John Quincy Adams">J Q A</abbr> Nadenbousch</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
