<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A7633"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A7633">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Freddy Nadenbousch to Hester J.
                    Nadenbousch, August 8, 1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county freddy nadenbousch to hester j nadenbousch, august 8 1864</title>
        <author>Nadenbousch, Freddy</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A7633</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502634</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Freddy Nadenbousch to Hester J. Nadenbousch, August
                            8, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county freddy nadenbousch to hester j nadenbousch, august 8 1864</title>
            <author>Freddy Nadenbousch</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Freddy Nadenbousch to Hester J.
                            Nadenbousch, August 8, 1864, J.Q.A. Nadenbousch Letters, Eleanor S.
                            Brockenbrough Library, The Museum of the Confederacy, Richmond,
                        Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Museum of the Confederacy, Richmond Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-08-08">1864-08-08</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>African Americans, Family, Home Front, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-06">June, 2005</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Kid W.</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A7633T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Freddy writes his mother and describes the long trip to Staunton, the death of
                    Henry, and his activities at the hotel. He sends messages for his sisters and
                    friends at home.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-08-08">August 8/64</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Ma-</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>supposing that you and little sisters will be glad to hear from us- I take my
                    seat for the purpose of writing you. we are here and we had a long troublesome
                    Journey up the Valley in the hot sun we laid by during the heat of the day and
                    drove late at night and camping out each night we eat our snack in the ambulance
                    &amp; slept in it &amp; had quite a good time not withstanding the
                    oppressive heat well we are now here- on our arrival we found poor Hen quite ill
                    indeed but he knew us and was glad to see us our arrival seemed to improve him
                        <pb n="2"/> but later got worse and in a few days he died poor fellow he is
                    now gone to his long home. the doctors and all did all they could for him but to
                    no purpose his race was run I hope the good man has taken him home to himself. I
                    am quite <orig reg="well">will</orig> pleased here. This is a fine large nice
                    house and I have good <add hand="h1" place="inline">a</add> time I some <add
                        hand="h1" place="inline">times</add> ride out for the cows &amp; take
                    the black boy george on behind me. He generally walks &amp; brings the cows
                    but is glad when I go with him. We have two cows &amp; buy some of our milk.
                        <orig reg="tell">till</orig> Jinnie we have two pretty little calves here
                    and a lot of nice hogs and a nice large bay horse <pb n="3"/> And the market
                        <add hand="h1" place="inline">man</add> drives him in his wagon mostly I
                    wish so much that you <orig reg="were">wire</orig>
                    <add hand="h1" place="inline">all</add> here with us Pa talks so much about you
                    all and wishing you were all here and I think he may yet Move you up if <hi
                        rend="underline">ma</hi> will come. this town is not as large as martinsburg
                    and lays in a hollow. I am quite <orig reg="well">will</orig> pleased here Pa
                    &amp; I <orig reg="went">wint</orig> to church last Sunday. We have a great
                    many <orig reg="visitors">viseters</orig> here daily always coming and going. Pa
                    thinks of going Down if can get off may go in a day or two give my love to Miss
                    Mary &amp; Jane and all of our kin Pa Joins me in <orig reg="sending"
                        >sinding</orig> much <pb n="4"/> love to you all if Pa comes down I will be
                    along I got my shoes and much olblige the remnant of our <orig reg="things"
                        >thinge</orig> have come. We lost the tea &amp; Some sugar and coffee
                    and all of the things in the barrels tell Mary Ella &amp; lily to take care
                    of my pigeons and rover tell Wiltre Diffinderfer that we sold old dove and
                    little Jeff tell Will ramer that I am trying to get a pair of pigeons for him
                    tell Miss Jane that I wish she <add hand="h1" place="inline">was</add> up here
                    to make my clothes I write this in the dining room the tables are crowded with
                    ladies &amp; gentlemen they are about done and I must close and get my <orig
                        reg="supper">super</orig> doctor Mchesney desires to be remembered by you</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>No more but remain your affectionate son</salute>
                    <signed>J. <abbr expan="Frederick">F.</abbr> Nadenbousch</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
