<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A8004"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A8004">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Millard Fillmore to Alexander H. H.
                    Stuart, July 5, 1848</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county millard fillmore to alexander h h stuart, july 5 1848</title>
        <author>Fillmore, Millard</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andrew J. Torget</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">6</num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A8004</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502656</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Millard Fillmore to Alexander H. H. Stuart, July 5,
                            1848</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county millard fillmore to alexander h h stuart, july 5 1848</title>
            <author>Millard Fillmore</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Millard Fillmore to Alexander H.
                            H. Stuart, 5 July 1848, Papers of Alexander H. H. Stuart and the Related
                            Stuart and Baldwin Families, 1776-1878, Accession #228-a, Box 2, Special
                            Collections Department, University of Virginia Library, Charlottesville,
                            Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1848-07-05">1848-07-05</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Slavery, Race Relations, Abolition, National Government</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A8004T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Fillmore denies being associated with abolitionism or being unfriendly to the
                    South. He denies he ever held "any desire" to "interfere with the rights or what
                    is termed the property of citizens of other States."</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1848-07-05">July 5, 1848</date>
                        <name type="place">Albany</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Sir</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I have yours of the 27th ult. saying that I am charged in Virginia with being an
                    abolitionist and unfriendly to the South, and requesting me to refer you to some
                    documents giving my sentiments on the subject. I have written books and papers
                    here connected with my congressional life, and if I had I am not aware that any
                    would furnish any evidence on the subject to which you allude.</p>
                <p>Of one thing I am certain and that is that I never felt any unfriendly feeling to
                    the South, and that no act of mine, public or private, ever indicated it.</p>
                <p>I perceive the Richmond Enquirer has published an article, containing a
                        <unclear>pretinched</unclear> extract from some remarks of mine, as to
                    printing a petition in reference to the abolition of slavery or the slave trade
                    in the district of Columbia in 1835. I have cut the extract from a paper and
                    herewith enclose it. I can not say whether the extract be true or false, but
                    admitting its truth, I am made to say that "<hi rend="underline">I disclaim most
                        unequivocally now and forever any desire on my part to interfere with the
                        rights or what is termed the property of citizens of other states</hi>."</p>
                <p>That I expressed this sentiment I have little doubt if I spoke at all--and really
                    I don't see anything in it like abolition or unfriendliness to the South.</p>
                <p>But I am utterly opposed on any condition whatever to writing any letter now for
                    publication; and I generally decline all answers, believing that no good but
                    much harm results from letter writing by candidates. My friendship for and
                    confidence in you however, has induced me to depart from the rule and I regret
                    that I am not able to refer you to something you desire.</p>
                <p>I send you however the leading Cass paper in this State, the Albany Argus, by
                    which you will perceive that Mr. Giddings at the late antislavery convention at
                    Worcester denounces me in common with Cass and Taylor.</p>
                <p>My official engagements are so pressing that I have little time for private
                    correspondence but I shall be most happy to hear from you often.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Sincerely &amp; Truly<lb/>Your Friend,</salute>
                    <signed>Millard Fillmore</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">
                        <name type="recipient">Hon A. H. H. Stuart</name>
                    </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
