<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A8015"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A8015">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Alex Rives to Alexander H. H.
                    Stuart, November 20, 1860</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county alex rives to alexander h h stuart, november 20 1860</title>
        <author>Rives, Alex</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andrew J. Torget</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A8015</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502667</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Alex Rives to Alexander H. H. Stuart, November 20,
                            1860</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county alex rives to alexander h h stuart, november 20 1860</title>
            <author>Alex Rives</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Alex Rives to Alexander H. H.
                            Stuart, 20 November 1860, Papers of Alexander H. H. Stuart and the
                            Related Stuart and Baldwin Families, 1776-1878, Accession #228-a, Box 4,
                            Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library,
                            Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1860-11-20">1860-11-20</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>National Government, State Government, Secession, Unionism</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A8015T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Rives responds to letter from Stuart and reports a "vague fear" in his area after
                    Lincoln's election. Rives proposes that Virginia confer with "other states"
                    about the crisis and discusses the issue of Lincoln's cabinet appointments.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1860-11-20">20 Nov. 1860</date>
                        <name type="place">Charlottesville--</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Sir,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Yours of yestderday is just received. I am glad, you are proceeding with
                    deliberation. Great unquiet &amp; apprehension, pervades the Public here. A
                    vague fear distresses us, lest our people should be maddened by occurrences at
                    the South and <hi rend="underline">dragged</hi> after the seceding States. I am
                    clear for keeping the State out of that vortex.</p>
                <p>I should be glad if we could make a migration to the Spottswood Hotel next
                    winter. It is better located; and particularly fresh and nice; and by taking
                    rooms in an upper Story, could lower the board to $12. But I know, it is
                    difficult to make a party of such friends as we should like to have; and hence,
                    we may have to retain our old lodgings. You, however, will have to be in
                    Richmond on the 1st <abbr expan="Wednesday">Wed.</abbr> in <abbr
                        expan="December">Dec.</abbr> as one of our Electors;--(for now I presume
                    there is no doubt of our success) and I must beg you to look out and secure us
                    lodgings wherever you think it best for us to be.</p>
                <pb n="2"/>
                <p>I have heretofore looked forward to the meeting of our Electoral College, for a
                    grand rejoicing. But, now, our political sky is so darkened that we may not have
                    the spirit for it. Still, I would suggest, that the occasion be improved by a
                    public dinner to the Electors, (which might be attended by our best men <orig
                        reg="from">form</orig> every part of the State,) for the purpose of giving
                    expression to our views; and sending on <hi rend="underline">informally</hi>
                    delegates to confer with the members of Congress <orig reg="from">form</orig>
                    the South, particularly from Tenn. N.C. Ky. Missouri, Md. &amp;c.</p>
                <p>Would not some of our Douglas allies attend by invitation such a dinner?</p>
                <p>Let me know what you think of this suggestion. Our public affairs are so
                    critical, it seems to me, we should use every means of consultation with our
                    friends in other States; and the meeting of Congress affords us a capital
                    opportunity for that purpose.</p>
                <p>I confess, I am quite concerned by the difference of opinion among us, as to
                    whether our friends should go into Lincoln's cabinet if invited. Of course, they
                    could not unless well assured of the correctness of his views &amp;<pb n="3"
                    /> feelings towards the South; and the agreement of the whole cabinet therein;
                    but with such assurance, I do not see how they could, in justice to the
                    distracted state of the country, decline to give such evidence of conciliation
                    &amp; pacification; though I well foresee, they would subject themselves to
                    the severest obloquy from the Disunion Press. Still, I deem it a sacrifice, that
                    should be made by them to the peace of the Country. Otherwise, the Public mind
                    must be fearfully inflamed by the absence of any representative of the South in
                    the Cabinet. Nevertheless, acceptance of such posts, must cripple our efforts to
                    overthrow the party in 1864, and somewhat demoralize our opposition to
                    Republicanism.</p>
                <p>This may be a <hi rend="underline">practical</hi> question to you; hence, I throw
                    out my impressions for your consideration with the assurance that I am perfectly
                    willing to yield them to your better judgment.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Most truly<lb/><abbr expan="Yours">Yrs</abbr> &amp;c.</salute>
                    <signed>Alex Rives</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">
                        <name type="recipient">Hon. A. H. H. Stuart</name>
                    </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
