<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A8036"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A8036">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: J. D. Imboden to John McCue,
                    September 26, 1859</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county j d imboden to john mccue, september 26 1859</title>
        <author>Imboden, J. D.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andrew J. Torget</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A8036</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502687</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: J. D. Imboden to John McCue, September 26, 1859</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county j d imboden to john mccue, september 26 1859</title>
            <author>J. D. Imboden</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>6 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: J. D. Imboden to John McCue, 26
                            September 1859, Papers of the McCue Family, 1777-1920, Accession #4406,
                            Box 3, Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library,
                            Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1859-09-26">1859-09-26</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Economy, Family, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A8036T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Imboden relates ongoings in Staunton and family issues.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1859-09-26">Sept 26, 1859</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My dear John.</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I <abbr expan="received">recd.</abbr> your letter of the 12th only one day before
                    I left for Charlotte to join my wife who accompanied her mother home about the
                    1st inst: on a visit to her family, and to attend to some matters she had left
                    unfinished when we came away in June. This accounts for my delay in replying to
                    it.</p>
                <p>Mary took Frank with her to Charlotte &amp; I carried Jennie &amp; Russie
                    along. We have left Russie at Mulberry Hill, where she will remain till next
                    Summer. Mrs. McPhail begged me so hard to allow her to stay there and go to
                    school with her own little daughter--Lily--of the same age, that I finally
                    consented. They have a private tutor in the family, &amp; I doubt not Russie
                    will be more benefitted there than here. And it is better for Jennie--inasmuch
                    as she will now be thrown upon Mary altogether for Society and will be greatly
                    improved by it. As long as she<pb n="2"/>and Russie were constantly together,
                    Jennie would retain her childish ways--and now she is so near grown, it is
                    important for her to conform more to the ways and manners of grown people.
                    Russie was delighted to stay--and I dont wonder at it. For, John, the family
                    &amp; the home at M. Hill are the most attractive to young, as well as old
                    folks, that I ever knew. I wish you could go with me there on a visit one of
                    these times.</p>
                <p>Your children are not more attached to their mother, than are mine to Mary. They
                    almost smother her with kisses &amp; caresses.</p>
                <p>Dr. Quarles is in town. He came in about a week ago to qualify at this term as
                        <abbr expan="Executor">Exc.</abbr> of Ben Reid's will. Jimmy Wills, I
                    presume informed you of the circumstances which prevented me from acting as his
                    counsel in the case. I have been Dr. Quarle's counsel in all his matters since
                    he left here, &amp; felt bound to decline taking a fee against him. Michie
                    &amp; myself are his counsel. We were notified this morning by Baldwin that
                    he would resist a motion to record the will.<pb n="3"/>We have therefore
                    determined to <unclear>proposed</unclear> it in the Circuit Court. I wish very
                    much that the case could by <hi rend="underline">consent</hi> be got ready and
                    tried in November. We proposed that to Baldwin this morning and he said he would
                    have to confer with Mrs. Wills and the Dr. before he could agree to it.</p>
                <p>Dr. Quarles will refuse the guardianship of little Reid. His legacy is $4000. <hi
                        rend="underline">with <abbr expan="interest">int</abbr></hi>: from Mr. R's
                    death. I am satisfied that Dr Q. had no agency in interfering with Mr. Reed's
                    plans in the disposition of his property. I have no idea that the will can be
                    set aside.</p>
                <p>Baldwin and myself are at loggerheads about the Lawyer fee. I collected the <abbr
                        expan="judgement">judgt.</abbr> &amp; offered 10 days ago to pay him his
                    third of the fee, but he claimed <hi rend="underline">half</hi> and declined
                    then to take the <hi rend="underline">third</hi>, proposing to submit the
                    question to Judge Thompson's decision. I declined the submission, on the ground
                    that I dont intend even <hi rend="underline">that far</hi>, to allow it to be
                    implied that he has any <hi rend="underline">claim</hi> to more than a <hi
                        rend="underline">third</hi>. I would as soon arbitrate the question whether
                    he or I should<pb n="4"/>be entitled to the <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> of my house and
                    lot--or my office. I dont know how it will end. I should be glad to hear from
                    you, what you think of his proposition to refer it to the Judge to settle. I
                    think the contract perfectly clear. <unclear>Sanger</unclear> has not been here
                    himself. he sent an agent to receive and disburse his share of the damages.</p>
                <p>You ask me whether it is true that old Billy and Jeff Kinney are drinking hard.
                    Such is the belief here. I dont believe that they or old Nick will live through
                    another year. I like you, feel great pity for old Nick. He has always borne
                    himself towards me as a gentleman, and I think he is a good hearted, and a good
                    man. Jeff is if possible more vindictive than ever. He can hardly walk. His
                    house in town is locked up. All the family have gone out to his farm to live.
                    Old Arch is loafing around town. Ches. is broke, having given a deed of trust.
                    By the way I never yet have got from the staff those little newspaper
                        <unclear>debts <hi rend="underline">vs</hi></unclear> Ches. <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    has promised me the money but has not paid up yet.</p>
                <pb n="5"/>
                <p>I have sent your <unclear>Exn. <hi rend="underline">vs</hi></unclear> Rice as
                    directed to Louisa County. My Clerk's fees in that case amounting to several
                    dollars, I endorsed, <hi rend="underline">receipted</hi> to the
                    <unclear>Pltts</unclear> some week's since asking them to remit me the <abbr
                        expan="amount">amt:</abbr> in stamps. I have not heard a word from them
                    since, and think it strange that they have not replied. I did not deem worth
                    while to trouble a Sheriff with them, and therefore accepted them &amp;
                    endorsed them to the parties owing me--Could they have failed to get them? I
                    have paid your draft to <unclear>Haner</unclear>--The gross earnings of the
                    Clerk's office from July 1st 58 to July 1st 59 were $5775.68 Deducting
                    insolvents, <abbr expan="Commissions">Comms.</abbr> for Collections and deputy
                        <abbr expan="Clerk">Clk</abbr> hire &amp; printing, it leaves me net
                    about $35. or $3600. a year. And I cannot see that my practice has fallen off
                    much on account of my being Clerk. I hope in a few years to be pretty
                    comfortable. I have brought 4 young<pb n="6"/>and handsome negroes over from
                    Charlotte, and have the offer of any others we may wish. Mary &amp; I dont
                    think we will take but one more, possibly two at Christmas. This will save me a
                    good deal in negro hire.</p>
                <p>I am truly gratified to hear of your continued good prospects, and hope your
                    brightest anticipations may be fully realized.</p>
                <p>Why dont you come over here. I am sure no man ever left Staunton, who would be
                    more cordially greeted on his return than you. Your old friends very very often
                    speak most affectionately of you. You must come over to the <abbr
                        expan="Circuit">Cir.</abbr> Court. Bring Liz along, and come right to my
                    house. We have room in our house &amp; hearts for you and all your family.
                    Mary has over and over again expressed an ardent wish to know you both.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>With love to all, I am as ever<lb/>Your friend</salute>
                    <signed>
                        <hi rend="underline">J. D Imboden</hi>
                    </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
