<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A8037"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A8037">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: J. D. Imboden to John McCue,
                    November 13, 1859</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county j d imboden to john mccue, november 13 1859</title>
        <author>Imboden, J.D.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andrew J. Torget</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">12</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A8037</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502688</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: J. D. Imboden to John McCue, November 13, 1859</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county j d imboden to john mccue, november 13 1859</title>
            <author>J. D. Imboden</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>6 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: J. D. Imboden to John McCue, 13
                            November 1859, Papers of the McCue Family, 1777-1920, Accession #4406,
                            Box 3, Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library,
                            Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1859-11-13">1859-11-13</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Economy, Agriculture</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A8037T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Imboden discusses ongoings at the circuit court and Staunton.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="note" id="d5">
                <p>The National Hotel stables were burnt on Thursday last--Fully insured--lost the
                    buildings &amp; 600 bushels of corn &amp; some hay. The <del rend="none" hand="h1"/></p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="letter" id="d6">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1859-11-13">Nov 13th 1859</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton Sunday night</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear John.</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I would have written to you on yesterday in reply to yours of the 7th, but I was
                    laid up with one of my very worst spells of nervous sick headache--and did not
                    leave my bed during the day.</p>
                <p>I have been, indeed we have <hi rend="underline">all</hi> been, very greatly
                    disappointed in not seeing you here before this time. I thought you certainly
                        <hi rend="underline">would</hi> have come over during this term of the
                    circuit court, and the remark in your letter that you "may not come <hi
                        rend="underline">at all</hi>", disappoints us greatly. There is a very
                    general, and earnest wish on the part of <hi rend="underline">all</hi> your old
                    friends of the Bar, and of the town generally to see you. I often hear the
                    remark "I would rather see John Howard McCue just now than any body in the
                    world". And since the Court commenced I have been asked by fifty persons I
                    suppose whether you would be here, all prompted by the friendly motive of
                    wishing to see you for the sake of "<unclear>auld lang syne</unclear>".</p>
                <pb n="2"/>
                <p>I do hope that you have got through your depositions in the Rice &amp;
                    Coleman cases, &amp; that you can come this week. We have just commenced the
                    Civil docket. Only two cases have been tried thus far. So you will still be in
                    time for most of the Court business of interest, if you come this week.</p>
                <p>Until you mentioned the fact in your letter I did not know that there were such
                    suits as you speak of between Dr. Rice &amp; Coleman. What did they
                    originate in? and when? I have only casually made an inquiry or two in respect
                    to the cause of Dr. Rice leaving here, and have not been able to learn anything.
                    I have no doubt that all the facts could be got from W<hi rend="underline"
                    >m</hi> H. Peyton, but it would only be <hi rend="underline"
                    >confidentially</hi>, and you could not use such information. If I can aid you
                    in any way, of course you may rely upon my doing so. I have not had time to look
                    into the law questions you submit whether in <hi rend="underline">libel</hi> the
                    12 <abbr expan="months">mos.</abbr> statues of limitation applies, and from what
                    time. I will try and examine it this week, and get Baldwin &amp; Doyle to do
                    so, and let you know the result. I have a decided "horse back" opinion, but that
                    you dont want. I think the 12 <abbr expan="months">mos</abbr> statue <hi
                        rend="underline">certainly</hi> ap-<pb n="3"/>plicable, &amp; the only
                    question is when does it begin to run? In the case you put, I think clearly at
                    the date when the <hi rend="underline">authorship</hi> of the libel was
                    ascertained, &amp; not from the <hi rend="underline">date</hi> of the libel
                    itself. If not so the false or antedating of a libel would always screen the
                    author or publisher. <hi rend="underline">The right of action</hi> can only
                    accrue when the author &amp; publication become <hi rend="underline"
                    >known</hi>, and from that date the <abbr expan="Statute">Stat.</abbr> of <abbr
                        expan="Limitations">Lim.</abbr> runs. I have no doubt that I can find ample
                        <hi rend="underline">authority</hi> on the question in some of the large
                    libraries here.</p>
                <p>Dr Quarles has gone to Missouri. He qualified as Curator before he left. He will
                    not accede to the terms you propose, I am satisfied, for it would all come out
                    of his <hi rend="underline">own</hi> pocket, as Sarah Reed is a minor. If Dr.
                    Quarle's own sense of right had been properly appealed to I dont doubt <hi
                        rend="underline">his</hi> liberal disposition to have done more for little
                    Reed than the will provides for. But until there is an end of litigation there
                    is no use in making propositions. He intends now to shew, not only that Mr. Reed
                    was of perfectly sound mind, but that he was uninfluenced in any way by him (Dr
                    Q.) in what he did. And I am perfectly satisfied that the Dr. had no more,
                        than<pb n="4"/>you or I, to do with the making of that will. The only points
                    upon which I have advised him are the legal questions involved in the pending
                    controversy, and voluntarily I advised him to decline the guardianship of little
                    Reed, which he told me he never dreamed of accepting. I deeply regret this
                    controversy for &amp; on account of the effect it may have on the relations
                    of Drs. Quarles &amp; Wills. If the latter understood the whole matter as I
                    do, he would not reflect on Dr. Quarles for what he doubtless regards as the
                    great injustice done to his child. Dr Quarles is not responsible for what was
                    done, nor is it in <hi rend="underline">his</hi> power to undo it. It <hi
                        rend="underline">was</hi> his purpose, <hi rend="underline">as I do
                    know</hi>, before this controversy arose to have been very liberal <hi
                        rend="underline">out of his own individual</hi> means towards little Reed.
                    How far that purpose has been changed by existing circumstances, I am not able
                    to say.</p>
                <p>The issue was made up on yesterday in the case. It would have been, and is now
                    very desirable to us, to have the case tried at this term, if that can be done
                    by consent. If not, I wish to take, as soon as the Court rises, the deposition
                        <hi rend="underline">
                        <unclear>de bent epee</unclear>
                    </hi> of John A. Harman &amp; Wm J. Nelson, the subscribing witnesses to the
                    will, and promised Dr Quarles before he left that I would do so. Major Kinney
                    has been appointed guardian <hi rend="underline">
                        <unclear>ad litern</unclear>
                    </hi> of little Reed, in making up the issue. Can we try the case at this term
                    or not? I would be glad if it could be done.</p>
                <pb n="5"/>
                <p>Your old friend Adam Bickle, Bob's father was buried <orig reg="today">to
                    day</orig>. He died Friday morning very suddenly. He was buried with military
                    honors, and an immense concourse of people today. Nick C. Kinney will not live
                    more than a few days. He was thought to be dying on Friday evening, but rallied
                    again. He has two immense tumours on his neck. They are
                    <unclear>running</unclear> inside, and are doubtless <hi rend="underline"
                        >cancerous</hi>, &amp; will carry him off very rapidly. From all
                    accounts, he will scarcely be able to live the week out. Poor old Nick! I feel
                    sorry for him. He is by far the best man of the name. Jeff &amp; old Billy
                    will not be long in following him. John Ches. a son of old Billy died a short
                    time ago of delirium tremers. They are all gone now except Charley Nick.</p>
                <p>Staunton is pleasant now. The usual winter evening entertainments over a bowl of
                    oysters and a few friends have commenced. Week before last my father in law was
                    here, &amp; was invited out to several dinings &amp; suppers.<pb n="6"
                    />By the way the old gentleman is disposed to do the liberal with me. He has
                    given us 5 negroes, and the offer of as many more as we may be disposed to have.
                    And one day whilst here we drove down the <unclear>McAdamized</unclear> road a
                    few miles. Mary called his attention to the Major Poage place, as one that I had
                    said I would like to retire upon. He looked at it as we drove down &amp;
                    returned, &amp; then said to me, if I wished it now, &amp; would make
                    the purchase he would enable me to meet the payments. I thanked him &amp;
                    told him, I did not wish to own a farm at present, nor until I was ready to quit
                    business. He has told Mary of his wish &amp; purpose to portion her off as
                    soon as possible. His expenditures last year were very heavy-- over
                    $10,000--&amp; have left him short of ready money, till he gets this years
                    crop to market, to do what he wishes. All this of course is between ourselves
                        <hi rend="underline">strictly</hi>.</p>
                <p>May writes in love to all of you, and had over &amp; over a hundred times
                    expressed the hope of seeing you and Coz. Liz in hour house this fall. Why cant
                    you come this week.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Kiss Liz and the Youngsters, As ever <abbr expan="Your">Yr</abbr> friend</salute>
                    <signed>J D Imboden</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
