<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A8030"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A8030">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: J. D. Imboden to John McCue,
                    February 24, 1861</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county j d imboden to john mccue, february 24 1861</title>
        <author>Imboden, J. D.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andrew J. Torget</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A8030</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502681</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: J. D. Imboden to John McCue, February 24, 1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county j d imboden to john mccue, february 24 1861</title>
            <author>J. D. Imboden</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: J. D. Imboden to John McCue, 24
                            February 1861, Papers of the McCue Family, 1777-1920, Accession #4406,
                            Box 4, Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library,
                            Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-02-24">1861-02-24</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Secession, Unionism, State Government, National Government, Patriotism,
                        Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A8030T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Imboden discusses his failed bid to represent Augusta at the Virginia state
                    convention, railing particularly against Alexander H. H. Stuart, and promises to
                    leave Virginia if the state does not secede.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="note" id="d4">
                <p>Wasn't Stuart's card to the people of Augusta an infamous document for <hi
                        rend="underline">any</hi> man--much less one who occupies the place of a <hi
                        rend="underline">gentleman</hi>, &amp; to publish?</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d5">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d6">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-02-24">Feby 24/61</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear John.</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Your letter asking me to meet you in Richmond this week was <abbr
                        expan="received">recd.</abbr>
                    <orig reg="yesterday">yesterdy</orig>. I am sorry I cannot do so, but as I
                    returned from Richmond on Thursday I cannot go back again so soon.</p>
                <p>I went down on last Monday to call Stuart to account for his denial on Friday of
                    what he had said to Harmon &amp; myself. At Gordonsville I first saw his
                    apology of Saturday morning, but kept on to the city. When I got there I found
                    that there was but one opinion in regard to the matter, and that was that Sandy
                    had said inconsistent things, that he had either lied on Friday or on Saturday.
                    Gov. Wise, O. J. Wise, Lt. Gov. Montague, Wm F. Gowan &amp; several others
                    with whom Harmon &amp; I conferred, said there was no need of our pressing
                    the matter, that he (S.) had wholly acquitted us of all imputation &amp; we
                    might drop it <del hand="h1">the matter</del>. But on our own
                    <unclear>hook</unclear> to make the matter perfectly clear<pb n="2"/>we
                    addressed Sandy a little <hi rend="underline">billet doux</hi>, asking his
                    attention to the published report of his remarks on <hi rend="underline"
                    >both</hi> Friday &amp; Saturday, and to say in reply exactly what we were
                    to understand he meant in respect to us. About midnight we got a reply which was
                    a square <hi rend="underline">back down</hi>, and exonerated us from all
                    possible imputation. I intended making a publication of this correspondence, and
                    also a more complete statement in detail of what he had said the evening he
                    mentioned the "plot" to us, and to have accompanied it with the letter of
                    another gentleman to whom he made a similar statement <hi rend="underline"
                    >nine</hi> days <hi rend="underline">after</hi> his conversation with Harmon
                    &amp; myself, and said unqualifiedly that "there was a plot on foot, and if
                    it succeeded, one of the first acts of the Convention would be to change the
                    organic law of the State, and turn Letcher out of office &amp; put Gov. Wise
                    in his place." The gentleman to whom he made this Statement furnished it to me
                    in writing, and another man in public life sent me word, that to him the same<pb
                        n="3"/>communication was made, and if it became necessary he would testify.
                    So that I should have had <hi rend="underline">four</hi> witnesses against him
                    on the fact he denied to Wise in the Convention. But on consultation with Gov.
                    Wise &amp; the other friends I have named, &amp; numerous outsiders, the
                    universal opinion was that we ought not to publish, that the public already
                    understood that Sandy had lied, and that being down in the mud it would
                    unmagnanimous and unmanly to gouge &amp; pummel him. We have therefore
                    simply filed away the documents for safe keeping &amp; future use if
                    circumstances require it. I shewed the correspondence to scores of persons
                    before I left <abbr expan="Richmond">R.</abbr> &amp; here since my return.
                    The idea you mention that my defeat had anything to do with this matter is
                    absurd, for the conversation occurred before either Stuart or myself were
                    candidates, &amp; not being in any sense <hi rend="underline">private</hi>,
                    was communicated to Douglas &amp; many others <hi rend="underline">the same
                        night</hi> 13th January, and was talked about by us in the City all the next
                    day, &amp; no doubt Stuart heard of our<pb n="4"/>speaking of it before we
                    came home from <abbr expan="Richmond">R.</abbr> &amp; before either of us
                    was a candidate. By the way he left the impression in his response to Wise that
                    Col. Baldwin was present at the conversation. He takes all that back in his
                    letter to us and says he only meant to say <abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Baldwin">B.</abbr> was <hi rend="underline">in the City</hi> at the
                    same time, &amp; being his <abbr expan="brother">bro.</abbr> in law the
                    probabilities were that he would have mentioned the matter to him! but did not.
                    I wish I could be with you in <abbr expan="Richmond">R.</abbr> You will soon be
                    disgusted with the submission feeling that pervades the body of the Convention.
                    Gov. Wise is the only real living embodiment of the true spirit which should
                    animate Virginia at this time. I told him in <abbr expan="Richmond">R.</abbr>
                    the other day that I delegated him to represent <hi rend="underline">me</hi> on
                    the floor of that body, as I have no immediate representative there. John we are
                    going to have fearful times here in Virginia. I am afraid we shall have a war
                    amongst ourselves. I have made up my mind that if <abbr expan="Virginia"
                    >Va</abbr> submits to the dishonor of standing by and seeing war made in the
                    Seceded states, I will leave <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> I am persuaded
                    that a majority of our people here are ready for that. I am not and never will
                    be. We must have <hi rend="underline">immediately</hi> the constitutional
                    guarantees of the Crittenden plan <hi rend="underline">at least</hi> or go with
                    the South. If these are refused, and <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>
                    <hi rend="underline">submit</hi>, I never will. I shall go to Florida or
                    Louisiana, take my family &amp; cast my lot there for life. I will <hi
                        rend="underline">write</hi> to Gov. Wise whilst you are in <abbr
                        expan="Richmond">R</abbr>. Mary writes in love to you and yours. She is a
                    red hot Southern Confederacy woman.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours truly</salute>
                    <signed>J D Imboden</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">P.S. Sorry you were beaten for <unclear>Cur.</unclear>
                        but am not surprised since I have heard the causes that were at work.</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
