<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A8038"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A8038">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: George W. Imboden to John McCue,
                    April 12, 1860</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county george w imboden to john mccue, april 12 1860</title>
        <author>Imboden, George W.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andrew J. Torget</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">6</num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A8038</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502689</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: George W. Imboden to John McCue, April 12, 1860</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county george w imboden to john mccue, april 12 1860</title>
            <author>George W. Imboden</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: George W. Imboden to John McCue,
                            12 April 1860, Papers of the McCue Family, 1777-1920, Accession #4406,
                            Box 4, Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library,
                            Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1860-04-12">1860-04-12</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Women, Slavery</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A8038T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Imboden relates ongoings in Staunton and warns McCue "to pay up or the lodge will
                    expell you for <hi rend="underline">non payment of dues</hi>.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1860-04-12">April 12 1860</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear John</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I have been wanting to write you for several weeks but have putting it off from
                    time to time and now I will drop you a few lines, we are all well, and I hope
                    you all are the same, John left for Richmond yesterday to meet his wife,
                    &amp; they will be at home today. I am anxious to see sister mary and her
                    big <hi rend="underline">boy</hi>. I have but little news to write, poor Sallie
                    Douglase was buried on last Sunday at Tinkling Spring. I wanted to go down, but
                    George McPhail came over from Greenwood and I could not go, all the people are
                    well on the meadows, I have purchased a lot. and am engaged in building a house,
                    I <orig reg="bought">bot</orig> from Mrs. Warden just above the Academy lot, and
                    will put up a small house three rooms below &amp; two above with a Kitchen
                    in the basement, I will build it of brick, as it will make a warmer house and
                    cost but<pb n="2"/>little more than frame, and when I get it finished you
                    &amp; <abbr expan="cousin">coz.</abbr> Liz &amp; family must not treat
                    me the way I have treated you, but must come and see me, though our house will
                    be small, I hope it will contain large hearts. that will ever be glad to receive
                    a friend.</p>
                <p>John we received your letter addressed to our commitee, and in reply will say
                    that you are laboring under some misapprehensions in regard to the order, "You
                    say that you do not think it fair for you to pay after leaving" but you forgot
                    that you could not have entered any other lodge, or become a member, without
                    having a visiting card from this lodge, or having taken a withdrawal card, for
                    one year and renewed the same at the expiration of the year. So you see that you
                    will have to pay up or the lodge will expell you for <hi rend="underline">non
                        payment of dues</hi>. Mr Patterson tells me that in January before you left
                    you gave him two dollars, all that you ever paid, Your case will be disposed of
                    at the next Lodge night, Thursday next, and I wish you to inform me what to
                        do<pb n="3"/>for you, in the premises.</p>
                <p>Mr Bill Crawford has spoken to me concerning a claim he has on you, for the hire
                    of a negro and requested me to write to you concerning it. I hope you will come
                    over with your family this Spring to see us all as it seems I will not be able
                    to come to see you as I have often promised.</p>
                <p>Give my love to all</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>In haste Yours Truly</salute>
                    <signed>
                        <hi rend="underline">GW. Imboden</hi>
                    </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
