<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A8039"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A8039">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: John H. McCue to His Wife, January
                    10, 1855</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county john h mccue to his wife, january 10 1855</title>
        <author>McCue, John</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andrew J. Torget</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A8039</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502690</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: John H. McCue to His Wife, January 10, 1855</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county john h mccue to his wife, january 10 1855</title>
            <author>John H. McCue</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: John McCue to "My Own Dearest
                            Wife," 10 January 1855, Papers of the McCue Family, 1777-1920, Accession
                            #4406, Box 3, Special Collections Department, University of Virginia
                            Library, Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1855-01-10">1855-01-10</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Women, Church/Religious Activity, Economy, National Government,
                        State Government</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A8039T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>John McCue sends his love to his wife and discusses his law practice, local
                    church activity, and politics.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1855-01-10">Jan'y 10th '55</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Own Dearest Wife,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>It has been several days since I have written to you and several since I heard
                    from you. I am anxiously expecting a letter from My Dear Absent Honey: Your
                    presence my love is indispensable to my happiness. The longer I live in the
                    world the more necessary are you to my peace of mind. The more I know you, the
                    more is my love strengthened. It increases daily. May God in his mercy spare us
                    to each other years to come, for how long could one live without the other!
                    During the day, when my mind is absorbed with business, its perplexities
                    &amp; annoyances, I do not so sensibly experience that you &amp; my
                    children are from me, but when night begins to settle around me in glooming
                    silence, there is an aching void. My thoughts revert to you &amp; them. I
                    wish I could but hear your sweet <unclear>ceurding</unclear> angelic voice
                    &amp; the merry laugh of my merry &amp; interesting children. God bless
                    them! Do they ever speak of their absent Papa, and express the desire to see
                    him? That laughing, merry, ever moving little <unclear>Olie</unclear>--How I
                    miss her as mornings breaks into my chamber! No little cherub
                    <unclear>lum</unclear> to crawl upon my breast, wake me with a kiss and whisper
                    "Papa." It is now past eleven at night: to the commencement of this letter, Mr I
                    &amp; myself have been engaged in business with two gentlemen in Mr. I's
                    parlor: He has gone to bed, and I am now at<pb n="2"/>his table in the parlor
                    engaged in holding sweet commune with my <hi rend="underline">wife</hi>! Wife!!
                    How endearing that name. How many lies and associations connected with the past,
                    and hopes connected with the future are embraced in that simple word <hi
                        rend="underline">wife</hi>!! But this is indulging in reflections that make
                    me sad: the distance is short, separating us. The time I trust will not be long
                    before I shall see you, kiss you and embrace you in my arms.</p>
                <p>I saw Otelia C. this morning. She will not depart for Martinsburg before
                    Saturday, in as much as James <unclear>Daman</unclear> as informed her <abbr
                        expan="through">thro</abbr> letter that he will be here Friday to see her.
                    His last letter to her <abbr expan="received">recd</abbr> yesterday, is long,
                    most interesting &amp; shows his affection to be strong as ever. She regrets
                    exceedingly to leave without seeing you. Says she loves you as a sister, and
                    fears her visit to you was not as pleasant to you as it should have been-
                    -&amp;c. I assured her to the contrary. I think she is a noble
                    girl--&amp; her resolve to teach, to be useful, to live to a purpose is the
                    strongest evidence of her elevation of character &amp; nobleness of soul.</p>
                <p>I believe I told you of Mr Castleman's call to Baltimore at a salary of $2000. An
                    effort is now being made to raise his salary here to $1400 as an inducement for
                    him to remain amongst us. He has greatly improved of late as a preacher and if
                    he is not retained, I fear another as acceptable cannot be had. But $1400 is too
                    much for a village<pb n="3"/>church to pay, and give a house. More anon.</p>
                <p>Mr Wilson has accepted the call of the Presbyterian's &amp; will be here in
                    the spring. Dont fail to have Mr. Imboden invited to Conny's wedding. He will go
                    if he possibly can. Our Special Court commences the 24th and not the 10-(to day)
                    as I supposed. If we go, you must, if you expect to return home the last of the
                    month, make your arrangements to return the day after the wedding, for we have
                    been retained in the big suit of McDowell Exon vs Hugh John Crawford, which may
                    be called up the first day of the court. I expect to go to Roanoke in a few
                    days, probably Friday. If not then, on Monday next. If we go
                    <unclear>South</unclear>, it will be out of our power to do so, until after the
                    rising of the Court. It will then be later in the Spring and decidedly more
                    pleasant. At the season of the year proposed by you, we might have a terrible
                    time of it. Dr. <unclear>Seehass</unclear> is here &amp; family. Cousins
                    Sally &amp; Eliza called on her to day. They report her to be a most
                    pleasant lady. The Dr has thrown himself into our hands, and we have provided a
                    snug place for him. You know <unclear>Moupin</unclear> acting no doubt under the
                    advice of Stuart threw him off because Dr H would not consent to make his paper
                    the organ of him, Sandy. He Dr H is to go into the Messenger as a partner of
                        <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> and that sheet is to be known as the "American Reformer" and
                        too<pb n="4"/>advocate the principles of the American party, known by some
                    as the Know Nothing party. This is to be a profound secret until the paper is
                    issued, which will not be till next week. So my love you must not speak of it to
                    any one. For I would not be the means of divulging it for the world. Sandy has
                    become very cool towards us. Never comes to our office, &amp; never calls us
                    into his. He has all this time been making a tremendous effort to win us to his
                    support for governor, but we would not be caught in that <unclear>way</unclear>.
                    We are determined to let the <abbr expan="Know Nothings">K. N.s</abbr> nominate
                    &amp; then we will support their ticket. This is the advice now of all the
                    Whig papers &amp; Stuart is bound to yield.</p>
                <p>Save now to our dear Small Mama, God bless her. A thousand kisses to you
                    love--&amp; my children--love to Annie, <unclear>Leil</unclear> &amp;
                    Nellie. Mr I, Cousin E. &amp; Maj. E, send <unclear>march</unclear>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> Good night. You are dreaming I know, of your absent
                        husband--<unclear>Ihercam on</unclear> darling--<unclear>the wishes of the
                        pass</unclear> &amp; innocent are always pleasant. May god protect you
                    from harm &amp; my children &amp; our dear <unclear>nickted</unclear>
                    &amp; <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> is the prayer of your</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Devoted Husband,</salute>
                    <signed>JH McCue</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
