<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A8040"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A8040">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: William S. Eskridge to John McCue,
                    May 21, 1858</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county william s eskridge to john mccue, may 21 1858</title>
        <author>Eskridge, William</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andrew J. Torget</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">11</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A8040</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502691</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: William S. Eskridge to John McCue, May 21, 1858</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county william s eskridge to john mccue, may 21 1858</title>
            <author>William S. Eskridge</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William Eskridge to John McCue,
                            21 May 1858, Papers of the McCue Family, 1777-1920, Accession #4406, Box
                            3, Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library,
                            Charlottesvile, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1858-05-21">1858-05-21</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>State Goverment, Slavery</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A8040T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>William S. Eskridge complains about political corruption and problems in Augusta
                    County.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1858-05-21">May 21. 1858</date>
                        <name type="place">Bayou <unclear>Sara</unclear>
                            <abbr expan="Louisiana">La</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Sir,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>The Kinneys have had possession of the public offices of Augusta long enough, as
                    might be shown by many circumstances, I will mention one or two, some years ago
                    Mr. <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> C Kinney held virtually the Deputy Clerkship of Augusta,
                    having rented the office of E. Stribling, &amp; the place of <abbr
                        expan="Deputy">D</abbr> Sheriff of the County at the same time.
                    <unclear>Sff</unclear> Woodward did the sheriffs part of the business, Kinney
                    attended to the <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> During the time of this joint business, there
                    were two run a way Negroes <unclear>sold</unclear> out of Jail, on the same day,
                    Churchman who acted at the time as <abbr expan="Deputy">D</abbr> Sheriff of one
                    of one half the County sold one &amp; Woodward the other; the course of
                    business as you know is the <abbr expan="Deputy Sheriff">D.S.</abbr> reports the
                    amount of sale to the <abbr expan="Clerk">Ck</abbr>, the Clerk certifies it to
                    the auditor, so that when the <abbr expan="Deputy Sheriff">D.S.</abbr> attends
                    the auditor for settlement, charges of this kind are made to appear against him,
                    in the sale above refered to, the sale of Churchman's Negro sold as <unclear>a
                        restaid</unclear> was certified, Woodwards was not, and it was a mere
                    accident that the money on the last mentioned sale was
                    <unclear>wirpared</unclear> into the treasury, the circumstances of the case
                    come out in this way. Churchman some year or two afterwards, had sold another
                    Negro out of Jail taken about paying the money to the auditor spoke of the
                    former sales, the auditor said he did not recollect of but one Negro's sale
                    being accounted for, this led to an investigation, and it was found, but one had
                    been reported, Mr. D. W. Patterson, as he<pb n="2"/>informed me, informed Mr.
                    Kinney of this <unclear>omission</unclear> the money was of course immediately
                    paid into the treasury--Now I would ask any <unclear>replacting</unclear>
                    whether this <unclear>omission</unclear> was by design or not, would not the
                    fact of certifying the sale of the Negro by Churchman, call up to the mind of a
                    man, <unclear>situated</unclear> as Kinney <unclear>was</unclear> the sale of
                    the Negro by Woodward???</p>
                <p>Another case, in which I was concerned, in May 1831 a short time before I was
                    ejected by honor Judge Thompson &amp; Mr. Kinney appointed to my Office,
                    about $800.00 was paid into Court as the case of <unclear>Paseter</unclear>
                    &amp; <abbr expan="agent">agt.</abbr>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>, as soon as the money was <abbr expan="received">recd.</abbr> I
                    loaned it to Thomas J. <unclear>Michie</unclear> and of course took his bond as
                    the security for it, I will here remark that when I went out of office, I had a
                    good deal of public money loaned out to some of my friends, which I did not wish
                    to go into Mr Kinneys hand, for several reasons, therefore ask <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    to retain the bond as <unclear>reiceived</unclear> (which his honor most
                    graciously awarded) &amp; pay the money as it might be called for which
                        <unclear>good</unclear> for several years, <unclear>mild nearly</unclear>
                    all the money in my hands was paid out, in the case above referred to that
                    collected of Miche &amp; feared <unclear>over</unclear> as well as I can
                    recall <unclear>ect</unclear> some three hundred &amp; odd dollars in 1837,
                    being a great deal. From <unclear>home</unclear> at the time I determined to
                    transfer the bond of Mche in this cast to Mr Kinney as
                    <unclear>reciever</unclear> of the <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> which I
                    <unclear>rcd</unclear>, at the same time I filed amongst the <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> in
                    the case a statement sharing the amount of money rcd. &amp; the amount
                        <unclear>year'd</unclear> &amp;c sharing a balance due <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> of <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> $750, with interest from 1837. You may
                    Judge of my astonishment when in Charlottesville in 1853, on reciving a notice
                    from <unclear>Court Henderson stationy</unclear><pb n="3"/>that Mr W Kinney was
                        <unclear>ringing</unclear> the payment of the <unclear>appointment</unclear>
                    balance in the interest as due from me Immediately and sued
                    <unclear>Herndon</unclear>, that I had not a <unclear>card</unclear> of momey in
                    my hands in the case, and asked him to get Mr. Kinney to <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> his
                    papers, and see if he could find any <unclear>hav</unclear> of this
                        <unclear>money</unclear> he said he did so, and <unclear>he denied</unclear>
                    that he had ever any thing to do with it, or know any thing about it--in this
                    state of the case &amp; found it necessary to visit Staunton, I had kept a
                    book, in which I <unclear>sol</unclear> down the receipt of
                    <unclear>palker</unclear> money to whom <orig reg="loaned">loand</orig>
                    &amp;c, on looking into this book I found a statement showing all about the
                    matter, and on <unclear>sacing</unclear> Mr Miche he stated he had made required
                    payments on the bond, &amp; that Kinneys <unclear>lite</unclear> held it
                    with a balance due-<unclear>him</unclear> My opinion is that Kinney
                        <unclear>thought</unclear> as I was two thousand miles off &amp; as
                        <unclear>seven</unclear>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> had <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> he could <unclear>throu</unclear> the
                    chains on me, &amp; thus <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> some fifteen or sixteen hundred
                    dollars. He did not think I could explain after such a long time, nor perhaps
                    should I had it not beef for the <unclear>minco landam</unclear> which I kept
                        <unclear>admil</unclear> he acted <unclear>Cowardly</unclear> on this
                    matter, about which I shall, <unclear>soull</unclear> can hardly <del hand="h1"
                    /> it was an unpardonable piece of neligence, on his part not to be able to give
                    any amount of such a large sum of money which had in <unclear>partpass</unclear>
                    &amp; <unclear>recipt</unclear> his <unclear>hands</unclear>. That he has
                    used the public money I never had a doubt because I have heard numerous
                    complaints of his not paying out money in his hands, belonging to cases when
                    called for a long time, indeed for years, and see it was the
                    <unclear>Cassione</unclear> course pursued towards him by the Judge, that I
                    heard it charged that it was supposed the Judge had himself<pb n="4"/>borrowed
                    some of the money--but I was glad to hear Mr. Stuart say he had
                        <unclear>asiamined</unclear> into the matter and he did not think it was the
                    case--I <unclear>wonder Chocran</unclear> and not charge him with withholding
                    the public money where <orig reg="collected">colled</orig> for this charge could
                    easily have been sustained I could give you some more of Mr. Kinney <del
                        hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> but it hardly <unclear>anch</unclear> while</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Very Respectuflly Yours</salute>
                    <signed>W<hi rend="underline">m</hi> S. Eskridge</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript"><unclear>NB</unclear> I hope you will be able to read the
                        above it is badly written but I have been sick a good deal lately have had
                        chills &amp; fevers--still a worse <unclear>case</unclear>
                        <hi rend="underline">old</hi> age I am now <unclear>ruar by</unclear>
                        severely two years old <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> can use my hand trembled<lb/>
                    W.S.E.</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
