<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A8063"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A8063">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title id="VShadow" type="main">Augusta County: L. M. Powell to Alexander H. H. Stuart, 19 January 1861</title>
                <title>[electronic resource] </title>
                <title type="sort">augusta county l m powell to alexander h h stuart, january 19
                    1861</title>
                <author>L. M. Powell</author>
                <editor/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Sarah Maxwell</name>
                </respStmt>
            </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A8063</idno>

                <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
                <availability status="public">
                    <p n="copyright">Copyright &amp;#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                    <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
                </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
                <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502658</idno>
            </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
                <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
            </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
                        <title>Augusta County: L. M. Powell to Alexander H. H. Stuart, 19 January 1861</title>
                        <title level="m"/>
                        <title type="sort">augusta county l m powell to alexander h h stuart, january 19
                    1861</title>
                        <author>L. M. Powell</author>
                        <editor/>
                        <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
                    </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: L. M. Powell to Alexander H. H. Stuart, 19 January 1861, Papers of Alexander H. H. Stuart and the 
                            Related Stuart and Baldwin Families, 1776-1878, Accession #228-a, Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library, Charlottesville, Virginia.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <projectDesc>
                <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library,
                    University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
            </projectDesc>
        </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-01-19">1861-01-19</date>
            </creation>
            <langUsage>
                <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
            </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>National Government, Secession, Unionism, Constitution</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
            <change>
                <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University
                        of Virginia Library</name>
                    <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD
                    (uva-dl-tei).</item>
            </change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A8063T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 id="d3" type="summary">
                <p>Powell, at the Naval Academy in Annapolis, Maryland, proposes to Stuart that Virginia call on the United States Congress to
                    demand a constitutional convention to end the secession crisis.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 id="d5" type="letter">
                <head>L. M. Powell (Annapolis) to <abbr expan="Alexander H. H. Stuart">AHHS</abbr>,
                    1861 <abbr expan="January">Jan</abbr> 19</head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-01-19">January 19th 1861</date>
                        <name type="place">Annapolis</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My dear Secretary,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I am here grinding out future naval heroes for national wars which I fear they will never have occasion to 
fight: already some from the South have left, and I hear of one of these chaps who is promoted to 1st 
Lieutenant in the Navy of the State of S. Carolina, and said to be spoiling for a fight.</p>
                <pb n="2"/>
                <p>You have a higher duty, "firing up the Southern heart &amp;c." for a general conflict with any and every body.</p>
                <p>I watch the progress of your body with the utmost interest, and at times greatly fear that our old state will 
submit to the destiny cut out for her by another [] further south: and not venture to follow the conservative 
and wise instincts of her wise and moderate people.  I see that my kinsman Charles Conrad has gone off 
with a // full head of steam, but I think I know that is more from motives of state policy, than through 
sympathy with the prevalent revolutionary spirit.  Dr[?] you know, that I have looked with amazement on 
the leaders and legislatures of the Southern states. they seem to fall upon every method but the plain 
demand of the constitutional provision which points to a speedy and effectual means of meeting a crisis 
like the present, and affords the remedy.  Why dont you do it in Virginia?  Why not propose a resolution to 
call on Congress, for a national convention to consider amendments, say on the basis of Mr Crittenden's.  
there is no doubt that the legislatures of two thirds of the states would follow your example instanter[?]. 
There is still time, and the feeling of the country approaching unamity.  The extreme men will oppose, but 
what of that, they are but a fraction.//</p>
                <p>If you will press such a measure through the legislature, the example would be followed almost by all the 
states and leave your convention little more to do.  Maryland would hail it as the solution of her present 
perplexities and the govr. would feel safe in calling the legislature, which he does not now.</p>
                <p>We shall conclude our labours here on Saturday and then I shall go home, to Washington and help our 
people to organize their forces to thrash the wide awakes or the minute men either, who may meditate a 
raid on the city.</p>
                <p>I left my wife well on the 3rd and very unhappy at the aspect
                of affairs.</p>
                <p>"God is great and Mahomet is his prophet," as the Turk says when at his wits end.  I feel just like him.  
Adieu my dear Secretary and think me as ever faithfully yours</p>

                <closer>
                    
                    <signed>L M Powell</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">
                        <name type="recipient">Hon: <lb/>Al. H H Stuart</name>
                    </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
