<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A8061"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A8061">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: William McCue to John McCue,
                    December 25, 1859</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county william mccue to john mccue, december 25 1859</title>
        <author>McCue, William</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andrew J. Torget</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A8061</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502712</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: William McCue to John McCue, December 25, 1859</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county william mccue to john mccue, december 25 1859</title>
            <author>William McCue</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>6 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William McCue to John McCue, 25
                            December 1859, Papers of the McCue Family, 1777-1920, Accession #4406,
                            Box 4, Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library,
                            Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1859-12-25">1859-12-25</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, State Government, National Government, Unionism, Secession, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A8061T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>John McCue's brother, William, discusses John Brown's raid and family
                matters.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1859-12-25">Dec 25th 1859</date>
                        <name type="place">Fincastle</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Brother</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Your kind favor bearing date <abbr expan="December">Dec</abbr> 16th was received
                    yesterday &amp; read &amp; reread with more than usual interest, so
                    replete was it with interesting items &amp; good advice. Permit me in the
                    commencement of my letter, to express my very high appreciation of the motives
                    which promted you to give expression to those feelings of paternal affection, so
                    beautifully &amp; affectionately set forth in your communication. Time
                    &amp; again have I meditated upon our brotherly conversation in the "Cabell
                    House" and have thanked heaven that such an opportunity was afforded me of
                    giving expression to those emotions of love and sympathy for you &amp; your
                    family which had been locked up in my soul for so long, I can now <del hand="h1"
                        >console</del> flatter myself that you can<pb n="2"/>appreciate something of
                    the feelings of that brothers heart, who has for so long been a silent observer
                    of passing events--one who has thought much but said little, because he <del
                        hand="h1">thought</del> deemed it far more prudent to remain
                    passive,-occupying as he did, a neutral position, (You understand my allusions)
                    Had I the time &amp; space to <unclear>dilate</unclear> upon this theme I
                    might consume hours &amp; pages, but I must forbear.</p>
                <p>The late excitement occasioned by the foray of John Brown, &amp; his infamous
                    coagators, is about to bring our school more prominently before the public,
                    Owing to the disturbed state of the public mind &amp; the dangers that
                    threaten the distinction of our once glorious honor, the citizens feeling the
                    importance of fostering the military spirits now aroused, and of giving the
                        <unclear>growth</unclear> of the country instruction in military <del
                        hand="h1"/> on last court day drew up a petition to the Legislature asking
                    an appropriation to assist<pb n="3"/>them in establishing a military
                    Professorship, in the <unclear>Botelomt</unclear>
                    <unclear>snule</unclear> Academy,--beleiving that the prosperity &amp;
                    usefulness of the institution would be greatly promoted thereby. which was
                    signed by a number of the most prominent citizens of the county &amp; sent
                    to their <orig reg="delegates">delagates</orig>, accompanied with a petition
                    from the "Board of Directors," If the petition should be granted, we may expect
                    a large acquisition to our school.</p>
                <p>9 of our students, members of a volunteer company, in obedience to Executive
                    orders were in public service at Charlestown during the execution of
                        <unclear>Coppie</unclear> &amp; Cook. If the said petition passes the
                    Legislature the school will at once be converted into a military school. Wilson
                    &amp; I will uniform &amp; take a regular course of military training.
                    Since the excitement a large company of voulunteers has been raised in<pb n="4"
                    />Fincastle &amp; a Company of cavalry is now being raised, to which I
                    belong I think it more than probable that I will be elected to one of the
                    offices, as I have the reputation of being one of the best horsemen in this
                    section of country, At the public meeting of which I spoke, there were a number
                    of resolutions adopted similar to those adopted throughout the state,--declaring
                    their intention to cut off all trade with the north to preserve the Union if
                    possible &amp; if not to maintain our rights at the point of the bayonet. A
                    number of warm &amp; eloquent speeches were made some were in favor of an
                    immediate secession but the prevailing sentiment seemed to be that contained in
                    the resolution adopted- which you will see in the Richmond papers- I for my part
                    love &amp; cherish the Union, &amp; do <orig reg="wholly">wholy</orig>
                    &amp; heartly endorse that sentiment of Webster "Union now &amp;
                    forever, one &amp; unseparable" but if this cannot be," I am ready to should
                    my musket at a moments warning &amp; die if need be in defence of my
                    country's rights.</p>
                <pb n="5"/>
                <p>I am sorry that the black does not suit you as a riding animal. I had not noticed
                    anything like <unclear>sting-salt</unclear>, However I only had her 2 days
                    before you got her &amp; of course did not have an opportunity of judging of
                    her imperfections. Barefoot is regarded by several judges as being much older
                    than she was represented to you She has been worked several times but did not
                    work gently, Owing to the state of the roads &amp; the small-pox in
                    Lexington I gave out my trip to Augusta, &amp; would certainly spend my
                        <orig reg="holidays">holydays</orig> with you all, if the rail road between
                    Charlottesville &amp; Lynchburg was completed. Nothing would afford me more
                    pleasure, than to spend a week with you all. When that road is finished I will
                        <orig reg="travel">tavel</orig> that road home altogether it being the
                    quickest &amp; much the most pleasant.</p>
                <p>I was in <unclear>Sursterdam</unclear> last week they are all well, but Lizzie
                    &amp; Aunt Margaret are contemplating<pb n="6"/>a visit to Augusta next
                    spring, &amp; will stop &amp; see you all on <unclear>their</unclear>
                    way Aunt Lizzie often speaks of the pleasant visit she had at your house, when
                    you were living in Staunton, Miss Mannie Turner &amp; Mr McDowel will be
                    married next Thursday. Our school is still flourishing &amp; is in public
                    favor, We have 36 scholars now (30 classical) &amp; expect an acquisition
                    the first of <abbr expan="February">Feb.</abbr> We are now boarding at <del
                        hand="h1"/> Glasgow's, a very nice place indeed, have every thing that is
                    necessary for our comfort.</p>
                <p>Give my love to sister Liz &amp; the children &amp; remember very kindly
                    to Mrs Wills &amp; <unclear>write</unclear></p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your brother</salute>
                    <signed>Billy</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
