<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A8517"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A8517">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: John D. Imboden to John H. McCue,
                    April 12, 1858</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county john d imboden to john h mccue, april 12 1858</title>
        <author>Imboden, John D.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A8517</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502730</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: John D. Imboden to John H. McCue, April 12, 1858</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county john d imboden to john h mccue, april 12 1858</title>
            <author>John D. Imboden</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: John D. Imboden to John H. McCue,
                            12 April 1858, McCue Family Papers, Accession # 4406, Special
                            Collections, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1858-04-12">1858-04-12</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Economy, Family, State Government, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-08">August 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A8517T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>John D. Imboden asks John H. McCue not to use a draft to pay a bill for the
                    Lynchburg Hose and Fire Insurance Company when they are able to wait for the
                    money. Imboden also writes, at length, of upcoming local elections.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1858-04-12"><abbr expan="April">Apl</abbr> 12/58</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear John</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I <abbr expan="received">recd</abbr> your letter last evening on my return from
                    Craigsville, and have only time for a hasty reply.</p>

                <p>Your matters are reported to me as going on very well out at home. George goes
                    out &amp; looks after them. Saw Jim this evening &amp; he says all goes
                    on well.</p>

                <p>I was surprised to hear of your abandonment of the Memphis trip, as I understood
                    you that it was determined on before you left. Perhaps it is as well to defer it
                        <orig reg="until">till</orig> you have got your business more straightened
                    up here.</p>

                <p>You ask Lumpkin to use the draft to pay the <abbr expan="Lynchburg">L.</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Fire">F.</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Insurance">Ins.</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Company">Compy.</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="balance">bal.</abbr> due them, secured in your deed. I have no
                    objection provided the draft is met at maturity in some way. Unless there is
                    some certainty of its being met, I would rather you would not use it, except in
                    case of absolute necessity. And I dont think this such a case. That <abbr
                        expan="Company">Compy.</abbr> Can afford to wait a little while for their
                    money, as it is safe &amp; bears them interest; and it will be a matter of
                    inconvenience to me to pay the draft. I will have to pay some $600 or $700
                    shortly on the two Cochran judgements for the White Storehouse, &amp; it
                    will strap me like thunder to do it. Patton was here <orig reg="today">to
                    day</orig> making arrangements for his part, &amp; I will have to stand up
                    to that of <abbr expan="Imboden">Im.</abbr> &amp; <abbr expan="McCue"
                    >McC</abbr>. On this account, I would rather you <abbr expan="should"
                    >shd.</abbr> not use the draft, unless you need it for some <hi rend="underline"
                        >personal expenditure</hi>, in which case you know I would willingly meet it
                    myself at all hazards. Your note to C. P. Woods for $54. must be met tomorrow by
                    me. <pb n="2"/>And another small note at Valley Bank in a few days. Under these
                    Circumstances, with the great difficulty in getting hold of money even on good
                    paper, of which I have a good deal on hands, you will understand why I ask you
                    not to use the draft merely to pay off a debt, already secured by you, &amp;
                    that to a party not in need of the money.</p>

                <p>Will attend to your instructions in regard to the several matters mentioned in
                    your letter, <unclear>Shff's</unclear> cases &amp;c.</p>

                <p>A few words as to the election. I never know so rapid a setting in of a current
                    in one direction as is going on. The <abbr expan="Kentuckys[?]">Kys.</abbr> are
                    scared out of their wits. They admit that Jeff is in great danger of being
                    beaten. My friends are so confident that they offer all sorts of bets. All the
                    Koiner's have wheeled into line for me, old &amp; young. We beat the Kys in
                    the Town election last Wednesday 74 votes, and it has killed them here. Peck
                    beat Craig &amp; we thrashed them out with the Council. A powerful effort
                    was made to defeat me, but I run ahead of the ticket even, on our side. Jim
                    Bumgardner, a warm <abbr expan="Kentucky[?]">Ky</abbr> man offered to bet Mike
                    Harman on Saturday, that my <hi rend="underline">majority</hi> over Ky. would
                    not exceed you!! Mike dared him to take $1000. on an even race, but he wouldn't
                    touch. Barring accident, I consider the thing "fixed" beyond all doubt.</p>

                <p>I shall be very little at home from now until after the election. Leave tomorrow
                    for Waynesboro -- Back Creek &amp;c &amp; shall not be back till
                    Saturday. Hope you will soon be home again.<lb/> Love to <abbr expan="Cousin"
                        >Coz.</abbr> Liz Mrs. Wills &amp; all the family. We are all well.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>In haste <abbr expan="yours">yrs</abbr> truly</salute>
                    <signed>J D Imboden</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
