<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A8520"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A8520">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: George W. Imboden to John H. McCue,
                    January 18, 1859</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county george w imboden to john h mccue, january 18 1859</title>
        <author>Imboden, George W.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A8520</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502733</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: George W. Imboden to John H. McCue, January 18, 1859</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county george w imboden to john h mccue, january 18 1859</title>
            <author>George W. Imboden</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: George W. Imboden to John H.
                            McCue, 18 January 1859, McCue Family Papers, Accession # 4406, Special
                            Collections, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1859-01-18">1859-01-18</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, National Government, State Government, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-08">August 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A8520T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>George Imboden confidentially writes John H. McCue, asking McCue to garner
                    support for John Baldwin as the nominee to the Court of Appeals. Imboden also
                    discusses the upcoming Congressional elections and the possibility of a
                    convention.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1859-01-18"><abbr expan="January">Jay</abbr> 18/59</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear John</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I drop you a few lines in a business point of view" there is a great stir in this
                    part of the world in regards to the election of <add hand="h1" place="inline"
                    >a</add> Judge of the Court of Appeals. We have been at work during the past few
                    days in getting up a <hi rend="underline">call</hi> for <del hand="h1">of</del>
                    John Baldwin, you will see this, in the paper I send you. We had but a few days
                    to get signers to the call. Baldwin has consented to run -- and I want <hi
                        rend="underline">you</hi> to get up a demonstration in his <orig reg="favor"
                        >favour</orig> in advance of Robinson. Robinson has announced himself a
                    candidate, I had a talk with Baldwin this morning and told him I was going to
                    write you, and he requested me to say to you, to see Whitehead in regard to the
                    matter of course you must not tell W. this, if you can get up a paper and get as
                    many signers as possible, and send it to me I will have it <pb n="2"/>published.
                    I think that if the friends of <abbr expan="Baldwin">B.</abbr> do their duty he
                    will be Elected beyond all doubt, there will be Robinson from Albemarle Parker
                    from Frederick <unclear>Jim</unclear> Barbour, and <hi rend="underline">perhaps</hi>
                    <abbr expan="Thomas">Thos.</abbr> J. Michie" So you see there will be a lively
                    time" John I want Baldwin elected on various grounds in the first place he is
                    the best qualified man in the district, 2<hi rend="underline">
                        <hi rend="super">nd</hi>
                    </hi> it would suit him, and third it would be a great thing for us <hi
                        rend="underline">small fry</hi> to get him out of the way, <orig
                        reg="though">tho</orig> you may think this a sinister motive, but let that
                    be as it may it is human nature and <orig reg="can't">cant</orig> be helped"</p>

                <p>We have a <unclear>sick</unclear> time in the Tenth Session for Congress Jim
                    Skinner to Harman J S <unclear>Harris</unclear> and a man by the name of Newman
                    from Rockingham are all out for Congress, and we will have a fine fight, if the
                    democracy do not call <pb n="3"/>a convention in self <orig reg="defense"
                        >defence</orig> I think the opposition do not intend to hold a convention,
                    but the democracy are becoming alarmed in this county" they have good reason for
                    it, if Harman and Skinner both run they will divide the vote and by that means
                    will electe John S. Harris, and they both Swear they will run. I <orig
                        reg="don't">dont</orig> care a <unclear>straw</unclear> who is elected <orig
                        reg="though">tho</orig>, I will vote for Harman"</p>

                <p>The only danger of the opposition<hi rend="super">s</hi> holding a convention is
                    this, if we hold a convention it will force the democracy into, a convention and
                    of course they will elect their man, and as it is, we have the choice of the
                    democracy and can elect the man we wish, otherwise a man from Rockingham would
                    get the nomination, and thereby we would <orig reg="lose">loose</orig> the
                    representative from this <abbr expan="county">Co</abbr>. Well John I was sorry
                    in looking over <pb n="4"/>the proceedings of the Nelson meeting to appoint
                    delegates to the Richmond Convention, not to see the name of my friend John H
                    McCue" and I want you to explain this matter. I would like to give you some of
                    my <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> in regard to the nominating an opposition ticket but have
                    not the time now, but will do so soon. I want to write you a long letter and
                    give you all the news from this county.</p>

                <p>I am going to Elizza's wedding on thursday" give my best love to <abbr
                        expan="Cousin">Coz.</abbr> Liz" and the little Boys and Kiss the little
                    girls for me. I will come to see you before spring</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>from your friend</salute>
                    <signed>
                        <hi rend="underline">GW.Imboden</hi>
                    </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">P. S. You must not fail to attend to this matter" burn
                        this letter after reading<lb/>GW.I</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
