<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A9603"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A9603">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta: John D. Imboden to Annie Lockett, December
                    1, 1870</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta john d imboden to annie lockett, december 1 1870</title>
        <author>Imboden, John D.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A9603</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502765</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: John D. Imboden to Annie Lockett, December 1, 1870</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta john d imboden to annie lockett, december 1 1870</title>
            <author>John D. Imboden</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: John D. Imboden Papers,
                            1831-1895, Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library,
                            University of Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1870-12-01">1870-12-01</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2007-03-28">2007-03-28</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A9603T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Imboden writes to Annie, who has accepted his offer of marriage, about his social
                    life in New York with his two daughters. He also discusses several other family
                    members, and his plan to return to Virginia for a visit.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1870-12-01">Dec. 1, 1870</date>
                        <name type="place"><abbr expan="New">N.</abbr> York</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My own little darling,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I have no reply to my last two letters - only your answer to my Keysville letter
                    - but no matter, I am sure you have some good excuse for the delay, and I will
                    not scold you, nor deprive myself of the pleasure of writing to you again.</p>

                <p>Unless I dwell upon the old theme of telling you over &amp; over again how
                    much I am in love with you, I have not much of interest to write about, as the
                    doings of these Yankees <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> interest any of us much. I
                    occupy most all my spare time with <hi rend="underline">our</hi> daughters -
                    Jennie &amp; Russie. They are enjoying themselves immensely. Two or three
                    nights of the week I take them to some theatre. The other evenings are spent in
                    returning visits. They have had quite as many calls as they can conveniently
                    return, and several invitations to <unclear>dismiss</unclear>.</p>

                <pb n="2"/>

                <p>With their quiet Virginia notions and manners, they felt a little nervous at the
                    prospect of force &amp; ceremony of <abbr expan="New York">N.Y.</abbr>
                    dinner parties, but the experiences of a couple of weeks has worn it all off,
                    &amp; they say now "they <orig reg="aren't">aint</orig> a bit afraid of
                    Yanks." Really they are meeting with so much kindness from my friends here, that
                    they think it would be delightful to live in <abbr expan="New">N.</abbr> York.</p>

                <p>Today they <add hand="h1" place="inline">saw</add>
                    <del hand="h1">say</del> more fine jewelry &amp; rich plate than they had
                    ever dreamed existed. Mr Tiffany the millionaire jeweler of <abbr
                        expan="New York">N.Y.</abbr> is an acquaintance of mine. He called on the
                    girls night before last, and was so kind as to come around this morning and take
                    them through his establishment. Amongst hundreds of things he showed them was
                    one diamond set, price fifty thousand dollars gold. A solitaire diamond $10,000.
                    A pearl necklace $12,000. A sapphire $4500. An emerald $5500. As Mr. Tiffany is
                    a bachelor of 50 years of age, I have urged Russie to "set her cap," so that you
                    and I may have a rich son-in-law here to visit.</p>

                <pb n="3"/>

                <p>How much I wish you were <hi rend="underline">now</hi> my dear little wifey, and
                    along with us here - it would add so much to my happiness, &amp; I am sure
                    you <add hand="h1" place="inline">would</add>
                    <del hand="h1">will</del> enjoy with a keen relish the pleasure of all the
                    novelties &amp; sights of the great metropolis. However these girls will get
                    so well "posted up" that next spring when they accompany you on your bridal trip
                    they can turn the tables, and matronize <hi rend="underline">Mama</hi>, instead
                    of being matronized by the <hi rend="underline">old</hi> lady! As is usually the
                    case.</p>

                <p>I look with great interest for a letter giving an account of your triumphs at the
                    Concert &amp; the wedding. I expect to hear that ever so many young fellows
                    have fallen victims to your fascinations, and are pleading most eloquently with
                    you to give up "that old widower" and cleave unto them. But you won't do any
                    such thing, will you? Did you deliver my message to the bride, that you were
                    soon to follow her good example?</p>

                <pb n="4"/>

                <p>I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know why sister Lou <orig reg="don't">dont</orig>
                    write again. And it is time I had a letter from that other pretty sister at
                    Tallahassee, unless she is mad that you <add hand="h1" place="inline">are</add>
                    taking the start of her. Well you know I tried to explain to her that if she had
                    only been at home last summer, <hi rend="underline">she</hi> would have been the
                    one, but that in her absence I fell an easy victim to the other fair charmer,
                    and it is now too late to mend the matter. I hope she is reconciled to it and
                    will forgive my precipitancy &amp; write to me. By the way turn over your
                    claims on that young Cotton Broker to her. May be he will feel that "one of the
                    name is as good as the same," and may thus escape dying of a broken heart.</p>

                <p>Bless your dear heart what would I not give tonight to sit by you a half hour and
                    get half a dozen of those sweet maidenly kisses, on the memory of which I have
                    lived now nearly three weeks. I do wish I had your picture to look at and kiss,
                    but how is a picture to be obtained away off in Mecklenburg? Impossible I know.</p>

                <p>I hope it will not be long before I see you. I expect <abbr expan="Colonel"
                    >Col</abbr> Flournoy here on Monday. Hope we will soon return to Virginia, and
                    that I will spend some weeks in Mecklenburg &amp; Brunswick Combining
                    business &amp; love making during some of the Cold dreary time intervening
                    before my happiness is crowned. When you get home I will <hi rend="underline"
                        >expect</hi> a letter by <hi rend="underline">every</hi> mail. With love to
                    all.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>I am always yours with my whole heart</salute>
                    <signed>J.D.I.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
