<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A9607"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A9607">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta: John D. Imboden to Annie Lockett, December
                    12, 1870</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta john d imboden to annie lockett, december 12 1870</title>
        <author>Imboden, John D.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A9607</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502769</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: John D. Imboden to Annie Lockett, December 12, 1870</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta john d imboden to annie lockett, december 12 1870</title>
            <author>John D. Imboden</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: John D. Imboden Papers,
                            1831-1895, Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library,
                            University of Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1870-12-12">1870-12-12</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Women, Economy</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2007-03-28">2007-03-28</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A9607T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Imboden teases Annie about Miss Parke and a Long Island heiress who has been
                    pursuing him. He also mentions that his business in the coming months will
                    concentrate on land sales between Norfolk and Danville.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1870-12-12">Monday Dec 12 /70</date>
                        <name type="place"><abbr expan="New York">N.Y.</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My own most darling,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know when you will be at home again, but I reckon
                    you will not object to find this letter there when you come, even if it should
                    be several days old.</p>

                <p>I write with the more pleasure to you as my hand is in from writing a long letter
                    to Miss Parke Perkins. Now wouldn't you like to see my letter to her? or at
                    least know its contents? If I thought it would make you really jealous, I would
                    send you a copy, for I like to see a jealous woman sometimes. But as a copy
                    would be very long I will give you the substance. I wrote to tell her how much
                    her poems were admired by several literary people to whom they were submitted. I
                    had to tell her what each one <pb n="2"/> said, about each little poem (three in
                    all) and as they said a great many pretty things - and I wished to say some
                    pretty things too it made a long letter. Then I had to tell her where I meant to
                    have them published. Then the news &amp; gossip of <abbr expan="New York"
                        >N.Y.</abbr> took up a page or two and then I told her that I had made up my
                    mind to get married soon and wanted to know what she thought of it, with her
                    peculiar notions on that old institution matrimony. I told her if she had been a
                    marrying woman, as she ought to have been when I first knew her, she would have
                    caught me before I ever saw my other sweet heart who is now to be my wife - but
                    the gig is all up now - it is too late. How often will you kiss me when we meet
                    for telling you all this?</p>

                <p>When Miss Parke's Poems come out I will send you a copy. They <pb n="3"/> are
                    mighty pretty.</p>

                <p>Here I have been running on without telling you I have been sick all day. Took
                    Cold Saturday night, &amp; have not been to my office since. Getting better
                    and hope to be out to <del hand="h1">day</del> morrow as usual.</p>

                <p>Am going with Jennie &amp; Russie to see the Black Crook on Thursday night.
                    Wish you were here to go with us. By the way I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig>
                    think I have mentioned before that the ugliest old maid I ever saw, who has
                    $300,000 in her own right is making the way easy for me if I am matrimonially
                    inclined that way. Previous engagements out of the way I <orig reg="don't"
                    >dont</orig> think the three hundred thousand would be an equivalent for the
                    ugliness. She lives on Long Island and gives the most pressing invitations to
                    come out often &amp; see her, &amp; spend my Sundays there!</p>

                <pb n="4"/>

                <p>I am now a little hopeful that I will get back to Richmond next week, not to
                    return to <abbr expan="New York">N.Y.</abbr> for a long time. I want now to
                    direct my labours to the Country between Danville and Norfolk for several weeks.</p>

                <p>When you write to Sister Ella tell her I am as mad as a hornet at her long
                    neglect of my letter. She has not written me a line.</p>

                <p>Bless your little heart how I do want to see you, and put my arms around that
                    little waist till you pant about it, and then kiss the panting lips till they
                    smile.</p>

                <p>I <orig reg="won't">wont</orig> write you any long letters till I get another
                    from you. All this love making on <hi rend="underline">one</hi> side won't do.
                    You must say a little bit of it yourself. Now good night.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Give my love to all, and believe me as ever devotedly yours</salute>
                    <signed>JD Imboden</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
