<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A9615"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A9615">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta: John P. Lightner to Kate Armentrout,
                    December 15, 1860</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta john p lightner to kate armentrout, december 15 1860</title>
        <author>Lightner, John P.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A9615</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502777</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: John P. Lightner to Kate Armentrout, December 15, 1860</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta john p lightner to kate armentrout, december 15 1860</title>
            <author>John P. Lightner</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William Brand Papers, Albert and
                            Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1860-12-15">1860-12-15</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Patriotism, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A9615T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Lightner's letter to Kate mostly centers on news of friends and family and his
                    hopes to leave Washington College for the Christmas holidays. He briefly
                    mentions his distaste for "disunion by lots."</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1860-12-15">Dec. 15<hi rend="super">th</hi>, 1860</date>
                        <name type="place">Washington College</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Friend;</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I hope you have not become impatient, as I have been somewhat remiss in not
                    answering your very welcomed epistle.</p>

                <p>I was very glad to receive a letter from you so replete, with good sentiments,
                    &amp; also exemplary.</p>

                <p>I suppose you hail the new world this morning, as well as myself. I was rather
                    surprised, when I saw the earth robed in white. I am afraid it will blast my
                    hopes, for I anticipated a fine time on Christmas, <add hand="h1" place="inline"
                        >if</add> I get out of this prison. I expect to leave here next Saturday or
                    whip some of the <abbr expan="Professors">Profs.</abbr> as you know I am a great
                    fighting character speaking ironically. I have not <pb n="2"/>been very well for
                    the last week or two. I had a very bad cold, but I think so much about
                    Christmas, I believe it has nearly left me. I think leap year must be doing its
                    duty, &amp; its whole duty, from the number of weddings you have attended,
                    or rather the number of marriages that have taken place, in your immediate
                    vicinity. I was rather surprised when you told me of J. Rubush's marriage. I
                    hope they will have a happy sail on the Sea of life. Miss R.P. is not married
                    yet. I think the report must have been without foundation. I would be a great
                        <hi rend="underline">looking</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">somebody</hi> to get married <orig reg="wouldn't"
                    >would'nt</orig> I? Any one that is so diffident as I am, should never think of
                    such a thing.</p>

                <p><pb n="3"/>I ask pardon for inviting you to the fair &amp; not telling you
                    when it was to be. It was certainly oversight in me, but I hope you will grant
                    my request.</p>

                <p>Miss R.P. was not there very unfortunately, but there were some others present,
                        who<del hand="h1">ich</del> pleased me very much, but I was <hi
                        rend="underline">so bashful</hi>, I did not <unclear>do more</unclear> than
                    speak to them.</p>

                <p>I have never been a visiting but once, since I returned to college, &amp;
                    then I thought every body was looking at me.</p>

                <p>I intended going a visiting to night, but the snow, has broken my arrangements.</p>

                <p>How is <hi rend="underline">cousin</hi> S.P. getting along at C.C. School. I
                    suppose you have a singing-school there, this winter. I <hi rend="underline"
                        >used</hi> to have some fine times <pb n="4"/>at that beloved spot, but I
                    declare I don't have them here. But one year longer, then I'll be through, after
                    this I expect to go South &amp; whip S.C. back into the Union. I am opposed
                    to <hi rend="underline">Disunion</hi> in lots. I have been wishing all day for a
                    good sleigh. I saw one or two pass by my window. I thank you for ever wishing me
                    success, if I should, by the grace of God, enter upon the mission I spoke to you
                    of, which I wished to be kept secret, for special reason.</p>

                <p>We have a very good band of students this year, no drinking which was as common
                    last year, as it well could be.</p>

                <p>Well you must excuse me for this short &amp; badly written letter. I beg to
                    be excused for tardiness in writing. I'm glad to hear that Nicholas is improving
                    so fast.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>I remain your Friend,</salute>
                    <signed>J.P.L.</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript"><pb n="1"/>I'll send you a ticket to the Anniversary of
                        our Society if I can get one.</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
