<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A9620"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A9620">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title id="VShadow" type="main">Augusta: John P. Lightner to Kate Armentrout, June
                    29, 1861</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta john p lightner to kate armentrout, june 29 1861</title>
        <author>Lightner, John P.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A9620</idno>

                <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
                <availability status="public">
                    <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                    <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
                </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
                <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502782</idno>
            </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: John P. Lightner to Kate Armentrout, June 29, 1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta john p lightner to kate armentrout, june 29 1861</title>
            <author>John P. Lightner</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William Brand Papers, Albert and
                            Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <projectDesc>
                <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library,
                    University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
            </projectDesc>
        </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-06-29">1861-06-29</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties, Home Front,
                        National Government, Patriotism, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A9620T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 id="d3" type="summary">
                <p>Lightner sends Kate a description of camp life and especially the religious
                    activities available in camp. He also writes that, although he generally hates
                    war, he believes that the Confederate cause is just, but still hopes that peace
                    will ultimately prevail.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 id="d5" type="letter">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Miss Amanda C. Armentrout, Greenville</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-06-29">June 29<hi rend="super">th</hi></date>
                        <name type="place">Stevens Camp</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Friend;</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I doubt not that you would be glad to hear from your old friend by this time, who
                    is now enjoying the pleasures or miseries of Camp life.</p>

                <p>I am very well at present, was not for several days after, I overlook my company,
                    which is now stationed 4 miles from Martinsburg, Beverly Co. some 6 miles from
                    the Potomac; we are getting pretty close to the Yankees. But the closer we
                    apprach them the faster they retreat. I like camp life very much if it was not
                    for cooking. I wish you could come down &amp; cook for me. I have engaged
                    one young lady to fight for me. She was so kind &amp; patriotic as to offer
                    her services, &amp; of course I could not refuse. I think most of the ladies
                    are more <pb n="2"/>patriotic than some of the Gentlemen. I met with a great
                    many of my old acquaintances in the different regiments stationed here, which
                    makes it more pleasant than it otherwise would be. They all seem very cheerful
                    &amp; lively, and most anxious to come into deadly conflict with their
                    enemy. I know I dont want to fight. I'm a great lover of peace, I would give a
                    million, if I had it, to be in Lincoln's position one day, peace would come, if
                    I could bring it. I abhor the idea of war, &amp; believed once that it was
                    morally wrong on all occasions. But this war is certainly a holy &amp; just
                    one, on our side; the other is none else than unconstitutional, brought on by
                    wicked usurpation of power, but from present indications &amp; from reports
                    now current, the <pb n="3"/>prospect for peace is flattering. I only hope the
                    present Congress will settle the whole affair. It is the will of our maker to
                    have peace at all times, if people would not become so rebellious, he would not
                    chastise so severely as by bringing war upon them. These have been in times past
                    &amp; must needs now be. Two ladies from Washington came to Martinsburg,
                    stated that the Cabinet were writing out a proclamation of peace. I dont <add
                        hand="h1" place="inline">know</add> how they know it, but suppose they had
                    some good reason for believing so.</p>

                <p>There are some hard customers here, care for nothing whatever, themselves nor any
                    one else.</p>

                <p>I would rather be at College about this time, at my studies. I hated worse to
                    leave them, than I hated to leave my friends. I had hoped the whole time <pb
                        n="4"/>&amp; still hope that this terrible calamity will be averted from
                    our once glorious country, but <add hand="h1" place="inline">now</add> agitated
                    &amp; dissevered. I was well taken care of from Staunton to Winchester by
                    two young ladies, I <add hand="h1" place="inline">
                        <orig reg="reckon">recon</orig>
                    </add>
                    <unclear>recon</unclear> you think they had a heap to do. I did not start as
                    soon from home as I had expected to do, from some mismanagement. I have not seen
                        <add hand="h1" place="inline">John</add> but once since I've been here; went
                    over this morning to see him, but this was wash day with him. He is well, or at
                    least I've heard nothing the contrary. 3 of our men were shot a few days ago,
                    one by <unclear>a</unclear> Yankee &amp; the other two accidentally. All of
                    them still living but badly wounded. We have religious services in our company
                    every night, conducted by different members of the company, had two sermons last
                    Sabbath. Have no regular chaplain, as I know of. You must excuse this short
                    &amp; badly written epistle. I have now an opportunity <pb n="1"/>of sending
                    it <del hand="h1" rend="none"/> to watch for opportunities to send mail as the
                    mail is not regularly brought. You must remember me. My love to whom you please.
                    Direct to Martinsburg, Care of Capt J.J. White. Write soon. It will be a great
                    pleasure to me to hear from you any time. I have heard nothing from the
                    neighborhood since I've been here.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>I remain your friend sincerely</salute>
                    <signed>Jno. P. Lightner</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
