<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A9635"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A9635"> 
<teiHeader type="migrated"> 

    <fileDesc> 
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta: James W. Vines to Kate Armentrout, September 12, 1861</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta james w vines to kate armentrout, september 12 1861</title>
        <author>Vines, James W.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt> 
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp> 
          <name>Jaime Martinez </name> 
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp> 
          <name>Jaime Martinez</name> 
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt> 

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num>kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt> 
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher> 
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace> 

        <idno type="VCDH">A9635.xml</idno> 

        <!--
<availability> 
<p>Publicly accessible </p> 
<p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p> 
<p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p> 
</availability>
--> 
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2002">2002</date> 
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502797</idno>
      </publicationStmt> 
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt> 
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt> 

      <sourceDesc> 
        <biblFull> 
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: James W. Vines to Kate Armentrout, September 12, 1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta james w vines to kate armentrout, september 12 1861</title>
            <author>James W. Vines</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt> 
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt> 
          <extent>3 pages</extent> 
          <publicationStmt> 
            <publisher/> 
            <pubPlace/> 
            <date value=""/> 
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William Brand Papers, Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia</idno>
          </publicationStmt> 
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt> 
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt> 
        </biblFull> 
      </sourceDesc> 
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc> 

    <profileDesc> 
      <creation>
        <date value="1861-09-12">1861-09-12</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage> 
      <textClass> 
        <keywords> 
          <term>Death/Casualties, Desertion/Leave, Family, Women</term> 
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords> 
      </textClass> 
    </profileDesc> 

    <revisionDesc> 
      <change> 
        <date value="2007-04-02">2007-04-02</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>proofed</resp>
          <name>Josh Botts</name>
        </respStmt> 
        <item/> 
      </change> 
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc> 
  </teiHeader> 

<text id="A9635T">
<front id="d2">
<div1 type="summary" id="d3">
<p>Vines writes to Kate with news of friends and family. He also complains that he was unlikely to receive a furlough before April.</p> 
</div1> 
</front> 

<body id="d4">
<div1 type="letter" id="d5">
<head>
    <name type="recipient">Miss Amanda C. Armentrout<lb/>Greenville<lb/>Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr> <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr></name> 
<name type="place">Camp Near <orig reg="Centreville">Centresville</orig></name> 
</head>

<opener>
<dateline>
<date value="1861-09-12">Sept 12<hi rend="super">th</hi> /61</date> 
</dateline> 
<salute>Dear Friend Kate</salute> 
</opener> 

<p>I received your kind &amp; welcome letter some three or four weeks since and I take this opportunity to answer it. I was very glad to hear from you and to hear that you were all well, you said all the girls looked well except Snake you named one in <orig reg="particular">perticular</orig> you called her my dear Maggie well if you say she is my dear, it must be so I guess you know, give her my love. Tell Snake I can very easily account for her looking badly she has parted with some one and she is grieving herself about him. I <orig reg="can't">cant</orig> <pb n="2"/> say who it is unless it is Mr <unclear>Quarles</unclear> tell her he is well and I hope it <orig reg="won't">wont</orig> be long before she may have the happy privilege of seeing him. I long to see that happy time when we all may be permitted to return to our homes, you <orig reg="can't">cant</orig> imagine how I would like to come home. I have tried to get a furlough but there was no earthly chance so I have come to the conclusion to wait patiently until next <orig reg="April">Aprile</orig> if I am spared to see it then I can come home, but I hope this fuss may be settled long before then. Kate I suppose you heard about Tom Supple <orig reg="losing">loosing</orig> all the letters that was sent by him &amp; never have been heard from since, we scolded him a <orig reg="great deal">greadeal</orig> about it but I suppose he did not <orig reg="lose">loose</orig> them intentionally <pb n="3"/> therefore we will have to forgive him. I <orig reg="received">recieved</orig> a letter from home yesterday the <orig reg="first">firse</orig> one for more than two weeks and was very sorry to hear of F Campbell's death poor fellow he suffered a <orig reg="great deal">greateal</orig> but I hope he is now at rest I would like to have come and see him before he died but that <orig reg="privilege">privilage</orig> was denied me. I think it very hard that no one are allowed to go home under any circumstance except on a sick furlough. I <orig reg="pitied">pittied</orig> James Trotter he tried several time to get a furlough to go home and see his Father before he died but there was no chance, well Kate as it is now about ten <orig reg="o'clock">oclock</orig>, and the candle is about out I will have to bring these few lines to a close give my love to all the Family &amp; all inquiring friend excuse all mistakes nothing more at this time.</p>

<closer>
<salute>from your true friend</salute> 
<signed>James W Vines</signed> 
<seg type="postscript"><pb n="1"/>Kate I had a talk with your dear friend John Lightner to night I see him nearly every day he looks very well <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> you wish you could see him. Write to me again as soon as <orig reg="convenient">convenent</orig>. JWV
<name type="recipient"><pb n="4"/>Miss Kate Armentrout<lb/>Rose Dale</name>
</seg>
</closer> 
</div1> 
</body> 
</text> 
</TEI.2>