<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A9648"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="A9648">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title id="VShadow" type="main">Augusta: John P. Lightner[?] to unknown [fragment]</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta john p lightner to unknown fragment</title>
        <author>Lightner, John P.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A9648</idno>

                <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
                <availability status="public">
                    <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                    <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
                </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
                <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502810</idno>
            </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: John P. Lightner[?] to unknown [fragment]</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta john p lightner to unknown fragment</title>
            <author>John P. Lightner</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William Brand Papers, Albert and
                            Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <projectDesc>
                <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library,
                    University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
            </projectDesc>
        </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value=""/>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties, Family</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2007-04-03">2007-04-03</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A9648T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 id="d3" type="summary">
                <p>This fragment of a letter seems to have been written by John P. Lightner to a
                    member of the Armentrout or Brand family before the war. The letter discusses
                    church affairs and the death of a brother.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 id="d5" type="letter">


                <p>the people around here were very liberal sending Clothing Provision and what
                    money they could get. Is Carter still with you. I <orig reg="haven't">havent</orig>
                    <orig reg="forgotten">forgoten</orig> what a time I use to have trying to boss
                    him around. I <orig reg="suppose">supose</orig> he is a very handsome Chap, does
                    he still catch fish? How is Mrs Watson and the girls. Does Mr Strickler still
                    Preach at Tinkling. I remember how I did hate to go to that Church. I <orig
                        reg="don't">dont</orig> think the people are so <orig reg="high-minded"
                        >hyminded</orig> and proud out here. I was at Waveland last Sabbath and I
                    liked it so well I went back that night, to the Presbyterian Church the preacher
                    reminded me a little of Mr. S. he spoke so much like him but I felt more at home
                    than I ever did at Tinkling we have been <orig reg="attending">tending</orig>
                    meetings generaly there was a protracted meeting held at our <pb n="2"/> nearest
                    Church 2 weeks, &amp; there was only one joiner, the Methodist preacher will
                    hold his meeting in a few weeks. It is true my friend our dear Brother is no
                    more it was so hard for us to give him up he was such a dear good brother and
                    yet I can <orig reg="scarcely">scarsely</orig> imagine he is no more, it was
                    such a sudden trial for us. We were looking for them the next week, but they had
                    set the day it just two weeks from the day he died, it was the 26<hi
                        rend="underline">
                        <hi rend="super">th</hi>
                    </hi> of <abbr expan="October">Oct</abbr>. he <orig reg="attended"
                    >atended</orig> the Fair two days, and was complaining there. he went out to
                    Grandmas from there he went to Mr Bayleys &amp; took sick <abbr
                        expan="Doctor">Dr.</abbr> said he had Billious Fever he did not complain
                    only of weakness, he would tell Bechie he <orig reg="wasn't">wasnt</orig> so
                    bad. she was with him, that was one consolation. they tell us he died without a
                        <orig reg="struggle">strugle</orig>.</p>

                <p>I hope we will all be prepared when death comes to meet him in Heaven. We have
                    lost so many dear ones, but it was hardest for me to give him up. We have felt
                    so lonely and sad but the neighbors are so kind to us. They tell us if we go
                    back there we <orig reg="won't">wont</orig> be satisfied but some there think we
                    had better go back but we are all very well satisfied.</p>

                <p>We often talk and think we would love to be back there but think it best to stay
                    out here as we can get along very <orig reg="easily">easely</orig>. I guess
                    Bechie will come out in the spring if she can get company. I <orig reg="can't"
                        >cant</orig> wait I want to see her so badly. Well I will close. hope you
                    will write soon and give me all the news for I think of you all so much. Was
                    much <orig reg="obliged">oblige</orig> for that <orig reg="receipt"
                    >recipt</orig> &amp; money. I gave 50 of it to the Church.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>from your true friend</salute>
                    <signed/>
                    <seg type="postscript">Please excuse this scribbled <orig reg="affair"
                        >afair</orig> will try do better in the future. Kiss your four little ones
                        for me. My love to all <orig reg="inquiring">enquiring</orig>, if any.</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
