<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A9901"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A9901">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: John D. Imboden to Annie Lockett,
                    September 29, 1870</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county john d imboden to annie lockett, september 29 1870</title>
        <author>Imboden, J.D.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A9901</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502844</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: John D. Imboden to Annie Lockett, September 29, 1870</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county john d imboden to annie lockett, september 29 1870</title>
            <author>J.D. Imboden</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: J.D. Imboden to Miss Annie, Sept.
                            29, 1870, John D. Imboden Papers, University of Virginia Library,
                            Accession Numbers 38-23, 580, 599, 2983a</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1870-09-29">1870-09-29</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Women, Family, Economy</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A9901T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Imboden writes to a young woman in Virginia and apologizes for not being able to
                    come viisit her as early as he promised because business has kept him in New
                    York.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1870-09-29">Sept. 29, 1870</date>
                        <name type="place"><abbr expan="New York [City]">N.Y.</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear, dear Miss Annie.</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I have time for only a very short reply to your long sweet letter of the 26<hi
                        rend="super">th</hi> which was <abbr expan="received">rec'd</abbr> today. I
                    had set my heart on writing to you a long, long letter tonight, but a little
                    while ago I <abbr expan="received">rec'd</abbr> a telegram from my brother in
                    Richmond that makes it necessary for me to go up the Hudson about 100 miles
                    tonight. I will try to return tomorrow night - and I hope will get off to
                    Richmond on Saturday night - though of this I am not absolutely certain.</p>

                <p>I lost several days from business lask week by being sick and it has delayed me
                    here much longer than I expected. I need not tell you how anxious I am to get
                    back to old <abbr expan="Virginia">V<hi rend="underline">
                            <hi rend="super">a</hi>
                        </hi></abbr> and especially to that remote and inaccessable old county of
                    Mecklenburg.</p>

                <p><pb n="2"/>Your special pleading that you were only bound to answer questions in
                        <hi rend="underline">September</hi> and at no other time won't hold good.
                    The intent and meaning of your refusal to answer when I was with you was that
                    you must have <hi rend="underline">until</hi>
                    <abbr expan="September">Sept.</abbr> when I expected to be again in your county.
                    Now the additional time that circumstances have forced me to defer my visit,
                    only gives you more time for deliberation and me a stronger right to insist all
                    the more earnestly for an answer. So don't flatter yourself that I am going be
                    put off on any such special pleading.</p>

                <p>I never was so sick of New York in my life, and feel that I would not give one
                    week with you at Lombardy Grove for a year of life here, unless you were here
                    with me - then I could stand it. <pb n="3"/> I am too tired &amp; too
                    hurried to make love to you a single bit in this letter. I wrote you an 8 page
                    letter on Sunday &amp; have it in my pocket now. When I come to read it over
                    Sunday morning I thought you would laugh at me, when you read it, as a love sick
                    swain and I wouldn't send it. May be I'll keep &amp; show it to you.</p>

                <p>Yes indeed I will miss "sister" Lou terribly when I am again at <abbr
                        expan="Lombardy">L.</abbr> Grove, unless you make me forget her by your own
                    sweet ways towards me. Take good care of that "neck." You mustn't take such mad
                    cab rides, especially if you get to musing &amp; forget yourself. I wish you
                    had told me what conclusions you came to in your self examinations your heart on
                    those solitary rides. I would give anything in the world to know.</p>

                <p><pb n="4"/>You must not conclude that I am not a man of my word in failing to
                    return to <abbr expan="Virginia">V<hi rend="underline">
                            <hi rend="super">a</hi>
                        </hi></abbr> in <abbr expan="September">Sept</abbr>. The business that
                    detains me here is of deep concern to your part of the State, and one day may be
                    of deeper concern to you personally. New York is slow place to conduct
                    negotiations. I have come here sometimes to stay 3 or 4 days and have been
                    detained as many weeks.</p>

                <p>My next will be from Richmond &amp; will tell you <hi rend="underline"
                    >when</hi> you will see me. Please answer this to <abbr expan="Richmond"
                    >R.</abbr> and mark it "personal" on the outside or my brother will open
                    &amp; read it.</p>

                <p>I am so glad you are well again. Do take good care of yourself. And when you
                    write to Sister Lou, give her my love. And now with kind regards to all at <abbr
                        expan="Lombardy">L.</abbr> Grove, and an apology for this hastily dashed off
                    letter.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>I am with all my heart yours</salute>
                    <signed>J.D. Imboden</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">I may see you before your reply reaches <abbr
                            expan="Richmond">R.</abbr> as I expect to hurry to you as soon as
                        possible.</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
