<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="AD9000"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="AD9000">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title id="VShadow" type="main">Augusta County: Diary of Sarah Cordelia Wright (1853-1854)</title>
    <title type="sort">augusta county diary of sarah cordelia wright 1853 1854</title>
    <author>Wright, Sarah Cordelia</author>
    <editor/>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
     <name>VCDH Staff</name>
     <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
     <name>Susanna Michele Lee, Virginia Center for Digital History</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>

   <extent>
    <num type="kilobytes"> 63 kilobytes</num>
   </extent>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

    <idno type="VCDH">AD9000</idno>

    <!--
<availability> 
<p>Publicly accessible </p> 
<p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p> 
<p>copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p> 
</availability>
-->
    <availability status="public">
     <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
      Virginia</p>
     <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
    </availability>
    <date value="2002">2002</date>
    <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500339</idno>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <p>Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
   </seriesStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
    <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
   </seriesStmt>
   <notesStmt>
    <note/>
   </notesStmt>

   <sourceDesc>
    <biblFull>
     <titleStmt>
      <title>Augusta County: Diary of Sarah Cordelia Wright</title>
      <title level="m"/>
      <title type="sort">augusta county diary of sarah cordelia wright</title>
      <author>Sarah Cordelia Wright</author>
      <editor/>
      <respStmt>
       <resp/>
       <name/>
      </respStmt>
     </titleStmt>
     <editionStmt>
      <p> </p>
     </editionStmt>
     <extent>xx pages</extent>
     <publicationStmt>
      <publisher/>
      <pubPlace/>
      <date value=""/>
      <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Stuart Hall Alumnae Association</idno>
     </publicationStmt>
     <seriesStmt>
      <p/>
     </seriesStmt>
     <notesStmt>
      <note>
       <p>The entry previously listed as "Saturday 12th" and placed between February 12 and 28,
        1853, has been tagged as Saturday, February 26, 1853. The entry previously listed as
        "Saturday 27th" is probably Sunday. Sarah Cordelia Wright wrote the "introduction" to her
        diary. Wright's granddaughter, Annie Hoge Lockett, transcribed and annontated the diary. All
        footnotes are the work of Ms. Lockett unless otherwise noted.</p>
      </note>
     </notesStmt>
    </biblFull>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <encodingDesc>
   <projectDesc>
    <p>Used with permission from Stuart Hall Alumnae Association</p>
   </projectDesc>
  </encodingDesc>

  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <dateRange from="1853-01-01" to="1854-07">1853-01-01 - 1854-07</dateRange>
   </creation>
   <langUsage>
    <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
   </langUsage>
   <handList>
    <hand id="h1"/>
   </handList>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term/>
     <term>American Civil War</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>

  <revisionDesc>
   <change>
    <date value="2002">Winter 2002</date>
    <respStmt>
     <resp/>
     <name>Susanna Michele Lee</name>
    </respStmt>
    <item>Proofread for typographical errors.</item>
   </change>
   <change>
    <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
    <respStmt>
     <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia
      Library</name>
     <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
    </respStmt>
    <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD
     (uva-dl-tei).</item>
   </change>
  </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="AD9000T">

  <front id="d2">
   <div1 id="d3" type="section">
    <head>Biography <!-- <ref>AD9000bio</ref> -->
    </head>
    <p/>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">


   <div1 id="AD9000int" type="introduction">
    <head>Introduction <!-- <ref>AD9000int</ref> -->
    </head>
    <div2 id="d6" type="section">

     <!-- <ref>Family, Women</ref> -->


     <p>Born in Guyandotte<ref n="1" target="wright1">1</ref> on the Ohio River, the 12th day of
      May, 1837. At the age of five, we removed to Charleston<ref n="2" target="wright2">2</ref>,
      Kanawha Co. (on the <abbr expan="Kanawha">Ka.</abbr> river, 50 miles above the mouth of the
      Ohio) where I remained until April, 1850, when I left <abbr expan="Charleston">C.</abbr> for
      the Sweet Springs<ref n="3" target="wright3">3</ref> Monroe Co. I remained here until
      September of the same <abbr expan="year">yr</abbr>. when I left my friends bound for the <abbr
       expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> Female Institute<ref n="4" target="wright4">4</ref>, Staunton.
      Where I have spent the last three years, except the months of July and August, which have been
      spent with my dear parents &amp; friends at home [Charleston].</p>

     <p>The first year of my stay in <abbr expan="Staunton">S.</abbr> I lived with my aunt<ref n="5"
       target="wright5">5</ref>, but the next, I boarded at the <abbr
       expan="Virginia Female Institute">V. F. I</abbr>.<ref n="6" target="wright6">6</ref> The
      first part of the session, my roommates<ref n="7" target="wright7">7</ref> were, S. A.
      Crawford, M. P. Bailey, &amp; M. Robertson. I changed my room towards the last of the
      session, my roommates were then L. Gray, B. Harrison, Julia Clagett, B. Stuart. The next
      session my roommates were M. Custis, E. Browne, S. Patrick. No. 3, Fannie Smith, Sallie
      Stephenson roomed with us the other part of the session. I could enjoy myself very much here
      if I did not get any marks, (but good ones) but it makes me feel unhappy on account of my
      parents for I know that their greatest wish is to see me grow up intelligent, &amp;
      beloved by all.</p>

    </div2>

   </div1>

   <div1 id="AD90001853" n="1853" type="part">
    <head>1853 <!-- <ref>AD90001853</ref> -->
    </head>

    <div2 id="d8" n="1853-01" type="section">
     <head>January 1853 <!-- <ref>Women, Family, Arts/Leisure</ref> -->
     </head>

     <div3 id="d9" n="1853-01-01" type="entry">
      <head>Jan. 1st 1853</head>
      <p>We have been spending our holy-days<ref n="8" target="wright8">8</ref> down town &amp;
       I have had a very <hi rend="underline">nice</hi> though quiet time; but <hi rend="underline"
        >now</hi> I am obliged to return to the <abbr expan="Virginia Female Institute">V. F.
       I.</abbr> to again prepare for our daily <orig reg="labor">labour</orig>. It is a solemn
       thought when we look back and see another <hi rend="underline">year</hi> has fled, &amp;
       we are one year older than we were the last, we should inquire of our hearts to know if we
       are any better than we were the last. How many of our friends &amp; acquaintances have
       passed from this world, &amp; yet we have been spared. How thankful should we be that we
       have been spared, and should we not <hi rend="underline">show that we are thankful</hi>.</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d10" n="1853-01-08" type="entry">
      <head>Jan. 8th</head>

      <p>I was down town a short while this evening. I called to see Aunt and from there went to the
        dagerian<ref n="9" target="wright9">9</ref> gallery to have my likeness taken: It is not
       thought to be very good, &amp; I do not expect to keep it. When I got back to the V. F.
       I. <hi rend="underline">I</hi> found the girls looking out for my coming, &amp; eager to
       hear from their friends. I found all <hi rend="underline">my</hi> friends laid up with bad
       colds, but could not stay long with them, but promised to call again soon.</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d11" n="1853-01-15" type="entry">
      <head>Jan. 15th</head>

      <p>I left the Institute about eleven o'clock, to make another attempt for my Dagero. I first
       called at Aunt's, but could find no one to go with me but Sallie, but I met M. K. on the
       street, &amp; she went with me down there, &amp; finding cousin Bec<ref n="10"
        target="wright10">10</ref> there left me. After making several unsuccessful attempts, Mr. K.
       at last got one to suit.<ref n="11" target="wright11">11</ref> I then returned to Aunt's and
       finding dinner ready staid of course, &amp; enjoyed myself very much until three when I
       begun to think of returning home. Accordingly I started &amp; cousin T.<ref n="12"
        target="wright12">12</ref> insisted on <orig reg="accompanying">accompaning</orig> me,
       although I refused to let him, yet he vowed he <hi rend="underline">would</hi>, so I gave up,
       before I reached the yard I saw the girls looking out for me, to see what I had brought back
       with me &amp; each one I met wanted to know if I had been down street, &amp; who I
       saw, &amp; many other questions of a <orig reg="similar">similer</orig> kind. As soon as
       I reached my room, my roommates had the greatest curiosity to know what I had in my bundle;
       but I would not satisfy their curiosity until after tea.</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d12" n="1853-01-20" type="entry">
      <head>Thursday Jan. 20th</head>

      <p>After school we were told by our teacher that we were going to attend a lecture on electro
        biology<ref n="13" target="wright13">13</ref> delivered by <abbr expan="Professor"
       >Prof.</abbr> Hall at the town hall: accordingly after tea we started, 21 of us in number,
       besides Mr. and Mrs. P.<ref n="14" target="wright14">14</ref> &amp; Mr. Wheat.<ref n="15"
        target="wright15">15</ref> The lecture was <hi rend="underline">very interesting</hi>
       indeed, as most of the experiments. After staying about two hours, we turned reluctantly
       homewards, &amp; had a very pleasant walk, for it was a lovely night, &amp; the moon
       was shining as bright as day, &amp; the air was very pleasant.</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d13" n="1853-01-29" type="entry">
      <head>Jan. 29th</head>

      <p>This morning we asked Mrs. P. if we could go down town, but she refused us on the plea that
       she did not know what our reports were. I did not care much about going so that I was very
       well satisfied, but the other two, were nearly <orig reg="crazy">
        <hi rend="underline">crasy</hi>
       </orig> to go; they sent to ask Mrs. P. again, &amp; told her she had given others
       permission, &amp; so she finally let us go. Fannie went with us to see Aunt, &amp;
       after dinner Sallie &amp; I went to see Mrs. Points.<ref n="16" target="wright16"
       >16</ref> Adel was spending the day at home, with three of her schoolmates; we staid a little
       while &amp; then went with the girls to the degarian gallery where we met Mr. Wheat, Miss
        Lizzy<ref n="17" target="wright17">17</ref>, &amp; Ellen G.<ref n="18" target="wright18"
        >18</ref> Sallie &amp; I did not stay long, but left the girls there &amp; went back
       to Aunts &amp; staid a little while, &amp; then came back home just about dark.</p>

     </div3>

    </div2>

    <div2 id="d14" n="1853-02" type="section">
     <head>February 1853 <!-- <ref>Family, Women, Arts/Leisure, Church/Religious Activity</ref> -->
     </head>

     <div3 id="d15" n="1853-02-01" type="entry">
      <head>Feb. 1st</head>

      <p>This is the first day of a <hi rend="underline">new <orig reg="month">mounth</orig></hi>,
       the old month has passed away, &amp; it seems to me but yesterday, since the first of
       that <del hand="h1" rend="none"/> the reports are being made off. I wonder what mine is?
       Nothing good I am sure; I fear it is not as good as the last, &amp; oh! how sorry I am
       for that will make Pa feel badly. I think <hi rend="underline">Mrs.</hi> P. might have taken
       those marks<ref n="19" target="wright19">19</ref> off, but I ought not to have expected it,
       for I do not believe she ever took one off <hi rend="underline">for me</hi>. If she did I beg
       her pardon for I do not remember. The day has passed very well <del hand="h1" rend="none"/>
       cousin V. &amp; E. called to see us this evening &amp; staid about half hour, after
       which <hi rend="underline">I</hi> had to take a music lesson &amp; the others had to
       walk.</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d16" n="1853-02-05" type="entry">
      <head>Feb. 5th</head>

      <p>We got up this morning, &amp; it was raining. Fannie is very much provoked that she
       cannot go to the D. gallery. After prayers we heard that we were going to have study hours in
       the morning instead of evening; upon the strength of which most of the girls got their
       curiosity raised to the <hi rend="underline">highest</hi> pitch to know what was to be done,
       although they tried to keep it a <orig reg="secret">seacret</orig>, yet it was known to <hi
        rend="underline">more</hi> than <hi rend="underline">two</hi> therefore it was obliged to be
       told to others. We found out though that they intended to celebrate A. G. P.'s<ref n="20"
        target="wright20">20</ref> birthday, in the midst of the bustle, Sallie S. received a box of
        <orig reg="eatables">eatibles</orig> from home; of course the girls in <hi rend="underline"
        >our room</hi> had much <orig reg="rejoicing">rejoycing</orig>; we were eating from the time
       that dinner was over, until supper was ready. After supper we all repaired to the school-room
       where we had tableau's &amp; <orig reg="charades">sherades</orig>, &amp; after they
       were over we had <orig reg="eatables">eatibles</orig> handed round <hi rend="underline"
        >&amp; then</hi> we had a dance, &amp; danced until the bell rung for us to retire.</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d17" n="1853-02-06" type="entry">
      <head>Feb. the 6th</head>

      <p>This is the first Sunday in the <orig reg="month">mounth</orig>, <orig reg="and">an</orig>
       the one for us to attend <hi rend="underline">the</hi> church<ref n="21" target="wright21"
       >21</ref>, but we could not on account of the rain. Mr. Phillips attended with the
       communicants, &amp; of course <hi rend="underline">we</hi> poor sinners did not have any
       service, but we left to do what we pleased: for my part I took my book &amp; sit down to
       read, but did not progress very rapidly, on account of the other girls making so much noise.
       I was reading in a book called Christian Ornaments, a story of Love, Joy, &amp; Peace,
       and found them very interesting indeed. We had service up here at night but Fannie &amp;
       I did not attend, so therefore I cannot say any about the sermon.</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d18" n="1853-02-07" type="entry">
      <head>Feb. 7th Monday</head>

      <p>This is the beginning of a new week. I hope that I will improve more this week than I did
       last week. Miss Weaber (our French teacher) left this morning; I feel sorry for her, for I
       think the girls treated her very unkindly indeed, for most of them left her and I am sure
       they were more to blame than her; she came and bid us (last night in our room &amp; Miss
       F's) goodbye, &amp; when we told the girls this morning, they made quite a fuss. The day
       has passed off very well. I had all my lessons prepared in time. I took one of my new pieces
       this evening "Old folks at home"<ref n="22" target="wright22">22</ref> it is a very pretty
       little piece. We had biscuits for supper tonight, &amp; Miss J. got very angry because
       she could not get any. My week begins today, to clean up the room, much to my sorrow.</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d19" n="1853-02-09" type="entry">
      <head>Wednesday, Feb. 9th</head>

      <p>This is Ash <abbr expan="Wednesday">W'</abbr> and at prayers, Mr. P. informed us that we
       would attend church, which we heard with pleasure. We recited our lessons until 10[:30]
       oclock &amp; then prepared for church. Where we heard a very fine sermon by the Rev. T.
       T. Castleman<ref n="23" target="wright23">23</ref> from Romans 2 chapter &amp; 4 verse.
       Depisest thou the riches of his goodness &amp; forbearance &amp; long suffering; not
       (knowing that the goodness of God leadeth thee to repentance. He spoke in strong terms of
       Gods goodness to us &amp; exhorted us to return his kindness by forsaking all worldly
       things, &amp; turning to him, for his door is open for the sinner; there is no sin <hi
        rend="underline">so great</hi>, no heart <hi rend="underline">so</hi> black that he cannot
       cure all. We had school again in the evening; after school Miss Lizzie took the girls to walk
       on the plank road<ref n="24" target="wright24">24</ref>, but I did not go as I had to take a
       music lesson. F. ran into see Mrs. P. and staid until the girls returned, &amp; Mrs. P.
       was there but I do not believe she saw her.</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d20" n="1853-02-11" type="entry">
      <head>Friday Feb. 11th 1853</head>

      <p>Nothing has happened today worth relating, everything has gone on as usual. Tonight we had
       a note <orig reg="soiree">soree</orig><ref n="25" target="wright25">25</ref> but I do not
       think that any of us displayed much knowledge of the rudiments of music. Mr. E.<ref n="26"
        target="wright26">26</ref> divided the music class into two divisions, &amp; these into
       sections &amp; grades. I am now in the 3rd section 4th grade, but I hope <orig reg="at"
       >a</orig> least to be in the 2nd <abbr expan="section">sec.</abbr> before the end of the
       section, as Mr. E. says we can all be promoted if we will <orig reg="practice"
       >practise</orig> &amp; I intend <hi rend="underline">to Try</hi>.</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d21" n="1853-02-12" type="entry">
      <head>Saturday 12th</head>

      <p>I <orig reg="practiced">practised</orig> an hour &amp; a half this morning, &amp;
       after dinner I received a letter from Nony<ref n="27" target="wright27">27</ref> &amp; a
       paper, &amp; Sallie got one from H. N. in which we received the joyful news of the return
       of William Cox from California.<ref n="28" target="wright28">28</ref> I answered Ma letter
       today that I received last week, in which Ma said that Cousin B's<ref n="29"
        target="wright29">29</ref> health was rapidly declining.</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d22" n="1853-02-13`" type="entry">
      <head>Sunday Feb. 13th</head>

      <p>Last Sunday was our day to attend <hi rend="underline">the</hi> church, but we could not on
       account of the weather, but we attended today because Mr. Phillip's throat was two sore to
       preach to us. We heard a very good sermon by Mr. Castleman from 2d King's 7 <abbr
        expan="chapter">chap.</abbr> 3d-4th verses. In the evening Mr. Wheat preached to us, but I
       did not attend, as I was not ready but F., M. &amp; I staid up here on the bed, waiting
       to be called every moment but no one came &amp; we staid up here until service was over.</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d23" n="1853-02-16" type="entry">
      <head>Wednesday 16th</head>

      <p>I have not written in my journal regularly as I had intended, but there is so much sameness
       about the way in which our time is spent, that one day is almost a picture of the hole. We
       renewed our scripture reading<ref n="30" target="wright30">30</ref> this morning, as it has
       been <orig reg="broken">broaken</orig> up for some time past. We meet Mr. P. now in the study
       hall at 6[:30] oclock, when he calls over the roll to see if we are all present. I have been
       reading a sunday school book called Grace Dermott, and I think that it is beautiful. I wish
       that I could overcome my faults as she did, &amp; <hi rend="underline">above all
       possess</hi> her forgiving disposition &amp; christian spirit, for then I could go to
       Christ as my friend in time of trouble &amp; be always sure of finding relief.</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d24" n="1853-02-18" type="entry">
      <head>Friday 18th.</head>

      <p>Miss V. McClung was married last night to Mr. A. Waddell, and I heard that they had a very
       large wedding about 550 persons being invited. <hi rend="underline">I</hi> was up here
       studying &amp; <orig reg="writing">writeing</orig> letters to Nony which I hope that she
       intends <abbr expan="answering">ans.</abbr> soon, but this is telling about last night. I had
       a nice run on the terrace before scripture reading, (riding some of the girls in the push
       cart) &amp; while we were out there the bell rung to call us in, after scripture reading,
       Mr. P. gave us a little lecture on the <hi rend="underline">manner</hi> of reading our bibles
       to which I listened with interest.</p>
      <p>Only five of us attended church this afternoon, but I was one of the number. We had an
       elegant sermon from Mark 13th &amp; 37th v. What I say unto you I say unto all, <hi
        rend="underline">Watch</hi></p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d25" n="1853-02-19" type="entry">
      <head>Saturday 19th</head>

      <p>The weather has changed very suddenly, yesterday was a beautiful day, but it is snowing
       very hard this <hi rend="underline">morning</hi>, and I am very glad, as we can have the
       evening to ourselves. I went in the study to see Mr. Phillips and had a long chat with him,
       he was advising me how to study<ref n="31" target="wright31">31</ref> so as to give an
       accurate idea when reciting. He advised me to try his method and come again next saturday and
       tell him how I succeeded, and he would give me more advice. I would do anything in the world
       to please him, for I love him to distraction. Oh! how I wish that I could <hi
        rend="underline">recite</hi> my lessons beautifully, as well as retain them after I had
       recited them. Fannie Stribling &amp; Margie &amp; Ellen C. K. have been in here
       tonight. The other girls have been dancing in the recitation room. I am afraid that the light
        bell<ref n="32" target="wright32">32</ref> will ring and catch me so I must stop.</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d26" n="1853-02-20" type="entry">
      <head>Sunday 20th</head>

      <p>It is still snowing. I did not get a book out of the library this morning, for I borrowed
       one from Mr. P. yesterday and I have been reading that all morning it is Layards Nineveh<ref
        n="33" target="wright33">33</ref> a very interesting work. Mr. Phillips preached to us this
       morning from Psalm 33-5 "The earth is full of the goodness of the Lord". I slept a little
       while this evening, but felt worse after I awoke than I did before. We did not have any
       service this evening but prayers. after which I read a good deal before <orig reg="retiring"
        >retireing</orig> to rest</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d27" n="1853-02-23" type="entry">
      <head>Wednesday 23rd</head>

      <p>The day has passed as usual, and I was going down stairs, to take my music lesson, when
       aunt Sarah<ref n="34" target="wright34">34</ref> told me that there was a lady in the <orig
        reg="parlor">parlour</orig> that wished to see me. As Mrs. P. was not at home I got my
       permission from Miss Lizzy. I went in <orig reg="and">an</orig> there was Miss Mary Whitcomb
       (come to bid us good bye) and Miss Ella Stribling. Fannie came in after a while but Mary T
       and Sallie P. were sick and could not come down. The ladies took a notion to go up to their
       room. <hi rend="underline">I</hi> wanted them to wait and let me ask Miss Lizzy but they were
       in too great a hurry so I followed on after them. Just before we got to our door, Miss Sallie
       came out and saw me taking a lady to my room, and of course reported me, and I got two <orig
        reg="censures">centures</orig>. I do not intend to say anything to Mrs. P. but will explain
       to Mr. P. and if he does not see fit to take them off I will write to Pa and tell him for
       what I got them (and perhaps) ask him to let me board down street. Although I prefer boarding
       in the Institute for a great many reasons, not only because I have a great many more
       advantages for improvement (which is the greatest) but I also have some dear friends of whose
       company I would be deprived.</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d28" n="1853-02-26" type="entry">
      <head>Saturday 12th</head>

      <p>This morning after finishing a letter to Ma and Brother<ref n="35" target="wright35"
       >35</ref>, &amp; <orig reg="practicing">practiceing</orig> &amp; doing my other
       duties, as so many of the girls were going, I finally made up my mind to go <orig reg="too"
        >two</orig>, so after a great deal of fussing, we started between 12 and 1 oclock. Rose
       Oliver went with us. We <orig reg="stopped">stoped</orig> at the shoe store on our way, and
       Mr. P. came in while we were there, and asked us what we were doing there. I asked him if I
       could not stay at aunts to tea, he said that we might, provided we could get in time to come
       home before dark. I knew that it was of no use to ask more so left. We staid so late that
       aunt had given us out. I spent a very pleasant though as usual a very <hi rend="underline"
        >quiet</hi> day. We did not get back home until after tea, and the girls had tableau's, and
       some of the scenes were very pretty &amp; others <orig reg="failed">failled</orig>
       because the girls were so unorderly.</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d29" n="1853-02-27" type="entry">
      <head>Saturday 27th</head>

      <p>I cannot say much for this holy day, for it has not been spent as profitably as it might
       have been. We had no service this morning, for Mr. Phillips did not feel well enough to
       preach, &amp; Mr. Wheat was not here, and I am sorry to say that <hi rend="underline"
       >I</hi> idled away my time very unprofitably (at least I did not do anything very improving).
       I read through a little sunday school book in the morning and read a few pages in a work on
       Neneveh in the evening. We expected to hear a sermon from brother Wheat in the evening, but
       we were very agreeably disappointed when Mr. P. came in. His text was Acts 14 cha. 17 verse.
       God hath not left himself without witness.</p>
      <p>It was a very good sermon as his always are. I believe that I like going to church at home,
       as much as at <hi rend="underline">the</hi> church, <abbr expan="although">althou.</abbr> I
       confess that I did not at first. I think that we are kept entirely <orig reg="too">two</orig>
       close, although I know it is not right for us to go out too much (&amp; besides I do not
       want to) as we are <hi rend="underline">only fitting</hi> ourselves for society now, but I
       think that we might go out more &amp; out hurt us.<ref n="36" target="wright36">36</ref></p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d30" n="1853-02-28" type="entry">
      <head>Monday 28th</head>

      <p>Well this is the last day of <abbr expan="February">Feb.</abbr> and a beautiful day it is.
       The teachers have changed several of the classes &amp; practice hours &amp; mine is
       among the number. My old hour was from ten to eleven but it has been changed to 7[:30] to
       8[:30] at night. We went to walk this evening, and as we were returning, we met Louisa going
       for the Dr. &amp; she told us that it was thought Mrs. Lowry was dying (this was the <hi
        rend="underline">only</hi> child of our matron<ref n="37" target="wright37">37</ref>), and
       sure enough we had not been at home long before she breathed her last. She was her mother's
       idol, for she almost worshiped her, and I expect that was why God saw fit to remove her from
       this world and take her to dwell with him.</p>

     </div3>

    </div2>

    <div2 id="d31" n="1853-03" type="section">
     <head>March 1853
      <!-- <ref>Family, Women, Arts/Leisure, Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties, Race Relations</ref> -->
     </head>

     <div3 id="d32" n="1853-03-03" type="entry">
      <head>Thursday March 3d</head>

      <p>We had no school today on account of the burial. The <orig reg="corpse">corps</orig> was
       laid out in the back <orig reg="parlor">parlour</orig>, they have kept her out of the ground
       four days<ref n="38" target="wright38">38</ref>, waiting for the arrival of her husband. who
       did not arrive until this morning. The day scholars and some of the ladies &amp;
       gentlemen from down town assembled here about ten, and about eleven we all proceeded to the
       church, where Mr. Castleman delivered an elegant sermon<ref n="39" target="wright39"
       >39</ref>, and warned us of putting off until our dying hour to repent of our <hi
        rend="underline">past sins</hi>. and giving our hearts to God, &amp; then went on
       enumerate the many good qualities of the departed friend who now layed-stretched before a
       lifeless <orig reg="corpse">corps</orig>. We girls after service were <orig reg="obliged"
        >obilged</orig> to return to the <abbr expan="Virginia Female Institute">V. F. I.</abbr> but
       the others went on to the cemetery. I felt as if I could not hold out get home for my throat
       was very sore, &amp; my head was aching very badly. After I got up here I went to sleep
       but that did me no good: after dinner I went to sleep again, and did not go to supper, and
       Mrs. P. sent up for Miss Sallie to mark me, but she came in &amp; found that I was sick.
       But that was not all, for after a while, Miss Lizzy came around with her paper &amp;
       pencil to see who had eaten in their rooms during the <orig reg="month">mounth</orig>,
       &amp; there went down a <orig reg="censure">centure</orig> for most every girl. I think
       that they might have waited a day at any rate &amp; not have a <hi rend="underline"
        >funeral</hi> in the morning &amp; <orig reg="censuring">centureing</orig> at night.<ref
        n="40" target="wright40">40</ref></p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d33" n="1853-03-05" type="entry">
      <head>Thursday 5th</head>

      <p>I have been very lowspirited all day, all on account of my marks &amp; have wished
       repeatedly to go home. I tried to practice but could not, as I cried so much that I could not
       see the notes, &amp; thus it was that I idled away all the morning, &amp; did not
       succeed in accomplishing anything. After dinner I received a letter from Pa, and this cheered
       me up a little. After this I scarcely know how I spent the rest of the evening, but it passed
       off somehow. Aunt Suey<ref n="41" target="wright41">41</ref> brought us a basket of cakes,
       and 17 or 18 of the girls had a party down stairs but we (all except Sallie P.) <orig
        reg="preferred">prefered</orig> enjoying our <orig reg="eatables">eatibles</orig> to
       ourselves.</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d34" n="1853-03-06" type="entry">
      <head>Sunday 6th</head>

      <p>This Holyday is here again &amp; a beautiful day it is. We attended the church today
       and heard a very fine sermon by Rev. T. T. Castleman from Romans 8 chap. 9 verse "If any man
       have not the spirit of Christ, he is none of his." At night we had service up here. Mr.
       Englebrecht came up and played for us, as they had no service at the church.<ref n="42"
        target="wright42">42</ref> Mr. Wheat read the service after which Mr. Phillips made some
       very solemn remarks. He spoke of the death we had in our family the last week, and he said
       that he thought it was sent as a warning to us, that a perfect stranger should come and make
       a visit to us &amp; stay 6 or 7 months &amp; be taken sick &amp; die <orig
        reg="among">amoung</orig> us could be nothing but a warning to us. He said that he had never
       had <orig reg="among">amoung</orig> so many young ladies <hi rend="underline">so few</hi>
       that had made religion their study &amp; I agree with him, for we have only 3 that are
       members of the church &amp; most of the others are as bad as bad can be in that respect.
       He told us to ask ourselves the question am I prepared to die? and to fix upon some <hi
        rend="underline">definite</hi> period when we would <hi rend="underline">begin</hi> to
       prepare, even if it should extend beyond the time allotted to us to live, let it be definite.
       I will try and fix mine <hi rend="underline">Now</hi> &amp; not defer it until a more
       convenient season, for that may never come. God hath said "Now is the accepted time, now is
       the day of salvation."</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d35" n="1853-03-07" type="entry">
      <head>Monday 7th</head>

      <p>My week has begun for me to clean how much I dislike it particularly sweeping. Our subject
       of Composition this week is Dress.<ref n="43" target="wright43">43</ref> I wonder what Mr. W.
       thinks of mine. I guess that he thinks it is <orig reg="quite">quit</orig> short, for it is
       only two pages. I went to walk this evening, the first time that I have been for I don't know
       when.</p>

      <p>The Methodists were just before us, and that made quite a long string, but they turned off
       from us at the end of the plank walk &amp; we walked out towards the institution,
       &amp; they turned down towards the hospital.<ref n="44" target="wright44">44</ref> We had
       a very nice walk, for as we returned we came down main street <orig reg="as">at</orig> far as
       the bank where we crossed over again to back st. Soon after study hours began this evening
       Agnes P. came around &amp; told us that her ma said that we must come down stairs at the
       ringing of the bell as Mrs. Lowry's child <orig reg="was">way</orig> going to be <orig
        reg="baptized">baptised</orig>. Accordingly the bell rung in a little while &amp; we all
       took our lights &amp; went down to the school room. Mrs. P. &amp; its Father stood
       for it, and Mr. P. christened her Francais Caroline.<ref n="45" target="wright45">45</ref></p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d36" n="1853-03-10" type="entry">
      <head>Thursday 10th</head>

      <p>This is a beautiful spring morning. After I had finished cleaning I went out &amp; had
       a run on the terrace, and felt quite refreshed after which the scripture bell rang and we all
       repared to the school room, for our usual silent perusal of the scriptures. This did not
       occupy more than 20 minutes, &amp; then came breakfast, after this was over we had three
       quarters of an hour before school to study our lessons (or do anything that we wished) school
       opens at a quarter of 9 &amp; closes at one, opens at 2 &amp; closes at 4 for the
       day. We had study hours from 4 to 5 so that we could go to the concert. We dressed after
       study hours and after supper we all collected in the hall. Mr. P. came in &amp; told us
       that it was raining &amp; we could not go (to tease us) but we started at last &amp;
       got there before the company had assembled &amp; got very good seats. I was much pleased
       indeed. They had a very large picture (oil painting) representing the Prophet Jeremiah
       rehearsing a lamentation to the Jews in captivity at Babylon. There were the principle
       persons connected with the Hebrew exilement clustered together in such a manner as to
       illustrate the sentiment of hope; the most natural looking <orig reg="images">immages</orig>
       that I ever beheld. After the exhibition of the picture, we had some very fine singing from
       Madam Rosalie Durand &amp; Signor Norvelli. I enjoyed myself more after the concert was
       over than any other time.</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d37" n="1853-03-12" type="entry">
      <head>Saturday 12th</head>

      <p>This morning after prayers. I finished writing a letter to Pa &amp; Ma &amp; then
       Mr. P. sent us word that all who wanted to go down &amp; see the picture by day light
       could do so. Of course I was among the number &amp; we all started off. There were very
       few persons in the room, &amp; we had a fair opportunity of seeing it. I scarcely know in
       what light it is prettiest artificial or natural, but of course nature is to be preferred to
       anything that is artificial. We did not have study hours until night, &amp; I took up all
       my time writing my composition, after which I had the room to clean up, &amp; prepare for
       bed. Fannie &amp; <orig reg="I"/> sewed &amp; fixed my dress &amp; read some,
       &amp; then retired for the night.</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d38" n="1853-03-13" type="entry">
      <head>Sunday March 13th</head>

      <p>I ask myself the question, am I any better this Sabbath than last? I fear not but rather
       the contrary. I fear that my heart is turning back to its old course, but O Father? be thou
       my guide &amp; <orig reg="preserve">perserve</orig> me from temptation &amp; lead me
       in the right path. Mr. P. sent us word that we could go to the church as he felt too unwell
       to preach to us. Accordingly we got ready &amp; went heard a sermon from Rev. T. T.
       Castleman from Luke 21 chap. 34 verse "And so that day come upon you unawares" He charged us
       to be upon our guard, least that day should come when we least expected it. At night Mr.
       Wheat preached up here, Matt 12 ch 42 &amp; 43 verses.</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d39" n="1853-03-19" type="entry">
      <head>March 19th.</head>

      <p>This morning after prayers Mr. P. told us that all of us that wished could go down
       &amp; see the Aztec Children, accordingly about 43 of us went. I expected to see them
       looking more like children than they did, for in my eye they bordered on the monkey tribe.
       There were two Bartola &amp; Maximo, &amp; real funny looking creatures to be human
       beings with all their organs as perfect as ours. They seemed very much attached to each
       other, &amp; although they had arrived at the ages of 10 &amp; 20, they were just
       learning to talk. After we left the Hall, I went down to aunt Sarah's &amp; took dinner,
       after which I went down to cousin Jane's,<ref n="46" target="wright46">46</ref> as I wanted
       to get some money from the bank for which pa had sent me a check.<ref n="47"
        target="wright47">47</ref> I staid down town <orig reg="until">untill</orig> between three
       &amp; four &amp; cousin F. walked up with me &amp; carried my basket of <orig
        reg="eatables">eatibles</orig>. We had study hours at night, but I did not study much, as I
        <orig reg="practiced">practised</orig>.</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d40" n="1853-03-20" type="entry">
      <head>Sunday 20th.</head>

      <p>We went to the church today &amp; heard Mr. C. preach his text was Luke 19th chap 43
       verse. "When he came near unto the city he wept over it."</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d41" n="1853-03-25" type="entry">
      <head>25th</head>

      <p>This is Good Friday, &amp; we have had holy day. We attended church today &amp; we
       heard a very fine sermon from Luke 24 chap. 26 verse. "Ought not Christ to have suffered
       these things &amp; to enter into glory." He spoke of God's kindness in giving his only
       begotten son to die for sinners. this was true Benevolence for he gave him for his enemies
       &amp; the punishment instead of resting on our heads rested on that innocent creature. As
       it was friday, we could not visit each others rooms, at night a good many of the girls went
       down to the <orig reg="recitation">resitation</orig> room, &amp; played but I stayed in
       my room (and Maria &amp; Mary Bailey came in &amp; spent the evening with me) and
       wrote three letters; one to Nony, Mary Van &amp; Miss Fannie and Mary wrote one to Mrs.
       B. The girls kept running in here to borrow things for the dance they expect to have tomorrow
       night, but the nine oclock bell<ref n="48" target="wright48">48</ref> rung &amp; then
       such a scattering.</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d42" n="1853-03-26" type="entry">
      <head>26th Saturday</head>

      <p>This is our regular day to go down street. We had study hours in the morning as we wanted
       to have some fun at night. After study hours were over, Fannie Smith, Sallie Patrick
       &amp; myself went down to aunt Sarah's to spend the day. I went down with Fannie
       Stribling &amp; left Fannie &amp; Sallie to come after me. After dinner Fannie
       &amp; I went up to Mrs. Points &amp; Sallie P. &amp; K. went up to aunt Mary
        Anns.<ref n="49" target="wright49">49</ref> After we came back it was time for the girls to
       go back home, so they only stopped a little while at aunts &amp; then departed for the
        <abbr expan="Virginia Female Institute">V. F. I.</abbr> but <hi rend="underline">I</hi> had
       no idea of going back yet for I had permission to stay to tea, for a wonder. Aunt <orig
        reg="begged">beged</orig> me to stay all night but I was afraid<ref n="50" target="wright50"
        >50</ref> but I wish that I had now. I left there soon after eight, but <orig reg="stopped"
        >stoped</orig> in at uncle William's<ref n="51" target="wright51">51</ref> a little while to
       see all the folks. I got home at nine o'clock, just in time to see the dancers before they
       broke up for the evening.</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d43" n="1853-03-27" type="entry">
      <head>Sunday 27th.</head>

      <p>Early this morning it looked as if it would rain but before church time the sun shone out
       very brightly, and as it was communion Sunday, of course we went to the church. Mr. C. took
       his text Matt. 27th chap. 42d verse, "He saved others;"</p>

     </div3>

    </div2>

    <div2 id="d44" n="1853-04" type="section">
     <head>April 1853
      <!-- <ref>Family, Women, Arts/Leisure, Church/Religious Activity, Race Relations</ref> -->
     </head>

     <div3 id="d45" n="1853-04-01" type="entry">
      <head>April 1st</head>

      <p>This was a real spring morning, and I feel very much like putting on my spring clothes. I
       do not know what is the matter with me, for my face is very much flushed &amp; broken
       out. Some of the girls think that I am taking the scarlet fever but I do not feel sick but
       only drowsy. After dinner I laid down and went to sleep &amp; did not awake until school
       was nearly over, and just as I awoke there was a loud peel of thunder followed by a streak of
       lightning. There were 20 or more April fool letters<ref n="52" target="wright52">52</ref>
       given out tonight, 18 of which were written by the Hon. M. J. Jesse.<ref n="53"
        target="wright53">53</ref> After supper we all collected in Maria Goodwin's room to see (as
       we thought) the burning of Mr. Imboden's house but then we came to find out it was only the
       woods on fire. This is the night for the first section to play, &amp; Mrs. Drery
       &amp; Miss Parks are up here. I did not want to stay down there as it was not my night to
       play so Mr. E. excused me. Maria is staying with me as she is not well enough to go down. We
       have had quite a little feast by ourselves over <hi rend="underline">tarkey</hi> bones
       &amp; biscuits &amp; cakes for dessert. Margie &amp; Fannie Stribling have been
       in here all dressed up, Margie as a boy. She <orig reg="makes">make</orig> a very handsome
       one indeed for she has so many of their ways.</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d46" n="1853-04-03" type="entry">
      <head>Sunday 3d.</head>

      <p>Today is very cloudy. I read before church a book called "Julia Changed Oh that my heart
       could be changed like <hi rend="underline">hers</hi> and I could be made a child of God's
       &amp; feel as she did. Oh Heavenly Father, change <hi rend="underline">my heart</hi>
       &amp; make a follower of the cross of thy dear son, who gave his precious blood as a
       ransom for our sins. We attended the church today, the new organ has come, &amp; a
       splendid one it is. Just before the sermon begun, a piece of the organ fell down &amp;
       came very near hurting some of the ladies very badly. Mr. C. took his text from Romans 8 -
       34th verse. "Who is he that condemeth? It is Christ that died, yea rather, that is risen, who
       is even at the right hand of God, who also maketh intercession for us." Tonight Mr. Phillips
       preached to us, &amp; his text was from Hosea 4th chap. 17th verse. Ephraim is <hi
        rend="underline">joined to his idols: let him alone</hi>." Oh! what did he not tell us, he
       warned us not to fix our heart on the things of this world but to give our hearts to God, for
       he is a jealous God &amp; visits the sins of the fathers upon the children. I cannot tell
       why but the girls this session (a great many of them) are so wicked, that is they use such
       wicked language, it makes me shudder to hear them. I expect that Mr. P. has heard some of
       their sayings for he spoke as if he had. He said that a great many of the young gents of the
        <abbr expan="Virginia Military Institute">V. M. I.</abbr><ref n="54" target="wright54"
       >54</ref> had experienced a change of heart &amp; asked us if in a school of 56 young <hi
        rend="underline">ladies some</hi> would not turn to God. I saw the error of my ways, my eyes
       filled with tears, and I was compelled to say "What lack I yet."</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d47" n="1853-04-04" type="entry">
      <head>Monday the 4th.</head>

      <p>I can scarcely tell how the day has passed but just as I had begun to <orig reg="practice"
        >practise</orig>, Mary Caperton<ref n="55" target="wright55">55</ref> came in and told me
       that Mrs. P. said that some one wanted to see me in the study. Accordingly I went down
       expecting to see a visitor but as soon as I entered the truth flashed across my mind
       directly. I was frightened at first, but resolved not to show it. I feared not for myself so
       much as for Ellen, but I knew that I had been the means of getting her into trouble when <hi
        rend="underline">I</hi> could have prevented it: but it was <hi rend="underline">all</hi>
       done thoughtlessly, not thinking for one minute of the consequences, but I have pledged my
       word not to do the like again, &amp; oh God will thou enable me to keep it. I have always
       loved Mr. P.<ref n="56" target="wright56">56</ref> since I have been under his care <hi
        rend="underline">but now &amp; forevermore</hi> I will love him like a father. Oh! how
       kind he was to me, he did not scold, but only told me how wrong I had done, &amp; talked
       to me as kindly as if he had been my father. I will never forget him <hi rend="underline">no
        never</hi>, and I will make all at home love him two. We all &amp; E &amp; M staid
       up until one &amp; had fine time.</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d48" n="1853-04-18" type="entry">
      <head>April 18th</head>

      <p>Oh how times does fly (for it is only little more than 2 months before we go home) two
       weeks have passed since I last wrote here. I was down street on the evening of the 6th
       &amp; 9th &amp; got me two very pretty dresses.<ref n="57" target="wright57">57</ref>
       On the morning of the 14th Miss Rebekah Kinney was married to Mr. S. A. Richardson. She did
       not have a large wedding (only her relatives &amp; intimate friends) as they were married
       at eleven &amp; left here at one, on their bridal tour. On last Sunday the 17th Bishop
       Boone of China &amp; Mr. Tong, a native of China delivered an address at the church.<ref
        n="58" target="wright58">58</ref> Mr. <abbr expan="Tong">T.</abbr> first arose and made his
       simple though affecting address. He told us of the different religions of his country,
       &amp; spoke of their great wickedness before the missionaries went to dwell <orig
        reg="among">amoung</orig> them. He told us that his people had three religions &amp; at
       the corner of most every street were small temples filled with idols &amp; that one of
       their religions permitted them to go into these temples once a month and bow to these images.
       "Six years ago said he I was the one that bowed to <hi rend="underline">these images</hi>,
       but it pleased God to send your missionaries to us &amp; my eyes were opened &amp; I
       was made to see the error of my ways. Schools were established. I learned your language
       &amp; I with six of my companions were admitted into the church. It is now my wish to
       study for the ministry that I may return &amp; teach my countrymen." He then ended his
       simple address by saying "Christian brethren, pity China, pray for China, pray for me." The
       Bishop then arose &amp; spoke of the progress they were making in China he spoke of those
       who had left this little place. He said that they reached China last Christmas a year ago,
       &amp; that seven months after <orig reg="their">there</orig> arrival Mr. Nealson read the
       service to the satisfaction of the natives, &amp; Mr. John Points addressed a sabbath
       school so that they could understand everything that he said. He told the number of school
       that they had established, &amp; how they obtained their scholars. In a boys school the
       parents bring their children &amp; place them under his care; they are taken on trial for
       a month &amp; if they like him he is then bound to them for ten years. If his parents
       attempt to get him away they are fined $30 a year for as many years as he has been with them.
       If they have had him 2 years they pay $60 &amp; if three $90 &amp; so on (for his
       board &amp; cloathing) so that after they have had him for three years they do not fear
       of his being taken. With the females it is different <hi rend="underline">they</hi> are
       thought so much beneath the <orig reg="males">mails</orig>, that they never go out until
       after they are married, &amp; it is with difficulty that the teachers can get them but by
       promising them a nice meal &amp; <orig reg="clothes">cloths</orig> they induce them to
       come to school, they only keep them seven months as their parents do not think their
       education of as much importance as their sons. Mr. T. was up here last night &amp; went
       around to the rooms, when they came in here, Mr. P. asked us how many pounds of candy we were
       willing to give &amp; told Mr. Tong that we spent a good deal in candy &amp; he
       replied that he thought that we had better establish a school there. Mr. P. sent around a
       collector &amp; got $37.25. for which he seemed very thankful. Mrs. Points had all our
       names put down &amp; sent them to John. Fannie &amp; I staid up from half past one to
       four.</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d49" n="1853-04-21" type="entry">
      <head>April 21st</head>

      <p>This has been a <hi rend="underline">real</hi> spring day: we had scripture reading earlier
       this morning, as we are trying to be more industrious. We have only two more months to stay
       here and I must try and improve as much as I can. There is so much <hi rend="underline"
       >less</hi> ambition in school this session than there was last. Last year the girls seemed to
       try to keep the rules &amp; there was a great desire to <orig reg="excel">excell</orig>;
       but <hi rend="underline">this year</hi> they do not mind the rules &amp; try how many
       marks they can get. <hi rend="underline">I try</hi> to keep from them, but the more I try the
       more I get, but so my conscience is clear that is all I want. Mr. P. says that it is his
       opinion that the marks never go down, unless for some cause, but I beg leave to differ with
       him there, for <orig reg="where">were</orig> there are so many of us together they might
       through mistake put one girls marks to another name, for I have seen it done.</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d50" n="1853-04-30" type="entry">
      <head>30th.</head>

      <p>This is Saturday morning, and I wanted to go down street, but Mrs. P. would not let us, as
       she said that it was <orig reg="too">two</orig> damp. Cousin Tom left town yesterday morning
       with the engineer company<ref n="59" target="wright59">59</ref> &amp; does not expect to
       return until <abbr expan="September">Sept</abbr>. Eliza Smart left here the same day for
        home,<ref n="60" target="wright60">60</ref> and cousin Bec returned on Monday last from her
       bridal tour. After the letters were given out, as I did not get one, I was very much
       disappointed &amp; consequently felt very low spirited for the rest of the day (as I had
       not gotten one for 3 weeks) &amp; not much like doing anything.</p>

     </div3>

    </div2>

    <div2 id="d51" n="1853-05" type="section">
     <head>May 1853 <!-- <ref>Family, Women, Arts/Leisure, Church/Religious Activity</ref> -->
     </head>

     <div3 id="d52" n="1853-05-11" type="entry">
      <head>Wednesday night May 11th</head>

      <p>I have not written in my journal for three weeks and many things have happened that I could
       have recorded. Last Thursday morning Margie Custis left here for home. I do not think that
       she wanted to leave much (of course she wanted to see all at home) but she had some very dear
       friends here that she did not like to part with. Friday 6th we had oranges<ref n="61"
        target="wright61">61</ref> for dinner and at night the Misses Tebbs<ref n="62"
        target="wright62">62</ref> had a party. We had a great deal of fun, although we could not go
       into the <orig reg="parlor">parlour</orig>, but we peeped around and managed to see some way.
       After the light bell rung, we opened our windows (at least No. 2) &amp; we could see as
       well as hear everything that was going on. We could hear the ladies singing &amp; see
       them promenading on the <orig reg="porch">poarch</orig>. Indeed we were flying around in
       every direction &amp; did not go to bed until after one, i. e. after the company had
       left. I had just retired when I heard a rap at my door &amp; found that it was Mary B<ref
        n="63" target="wright63">63</ref> &amp; Lizzie M.<ref n="64" target="wright64">64</ref>
       come to light their candle. They begged me to come &amp; see what was the matter with
       Ellen. I heard her crying as soon as I opened my door &amp; when I entered <hi
        rend="underline">her</hi> room I soon perceived that her thoughts were wandering, for she
       was talking about all manner of things. It was some time before I could persuade her to hush
       as she had taken it into her head that some one was going to kill her &amp; she said that
       she was not ready to go. She would not let us leave her, but held our hands so we could not
       move &amp; she could not bear to look at the door, as she imagined that some one was
       coming after her. Saturday 7th I spent the day down town &amp; had a very pleasant though
       quiet day. Sunday we could not attend church on account of the rain &amp; at night Mr.
       Phillips preached to us. Today has been a very pleasant day. Miss Sallie took us to walk out
       by the cemetery with the sun shining <hi rend="underline">full</hi> in our faces, as
       disagreeable as it could be. I walked with Sallie Drewry<ref n="65" target="wright65"
       >65</ref> (she is a sweet girl if there ever was one) this evening, and just as we were
       turning Mr. Clark's corner, we met about half dozen boys. F. M., W. J., J. G., B. H.,
       &amp; they make a regular business of walking by here as if any one cared to see them,
       but I wish they would stay away, for if we happen to go to the window, oh yes, we go to see
       the boys &amp; nothing else. Mr. P. has bought a very gentle horse (as his other one
       died) &amp; sometimes Charlie &amp; Henry let us ride around the yard, but I do not
       think that their father likes it much for us to ride.</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d53" n="1853-05-12" type="entry">
      <head>May 12th<ref n="66" target="wright66">66</ref></head>

      <p>What a beautiful morning this is the sun is shining in all its loveliness, the little birds
       are singing &amp; all nature seems to <orig reg="praise">prais</orig> the maker of <hi
        rend="underline">all</hi> for their existence and shall I forget to praise him also. He who
       has spared my parents and friends while many others have been deprived of them. evening Oh
       how sad I have felt today, just as if I did not have a friend on earth. This evening I have
       been reading the history of little Jane S. Oh how I wish that I could feel as she did and
       have God for my friend to go in time of need. Who can read those beautiful lines &amp;
       not feel a pleasant emotion arise in their bosom. To think of a young girl becoming pious,
       &amp; dying the death of the righteous. Oh Lord bless me and let my last end be like
       hers.</p>

      <p>"This lovely bud, so young and fair,<lb/> Call'd hence by early doom,<lb/> Just came to
       show how sweet a flower<lb/> In Paradise would bloom."</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d54" n="1853-05-19" type="entry">
      <head>May 19th</head>
      <p>I have now taken my seat once to write in my journal. It has been so warm that it has made
       me quite lazy and I have neglected to write this week. Last Saturday evening Archie<ref
        n="67" target="wright67">67</ref> came up here to bring Sallie P.'s cape that his Mother had
       borrowed, we were in the <orig reg="parlor">parlour</orig>, &amp; a gentleman came in
       &amp; we went into the hall. Mr. P. came by and asked us what bell that was rung,
       &amp; we told him the study bell, &amp; I thought that was a hint<ref n="68"
        target="wright68">68</ref> for Archie to leave so I bid him goodbye &amp; left. Sunday
       we went to church <orig reg="and">an</orig> Mr. P. preached (as Mr. C. was absent). His text
       was in John Chap 5 6 verse. Wilt thou be made whole? It was a very fine sermon. He said that
       we should ask ourselves the question and then say with the P. "Here Lord I give myself away
       tis all I can do" We attended also at night (something new for us since Christmas) and Mr.
       Wheat preached. His Text was from John 1 - 29th "Behold the Lamb of God which taketh away the
       sins of the world." He doesn't preach as well as Mr. Phillips for his delivery is not good,
       at least he says that whenever he preaches at the church or up here he knows what <hi
        rend="underline">would be</hi>
       <orig reg="critics">crittics</orig> the girls are) he becomes <orig reg="embarrassed"
        >embarassed</orig>. The weather has been oppressively warm for the last week, but this
       evening there was a very sudden change. Ellen has been in here almost all evening, trying how
       many smart remarks she could make. My lessons were over at 3 o'clock &amp; I laid down on
       the bed &amp; took a nap and awoke just as school closed.</p>

     </div3>

     <div3 id="d55" n="1853-05-28" type="entry">
      <head>May 28th</head>

      <p>This is a very warm day, and the dedication of the Cemetery took place the morning. The
       Masons, Sons of Temperance (&amp; it seemed to me) everybody else in town marched out
       there. After this was over all the people assembled in the Methodist Church, and heard an
       address from the Hon. Dr. McGuffy.<ref n="69" target="wright69">69</ref> As I didn't attend
       of course I cannot tell anything about it but as all the <hi rend="underline">rulers</hi>
       left our establishment (of course when the rats are away the mice will play) F. S. &amp;
       I thought that we would cut some novel capers, so we <orig reg="took">tok</orig> it into our
       heads (Last night we attended the Panoram representing from the Creation to the Deluge or
       after. I was very much pleased as it was the first I had ever seen one before, but those who
       had seen finer ones in the cities said that was not good) I have not done scarcely anything
       today: I wasted most of the morning (except the time that I was writing my composition) in
       looking at the people, for I believe that I saw more than I have ever seen assembled together
       here at any other time; unless it was at Mr. Points, or little Frankie Stribling funeral.</p>

     </div3>

    </div2>

    <div2 id="d56" n="1853-06" type="section">
     <head>June 1853 <!-- <ref>Family, Women, Arts/Leisure</ref> -->
     </head>

     <div3 id="d57" n="1853-06-11" type="entry">
      <head>June 11th</head>

      <p>This morning I went to Mrs. Phillip &amp; asked her to let us go down street that is
       all in my room, she refused at first of course I told her that aunt wanted the girls to spend
       the day with her, but she said that aunt would have to write a note to <hi rend="underline"
        >Mr.</hi> P. but after a while Sallie R. came up &amp; asked her &amp; finally she
       consented to let us go. Sallies P. &amp; K. went down before us but after so long a time
       we started also. We had not been down there long when Bettie B. came over &amp; after a
       while Miss. Lizzie T. &amp; cousin Eliza.<ref n="70" target="wright70">70</ref> The other
       girls were roaming all over the place but I staid mostly with Bettie &amp; we had a very
       nice time: after a while dinner was announced &amp; I do not remember when I ate such a
        <orig reg="hearty">harty</orig> one. About 4 o'clock Aunt Lucy called all of us girls out in
       her room &amp; gave us some warm biscuits &amp; <orig reg="strawberry"
       >straw-bury</orig> preserves &amp; we ate those to our heart's content then we went to
       Mr. H. J. Crawford's store &amp; spent nearly an hour &amp; Fannie &amp; Sallie
       S. got their <orig reg="traveling">travelling</orig> dresses. Sallie S. &amp; I went up
       to Mrs. Staffords &amp; Fannie &amp; other two Sallies went home. We had a good deal
       of fun before supper &amp; after that was over I was compelled to leave earlier than I
       would have done in order to get off my dress, for it had gotten so tight all at once that I
       could not stand it, so that I bid them goodbye &amp; left. I brought Ellen &amp;
       Maria something to eat but they were not very hungry, as Sophia had been up here with her
        <orig reg="eatables">eatibles</orig>.</p>

     </div3>

    </div2>

    <div2 id="d58" n="1853-08" type="section">
     <head>August 1853 <!-- <ref>Family, Women, Arts/Leisure, Church/Religious Activity</ref> -->
     </head>

     <div3 id="d59" n="1853-08-01" type="entry">
      <head>Aug. 1st 1853</head>

      <p>This is the first day of <abbr expan="August">Aug.</abbr> nearly two months have passed
       since I wrote last here; and what changes too. On the 24th of June our sessions closed (at
       least school duties) and I went down to aunts on Saturday morning. Sunday I went back to
        <abbr expan="Virginia Female Institute">V. F. I.</abbr> to get another dress and the girls
       told me how much fuss Mr. P. had made about <hi rend="underline">some</hi> of the girls
       staying out &amp; I did not go back that day, but I did the next. On the morn of the 28th
       Fannie Smith came down to aunts &amp; after she had been there a while Ellen King
       &amp; Rosa Oliver came in. They did not stay more than an hour but the others stayed to
       dinner after which Fannie &amp; I went up to bid Mrs Points goodbye. Just after we got
       back to aunts the hardest rain came up that I most ever saw &amp; we were detained there
       nearly an hour &amp; as soon as it cleared up we went back to the Institute to prepare
       for the exhibition. We had then but a few hours to spend together; all the girls looked very
       happy but I felt sad. After the performances were over the Rev. H. Stringfellow delivered an
       address to us which was very affecting. After everybody had left Ellen K. introduced me to
       her father &amp; I liked him very much. I talked with him until Maria Goodwyn's called
       him to go down to the hotel. The girls in our room &amp; in Ellens &amp; Maria's room
       did not go to sleep that night, as they all expected to leave early next morning. At five
       o'clock all the girls most had left but I was disappointed in getting off as I had expected
       &amp; as I had written to Pa that we would meet him at the White<ref n="71"
        target="wright71">71</ref> he did not come for us &amp; we were detained until the next
       Monday. Sallie P. &amp; I staid with aunt Sarah &amp; we had a very pleasant time,
       but I was very anxious to get home. Pa did not get there until 11 oclock Sunday night
       &amp; we left the next morning about five. When we got to the post office corner we meet
       Mr. P. who had come down to see us start. We had a little chat with him while they were
       getting the mail &amp; when we were all ready, we bid him goodbye &amp; left town
       homeward bound. We <orig reg="traveled">travelled</orig> on &amp; nothing occurred worth
       relating until we arrived at the dinner stand. Just as the stage <orig reg="stopped"
       >stoped</orig>, a gentleman came to the stage door &amp; asked the passengers if they
       would not walk out to the <hi rend="underline">
        <orig reg="barbecue">barbaque</orig>
       </hi> grounds &amp; get their dinner. We turned off a little from the main road and
       entered a grove &amp; there were collected together about 200 persons to celebrate the
        <orig reg="fourth">forth</orig> of July. They seemed to enjoy it very much as it was the
       first thing of that sort that they ever had in the county. We spent about half hour with them
       &amp; then took our departure. Mr. Cook of Richmond made himself known to Pa &amp; he
       introduced him to us. When we again reached our coach we found that four new passengers had
       gotten there before us &amp; taken their seats. Not knowing who they were or where they
       came from, we of course had to dispute about our seats, &amp; when Pa &amp; the other
       gentlemen saw that there was a young looking gent inside they were for making him get outside
       but the ladies said that he had been suffering with <orig reg="rheumatism">reumatis</orig>,
       &amp; that they came over that morning in the Rockbridge Alum stage, &amp; the people
       promised them they should go on that evening we said no more but we were very much crowded.
       Just as we were starting, one of the ladies turned around (who had been talking with some one
       outside) &amp; we <orig reg="recognized">recognised</orig> an old acquaintance that we
       had traveled with going on last summer. Mrs. John Lewis from Lewisburg, &amp; her aunt
       old Mrs. Stuart. We did not reach the Warm<ref n="72" target="wright72">72</ref> that night
       until nine o'clock, &amp; we concluded to take our supper there, as it would be so late
       before we reached Jackson's river, which was to be our night stand. At the Warm, We lost most
       of our company: the chartered coach <orig reg="stopped">stoped</orig> &amp; two of our
       passengers, Mr. Clark &amp; Wade.) At the Hot we lost two more so that our party was now
       reduced to five, &amp; we traveled on, on, on, until one that night, when we at last
       reached our night stand. Mrs. Lewis &amp; I laid down to get a little rest, &amp; the
       other Sallie &amp; Mrs. S. sat up to keep watch so they said, but Mrs. Stuart kept making
       so many funny remarks that she made us laugh so much that it was a long time before we could
       get to sleep. Finally we got to sleep &amp; slept until four next morning when we left
       there for the White, which we reached about eleven that day. This was the day for the stage
       to rest there, but we <orig reg="preferred">prefered</orig> going on to Lewisburg as part of
       our company lived there, &amp; <hi rend="underline">we</hi> had some friends there that
       we wished to see. There were three or four gentlemen already at the White, that wished to go
       over that evening, so we joined with them, &amp; got a coach &amp; left the White at
       four that evening, &amp; in two hours after arrived in Lewisburg. We took supper at the
       hotel, after which Sallie &amp; I went over to Mr. Novels to spend the evening. I did not
       enjoy myself very much for they kept making puns on my name until I got sick and tired of
       them. There was Charly &amp; Mary Norvell, &amp; a Mr. Mayo, &amp; Sally Patrick
       &amp; myself. I joined them in their play of words for a while, but they soon over did
       the thing as Wright was quite easy to pun on, &amp; I got weary of it &amp; proposed
       returning to the hotel.</p>
      <p>Final entry</p>

     </div3>

    </div2>

   </div1>


   <div1 id="AD90001854" n="1854" type="part">
    <head>1854 <!-- <ref>AD90001854</ref> -->
    </head>

    <div2 id="d61" n="1854-06" type="section">
     <head>June 1854 <!-- <ref>Arts/Leisure, Race Relations</ref> -->
     </head>

     <div3 id="d62" n="1854-06-27" type="entry">
      <head>Wednesday June 27, 1854</head>
      <p>Left Staunton 6 oclock reached Alexandria at 2 took passage on the steamer George Page over
       to Washington, put up at Brown's Hotel. It was then between 3 &amp; 4 we ordered our
       dinner, after which it being quite late &amp; we very much fatigued with our days ride
       retired to rest. After breakfast next day we hired a hack to visit the places of note in the
       city We visited the President's house, Jackson's statue, The Washington monument, Smithsonian
       Institute Patent office, and Capitol.</p>
      <p>Smithsonian Institute, this is a beautiful building under the charge of the Government. We
       went into the entrance hall which contains a very fine library. &amp; hung on every side
       with paintings of the different tribes of Indians, showing their different <orig reg="style"
        >stile</orig> of dress. The only white man that we saw <orig reg="among">amoung</orig> these
       numerous paintings was that of John Ross, who has done so much towards civilizing the Indian.
       The Smithsonian Institute was founded by James Smithson an eminent Englishman. He died in
       1828 &amp; left the sum of $515,169 to the U. S. for the purpose of founding this
       institution - so in 1846 Congress passed an act to establish it, &amp; in May 1847 the
       cornerstone was laid with Masonic ceremonies in the presence of President Polk &amp; an
       immense concourse of strangers.</p>
      <p>Patent Office. This building occupies two</p>
     </div3>
    </div2>

    <div2 id="d63" n="1854-07" type="section">
     <head>July 1854 <!-- <ref>Family, Women, Arts/Leisure</ref> -->
     </head>

     <div3 id="d64" n="1854-07-xx" type="entry">

      <p>Left Washington 5 oclock P. M. reached Baltimore at 7. The next evening pa &amp; I
       walked out to do some shopping &amp; see as much of the city as we would have time. We
       intended going to visit the Washington monument, but found it was almost time to leave the
       city before we completed our <orig reg="shopping">shoping</orig>. We left in the 7 oclock
       train, when we had gone about 9 or 10 miles, we ran over a cow, &amp; ran off the track.
       This detained us about two hours. Finally we started again, &amp; papa was taken quite
       sick &amp; I sat &amp; held his head all night while Sally P. &amp; Alex slept We
       were obliged to get off at Cumberland as Papa was too sick to go on, &amp; he had a real
       spell of Cholera we spent our 4th there, at the Revere House &amp; also the week
       following.</p>
     </div3>

    </div2>

   </div1>

   <div1 id="AD9000notes" type="notes">
    <head>Notes <!-- <ref>AD9000notes</ref> -->
    </head>
    <note id="wright1" n="1" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{1}</seg>
     <p> Sarah Cordelia Wright was the daughter of John Grant Wright and Catherine Price Holloway
      Wright. John Wright went to Guyandotte, Va., about 1830 to take charge of the terminal office
      and inn of the James River and Kanawha Turnpike. The Turnpike followed the Kanawha or Buffalo
      Trail across the Allegheny Mountains into the Greenbrier Valley east of Marlinton, crossed
      Gauley Mountain and followed the Great Kanawha Valley to Charleston. Here the trail divided,
      one branch following the Great Kanawha to the Ohio at Point Pleasant, and the other crossing
      the Teays Valley to Guyandotte. The Turnpike ended here, but the old trail crossed the Big
      Sandy River into eastern Kentucky. Guyandotte was also an important point of steamboat
      embarkation. It lost its identity when C. P. Huntington established a railroad center bearing
      his name a few miles west of the old stagecoach - steamboat center.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright2" n="2" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{2}</seg>
     <p> In the spring of 1842 John Wright moved his family to Charleston where he took charge of
      the Kanawha House.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright3" n="3" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{3}</seg>
     <p> Sweetsprings opened as a watering place in 1792 but reached the height of its popularity
      after 1833. The first hotel was built by William Lewis, son of John Lewis, and contained 72
      rooms, 72 fireplaces, no baths. A later building was based upon a design of Thomas
     Jefferson.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright4" n="4" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{4}</seg>
     <p> Virginia Female Institute was founded in 1843 as a small day school. It was renamed Stuart
      Hall in 1907 in honor of Mrs. J. E. B. Stuart, who became principal in 1880. The school is
      owned and operated by the three Episcopal dioceses of Virginia. The "Register of 1853" says:
      "The Institute is beautifully located on one of the heights in Staunton, Va., and enjoys the
      most salubrious and invigorating atmosphere. Occupying a central position, easy of access,
      commanding beautiful views of mountain scenery and remote from the peculiar temptations
      incident to cities - this Institution presents important considerations to every Parent, who
      desires a Home-school for his daughters."</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright5" n="5" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{5}</seg>
     <p> Mrs. Jefferson Kinney, nee Sarah Robert Holloway.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright6" n="6" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{6}</seg>
     <p> "The Building was designed by a skillful Architect, and in 1846, was erected and furnished
      in handsome style, at an expense of more than fifteen thousand dollars. Its dormitories
      designed for four pupils each, are large and airy, and can comfortably accommodate fifty
      Boarders. The Principal and his family reside in the Institute, and the rooms of the Female
      Assistants are adjacent those of the pupils."</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright7" n="7" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{7}</seg>
     <p> "Roommates" listed in the 1853 Register are: Mary P. Bailey, Buckingham County Mary J.
      Robertson, Salt Sul. Springs Alice B. Harrison, Leesburg Julia A. Clagett, Leesburg Isabella
      V. Stuart, Fairfax County M. A. W. Custis, Norfolk Ella Brown, King William County Sarah A.
      Patrick, Charleston Fannie Smith, Parkersburg Sallie Stephenson, Parkersburg.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright8" n="8" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{8}</seg>
     <p> Throughout, this archaic form of holiday is used.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright9" n="9" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{9}</seg>
     <p> Daguerre announced the perfection of his process in 1839, and in November of that year the
      process was first used in this country by a silversmith in Zanesville, O.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright10" n="10" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{10}</seg>
     <p> Rebekah Kinney</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright11" n="11" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{11}</seg>
     <p> Now in the possession of the diarist's daughter, Sallie Kerr Hoge Lockett.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright12" n="12" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{12}</seg>
     <p> Tom Kinney</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright13" n="13" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{13}</seg>
     <p> The scientific advances in the natural sciences were the most intellectually stimulating
      news of the nineteenth century. In 1850 Cohn's theories on protoplasm were announced. The
      Register says: "Natural Sciences. The Botany classes are taught to analyze the living
      specimens in their season; and, under the direction of the Professor, have access to an
      extensive and beautifully arranged Herbarium, consisting of nearly ten thousand
     specimens."</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright14" n="14" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{14}</seg>
     <p> Rev. R. H. Phillips, A. M., Principal and Head of the Family, and Mrs. Phillips.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright15" n="15" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{15}</seg>
     <p> Rev. J. C. Wheat, A. M., Vice-Principal.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright16" n="16" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{16}</seg>
     <p> Mrs. James Points, wife of a Trustee of the Institute.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright17" n="17" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{17}</seg>
     <p> Probably Miss E. P. Tebbs, Assistant Teacher.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright18" n="18" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{18}</seg>
     <p> Probably Eleanor R. Goodwin, Fredericksburg.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright19" n="19" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{19}</seg>
     <p> "A regular record is kept of the Diligence, Neatness, Deportment and Scholarship of each
      pupil. To this end, each teacher makes a monthly report to the Principal, an abstract of which
      he renders monthly to the Parents. At the end of the Academic year, a certificate is given to
      each pupil, according to her grade in the four particulars above mentioned."</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright20" n="20" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{20}</seg>
     <p> Agnes G. Phillips, Staunton.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright21" n="21" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{21}</seg>
     <p> Probably old Trinity Church. The present edifice, the third on this site, was built in
      1855. The first church of Trinity Parish, organized in Augusta County in 1747, was erected in
      1760-63 on land acquired from William Beverley for 6. The Virginia Assembly met in this
      building in 1781, after crossing the mountains to escape the British.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright22" n="22" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{22}</seg>
     <p> Stephen Collins Foster published "Old Folks at Home" in 1851.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright23" n="23" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{23}</seg>
     <p> Rev. T. T. Castleman, Vice President of the Board of Trustees and Instructor of Moral
      Philosophy and Evidences of Christianity.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright24" n="24" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{24}</seg>
     <p> During the 50's, many planked roads - such as the Jerusalem, Orange and Boydton - appeared
      in Virginia.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright25" n="25" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{25}</seg>
     <p> "The Music class is divided into several sections, one of which performs at a weekly
      soiree, conducted by a Professor, in the presence of the class."</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright26" n="26" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{26}</seg>
     <p> Prof. J. C. Engelbrecht, Music and Botany.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright27" n="27" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{27}</seg>
     <p> Probably Lenora Ruffner of Charleston.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright28" n="28" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{28}</seg>
     <p> The California Gold Rush occurred in 1849.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright29" n="29" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{29}</seg>
     <p> Not identified.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright30" n="30" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{30}</seg>
     <p> "Three quarters of an hour after the rising bell, the Boarders assemble with the Principal,
      for the silent study of the Scriptures."</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright31" n="31" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{31}</seg>
     <p> "Collegiate Department. In the study of this course, the great aim is to teach the pupil to
      think, to acquire the control of her attention in the discipline of her mind, and to evolve
      and expand its powers. Much use is made of analysis, to enable the pupil to acquire a
      practical knowledge of principles and illustrative facts, that she may give, in her own
      language, at recitations, a connected outline of the subject."</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright32" n="32" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{32}</seg>
     <p> "The light bell rings at ten o'clock, when the lights are extinguished."</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright33" n="33" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{33}</seg>
     <p> "Nineveh and its Remains" by Sir Austen Henry Layard, English traveler and diplomatist, was
      published in 1849.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright34" n="34" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{34}</seg>
     <p> This "aunt Sarah" must have been a servant.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright35" n="35" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{35}</seg>
     <p> George A. Wright who later served in the Army of the Confederacy, took his degree in
      medicine from Washington and Jefferson College, married Helen Ruffner of Charleston, W. Va.
      and moved to Deport, Texas.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright36" n="36" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{36}</seg>
     <p> "It is a leading object to enlighten the mind with the instruction of Holy Writ; and
      present to the Pupil considerations derived from the moral relations she sustains, and the
      important influences of her present pursuits on her future destiny. Her moral and social
      position is constantly referred to, and the principles which should govern the one, and the
      decorum which should distinguish the other, are daily inculcated."</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright37" n="37" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{37}</seg>
     <p> Mrs. M. L. Rodgers, Matron.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright38" n="38" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{38}</seg>
     <p> This was unusual at the time and was probably possible because of the cold weather.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright39" n="39" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{39}</seg>
     <p> The Episcopal Church burial service makes no provision for a sermon.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright40" n="40" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{40}</seg>
     <p> March 4, 1853, Franklin Pierce was inaugurated President of the United States.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright41" n="41" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{41}</seg>
     <p> Probably a servant of the Kinney's.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright42" n="42" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{42}</seg>
     <p> Apparently Mr. Englebrecht was church organist as well as professor at V. F. I.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright43" n="43" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{43}</seg>
     <p> "Every pupil is required to write, weekly, a composition on a subject previously selected
      for her, and to read the same before the Teacher in charge of the section of which she is a
      member."</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright44" n="44" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{44}</seg>
     <p> Probably Western State Hospital, asylum for the white insane establlshed in 1825 as the
      Western Lunatic Asylum. </p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright45" n="45" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{45}</seg>
     <p> March 7, 1853, Jefferson Davis was appointed Secretary of War.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright46" n="46" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{46}</seg>
     <p> Not identified.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright47" n="47" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{47}</seg>
     <p> "Store bills are not allowed unless expressly authorized. Letters and parcels for the
      pupils should be directed to the care of the Principal. Jewelry and pocket money must be left
      in the care of a Teacher."</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright48" n="48" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{48}</seg>
     <p> " ** the silence bell announces the hour for retiring." This preceded the light bell.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright49" n="49" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{49}</seg>
     <p> Mary Ann Henry Holloway Lane.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright50" n="50" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{50}</seg>
     <p> "Pupils will not be allowed, under any circumstances, to spend the night out of the
      Institute."</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright51" n="51" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{51}</seg>
     <p> William Henley who married Betsy Ann Holloway.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright52" n="52" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{52}</seg>
     <p> I have not been able to find anything on the custom of an April fool letter. It must have
      been something like a comic Valentine.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright53" n="53" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{53}</seg>
     <p> Mary J. Jessie, Lancaster County, Va., in the Junior Section.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright54" n="54" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{54}</seg>
     <p> Virginia Military Institute opened in 1839. One of the students in 1853 was Sarah Wright's
      friend and neighbor from the Kanawha Valley, John McCausland, who was graduated from VMI in
      1857. McCausland served as a General in the Army of the Confederacy and is known as "The Man
      who Burnt Chambersburg". A formal invitation from Cadet McCausland to Miss Wright to attend a
      ball at VMI was found among her papers and given to General McCausland's daughter who lives in
      the old homeplace on the Winfield - Point Pleasant road a few miles northwest of the diarist's
      Putnam County residence.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright55" n="55" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{55}</seg>
     <p> Mary Caperton of Monroe County, Va.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright56" n="56" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{56}</seg>
     <p> "The Teachers are all exclusively connected with the Institute, and are Officers of
      Government in their several Departments; but cases of discipline are submitted to the
      Principal. The discipline is Parental, firm, prompt and uniform."</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright57" n="57" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{57}</seg>
     <p> Apparently Staunton had ready made dresses available.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright58" n="58" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{58}</seg>
     <p> Interest in the Orient was particularly high at this time because of Commodore Perry's
      expedition to Japan. He presented his credentials to the Emperor 15 July 1853.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright59" n="59" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{59}</seg>
     <p> Since the Central Railroad completed its tracks west as far as Staunton in 1854, it would
      seem Tom was "working on the railroad".</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright60" n="60" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{60}</seg>
     <p> Leesburg, Va.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright61" n="61" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{61}</seg>
     <p> This must have been a real event.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright62" n="62" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{62}</seg>
     <p> Assistant teachers.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright63" n="63" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{63}</seg>
     <p> Mary P. Bailey, Buckingham County, Va.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright64" n="64" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{64}</seg>
     <p> Elizabeth T. Meade, Dinwiddie County, Va.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright65" n="65" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{65}</seg>
     <p> Sally R. Drewry, Richmond, Va.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright66" n="66" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{66}</seg>
     <p> This is the diarist's sixteenth birthday anniversary.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright67" n="67" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{67}</seg>
     <p> Archie Kinney.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright68" n="68" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{68}</seg>
     <p> "The calls of gentlemen, who may be strangers to the Principal, and not specified by the
      parents, are not received by the pupils, unless authorized by letters of introduction. From 4
      o'clock to 5 P. M., is the most convenient hours for such calls."</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright69" n="69" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{69}</seg>
     <p> William Holmes McGuffey, at that time Professor of Moral Philosophy at the University of
      Virginia, but best known for the McGuffey Readers. Schools in western Virginia commonly used
      the McGuffey Readers, and no doubt they were part of the diarist's early instructional
      material.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright70" n="70" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{70}</seg>
     <p> Probably Eliza Lane who married Tom Reese of Huntington, W. Va.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright71" n="71" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{71}</seg>
     <p> White Sulphur Springs.</p>
    </note>

    <note id="wright72" n="72" place="end">
     <seg type="note-symbol">{72}</seg>
     <p> Warm Springs.</p>
    </note>


   </div1>

  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
