<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="B0523"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="B0523">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Freedmen's Bureau Records: W. Storer How to Orlando
                    Brown, September 29, 1865</title>
        <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records w storer how to orlando brown, september 29 1865</title>
        <author>How, W. Storer</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">B0523</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500778</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Freedmen's Bureau Records: W. Storer How to Orlando Brown, September
                            29, 1865</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records w storer how to orlando brown, september 29 1865</title>
            <author>W. Storer How</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives and Records
                            Administration, Records of the Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen, and
                            Abandoned Lands, Record Group 105, Box E4302.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1865-09-29">1865-09-29</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Employment/Labor, Legal System, Military Authority, Patriotism, Property,
                        Slavery</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2004-07">July 2004</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Ryan Fleenor</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item checked against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="B0523T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>How introduces the case of James Hamilton, a free black living in Maryland who
                    was captured and taken to Harrisonburg, where he was sold to William Shumate of
                    Staunton, Virginia. How presents what information he has, and asks for advice on
                    a possible course of action to reimburse Hamilton.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Bureau <abbr expan="Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands">R.F. &amp;
                        A.L.</abbr><lb/>Sixth <abbr expan="District, Virginia">Dist, Va</abbr>
                    <name type="recipient"><abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> O. Brown<lb/><abbr
                            expan="Assistant Commissioner">Asst. Comr.</abbr><lb/>Richmond, <abbr
                            expan="Virginia">Va</abbr></name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1865-09-29"><abbr expan="September">Sept</abbr> 29t 1865</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Colonel</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I have the honor to submit for your revision the following case with my action
                    upon it.</p>

                <p>James Hamilton, colored, says he was a free man living in Hancock <abbr
                        expan="Maryland">Md</abbr> before the war -- was free-born -- He was
                    captured by the rebels while driving a team in the service of the Government
                    somewhere between Winfield and Cumberland, and taken to Harrisonburg, Rockingham
                        <abbr expan="County, Virginia">Co, Va</abbr>, where he was put in Jail and
                    kept there four (4) months. In May 1864 he was sold to Mr. <abbr expan="William"
                        >Wm.</abbr> J. Shumate and by him taken to Staunton <abbr expan="Virginia"
                        >Va</abbr> where he was kept in Jail (1) one month. When <abbr
                        expan="General">Genl.</abbr> Hunter came along and Shumate took him out of
                    Jail Handcuffed and kept him so (4) four days and nights. He lived with and
                    worked for Shumate during one year leaving his service about the last of May
                    1865.</p>

                <p>I sent for Mr. Shumate who appeared and substantiated the main points of
                    Hamilton's statements.</p>

                <p>Shumate said he bought Hamilton of Mr. Trick, Jailer, in <orig reg="Harrisonburg"
                        >Harrisonburgh</orig> for 505, or 510 dollars. He was sold as he understood
                    by order of <unclear>Court</unclear>. Did not see the order knew that he
                    Hamilton claimed to be free, and that some one in Md had answered to Jailer's
                    letter to that effect. Knew also that he was a prisoner of war.</p>

                <pb n="2"/>

                <p>Afterwards brought to me the bill of sale, of which the following is a true
                    copy.<lb/> "<abbr expan="Received">Rec'd</abbr> of William Shumate - five
                    hundred Dollars it being in full for the purchase of a Negro man named James
                    Hamilton aged about 30 years. The <orig reg="right">write</orig> and title of
                    which man I sell for the term of twenty years, at which he is free unless some
                    one claiming proves a <orig reg="right">write</orig> to him as property. Witness
                    my hand and seal this the 4th May 1864."<lb/><abbr expan="Signed">Sigd</abbr>
                    Peter Trick (seal)</p>

                <p>Upon the facts as they thus appear and in the view of the fact that this Shumate
                    was a trader in doubtful "property" of that kind, and considering that Hamilton
                    would probably have been released as were the other prisoners in Harrisonburg
                    Jail by the troops under <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr> Hunter had not
                    Shumate gone there and speculated in him, I decided that Shumate should pay
                    Hamilton thirty (30) dollars per month (Hamiltons wages for one (1) year. He
                    demured and thought Irick, if anybody, should pay and wished me to see Irick,
                    which I did, but he is a poor, infirm old man who can recollect nothing except
                    that he sold Hamilton to Shumate for Jail Fees by order of
                    <unclear>Court</unclear> - the records of which have been destroyed.</p>

                <p>He claims to have been a "Union Man" but was old and could only do as he was bid.
                    I also submit without comment a letter from Shumate's attorney Mr. John B.
                    Baldwin, and repsectfully ask Instructions,</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute><abbr expan="Respectfully">Respy</abbr> &amp;c</salute>
                    <signed>W Storer How</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
