<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="B1005"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="B1005">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Freedmen's Bureau Records: George T. Cook to R. S.
                    Lacey, October 31, 1866</title>
        <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records george t cook to r s lacey, october 31 1866</title>
        <author>Cook, George T.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">B1005</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500873</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Freedmen's Bureau Records: George T. Cook to R. S. Lacey, October 31,
                            1866</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records george t cook to r s lacey, october 31 1866</title>
            <author>George T. Cook</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives and Records
                            Administration, Records of the Assistant Commissioner for the State of
                            Virginia, Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands, 1865-1869,
                            Record Group 105, M1048, roll 45.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1866-10-31">1866-10-31</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Economy, Employment/Labor, Family, Politics/Political Attitudes, Race
                        Relations, Slavery, Local Government</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2004-05">May, 2004</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="B1005T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Cook's detailed monthly report includes his commentary on the problems of labor
                    and employment, low wages, the struggles to provide for children in freedmen's
                    families, poll taxes, and the level of political engagement in Augusta County.
                    He concludes his letter by stating: "The prejudice of the white man against
                    allowing any rivalry by the black man must be conquered before the latter can
                    become in the full sense of the word, free."</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Bureau Refugees Freedmen and <abbr expan="Abandoned Lands">A.L.</abbr><lb/>Office
                    <abbr expan="Assistant">Asst.</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Superintendent">Supt.</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Sub-District">Sub-Dist.</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Number">No.</abbr> 10. 7<hi rend="super">th</hi>
                    <abbr expan="District">Dist</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Department">Dept</abbr> Potomac<lb/>Consisting of Augusta and
                    Highland Counties
                    <name type="recipient">Captain R. S. Lacey<lb/>Superintendent 7th <abbr
                            expan="District">Dist.</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr><lb/>Lynchburg, <abbr expan="Virginia"
                        >Va.</abbr></name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1866-10-31"><abbr expan="October">Oct</abbr> 31<hi rend="super">st</hi> 1866</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr><abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Captain</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I have the honor to submit the following report of Bureau Affairs in this <abbr
                        expan="Sub-District">Sub-Dist</abbr> for the Month ending October 31<hi
                        rend="super">st</hi> 1866.</p>

                <p>The freedmen are very quiet seeming to feel that it is the better for them to
                    submit to small inconveniences in order to live peaceably with their white
                    employers - The number of idlers is largely on the increase the working season
                    being nearly at an end; the majority of those who worked by the day must now be
                    unemployed or work for their board during the coming winter. Many families
                    throughout the Counties are now working on the same basis as before their
                    freedom, this will if continued soon bring a large class of them completely
                    dependent upon the will of the whites.</p>

                <p>This state of affairs is attributable in some degree to the manner in which
                    Slaves were treated here - it seems never to have been the practice to exact the
                    hard labor from them in this portion of the State, exacted through most of the
                    South the consequence is that as a class their labor is not as valuable</p>

                <pb n="2"/>

                <p>The fact that there is a great scarcity of money is another cause. The whites
                    claim to be unable to pay high wages, actual monied transactions in everyday
                    business dealings are rare and the enormous rates of interest which money
                    commands would seem to justify a belief in their plea of lack of money. If
                    whites in business transactions cannot trust each other how can it be expected
                    that justice will be done the ignorant freedpeople.</p>

                <p>The marriage register of the County of Augusta shows more than an average of
                    three children to each married couple. Many of these children are grown, still
                    the system of sale so lately in vogue has left a large proportion of small ones
                    for which the freedpeople are obliged to provide hence the services of the
                    Mother are generally obtained for her board and perhaps a few articles of
                    clothing, or if the family has more than its proportion of children the Mother
                    must have a house to live in and the family be chiefly subsisted by the Father
                    who if a first class hand may obtain from 8 to ten dollars per month for his
                    services with the understanding that the employer shall furnish him with
                    subsistance for his family at <hi rend="underline">Store</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">rates</hi> - the amount considered and the prices charged
                    are sometimes curious, and of course indisputable proofs of what can be made way
                    with in a small family. The effect in most instances is to leave <pb n="3"/>the
                    freedman little or nothing to look upon as saved at the end of a year of labor,
                    indeed he may be thankful if he is not in debt. I make the above statement to
                    show the system of labor in this County. I fear the result will be to leave a
                    large class in very destitute circumstances this winter.</p>

                <p>The system of County taxation seems very <unclear>unjust</unclear> the County
                    taxes in this Sub-<abbr expan="District">Dist</abbr> are altogether poll tax
                    amounting <add hand="h1" place="inline">in Augusta <abbr expan="County"
                        >Co</abbr></add> to three (3) dollars each this bears <add hand="h1"
                        place="inline">as</add> heavy upon a poor man as upon a man of property, it
                    is an outside matter but has its effect many of the freedmen call upon me to see
                    about the payment of tax; they seem to think it unjust to pay so much, and many
                    of them have ideas about voting in connection with paying tax, which in time
                    will lead them to demand good reasons for doing one and not the other. It seems
                    to have touched them in a sensitive spot when called upon to pay.</p>

                <p>The course of politics North is closely watched by them, in this town they are
                    remarkably well posted and I have found that news of that kind spreads through
                    the County very quickly. I am acquainted with one colored man who takes the
                    "Washington Chronicle" and regularly imparts the news to his Color.</p>

                <p>The freedmen are laboring under many disadvantages now which will require time
                        <pb n="4"/>at least to remove. The prejudice of the white man against
                    allowing any rivalry by the black man must be conquered before the latter can
                    become in the full sense of the word, free.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Very Respectfully<lb/>Your <abbr expan="Obedient">Obt</abbr> Servant</salute>
                    <signed><abbr expan="George">Geo.</abbr> T. Cook<lb/>1<hi rend="super">st</hi>
                        <abbr expan="Lieutenant">Lieut</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="Veterans Reserve Corps">V.R.C.</abbr> and <abbr
                            expan="Assistant">Asst.</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="Superintendent">Supt.</abbr></signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
