<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="B1016"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="B1016">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Freedmen's Bureau Records: Thomas P. Jackson to
                    Orlando Brown, September 30, 1867</title>
        <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records thomas p jackson to orlando brown, september 30 1867</title>
        <author>Jackson, Thomas P.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">11</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">B1016</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500884</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Freedmen's Bureau Records: Thomas P. Jackson to Orlando Brown,
                            September 30, 1867</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records thomas p jackson to orlando brown, september 30 1867</title>
            <author>Thomas P. Jackson</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives and Records
                            Administration, Records of the Assistant Commissioner for the State of
                            Virginia, Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands, 1865-1869,
                            Record Group 105, M1048, roll 48.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1867-09-30">1867-09-30</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Aid/Relief, Church/Religious Activity, Community Values/Local Behavior,
                        Employment/Labor, Legal System, Politics/Political Attitudes, Slavery, Race
                        Relations, Violence/Crime, Women, Health/Illness</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2004-05">May, 2004</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="B1016T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>One of the issues Jackson discusses in his monthly report concerns the ease with
                    which white employers defraud free blacks, because blacks are not yet
                    sufficiently educated to keep records pertaining to their employment. Jackson
                    also notes a rise in complaints related to physical assaults against women. The
                    letter also discusses relief for the poor, the ineffectiveness of the judicial
                    system, and the need for religious and moral education among former slaves.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Bureau <abbr expan="Refugees">Ref</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Freedmen">Fmen</abbr> &amp; <abbr expan="Abandoned">Aban<hi
                        rend="super">d</hi></abbr> Lands<lb/>Office 4 <abbr expan="Division"
                            >Div</abbr> 9<hi rend="super">th</hi>
                    <abbr expan="Sub-District">Sub Dist</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>
                    <name type="recipient"><abbr expan="Brevet">Brev</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="Brigadier">Brig</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr> O. Brown<lb/><abbr expan="Assistant">Asst.</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="Commissioner">Com<hi rend="super">r</hi></abbr> District of
                            <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr><lb/>Richmond (Thru <abbr
                            expan="Headquarters">H<hi rend="super">d</hi>Qrs</abbr> 9 <abbr
                            expan="Sub-District">S.Dist</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>)</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1867-09-30">
                            <abbr expan="September">Sept</abbr>
                            <abbr expan="30, 1867">30/67</abbr>
                        </date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>General</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>In compliance with the requirements of <abbr expan="Circular">Cir</abbr> Order
                        <abbr expan="Number">No.</abbr> 6 Series 1866 (<abbr
                        expan="Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands"
                    >B.R.F.&amp;A.L.</abbr>) I have the honor to report a condition of Bureau
                    affairs in this Division (counties of Augusta &amp; Highland) that
                    Freedpeople are peaceable and generally industrious, while employment is readily
                    procured at fair wages. While this is the rule there are of course exceptions -
                    some Freedmen are restless or indolent and many employers are not disposed to
                    treat with entire fairness the laborers that hire. This is becoming more
                    apparent as engagements for the crop season or year come to a close, and
                    disputes arise (now frequent) on the settlement. The system of long open
                    accounts with Freedmen is a door wide open to admit cheating. The laborer cannot
                    get his money from the employer but his family must eat and he takes Bacon,
                    Flour &amp;c for which he is charged store prices, while for Sugar
                    &amp;c or clothing he must accept <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> on some storekeeper who
                    charges his own price &amp; quantity and even if these are fairly charged he
                    is not able to keep an account and without knowing it he spends all his
                    earnings. During the past month <pb n="2"/>complaints of this kind have been
                    numerous, but as the Freedman has no check account of his own he cannot
                    substantiate his side of the transaction while the employer has books to verify
                    his side and the complaint falls to the ground. When I ask the question, why did
                    you take all these goods or orders when your contract calls for money, the
                    common answer is "I could not get money and my family had to eat and be
                    clothed." If the Freedman had eduction sufficient to keep an account of quantity
                    &amp; price of all they receive in lieu of money wages it would be no
                    disadvantage to them to take pay in the way but as it is now with them such a
                    custom which is rapidly becoming the system will give opportunity for endless
                    fraud. Where the facts in the case are clear I still find no difficulty in
                    securing payment <add hand="h1" place="inline">of wages</add> where there is
                    doubt I can do nothing. There is a general disinclination to come to the Bureau
                    agent to have contracts drawn some employers will not hire a man who wishes it.
                    The circumstances of a majority of Freedmen here are comfortable but those who
                    have to <unclear>incumbrance</unclear> are prone to frequent change and <hi
                        rend="underline">do not</hi>, while those with large families <hi
                        rend="underline">cannot</hi> accumulate. The Aged and helpless will be
                    reasonably cared for by the Overseers of the Poor, but medical aid for the sick
                    in the absence of any Dispensary in the county is out of reach of the poor or if
                    availed of in many cases involves the sick person in debt he cannot pay. <pb
                        n="3"/>I regret the Department is unable to furnish some Medicines for the
                    indigent Freedpeople here, the Social relations between white and colored though
                    in the main unchanged present no sign of improvement, in fact more complaints
                    than usual have been made during this month of both Freedmen and <hi
                        rend="underline">women</hi> being beaten by whites on trivial or no
                    provocation. I refer such cases promptly to the District Magistrate but redress
                    is so slow, uncertain &amp; expensive that the result practically increases,
                    not remedies the injury. Nothing can set this right but having at least a
                    majority of Magistrates selected from the non slaveholding class.</p>

                <p>The Political relations of the White and colored are as friendly as can be
                    expected between parties whose principles are diametrically opposite. That
                    Freedmen will cast their votes for Republican candidates is certain and it is
                    equally certain that their doing so will give great offense to many employers.
                    Already men are being punished in advance in the various ways, so easy for
                    proprietors or employers to resist to without infringing the letter of the law.</p>

                <p>The moral condition of the Freedmen admits of infinite change for the better and
                    such changes must be brought about before they can advance in the social scale.
                    Even yet the marriage relation is considered more a legal than moral bond <pb
                        n="4"/>and nothing but religious education of the young can obliterate the
                    demoralizing effect of generations of promiscuous intercourse between the sexes,
                    but consent if not encouragement of their masters. I regret I must again report
                    that no Division has yet been organized in Augusta or Highland in connection
                    with the "Lincoln Temperance Association" I have tried publicly and privately to
                    form such Divisions but the apathy of those who should <hi rend="underline"
                    >lead</hi> neutralizes my efforts for the present. There has been less
                    intoxication among freedmen here, during this month than the past. Numerous
                    enquiries continue to be made for relatives sold &amp; separated from each
                    other, but in the large majority of cases the clue is too indistinct to render
                    successful <orig reg="inquiry">enquiry</orig>
                    <add hand="h1" place="inline">probable</add> and I do not forward them.</p>

                <p>The general aspect of the Freedmens future is favorable compared with their
                    former position. Still they have much to do and much to learn to enable them to
                    advance in the march of progress in a corresponding degree with white men and of
                    this fact the Thinking men among them are becoming rapidly convinced and the
                    disposition is not to act aggressively against white men's rights but to be most
                    severely careful of their own rights so suddenly accorded to them.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Respectfully submitted<lb/><abbr expan="Your obedient servant">Yr obt
                            servt</abbr></salute>
                    <signed><hi rend="underline"><abbr expan="Thomas">Tho</abbr><hi rend="super"
                            >s</hi> P. Jackson</hi><lb/>Agent</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
