<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="B1012"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="B1012">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Freedmen's Bureau Records: Thomas P. Jackson to
                    Garrick Mallery, June 3, 1867</title>
        <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records thomas p jackson to garrick mallery, june 3 1867</title>
        <author>Jackson, Thomas P.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">B1012</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500880</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Freedmen's Bureau Records: Thomas P. Jackson to Garrick Mallery, June
                            3, 1867</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records thomas p jackson to garrick mallery, june 3 1867</title>
            <author>Thomas P. Jackson</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives and Records
                            Administration, Records of the Assistant Commissioner for the State of
                            Virginia, Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands, 1865-1869,
                            Record Group 105, M1048, roll 47.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1867-06-03">1867-06-03</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Aid/Relief, Community Values/Local Behavior, Economy, Employment/Labor,
                        Politics/Political Attitudes, Race Relations, </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2004-05">May, 2004</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="B1012T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Jackson's monthly report to the Bureau is relatively optimistic. He writes that
                    the local population is coming to accept the fact that freedmen are citizens,
                    and that they are more willing to settle contract disputes justly. Jackson also
                    discusses the improving prospects of the poor, and the general lack of
                    drunkenness, although medical care is still in short supply.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Bureau <abbr expan="Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands">R. F. &amp; A.
                        L.</abbr><lb/>Office 4th <abbr expan="Division">Div</abbr> 9 <abbr
                            expan="Sub-District">Sub Dist</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>
                    <name type="recipient"><abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> Garrick Mallery 43<hi
                            rend="super">d</hi>
                        <unclear>U.S.I.</unclear><lb/><abbr expan="Acting Assistant">A.A.</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="Adjutant">Adjt.</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="General">Gen'l</abbr><lb/>Richmond <abbr expan="Virginia"
                        >Va</abbr> (Through <abbr expan="Headquarters">HdQrs</abbr> 9th <abbr
                            expan="District">Dist</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>)</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1867-06-03">June 3, 1867</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Captain</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>In compliance with <abbr expan="Circular">Cir.</abbr> 6 S. 1866 (<abbr
                        expan="Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands"
                    >BR.F&amp;A.L</abbr>) I have the honor to report on the condition of Bureau
                    affairs in the 4th Division 9th <abbr expan="Sub-District">Sub Dist</abbr>
                    comprising the counties of Augusta &amp; Highland. The condition of
                    freedpeople is improving slowly it is true, as the large majority of Whites who
                    are employers are in straitened circumstances themselves but surely they are
                    being thrown more and more on their own resources, and are learning the value -
                    here at least - of time and money. The fact that the Freedman is now a citizen
                    is generally recognized and he is spoken of and treated with more consideration.
                    Employment is readily procured on farms, public works and lumbering at fair
                    wages and the large crop of grain and grass which will soon be ready for harvest
                    must place labor at a premium in this Valley. Numerous complaints are made at
                    this office of refusal to pay for labor under old contracts or sharp practice in
                    settlements under them but as a general rule I find the parties willing to
                    settle promptly and justly. Threats of discharge of Freedmen vote contrary to
                    the wishes of employers are very common but I attach but little importance to
                    them for the Freedmen will vote Republican almost <pb n="2"/>to a man and the
                    farmers of the two are the most dependent upon the other as with their large
                    prospective harvest <add hand="h1" place="inline">they have</add> the most at
                    stake and they will care less how the Freedman votes than how he works. The
                    feeling between the Freedmen and their <unclear>former</unclear> masters is
                    friendly with remarkably few exceptions. The condition of the sick, aged and
                    helpless both old and young has been much improved by the issue of rations
                    received at this Station and I am hopeful that with the incoming of garden
                    vegetables, further assistance from the Bureau will not be necessary as most
                    have small garden or corn patches and these will supply considerable food, while
                    friends will be able to help also.</p>

                <p>As to Medical attendance I respectfully renew my remark as to the needs of
                    freedpeople in this Division. Dr. S.C. Harris completed this month twelve month
                    gratuitous prescriptions and supply of medicine to the most indigent and
                    afflicted colored people in Staunton. I have been personally cognizant of these
                    services since my assignment to this station and I regret much that Dr. Harris
                    informs me this morning he cannot afford his services and medicine longer,
                    without remuneration sufficient to pay for the latter.</p>

                <p>I received a copy of <abbr expan="General">Genl.</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Oliver">O.</abbr> O. Howards <abbr expan="Circular">Cir.</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Letter">Lett.</abbr> of May 15/67 with reference to establishment
                    of "Lincoln" Temperance Associations and the general discouragement of drinking
                    intoxicating liquor and have made a suggestion in accordance therewith to some
                    of the leading <pb n="3"/>colored men in Staunton. If a copy of the constitution
                    and <orig reg="bylaws">bye laws</orig> of the Central Society at Washington can
                    be furnished I have no doubt a branch organization can be established here. I am
                    happy to state that in Augusta &amp; Highland, drunkenness is much more
                    prevalent among White than colored people and <hi rend="underline">quite
                        exceptional among</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">the Whites</hi>.</p>

                <p>Generally the future of the Freedman in my Division is full of promise. The aged
                    and orphans, of whom there are many, must continue dependent upon local or
                    National charity for some years, but the <orig reg="able-bodied">able
                    bodied</orig> male and female will shortly be able to take care of themselves,
                    physically and politically.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Respectfully submitted<lb/><abbr expan="Your obedient servant">Yr obt
                            servt</abbr></salute>
                    <signed><hi rend="underline"><abbr expan="Thomas">Thos</abbr> P
                        Jackson</hi><lb/>Agent</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
