<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="B1028"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="B1028">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Freedmen's Bureau Records: Roswell Waldo to Orlando
                    Brown, September 30, 1868</title>
        <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records roswell waldo to orlando brown, september 30 1868</title>
        <author>Waldo, Roswell</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">B1028</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500896</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Freedmen's Bureau Records: Roswell Waldo to Orlando Brown, September
                            30, 1868</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records roswell waldo to orlando brown, september 30 1868</title>
            <author>Roswell Waldo</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>6 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives and Records
                            Administration, Records of the Assistant Commissioner for the State of
                            Virginia, Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands, 1865-1869,
                            Record Group 105, M1048, roll 49.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1868-09-30">1868-09-30</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Community Values/Local Behavior, Church/Religious Activity, Aid/Relief,
                        Economy, Education, Employment/Labor, Property, Race Relations, Slavery</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2004-05">May, 2004</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="B1028T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Waldo's first monthly report as the Agent in Augusta and Highland Counties talks
                    about the deceptive behavior of white employers when settling labor contracts,
                    and he labels such practices "unmanly, ungenerous [and] outrageous." He also
                    mentions that almost no preparations had been made to make schools ready to open
                    at the beginning of the fall term because the local black communities lacked
                    resources and outside help was rare. </p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Bureau <abbr expan="Refugees">R.</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Freedmen">F.</abbr> and <abbr expan="Abandoned">A.</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Lands">L.</abbr><lb/>4th Division 9th <abbr expan="Sub-District"
                        >Sub Dist</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>
                    <name type="recipient">General O Brown<lb/><abbr expan="Assistant">Asst</abbr>
                        Commissioner<lb/>Richmond <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr></name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1868-09-30"><abbr expan="September">Sept.</abbr> 30. 1868</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>General:</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>In compliance with Circular <abbr expan="Number">No</abbr> 6 dated HeadQuarters
                        <abbr expan="Assistant">Asst</abbr> Commissioner Richmond <abbr
                        expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="January">Jany</abbr> 29, 1866 - I have the honor to submit the
                    following report of Freedmens Affairs in 4th <abbr expan="Division">Div</abbr>
                    (Comprising the Counties of Highland and Augusta) 9th <abbr expan="Sub-District"
                        >Sub Dist.</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> - viz.</p>

                <p>In consideration of the fact that the Fall work is not yet completed - the
                    freedmen as a general thing are well and lucratively employed, and will probably
                    continue to be so until Winter approaches, when as the demand for labor
                    decreases, many, in my opinion, will be discharged by their present employers,
                    and left without means for the support of themselves and <pb n="2"/>their
                    families, and as the colored people, almost without exception, are obliged to
                    rent the houses they live in (their extreme poverty preventing their owning
                    property) - and as their landlords universally charge such exorbitant prices for
                    their hovels and are so cruelly exacting in the prompt payment of their tenants
                    - much suffering may ensue. Instances of this character which have come to my
                    notice incline me to this opinion.</p>

                <p>The unmanly, ungenerous and I may add outrageous spirit manifested by many white
                    men in settling their accounts with their colored employees seems to demonstrate
                    the hatred and entire disregard for the welfare of the freedmen entertained by
                    their more fortunate neighbors. There are of course honorable men among them but
                    they can only be classed as the exceptions.</p>

                <p>As the white man is superior to the freedmen in point of intellect and self
                    government every advantage is taken of the ignorance of the latter in making
                    their settlements. Many colored men have suffered <pb n="3"/>gross injustice, at
                    the hands of their Employers in this manner. No matter how just may be the
                    account, some imaginary or trivial grievance is brought into requisition which
                    nearly or quite counterbalances it - and the colored man anxious for a
                    settlement of some kind readily yields, and he soon finds that if he is not
                    indebted to his supposed debtor he has little or nothing coming to him.</p>

                <p>As far as my observation has extended, I believe the freedmen, with few
                    exceptions are an industrious &amp; hardworking class willing and anxious to
                    do all in their power to Elevate themselves from their past condition and become
                    self-supporting - but they have difficulties to overcome and <orig
                        reg="obstacles">obsticles</orig> to surmount which the white man has not -
                    hence the<del hand="h1">ir</del> comparatively slow progress made in their
                    advancement. Their sudden transition from Slavery to freedom found them without
                    knowledge, property, or even implements of agriculture, with nothing but a <pb
                        n="4"/>strong arm and will to protect and sustain them against popular
                    prejudice - and with which to gain a livelihood. Should the Bureau be withdrawn
                    from their aid and protection at this time, while such an antagonism of feeling
                    exists between the races, I fear the result - as far as the promotion and
                    welfare of the colored man is concerned.</p>

                <p>I had received the impression when I first came to this Division that the
                    necessary preparations had been made for the opening of the Colored Schools for
                    their Fall term, but their failure <del hand="h1">of</del>
                    <add hand="h1" place="inline">to</add> commence the session when the proper time
                    arrived left me to inquiry, when to my surprise, I found nothing had been done
                    in that direction. No charitable Association has, as yet, interested itself
                    toward the support of a school in this Division for the coming Fall &amp;
                    Spring terms, I therefore urged the Colored people in this vicinity to call
                    meetings and take such means and support a school on their own responsibility.
                    This has been done in two or three localities, but it was found that their
                    poverty prevented their doing more than <pb n="5"/>paying the teacher's board.
                    One school, supported entirely by freedmen, and taught by a colored girl was
                    opened on the 21<hi rend="super">st</hi> inst. at Arbor Hill, Augusta County,
                    with this exception, there are at present no day schools in operation in my
                    Division. In Waynesboro, Augusta County, the colored people are striving to put
                    their church in a condition that a school may be opened there by the 15<hi
                        rend="super">th</hi> proximo in case a teacher and books can be provided. In
                    fact several schools might be opened in this Division during the coming winter,
                    if it were in the power of the Bureau or some charitable association to aid them
                    in procuring suitable school rooms and books for use of scholars.</p>

                <p>As to <hi rend="underline">Intemperance</hi>, the colored population seem to be
                    almost entirely free from it. Their failings and evil proclivities seem to
                    develop in another direction, that of choosing <hi rend="underline">mates</hi>
                    without performing the proper marriage ceremony etc. etc.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>I am General<pb n="6"/>Very Respectfully<lb/>Your obedient servant</salute>
                    <signed>Roswell Waldo<lb/><abbr expan="Assistant Sub Assistant Commissioner"
                            >A.S.A.Comr</abbr></signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
