<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="B1057"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="B1057">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Freedmen's Bureau Records: John W. Jordan to Orlando
                    Brown, June 30, 1868</title>
        <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records john w jordan to orlando brown, june 30 1868</title>
        <author>Jordan, John W.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">B1057</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500925</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Freedmen's Bureau Records: John W. Jordan to Orlando Brown, June 30,
                            1868</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records john w jordan to orlando brown, june 30 1868</title>
            <author>John W. Jordan</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>5 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives and Records
                            Administration, Records of the Assistant Commissioner for the State of
                            Virginia, Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands, 1865-1869,
                            Record Group 105, M1048, roll 61.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1868-06-30">1868-06-30</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Administration/Bureaucracy, Legal System, Military Authority, Patriotism,
                        Politics/Political Attitudes, Race Relations, Local Government</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2004-07">July 2004</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Ryan Fleenor</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item checked against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="B1057T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In his very detailed report, Jordan states that he tries to avoid the
                    adjudication of disputes involving freedmen in the courts because of the
                    pervasive prejudice in the system. He recommends the establishment of military
                    courts that would have jurisdiction over blacks and other "loyal" citizens, so
                    that they would be able to receive fair trials. He also calls for the extension
                    of the Bureau's tenure, and an increase in its powers to work against opposition
                    to the government.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands,<lb/>Office 4th Division, 9th
                    Sub-District, Virginia.
                    <name type="recipient"><abbr expan="Brevet Brigadier General">Bvt Brig
                        Gen.</abbr> O Brown<lb/><abbr expan="Assistant Commissioner">Asst
                        Comr</abbr> &amp;c<lb/>Richmond <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr></name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1868-06-30">June 30<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1868</date>
                        <name type="place">STAUNTON, VA.</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>

                <p>In compliance with Par VI <abbr expan="Circular">Cir</abbr> No 10 <abbr
                        expan="Headquarters">Hd Qrts.</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Assistant Commissioner">Asst Comr.</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands">B of R.F.
                        &amp; A.L.</abbr> Richmond <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr> March 12
                    1866 concerning the result of the operation of the "Order" restoring to the
                    "Civil Courts" jurisdiction over colored persons &amp;c. I have the honor to
                    submit the following Report pertaining thereto for the present month so far as
                    my Division is concerned.</p>

                <p>By reason of the fact that I still <pb n="2"/>persist in preventing the
                    adjudication of Freedmen's cases by the civil authorities there have been but
                    few cases in which colored persons appeared as parties brought before the courts
                    &amp; consequently I am not able to report any instances of injustice or
                        <unclear>oppression</unclear> towards the race growing out of indifference
                    to their complaint or prejudice to their interests. My experience in this sphere
                    of operation has resulted in the conviction that as a general thing the Civil
                    Courts and authorities in Virginia are in judgments, verdicts, and action <orig
                        reg="biased">biassed</orig> in fact controlled by partiality and prejudice
                    in their management &amp; disposition of cases in which colored persons are
                    interested and hence cannot in <unclear>justice</unclear> to my sense of duty
                        <pb n="3"/>permit the indiscriminate adjudication of such cases by said
                    authorities &amp; I am well satisfied the truth of this
                    <unclear>proposition</unclear> would be clearly and speedily demonstrated if the
                    Military authority was withdrawn if such a thing was necessary.</p>

                <p>Because of these facts I assume the responsibility of bringing the parties
                    together and giving them every reasonable opportunity of comprehending each
                    other which policy in a large majority of cases results in amicable settlements
                    of the differences, and the promotion of kindly feeling towards each other,
                    besides saving time and expense to all concerned.</p>

                <p>It cannot be concealed that <pb n="4"/>the feeling of bitterness against the
                    Government and its representatives is daily increasing and becoming more
                    aggressive this is evident from the bearing of those men who give
                    <unclear>tone</unclear> to public sentiment and thus direct the vindictive
                    hatred of the enemies of the <abbr expan="Government.">Govt.</abbr> The
                    treatment extended to those men who have shown a disposition to accept the
                    situation and who are earnestly striving to secure the speedy restoration of the
                    state to its rightful political relations to the <abbr expan="Government."
                    >Govt.</abbr> The threats made that freedmen shall be driven out of the land
                    &amp;c all contribute not only to rendering the continuance of the Bureau a
                    necessity but toward <pb n="5"/>extending the <hi rend="underline">powers</hi>
                    of Bureau officers.</p>

                <p>I believe now that it would greatly facilitate reconstruction, and make
                    substantial reliable loyal men out of kindly disposed but mild citizens if
                    Military Courts were established in each County with limited jurisdiction of
                    course, but which would secure especially to the Freedmen as well as loyally
                    disposed citizens equal &amp; impartial justice which I am afraid they
                    cannot obtain, especially in the lower Courts.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>I am General<lb/>Very Respectfully<lb/>Your <abbr expan="obedient">obt</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="Servant">Svt</abbr></salute>
                    <signed>Jno W. Jordan<lb/><abbr expan="Assistant Sub Assistant Commissioner"
                            >A.S.A. Comr</abbr> &amp;c</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
