<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="B1160"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="B1160">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Freedmen's Bureau Records: W. Storer How to Orlando
                    Brown, January 9, 1866</title>
        <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records w storer how to orlando brown, january 9 1866</title>
        <author>How, W. Storer</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">B1160</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501020</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Freedmen's Bureau Records: W. Storer How to Orlando Brown, January 9,
                            1866</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records w storer how to orlando brown, january 9 1866</title>
            <author>W. Storer How</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives and Records
                            Administration, Records of the Assistant Commissioner for the State of
                            Virginia, Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands, 1865-1869,
                            Record Group 105, M1048, roll 14.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1866-01-09">1866-01-09</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Administration/Bureaucracy, Aid/Relief, Community Values/Local Behavior,
                        Economy, Education, Employment/Labor, Legal System, Military Authority,
                        Property, Slavery, Race Relations</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2004-07">July 2004</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Ryan Fleenor</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item checked against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="B1160T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>How summarizes conditions throughout the Sixth Sub-District. In reference to
                    Augusta County, he mentions a riot on Christmas day, and the intransigence of
                    the white community.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands<lb/>Head Quarters, Sixth
                    District, Virginia
                    <name type="recipient"><abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> O. Brown, <abbr
                            expan="Assistant Commissioner">Assist Comr</abbr><lb/>Richmond, <abbr
                            expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1866-01-09"><abbr expan="January">Jany</abbr> 9, 1866</date>
                        <name type="place">Winchester, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Colonel</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I have again to respectfully report the condition of affairs in this District as
                    reasonably satisfactory in view of all the circumstances which are not favorable
                    to the greatest efficiency, since, as a rule, the usefulness of the Bureau is in
                    a direct ratio to the number of troops in the field.</p>

                <p><abbr expan="Lieutenant">Lt.</abbr>
                    <unclear>Tubbs</unclear>, <abbr expan="Assistant Superintendent">assist
                    Supt</abbr> says that in Botetourt County our forces "have been withdrawn and
                    the feelings are so bitter that it is impossible to do anything to assist the
                    Freedmen without the presence of the military. It would be worse than useless to
                    organize schools without protection, and there should be a school at Fincastle,
                    the <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <unclear>town</unclear>. This county is over seventy (70) miles from Rail
                        <unclear>communication</unclear> by way of Lexington, while it is only
                    fourteen (14) miles from Bradford Station on the Lynchburg <abbr
                        expan="Railroad">RRoad</abbr>."</p>

                <p>I therefore repeat the suggestion that it might be better controlled from the
                    Seventh than the Sixth District.</p>

                <pb n="2"/>

                <p>In Alleghany County the freedmen "are busily engaged trying to earn and furnish
                    living" and have no difficulties with the citizens although there are no troops
                    there. And this fact is properly accounted for by the <unclear>fine</unclear>
                    freedmen, the demand for their labor, and the absence of large plantation habits
                    and interests among the Whites, who are generally small farmers.</p>

                <p>Through the rest of this Sub District "a large percentage of the freedmen are
                    contracting for the next years labor, but money is so scarce that the employers
                    make their own contracts which are quite liberal to the freedmen." "I know of no
                    paupers or vagrants in this Sub District." "During the past Christmas they have
                    behaved so nobly that they have won praises from their bitterest enemies." Every
                    effort to organize a Board of Agents has failed, and <abbr expan="Lieutenant"
                        >Lt.</abbr> Tubbs thus has to adjudicate all cases, and he says "there are
                    but few crimes committed by the freedmen."</p>

                <p>In Augusta County there is no <unclear>noticed</unclear> change. There was very
                    nearly a riot in Staunton on Christmas day through the free use of liquors, and
                    the fact was unmistakenly evidenced that the freedmen need protection from bad
                    men who were <pb n="3"/>but lately "masters" and "<unclear>Whites</unclear>,"
                    and who would now override any civil laws not in accordance with their notions
                    of a White mans privilege.</p>

                <p>In Highland <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr> I have but just been able to get a
                    foothold, and temporarily stationed <abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> Wells,
                    again at Harrisonburg who <unclear>operated</unclear> with good effort upon the
                    peculiarly rebellious spirits there, who had succeeded in frightening away Mr
                    McLean, a teacher of the freedchildren.</p>

                <p>I have arranged for his successor who would be maintained there so long as there
                    is any force at my disposal.</p>

                <p>In Shenandoah <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr> everything is working as well as
                    could be expected.</p>

                <p>In Warren County I have no agent for want of troops to sustain him. An attempt
                    has been made to establish a school at Luray, but the teacher has already asked
                    for military support which I shall be unable to find him.</p>

                <p>In Frederick and Clarke Counties the condition of the freedmen is as each
                    reported, good.</p>

                <pb n="4"/>

                <p>In Jefferson and Buckley counties they are generally well off and fairly treated.</p>

                <p>Taken as a whole, the freedmen in this District are in comfortable circumstances,
                    and conducting themselves in a highly creditable manner. Yet there are many
                    cases of suffering among the very poor and helpless, and especially needed for
                    their relief is <hi rend="underline">fuel</hi>. I have been able to supply
                    clothing and food to quite a large number, but the want of wood -- with the
                    thermometer below <unclear>0 zero</unclear> -- has been seriously felt, and
                    great suffering has been and will be the result of our inability to afford the
                    desired relief.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>I am Colonel<lb/>Very Respectfully<lb/>Your obedient Servant</salute>
                    <signed>W. Storer How, <abbr expan="Captain">Capt</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="Assistant Quartermaster">AQM</abbr><lb/><abbr
                            expan="Superintendent">Supt</abbr> Sixth <abbr expan="District">Dist</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr></signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
