<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0012"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F0012">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter,
                    December 3, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, december 3 1862</title>
        <author>Potter, Samuel M.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F0012</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501187</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter, December 3, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, december 3 1862</title>
            <author>Samuel M. Potter</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>1 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Pennsylvania Historical and
                            Museum Commission, Civil War Material, Misc. Diaries, and Letters,
                            Microfilm, MG-132</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note>
                            <p>This transcription was made from a typescript of the original
                            letter.</p>
                        </note>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-12-03">1862-12-03</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties, Desertion/Leave,
                        Family, Medicine/Hospitals, National Government, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-01">January 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against transcription; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F0012T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Potter describes his camp near Washington, D.C. and tells his wife about his trip
                    through the city with a doctor, where he saw the White House and the Georgetown
                    College Hospital. His letter includes a postscript addressed to his sister Mary
                    with individual messages to each of his children.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-12-03">Dec3 1862</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Casey Near Washington D.C.</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Wife</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Our boys came from Harrisburg yesterday bringing your last letter with them
                    &amp; it made me feel sorry that Bell was sick but I hope she will get
                    better soon &amp; be running around singing &amp; playing with Josey
                    &amp; Lucy making you <orig reg="feel">fell</orig> more cheerful. The box
                    has never come yet with Polly Harvey's mince pies. Tell Polly I am sorry she
                    could not get her pies sent, that her kindness will compensate for their loss.
                    Our camp here is very pleasant &amp; we are getting along very comfortable.
                    The Doctor took me with him to the city on Monday. We passed through it seeing
                    the White House and a great many other things that paid for the trip. We went
                    over to the Georgetown College Hospital where there are about 500 sick &amp;
                    wounded soldiers. This was a Catholic College &amp; I saw a number of the
                    priests in their long black robes with white crosses hanging from their belts.
                    They were going about with books in their hands reading to the boys. We took
                    dinner then with the Doctors of the Hospital &amp; visited some of the
                    patients. It was the cleanest &amp; <orig reg="airiest">airyest</orig> place
                    for the sick I have seen yet. We did not cross the Potomac river but we met a
                    brigade of New Jersey infantry that had &amp; I tell you the soldiers were
                    sweating with their heavy knapsacks, muskets &amp; cartridge boxes.
                    Washington City appears to be full of Government wagons. We met them &amp;
                    passed them at every street by hundreds. There were not very many soldiers
                    around but on every hill there was a camp. Congress is in session now &amp;
                    I wish to go if I can &amp; see the August body. You speak about Miller
                    &amp; Gunn being at home &amp; why may not I be there as well as them.
                    Well I could if I would only run the risk. They only get 24 hours leave of
                    absence &amp; then stay a week or two &amp; no person in the company
                    bothers about reporting them to the Colonel. But my situation is quite different
                    &amp; if I were to go it would cost me my position. It is for your sake that
                    I wish to hold it, so that I can do more for you &amp; the children. Still I
                    will try all I can to get home. We have some sick to see evey day. I have had my
                    bounty 27 dollars &amp; spent part of it. The balance of it I wish to keep
                    to go home on. In the last letter I wrote you I gave you the wrong directions
                    for sending <orig reg="your">you</orig> letters. Send</p>

                <p>S.M. Potter<lb/>16Pa. Cavalry<lb/>Camp Casey<lb/>Washington D.C.</p>

                <p>Be sure to put the number of the regiment on the letter and send it to Washington
                    City &amp; they will send it after the regiment.</p>

                <p>I will close my letter here by sending my love to you alike my best wishes to
                    Polly Harvey, Mrs. Roney, &amp; the rest of the neighbors.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your affectionate husband</salute>
                    <signed>S. M. Potter</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">I dont think of anything else to write. I dreamed of
                        being at home with you last night &amp; had a good talk with you.<lb/>
                        Sister Mary <lb/>Cynthia said you were spinning. You did not write any in
                        her last letter &amp; I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> think I answered
                        your last. Since I commenced writing this the Doctor has gone to town, the
                        nurses are out &amp; I am in here by myself with the sick &amp;
                        cannot have much time to write without being <orig reg="interrupted"
                            >interupted</orig>. Mary you are very kind to mine &amp; I wish you
                        may be rewarded for your kindness. Josey I am glad that you are at the head
                        of your class. That is the way my boy <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> be
                        behind. &amp; Lucy carries <unclear>chips</unclear> &amp; goes to
                        town on errands like a good girl. Poor Bell is sick. Pa would nurse you in
                        his arms Bell if he was at home &amp; Show you the pictures in your new
                        book. Lucy you will help Ma &amp; Aunt Mary wont you. </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
