<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0022"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="F0022">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter,
                    September 5, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, september 5 1863</title>
        <author>Potter, Samuel M. </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Murrell </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">13</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0022</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501197</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note>
                    <p>This is transcribed from a typescript.</p>
                </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter, September 5,
                            1863</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, september 5 1863</title>
            <author>Samuel M. Potter</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Potter Letters, Microfilm MG-132, Civil War
                            Material, Misc. Diaries and Letters, Pennsylvania Historical and Museum
                            Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-09-05">1863-09-05 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Desertion/Leave, Medicine/Hospitals, Home Front </term>
                    <term>Regiment: 16th Pa. Cav. </term>
                    <term>Company: </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0022T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Potter announces that he has recovered from his illness and explains in detail
                    how he and his fellow soldiers cook food in camp. He also responds to his wife's
                    suggestion of buying some property.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Cynthia Potter</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-09-05"><abbr expan="September">Sept.</abbr> 5<hi
                                rend="super">th</hi> 1863 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp 16<hi rend="super">th</hi>
                            <abbr expan="Pennsylvania 
                                Cavalry">Pa. Cav.</abbr> Near Sulphur Springs
                            <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>
                        </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Cynthia </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Your most welcome letter dated August 28<hi rend="super">th</hi> was received
                    yesterday evening &amp; I was glad to hear that you are all well. It has
                    been some time since I heard from you. I was beginning to think there was
                    something wrong with the mail of our Corp, as I understood the 2<hi rend="super"
                        >nd</hi> Corp mail had been robbed. I got a letter the other day that you
                    had written while I was sick &amp; sent to the care of John Milligan
                    (&amp; by the way he is quite unwell now) inquiring about my sickness as I
                    was stout &amp; hearty when it arrived &amp; you had been informed of
                    the improvement of my health I did not answer it. You wish to know if I am quite
                    well now. Well I can assure you that it is the best that it has been in years
                    &amp; in regard to what I get to eat. It is better living than I have had
                    since I came out. We have corn syrup or fried corn or have it roasted. Every day
                    we have green beans, corn &amp; pickled pork cooked together an <orig
                        reg="excellent">excellant</orig> dish. We draw potatoes &amp; roast them
                    or cook them any way we like for breakfast. Several days back we have had our
                    potatoes pared &amp; an onion or two &amp; sliced &amp; then after
                    frying our meat we put them in with it &amp; pour on some water &amp;
                    let them stew down cooking soft with a rich gravy. Then our cup of coffee
                    &amp; my dish of elderberries &amp; fox grapes stewed with plenty of
                    sugar to season &amp; our soft bread (as we are getting it now) makes a good
                    enough meal for a soldier. The boys are all living well now. We got some pickled
                    cabbage from the commissary the other day &amp; I <orig reg="don't"
                    >dont</orig> think any of them care for it. As far as food &amp; clothing
                    are concerned there are thousands of soldiers better provided for here than they
                    would be at home. You ask if I think the boy is pretty. He is quite good looking
                    in the picture &amp; the mother I suppose is not bad looking at least if the
                    picture is a good one. I reckon you think she is quite a beautiful lady. Well
                    maybe you are not far wrong. About George McDavid. He was not seriously ill.
                    When I was with him in dismounted camp his <orig reg="stomach">stomache</orig>
                    &amp; liver were deranged having a <orig reg="diarrhea">diarrhoea</orig> of
                    billious character. When he went to Doctor's call in the morning the most he
                    complained of was the <orig reg="diarrhea">diarrhoea</orig> &amp; all they
                    gave him was Camphor &amp; Opium mixed (a very good remedy in simple <orig
                        reg="diarrhea">diarrhoea</orig> but doing his <orig reg="stomach"
                    >stomache</orig> &amp; liver no good. His color was good. Neither did he
                    appear to lose flesh much but complained of palpitation of the heart at times
                    &amp; I think that was hurting him as he had a certificate formula from a
                    Doctor of New Brighton that his heart was diseased which would scare him some
                    &amp; make him think he would not be fit for active service. Now my opinion
                    is that if his <orig reg="stomach">stomache</orig> &amp; liver were all
                    right his heart would not bother him any. You speak of buying the Dougherty
                    property for 125 dollars &amp; ask me what I think of the bargain. Well it
                    will take a sum of money you will have to pay for the property &amp; to
                    improve it will pay your rent where you are &amp; then we will have a chance
                    for getting a better location for business, for if you put the money into it it
                    maybe a good number of years before you can get it out again. You know best if
                    there is any speculation in it if you could sell it after awhile for more than
                    you put into it. Such property did not sell very good in Good Intent. You would
                    know better than I would if there is any demand for it now. I <orig reg="don't"
                        >dont</orig> think there is anything to be gained in buying. Write me more
                    about it in your next. Is the place improving any. Are there any mechanics or
                    other business men coming to settle in it &amp; how are those doing who are
                    doing business in it. How are the stores Flourishing. Have they good stocks of
                    goods &amp; is there much custom coming to the place or do the farmers go to
                    Scrabble, Claysville, Knoxes, Burnsville or Washington. Bell wants to know where
                    Pa is when it is raining. If you would spread a sheet over a pole raised about
                    six feet from the ground she would have some kind of an idea of the house I live
                    in. We have been blessed this fall with the finest kind of weather. It is
                    delightful. Cool enough to be pleasant &amp; dry. Our camp is in a grove
                    quite shady &amp; cool. I have a bunk in our tent &amp; some hay in
                    coffee sacks making a delightful bed &amp; as I have told we have plenty to
                    eat of the best. We have been in this camp about 2 weeks. Have good water. Can
                    go to the river &amp; take a bath or go to the springs &amp; drink
                    Sulphur water if we like. The men in the companies have some duty to do. They
                    have to ride 20 or 30 miles some days on a scout. (now and then not every day).
                    At this time they are out on picket. We have the lame &amp; sick in camp.
                    Tell Josey if he wants to soldier put his cup full of water on the fire. Let it
                    boil. Put in a spoonful of coffee &amp; let it burn his fingers when it
                    boils over &amp; he tries to take it off. Then take a piece of fat pork. Get
                    a rod about 2 feet long. Sharpen one end &amp; stick it in the pork. Then
                    hold it over the fire. The grease dripping will make it blare. Nicely roast his
                    meat a little then put some water over it it to wash off the salt which the fire
                    draws out. Then hold it over the fire again &amp; it is done &amp; very
                    good it will be to eat if he has not had anything to eat since yesterday
                    morning. That is our style of cooking sometimes on the march. Then if he wants a
                    bed let him go into a fence corner when it rains. Put a blanket on the ground,
                    an over coat over him &amp; an oil cloth over all &amp; let it rain. We
                        <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> have it often that way. At Gettysburg we got
                    to camp after dark one night &amp; Dr. Miller &amp; I made such a bed
                    but happened to make it in a hollow. About 3 <orig reg="o'clock">oclock</orig>
                    in the morning we <orig reg="awoke">awaked</orig> in about six inches of water
                    &amp; just remembered the old adage early to bed &amp; early to rise so
                    we thought we would rise early from our soft bed, built a large fire &amp;
                    enjoyed early rising. Lucy would not have much to do in the way of washing
                    dishes as she would be scolded for breaking any. I think I will be able to make
                    good cooks of you all after I get home. As our house is open at both ends I
                    would not want you to be here when it is raining &amp; the wind blowing hard
                    I am afraid your clothes would get damp but some of these nice days I think I
                    would like to see them playing around this nice place. You need not come though
                    for I would not know where to get a chair for Jimmy to push around &amp;
                    then if we do get a chair it would catch in the roots of a tree in our floor
                    &amp; he would not like that. You tell me to ask the Captain for a furlough.
                    I see you <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know much about it. In the first place I
                    would write out a form, the Doctor would sign &amp; then send it to the
                    Colonel who would approve it, the Adjutant would then send it to the <orig
                        reg="Brigadier">Brigidier</orig> General. He must approve it, then it is to
                    be sent to the General of our division. He must approve it &amp; then it
                    would be sent to General Pleasanton Commanding the Cavalry Corps &amp; he
                    approves it &amp; send it back the same route. In about 2 weeks it come back
                    if they all approve it written all over inside &amp; out. They are not
                    giving any at all now. It was through the influence of <del hand="h1">Gen</del>
                    <abbr expan="Colonel">Col</abbr> &amp; Gregg that I got one in July
                    &amp; that was not a furlough but an order to be absent for a number of
                    days, which I am sorry I did not get as it came back to regiment while I was
                    sick in Maryland Harpers Ferry &amp; Miller thought I was in a Baltimore
                    Hospital so he mailed it to Baltimore &amp; I did not get it. I do not hope
                    to get one until cold weather sets in. The Post Master will soon be here so I
                    will close &amp; take a ride down to the river as I have been writing all
                    day making out reports etc. </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Your most affectionate husband &amp; father </salute>
                    <signed>S.M. Potter </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
