<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0020"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="F0020">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter,
                    July 20, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, july 20 1863</title>
        <author>Potter, Samuel M. </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Murrell </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0020</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501195</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War. </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note>
                    <p>This is transcribed from a typescript.</p>
                </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter, July 20, 1863</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, july 20 1863</title>
            <author>Samuel M. Potter</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Potter Letters, Microfilm MG-132, Civil War
                            Material, Misc. Diaries and Letters, Pennsylvania Historical and Museum
                            Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-07-20">1863-07-20 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Battle Description, Death/Casualties, Family, Medicine/Hospitals, Troop
                        Movement </term>
                    <term>Regiment: 16th Pa. Cav. </term>
                    <term>Company: </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0020T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Potter explains his lapse in writing as the result of a stomach and liver illness
                    he contracted after the battle at Gettysburg.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Cynthia Potter</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-07-20">July 20<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1863 </date>
                        <name type="place">Harpers Ferry <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Cynthia </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Will you ever excuse me for not writing you for so long a time. I know you will
                    &amp; I must assure I feel very sorry for you &amp; will hurry &amp;
                    tell you the reason for not writing sooner. Soon after the battle at Gettysburg
                    I got sick. My stomach &amp; liver were out of order. I hung on day after
                    day hoping to get better but instead got worse. We were moving over the
                    mountains until we came to <orig reg="Boonesboro">Boneboro</orig> Md. when I got
                    so sick as not to be able to go any farther. The Doctor sent me to a barn with
                    John Milligan to wait on me. I lay there a week &amp; got some better. Then
                    we come down here yesterday Sabbath. I was still better but did not feel strong
                    enough to ride every day with the retiment, when I got the Doctor to write an
                    order for me to go to Baltimore to go to the hospital. Well the Dr. wrote the
                    order &amp; I came here. Saw the Quartermaster who had charge of the <abbr
                        expan="Railroad">R.R.</abbr> &amp; he told me I would have to get a
                    transportation order from <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Lockwood. I called
                    on him &amp; he sent me to his Medical Director who told me I would have to
                    go into the hospital here. He could not send me to Baltimore so I stopped here.
                    There are about 200 sick here. I have to act as Hospital Steward for them. They
                    have not been in operation long &amp; are not fully arrayed yet. The <abbr
                        expan="Doctors">Drs.</abbr> are very glad that I did come, as they had no
                    one who knew anything about a Hospital Stewards duties &amp; some of the
                        <abbr expan="Doctors">Drs.</abbr>
                    <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know much about Hospital practice. They treat me
                    very kindly. I hope to be able to get a furlough &amp; get home before I got
                    back to the <abbr expan="Regiment">Regt.</abbr> I have felt very bad about you
                    since I was sick knowing that you would be uneasy. You would go over to the
                    postoffice &amp; wait patiently for letter then to be <orig
                        reg="disappointed">dissapointed</orig> time after time. I know it would be
                    very unpleasant for you. It has been the greatest trouble &amp; sorrow I
                    have known to be <orig reg="disappointed">dissapointed</orig> in getting your
                    letters &amp; the children too would wonder where Pa is. I do wish I knew
                    where he is. I think I can hear Josey saying. &amp; so you are all at home
                    again, you wrote to me in your last. I forgot myself when I was reading it
                    &amp; I thought I was at home on the back porch reading your letter
                    &amp; you were getting dinner for me. I felt bad about it &amp; wished I
                    could have got up &amp; run there on the double quick. Well we have driven
                    the rebs back into Old <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> again &amp; hurt
                    them some as they were going. Our regiment had a brush with them while I was
                    sick &amp; several were killed &amp; some wounded. Abe Lezarden was
                    killed &amp; James Milligan was wounded. I hear our hospital was a factory
                    &amp; stands high on the Virginia side of the Potomac which washes the walls
                    of the building. The Stewards room has a window looking out on the river
                    &amp; I am writing this on the window seat with the roar of the river in my
                    ears as I write. This is called the Factory Hospital &amp; if you write soon
                    address Factory Hospital, Harpers Ferry.</p>

                <p><orig reg="Tuesday">Teusday</orig>. The mail has not gone yet but will in an hour
                    or two &amp; I will write a little more since this is the most enjoyment I
                    have since your letters can not reach me from the Regiment. I feel quite well
                    this morn &amp; should go back to the Regiment but as they want me to stay
                    here I will remain &amp; see if I can not get a furlough. to get home. I
                    would like so well to see you all once more. I would like to hear from you soon
                    to find out how you all are. How Josey has got over scared at drowning. I hope
                    he will be more careful of the millrace &amp; keep a respectful distance
                    from it. How do Lucy &amp; Bell get along. Tell about them when you write
                    &amp; Jimmy I suppose Jumping Jimmy from what you say of his activity is he
                    walking yet. How is the cow getting along. Do you have her in a pasture or is
                    she living as usual in the road. I suppose you have a good garden. I hope to be
                    able to help you eat some of it this summer, if my furlough comes all right. I
                    will still leave you in the hands of our Great Preserver who has kept us all so
                    long in the midst of dangers &amp; preserve us from harm. Oh how I would
                    like to be sitting beside you in the old church on the hill listening to Mr.
                    McKee. Those were among the most pleasant hours of my life there to have them
                    with the children &amp; me there &amp; oh how I would like to enjoy them
                    again. I hope God will preserve &amp; protect us &amp; permit us to meet
                    again to enjoy the service of his sanctuary again on earth. Pray for me dear
                    Cynthia that I may grow in grace maybe more sanctified &amp; that I may be
                    more acceptable to my Creator &amp; I will still pray for my dear wife that
                    she may be kept in the hollow of Gods hand, that no harm may <orig reg="befall"
                        >befal</orig> her that she may be made holy &amp; righteous that we all
                    parents &amp; children may be accepted by the Almighty through his son the
                    Lord Jesus Christ. That will bless you all in the prayer of your most
                    affectionate husband. </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute> </salute>
                    <signed>S. M. Potter </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
