<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0034"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="F0034">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter,
                    April 21, 1864</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, april 21 1864</title>
        <author>Potter, Samuel M. </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Murrell </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0034</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/ </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501209</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note>
                    <p>This is transcribed from a typescript.</p>
                </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter, April 21, 1864</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, april 21 1864</title>
            <author>Samuel M. Potter</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Potter Letters, Microfilm MG-132, Civil War
                            Material, Misc. Diaries and Letters, Pennsylvania Historical and Museum
                            Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-04-21">1864-04-21 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Troop Movement </term>
                    <term>Regiment: 16th Pa. Cav. </term>
                    <term>Company: </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0034T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Potter reports on his brigade's movement away from Warrenton, Virginia, and asks
                    about the family.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Cynthia Potter</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-04-21">April 21<hi rend="super">st</hi> 1864 </date>
                        <name type="place">Hospital Dept. 16th Pa. Cav., Turkey Run, VA. </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Wife </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Yours of the 15<hi rend="super">th</hi> was <orig reg="received">recieved</orig>
                    this evening &amp; I am glad to see that you are all well. We had a report a
                    day or two ago that the mail would be stopped for 60 days. Now I am convinced
                    that it was a false report &amp; the letter that I wrote needlessly alarmed
                    you.</p>

                <p>Our 1<hi rend="super">st</hi> Brigade moved today from Warrenton to a point
                    between us and the Junction. Our Brigade which has been scattered has moved
                    closer together our regiment remaining in our old quarters. There is no enemy
                    near that we know of. My health continues good as usual. You ask what we have to
                    eat. Well the usual army rations. Fresh bread, potatoes, dried apples, coffee,
                    sugar &amp; beans every day. Fresh beef 3 days in the week &amp; fat
                    pork the other 4 days. Some times we get onions &amp; pickled cabbage
                    sometimes molasses. So you see that I live very well. I wish my family lived as
                    well.</p>

                <p>When you go to my party at Mr. McGills you will find more <orig reg="delicious"
                        >delecious</orig> things than we do in Dixie. </p>

                <p>George <orig reg="Sutherland's">Sutherlands</orig> was a rather sudden death. How
                    is his <orig reg="father's">fathers</orig> health. This will be hard on him. </p>

                <p>John Danely you say is very bad. He has been very much afflicted. Is his
                    complaint the same &amp; how is <orig reg="Elizabeth's">Elizabeths</orig>
                    health. She was not very stout when I was there.</p>

                <p>Frank McCoy must be quite hearty now. Give him my compliments if at home yet. So
                    you think I am a sensible fellow for loving the smiling woman whose picture I
                    have before me. I will expect that smile kiss &amp; sweet welcome when I get
                    home.</p>

                <p>Has Debby bronchitis as bad as she had formerly. I hope not. When the weather
                    gets warm she will get better.</p>

                <p>Sam Danley has had some of our luck in cows. Well he can easy replace one. Give
                    Catherine &amp; him my kindest regards.</p>

                <p>I suppose you are quite proud now that you have two boys to carry up wood for you
                    &amp; to work for you. Well keep them employed &amp; that will keep them
                    out of bad company. Can your daughters Lucy &amp; Bell get a dinner for you
                    yet. I hope you may get up to Grandpas with the children this summer. If I do
                    not get home to take you try &amp; get up anyhow. I would like to eat some
                    of your eggs just for the fun of it &amp; then to see the race among the
                    little fellows. How does Jimmy get along &amp; does he lay <orig reg="too"
                        >to</orig> late in bed to be in the egghunting business. Tell Bell I think
                    she has the advantage as Mother helps her. Does she get the most eggs. What a
                    fine time Josey will have at McGills hunting with Bennie. Jimmie wants you to
                    tell Pa that you will have a kiss for him. I expect Lucy &amp; Bell are good
                    girls to help amuse their little brother. Could Josey &amp; Lucy go up the
                    hill to Sunday School this summer &amp; get some of their books out of the
                    library. It would be nice. You must send up to <orig reg="Grandpa's"
                    >Grandpas</orig> &amp; get some money. Get yourself shoes &amp; the
                    children if they need any.</p>

                <p>I would like to be with you when Jimmy is baptized &amp; will ask you to wait
                    awhile. It is my duty &amp; a great pleasure &amp; one I hope to enjoy
                    God willing. So my dear wife if it is his will I will stand at your side
                    &amp; take the vows with you hoping God will give us grace to keep our vows
                    &amp; bring the children up in his fear &amp; walk in his paths
                    ourselves.</p>

                <p>I fear I <orig reg="can't">cant</orig> get home in time for Communion at the
                    Lords Supper with you but do go by all means &amp; when at the table pray
                    for me. Give my respects to all our neighbors &amp; friends. Rest assured of
                    the continued love &amp; esteem of</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your husband </salute>
                    <signed>S. M. Potter </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">I will not close until morning &amp; give you all the
                        news although that is our busiest time.<lb/> Morning pleasant nothing new
                        all is quiet. I am well yet &amp; hearty. It is thought that we will
                        move soon. Mail goes out soon. Kiss the children for me. My love to them
                        &amp; a kiss to you. </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
