<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0053"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="F0053">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Bob Taggart to his sister Mary,
                    January 5, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county bob taggart to his sister mary, january 5 1863</title>
        <author>Taggart, Bob </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Murrell </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0053</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501228</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Bob Taggart to his sister Mary, January 5, 1863</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county bob taggart to his sister mary, january 5 1863</title>
            <author>Bob Taggart</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Taggart Letters, Microfilm MG-132, Civil War
                            Material, Misc. Diaries and Letters, Pennsylvania Historical and Museum
                            Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-01-05">1863-01-05 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Desertion/Leave </term>
                    <term>Regiment: 9th Pa. Res. </term>
                    <term>Company: </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0053T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Taggart discusses camp life and evaluates the likelihood of receiving a leave of
                    absence.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Mary</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-01-05">January 5<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1863 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp near White Oak Church Va. </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>
                        <hi rend="underline">Dear</hi>
                        <hi rend="underline">Mary</hi>
                    </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Your letter of the 30<hi rend="super">th</hi>
                    <abbr expan="ultimate" cert="no">ult</abbr> came to hand yesterday, and one of
                    the 22<hi rend="super">d</hi>
                    <abbr expan="ultimate" cert="no">ult</abbr> came to hand today. The latter was a
                    little behind time but very welcome, nevertheless, on the principle of "better
                    late than never." I confess to forgetfulness in not mentioning Holland's safety
                    in my first letter after the late battle, but under such circumstances a person
                    has so many things to think about and generally so little time to do it all that
                    he cannot just bring to mind every thing he would wish. Now that there seems to
                    be a <hi rend="underline">sure</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">way</hi> of conveying information to Mrs. <abbr
                        expan="Holland" cert="no">H.</abbr> I will bear in mind in my letters to <hi
                        rend="underline">you</hi> here after to mention his name. However, he
                    generally stands a good chance of escaping the accidents of the field, as he is
                    a Regimental Post Master and is not required to go into battle.</p>

                <p>I have no doubt but there are a great many officers about Pittsburgh on leave
                    now. Some officers seem particularly fortunate or favored so far as getting home
                    to see their friends is concerned<pb n="2"/> but you don't see many from the
                        9<hi rend="super">th</hi> Regiment unless they are wounded or crippled in
                    some way. there is no use to apply through the <hi rend="underline">regular</hi>
                    channel here for leave of absence unless you can get a board of Surgeons to
                    certify that a change of climate is necessary to save life or prevent permanent
                    disability. Most "leave of absence" are obtained directly from Washington
                    through the influenceof Members of Congress and at the War Department.</p>

                <p>If you should happen to get acquainted with Mrs. Holland you will find her very
                    much of a lady, at least with the short acquaintance I had. I thought her such,
                    and know that she enjoys that reputation amongst her friends and acquaintances.
                    But then I have always thought the girls had a peculiar <orig reg="knack">
                        <hi rend="underline">nack</hi>
                    </orig> in finding out each others <hi rend="underline">faults</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">and</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">failings</hi> and after discovery, of mag<hi
                        rend="underline">nifyi</hi>ng and pu<hi rend="underline">blish</hi>ing
                    instead of exte<hi rend="underline">nuat</hi>ing and hi<hi rend="underline"
                    >din</hi>g them. Perhaps it is only a notion of mine.</p>

                <p>We are getting along about as well as could be expected in this out of the way
                    place, it seems to me we are about forty miles from no place. There are some
                    vague rumors about us going back to Washington within the fortifications, but as
                    every Division in the army has the same story <orig reg="afloat">aflout</orig>
                    in relation to themselves -- even the new Regiments, which have not been six
                    months in service -- I do not place much confidence in the reports.</p>
                <pb n="3"/>

                <p>Mr. Miller, husband of late Jennie A., called to see me the other day. I learned
                    from him that Sam was well. I also learned that they had, a day or two previous,
                    received something like fourteen dry good boxes filled with good things for
                    Christmas, and that they received marching orders the same day, and being afraid
                    that they would not have time to <hi rend="underline">leisurely</hi> enjoy their
                    presents, they <orig reg="ate">eat</orig> away, until nearly every man in the
                    regiment was sick.</p>

                <p>The weather here continues quite mild and pleasant, during the day time, but
                    rather cool and frosty at nights. Most of the men are very comfortably fixed in
                    their little log huts, in fact on an average much more comfortably than they
                    were at any time last winter. The idea that the men would willingly leave their
                    tents to <hi rend="underline">meet</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">the</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">enemy</hi> may exist in the minds of newspaper
                    correspondents, but does not pervade the camps in this section of the Country. </p>

                <p>Yesterday we got word of the late battle in the South west, and of the loss of
                    the Monitor. I received <orig reg="John's">Johns</orig> note containing some
                    post stamps for which I am much obliged. Give my love to John and family, and to
                    all the folks at home. Respects to <orig reg="inquiring">enquiring</orig>
                    friends. </p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your Affectionate Brother </salute>
                    <signed>Bob </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">P.S. <hi rend="underline">Holland</hi>
                        <hi rend="underline">is</hi>
                        <hi rend="underline">well</hi> and wishes to be remembered. </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
