<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0060"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="F0060">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Bob Taggart to Captain John Taggart, August 28, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">bob taggart to captain john taggart, august 28 1863</title>
        <author>Taggart, Bob </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Murrell </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0060</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501235</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Bob Taggart to Captain John Taggart, August 28, 1863</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county bob taggart to captain john taggart, august 28 1863</title>
            <author>Bob Taggart</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Taggart Letters, Microfilm MG-132, Civil War
                            Material, Misc. Diaries and Letters, Pennsylvania Historical and Museum
                            Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-08-28">1863-08-28 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Desertion/Leave, Military Authority, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 9th Pa. Res. </term>
                    <term>Company: </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0060T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Taggart discusses military business, including a sword presentation and an
                    execution of deserters. </p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Captain John Taggart, 9th Penn. Reserve Infantry</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-08-28">August 28<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1863 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp near Rappahannock </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>
                        <hi rend="underline">Dear</hi>
                        <hi rend="underline">John</hi>
                    </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I received yours of the 26<hi rend="super">th</hi>, Sam's of the 25<hi
                        rend="super">th</hi>, Tilly's of 26<hi rend="super">th</hi>, together with
                    one from Cunningham one from Waterman, and one from a member of the Company
                    (Agnew) who was wounded at Gettysburg, and is now at home in Allegheny, all by
                    to-days mail. I will consider yours and Will's to-night. </p>

                <p>The sword presentation to <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi rend="super">l</hi></abbr>
                    Meade came off at Division Head Quarters yesterday. The presentation speech was
                    made by <abbr expan="General">Gen<hi rend="super">l</hi></abbr> Crawford. <abbr
                        expan="General">Gen<hi rend="super">l</hi></abbr> Meade replied in a very
                    handome manner and was followed by <abbr expan="Governor">Gov</abbr>
                    <orig reg="Curtin">Curten</orig>, <abbr expan="Colonel">Col</abbr>
                    <unclear>
                        <orig reg="Ferney">Ferney</orig>
                    </unclear>, <abbr expan="Colonel">Col</abbr> Roberts and others -- After the
                    speeches came the feasting in which<pb n="2"/> about Three hundred officers
                    embracing all grades, from 2<hi rend="super">d</hi>
                    <abbr expan="Lieutenants">Lieuts</abbr> up to Major Generals, took an active
                    part. It looked quite gay to see such a congregation of officers all in sunday
                    clothes, and side arms. and it was truly astonishing the way Champagne and about
                    a dozen different <hi rend="underline">etcs</hi> were disposed of. I <orig
                        reg="ain't">a'nt</orig> going to "tell tales out of school" but I may be
                    allowed to say that I returned to Camp all right. </p>

                <p>To-day we had a performance of a different character. We were marched out along
                    with the rest of the Corps to witness the execution of five deserters from the
                        1<hi rend="super">st</hi> division notwithstanding I have a <hi
                        rend="underline">hearty</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">contempt</hi> for all Deserters. -- more especially for
                    such as follow up the practice time after time for pecuniary purposes, and
                    believe they ought to be shot, to<pb n="3"/> death as an example and terror to
                    such evil doers. I could not help indulging in feeling of commiseration for the
                    five poor wretches as the escort marched in front of the Corps to the "<hi
                        rend="underline">Dead</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">March</hi>" each criminal following his own Coffin, and
                    sitting down on it at the foot of his own grave, facing the soldiers who stood
                    ready to execute the sentence of the law. A few moments of preparation, the
                    Command ready -- aim -- fire -- a volley and the scene ends. You will read full
                    particulars in the papers, and it is unnecessary for me to say more</p>

                <p>Mr. Kelly was up at the <abbr expan="Regiment">Regt</abbr> today and stopped an
                    hour or so. He looks as well as I ever saw him. Burck Campbell called in as he
                    was passing this evening. He is well and wishes to be kindly remembered<pb n="4"
                    /> Now to business -- In relation to that money you deposited, -- if the <abbr
                        expan="Regiment">Regt</abbr> is mustered out in May as all think it will be,
                    or in April, as many think, I will have to square up. But then, I can manage to
                    save enough before that time to settle. I have about $100 belonging to the Fund
                    loaned in the Regiment. I will get it next pay day. The "fund" for which I am
                    responsible is about $260 or thereabouts which will leave me only $160 to deduct
                    from some pay day between this and settlement! You need have no hesitancy about
                    using the present deposit, and as I think we will be paid now in two or three
                    weeks. I can let you have more if you need it.</p>

                <p>Give my love to all the folks. Respects to <orig reg="inquiring">enquiring</orig>
                    friends </p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your <abbr expan="Affectionate">Affect</abbr> Brother </salute>
                    <signed>Bob </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
