<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0109"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="F0109">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Lucius P. Mox to Jennie, April 30, 1865</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county lucius p mox to jennie, april 30 1865</title>
        <author>Mox, Lucius P. </author>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Sarah Richardson </name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
        <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
        <idno type="VCDH">F0109 </idno>
        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The University of Virginia.
      All rights reserved. </p>
     <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2 </p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1998">1998 </date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501250</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note> </note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Lucius P. Mox to Jennie, April 30, 1865</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county lucius p mox to jennie, april 30 1865</title>
            <author>Lucius P. Mox</author>
            <respStmt>
              <resp> </resp>
              <name> </name>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher> </publisher>
            <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
            <date value=""> </date>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p>Source copy consulted: Lucius P. Mox Papers, Archives of the U.S. Army Military History
       Institute, Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania.</p>
          </seriesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from U. S. Army Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1865-04-30">1865-04-30 </date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Troop Movement, Patriotism, Camp Life </term>
          <term>Regiment: 17th Pa. Cav. </term>
          <term>Company: none </term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text id="F0109T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Mox has heard the news that the Confederates have surrendered and expresses his hope that he
     can return home soon.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>
  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Jennie</name>
    </head>


    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1865-04-30">Sunday April 30th 1865 </date>
      <name type="place">Chapel Point Md. </name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Jennie </salute>
    </opener>
    <p>Since I wrote to you last I have changed my place of residence I am now on the right bank of
     the Potomac about 60 miles below Washington it is one of the prettiest places that ever was
      <orig reg="occupied">ocupied</orig> by a Yankee camp - Pleasant Valley is entirely abandoned
     and all the volunteer cavalry in the U.S. Army is concentrating at this place and it is
     reported that we will all be discharged here soon - the whole Confederacy has withered before
     the Yankee arms and their last star of hope has disappeared behind the blue clouds of the North
     - Gen. Johnson has surrendered with ninety thousand men<pb n="2"/> this comprises the whole
     army of <orig reg="Dixie's">Dixies</orig> land - our old flag once more floats in triumph over
     every state in the Union - and since our work is done every soldier is impatiently waiting for
     his discharge for my part I was <orig reg="never">neve</orig> so homesick since I was in the
     army. I <orig reg="can't">cant</orig> keep still long enough to eat my dinner - indeed I am
     afraid some of us will get nearly crazy if our officers <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> sober up
     a little and send us home if they <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> be careful we will "<orig
      reg="rub">reub</orig> some of them out" it <orig reg="won't">wont</orig> do for them to be
      <orig reg="very">verry</orig> stubborn after teaching us how to fight.</p>

    <p>But I must quit talking about my superiors or I may get into trouble. Jennie I am afraid that
      <hi rend="underline">important</hi> letter will be lost that I asked you to direct in care of
     Capt. Littleboy without any company or Regiment on it - but you can tell me again a good
     sentiment will bare twice telling<pb n="3"/> - and more too for I can enjoy myself reading over
     your old letters better than any other amusement I can find although I have read them more than
     a dozen times already I only wish I had more of them to read - but I think we will not long be
     confined to this written communication and then with your <orig reg="consent">concent</orig> I
     will spend the rest of my life <hi rend="underline">where</hi>
     <hi rend="underline">we</hi>
     <hi rend="underline">will</hi>
     <hi rend="underline">not</hi>
     <hi rend="underline">have</hi>
     <hi rend="underline">to</hi>
     <hi rend="underline">write</hi>
     <hi rend="underline">to</hi>
     <hi rend="underline">each</hi>
     <hi rend="underline">other</hi>. I still have your picture in my portfolio it is the choicest
     treasure I posess except the love of its original -- I also have that "<hi rend="underline"
      >Nice thing</hi>" you sent me last winter and "I calculate to keep it till I come home."</p>

    <p>I have quit working in the Bakery and intend to stay with my Regiment till it is discharged
     there are four boat loads of soldiers<pb n="4"/> at the landing now who just came in from the
     front we expect some more before night.</p>

    <p>Now Dear Jennie I must confess I am getting <orig reg="very">verry</orig> lazy for the
     weather is <orig reg="very">verry</orig> warm and my little tent stands out in an open field in
     the hot sun shine.</p>

    <p>I think I must quit and take a sleep and perhaps a dream of you for that would be nothing
     uncommon - you would not believe how the Yankee ladies haunt the soldiers pillows.</p>

    <p>I shall hope to hear that you have entirely recovered your health by the time you answer this
     - please write soon again to</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Yours affectionately </salute>
     <signed>Lucius<lb/>Co I, 17<hi rend="super">th</hi> Pa. Cav.<lb/>Washington<lb/>D.C.<lb/>
     </signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
