<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0124"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F0124">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Peter Boyer to Cyrus Boyer, [date unknown]</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county peter boyer to cyrus boyer, date unknown</title>
        <author>Peter boyer</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">6</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">F0124</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501264</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>
          <p>Transcription from photocopy.</p>
        </note>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Peter Boyer to Cyrus Boyer, [date unknown]</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county peter boyer to cyrus boyer, date unknown</title>
            <author>Peter boyer</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>2 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: USMHI, Carlisle, PA</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from U. S. Army Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1863">1863?-XX-16</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Home Front, Women, Camp Life</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""> </date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="F0124T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Peter Boyer writes to his brother Cyrus at home about letters he has and has not received,
     and asks Cyrus to save some girls for him until he gets home.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Cyrus Boyer</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1863">Mon 16th</date>
      <name type="place">Camp near Falmouth</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Brother Cyrus</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I take the present opportunity to let you know that I have received your most welcome letter
     dated March 8th on the 14th but had no opportunity to write until at present - when I will let
     you know that I am still enjoying the same state of good health which I am proud of and I am in
     hopes these few lines may find you and all the rest of our family and friends and acquaintances
     enjoying similar blessings</p>

    <p>Further I let you know that you mentioned in your letter about Brother John I sent him a
     letter already I sent one a few days after the time I sent one to you I <orig reg="can't"
     >cant</orig> see the reason <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> Engle got a letter 2 days before I got mine and
     they were dated and mailed the same day. Cyrus you said this Sunday morning you would write to
     me Sunday I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know what that is we <orig reg="don't">dont</orig>
     have any such a day or at least there is no difference in the days You also said that you and
     John <unclear>Gossie</unclear> were at <unclear>Lehafferstown</unclear> and got on a spree. <pb
      n="2"/> I wish I could have enjoyed that time not for the sake of the spree but the fun and
     then the girls I would like to <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> one once Cyrus Engle and myself request you to
     have a few girls engaged for us until we get home so that we have no trouble to hunt some only
     to jump right in up to the knees. Brother Daniel was on a visit to me once to and I am very
     sorry for Jonathan that he is unwell I am going to write to him today I think you felt like a
      (<del rend="none" hand="h1"/>) the time you fell in the creek. I think you made tracks for home then news
     is very <orig reg="scarce">scarse</orig> we have good times and nothing to do we only work
     about three days in a week that is doing orderly duty the rest of the time lay in camp and
     sometimes go on <orig reg="patrol">Patrole</orig> and take prisoners from one place to the
     other. they are again working at the pay rolls and we expect to be paid soon which is the
     report - but these reports come so often and the pay day never makes its appearance. I am out
     of postage stamps and can not get any here you will please and send me some by your next letter
     and you will oblige me very much give my best respects to Father Mother and Brother</p>



    <closer>
     <salute>so much of your Brother</salute>
     <signed>Peter Boyer</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
