<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0381"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="F0381">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Christian Geisel to Louisa Geisel,
                    February 12, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county christian geisel to louisa geisel, february 12 1862</title>
        <author>Geisel, Christian</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Justin Hill </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">6</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0381</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/personal.html </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501280</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow Project </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Christian Geisel to Louisa Geisel, February 12, 1862</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county christian geisel to louisa geisel, february 12 1862</title>
            <author>Christian Geisel</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Collection, Division of Archives and
                            Manuscripts, Christian Geisel Collection, Microfilm, MG226</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p> </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-02-12">1862-02-12 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 6th Pa. Cav. </term>
                    <term>Company: H </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""> </date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name> </name>
                </respStmt>
                <item> </item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0381T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Geisel thanks his sister for the food and letters that the family has sent.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Louisa Geisel </name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-02-12"><abbr expan="February">Feb.</abbr> 12<hi
                                rend="super">th</hi> 1862 </date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Sister! </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I write to you these few lines, hoping that they may find you in as good health
                    as they leave me in at present. I received the letter which Father <unclear>
                        <orig reg="sent">send</orig>
                    </unclear> to me, and the box arrived here a few days afterwards. your <orig
                        reg="Spongecakes">Spunchcakes</orig>, which you <unclear>
                        <orig reg="sent">send</orig>
                    </unclear> were excellent, and the sausage were something new to us. they <pb
                        n="1"/>tasted first rate; and i am very much obliged to you for your trouble
                    and kindness. I suppose you were looking for a letter from me for some time, but
                    i hope you will excuse me for not writing sooner for i did not discover the
                    letter which you <unclear>
                        <orig reg="sent">send</orig>
                    </unclear> to me in the box until last sunday; i had several letters and some
                    papers in the box, and by looking over them last sunday i found, to my
                    astonishment, a letter sealed up with my name on it, which i had not seen
                    before, and after opening it i found it was from you. i would have <orig
                        reg="written">wrote</orig> to you right away, but as you said you would like
                    to see my likeness, i thought i would get it first, which i did today. i wrote a
                    letter to Polly Furhman last week. when you write to me again tell me <sic
                        corr="whether">wether</sic> she said anything about it, <pb n="2"/>and how
                    they are getting along in your neighbourhood. i think you had better put Polly
                    on the old maids list if she <orig reg="doesn't">dondt</orig> get married before
                    long. We are in our old camp yet near Washington. Levi Markley and, some
                    relations of Markley's, whose name i do not know, were here to see me yesterday.
                    Levi is well and all the rest from our neighbourhood, except Haberstroh, he was
                    taken sick some time ago, and they think he <unclear>
                        <orig reg="will not">wont</orig>
                    </unclear> get over it. We have had fine weather for a few days and the ground
                    is drying of mud and if it keeps on this way a few weekks, i think we will make
                    a move further south, but we do not know yet how soon we are going to move. I
                    heard today that they had a battle in North Carolina and <pb n="3"/>our men
                    gained the victory. in our neighbourhood everything is quiet. this is all i can
                    write at present. i am well and hope that this letter may find you all the same.
                    give my best respects to all who may inquire after me. remember me to all the
                    young folks in the neighbourhood and write to me soon. </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>your affectionate brother </salute>
                    <signed>Christian Geisel </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">the directions: Christian Geisel, <abbr expan="Company"
                            >Co.</abbr> H, 6th regiment, <abbr expan="Pennsylvania">Pa.</abbr>
                        Cavalry, <abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> R. Rush D.C. </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
