<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0392"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="F0392">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Christian Geisel to Louisa Geisel,
                    May 20, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county christian geisel to louisa geisel, may 20 1863</title>
        <author>Geisel, Christian </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Justin Hill </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0392</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/personal.html </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501291</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow Project </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Christian Geisel to Louisa Geisel, May 20, 1863</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county christian geisel to louisa geisel, may 20 1863</title>
            <author>Christian Geisel</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/> 
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: </idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Collection, Division of Archives and
                            Manuscripts, Christian Geisel Collection, Microfilm, MG226 </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-05-20">1863-05-20 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Battle Description, Camp Life, Prisons/Prisoners, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 6th Pa. Cav. </term>
                    <term>Company: H </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""> </date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp> </resp>
                    <name> </name>
                </respStmt>
                <item> </item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0392T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Geisel writes his sister about a dramatic cavalry raid by his unit into the area
                    around Richmond.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Louisa Geisel </name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-05-20">May 20<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1863 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp near Brooks Station </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Sister </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Being now settled in campaign for a few days I embrace the present opportunity to
                    write you a few lines hoping that they may find all in as good health as I enjoy
                    at present. I received your welcome letter of the 3<hi rend="super">rd</hi>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> on the 13<hi rend="super">th</hi> while on picket near Hartwood
                    Church and I was very happy to hear from you. We had a short but successful
                    campaign as far as cavalry is concerned from April 29<hi rend="super">th</hi> to
                    the 9<hi rend="super">th</hi> of May; it lasted but a short time, much shorter
                        <orig reg="than">then</orig> I expected when we started, but long enough for
                    us to be going night and day getting but little rest or sleep and to do a good
                    deal of destruction in rebeldom. I had some idea of where we were going when we
                    started but I would not have believed that we could have gone as near to
                        Richmond<pb n="2"/>as we did without encountering and being opposed by some
                    portion of the rebel army. We captured a number of prisoners on our march but
                    they were all in small parties and could make no resistance; we crossed and
                    recrossed the Rappahannock, Rapidan; North Anna + South Anna, the three former
                    we had to ford and in our return the Rappahannock was so swelled from the rain
                    that our horses had to swim; all of our Regt. got across safe, I only heard of
                    one man being drowned, the South Anna R. had a bridge across. The people in the
                    vicinity of Richmond did not know what to make of it that we were down there and
                    the rebel army up at the Rappahannock, with all their communication and supplies
                    cut off and i have no doubt Jeff Davis himself was alarmed about his his safety
                    in Richmond. It is any belief that we could have made a dash into Richmond and
                    destroyed it and by what I can learn Gen. Sherman would have done it if he would
                    have been <pb n="3"/> supported by Gen. Averell, who was to go to Gordansville,
                    and failed to do so. We destroyed all the railroad and telegraph running North
                    from Richmond, captured several trains of cars, and wagon trains, which were all
                    burned up, and a large quantity of army stores. A squadron of the 5<hi
                        rend="super">th</hi> U. S. belonging to our Brigade had a scrimmish near
                    Thompsons crossroads in which they lost a few men but the rebels soon took to
                    their heels. We stopped at Thompsons crossroads on the 4<hi rend="super">th</hi>
                    of May, I got some writing there over a hundred years old, I will enclose a page
                    for curiosity. We lost two men of our Co. one was our <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>Workman,
                    his horse gave out near Louisa Courthouse and our Capt. Cook fell out of the
                    ranks near the same place, they both got in the rear and did not join us again,
                    and I expect were taken prisoner. we have not heard from them since. I got
                    through safe myself, lost my old horse and two caps going through the woods at
                    night but I had the good luck to get both another horse and cap again without
                    expense. <pb n="4"/> My horse gave and the second day after we crossed the
                    Rappahannock, near the Rapidan with the sore back, the first time I ever had
                    that misfortune, but I managed to get a young secesh in place of him who
                    answered the purpose very well. From the 29<hi rend="super">th</hi> of April to
                    the 9<hi rend="super">th</hi> of may we only had our horses<del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    three hours, after the provisions had run out we carried along we lived on ham
                    and corncakes of which we found a large quantity stored away in some places, we
                    found at one house over 2,000 Hamas stored away; there is no able bodied man to
                    be seen <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> through Va. they have all been drafted in the army, and
                    the people down there are getting tired of the war. </p>
                <p>I expect we will stay at this camp, <orig reg="until">till</orig> we get filled
                    out again with things that got lost and broke on the raid and many of our horses
                    are worn down so that they are unserviceable for which we will have to get other
                    ones. No other movement has as yet commenced in this part of the army that I
                    know of, everything is quiet. The weather is beautiful. I must now come to a
                    close with only my best respects to all our family and all inquiring friends,
                    hoping soon to hear from you again. </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I remain your affectionate Brother </salute>
                    <signed>Sergt. Christian Geisel <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">Co.H 6<hi rend="super">th</hi> Penn. Cavalry Army of the
                        Potomac. Va. </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
