<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0397"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="F0397">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Christian Geisel to Louisa Geisel,
                    October 30, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county christian geisel to louisa geisel, october 30 1863</title>
        <author>Geisel, Christian </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Justin Hill </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0397</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/personal.html </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501296</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow Project </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Christian Geisel to Louisa Geisel, October 30, 1863</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county christian geisel to louisa geisel, october 30 1863</title>
            <author>Christian Geisel</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: </idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Division of Archives and
                            Manuscripts, Christian Geisel Collection, Microfilm, MG226 </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-10-31">1863-10-31 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Church/Religious Activity, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 6th Pa. Cav. </term>
                    <term>Company: H </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""> </date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp> </resp>
                    <name> </name>
                </respStmt>
                <item> </item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0397T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p> Christian Geisel writes home to his sister Louisa about camp life and potential
                    movements of his unit in Northern Virginia. He makes special note of visiting
                    the camp of a Pennsylvania unit that contains many people from his native area.
                    He also describes a prayer meeting that took place while he visited the camp. He
                    makes several inquiries into how certain relatives and friends back home are
                    doing. </p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Louisa Geisel </name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-10-30">October 30<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1863 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp near Germantown, Va. </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Sister Louisa </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I received your welcome and interesting letter of the 17<hi rend="super">th</hi>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> and I was happy to hear that you were all in good health. </p>
                <p>I will now try to write you a few lines to inform you of our whereabouts and to
                    let you know that I am among the living yet and in good health. We left
                    Washington again on the 11<hi rend="super">th</hi>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> and were with the army while they fell back from the
                    Rappahannock, but we were only engaged once in a scrimmish at Bristol Station.
                    Since then we have been on duty along the Railroad from Bull Run down to
                    Warrenton Junction. Our monday night last we marched from Manassas Junction to
                    about two miles below Warrenton<pb n="2"/> Junction and expected to have a fight
                    near the Rappahannock on tuesday but for some reason it did not come <orig
                        reg="off">of</orig>, and we have been encamped here since. On <orig
                        reg="Wedsday">wensday</orig> one division of the third corps came up and
                    encamped near us and next morning we found that the 139<hi rend="super">th</hi>
                    Pa. was among them. John Markley was over in our camp yesterday afternoon; he
                    looks as fat and hardy as ever; <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> seen Henry's step brother who
                    is in the same Camp. he is in good health. I was ever in their camp last night.
                    they had a prayer meeting while I was there, and they had quite a large
                    attendence. I was delighted to see so many of my old aquantences, I believe
                    there is more of them in that Regt. than in any other I know of, a good many
                    from Montgomery County and some that were out with me in the three month. John
                    Markley seemed to be very much pleased to see me he said<pb n="3"/>I was the
                    only aquatence he <orig reg="has seen">seen</orig> from our neighbourhood since
                    he has been out. We have not orders to move from here yet, but <orig
                        reg="do not">dondt</orig> expect we will lay here long. The rebels destroyed
                    the railroad from Bristol Station to the Rappahannock, and our men are at work
                    repairing it as speedily as possible, and as soon as supplies can be transported
                    on it again I think our army will advance again. </p>
                <p>We have had nice, clear weather for the last week, but it is cold at night, today
                    it looks as if we might get rain soon. Give my kindest regards to Lydia Brand. I
                    am glad that she thinks of me yet, but sorry to disappoint her in her request as
                    it would be impossible to get a photograph taken here, but tell her I would be
                    pleased to see hers, I have no doubt you young folks have changed a good deal
                    since I saw you last, and also give my best repsects to all the rest <pb n="4"/>
                    of Brands family, and all inquiring friends. I must now close with my love to
                    all at home, hoping that this may find you all in as good health as I enjoy at
                    present, and write soon again to your affectionate Brother. </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute> </salute>
                    <signed>Christian Geisel </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">Co. H 6<hi rend="super">th</hi> Pa. Cavalry Washington DC
                            <name type="recipient">Mrs Annie Geisel Montgomery Ville Montgomery Co.
                                <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> Montgomery Ville Montgomery Co. Pa. in care of Mr.
                                <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> Mrs. Annie Geisel Montgomery Ville Road Mongomery
                            Co. Reedes Pa. in care of </name>
                    </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
