<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0653"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="F0653">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Henry C. Metzger to His Father,
                    January 12, 1865</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county henry c metzger to his father, january 12 1865</title>
        <author>Metzger, Henry C. </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Sally Henninger </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0653</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/ </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501317</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note>
                    <p>The initial page of the letter is printed with "CITY OF CINCINNATI." and
                        "City Clerk's Office." and includes an engraving of that building.</p>
                </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Henry C. Metzger to His Father, January 12, 1865</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county henry c metzger to his father, january 12 1865</title>
            <author>Henry C. Metzger</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Henry C. Metzger Records, 16th and 184th
                            Pennsylvania Infantry, Harrisburg Civil War Round Table Collection,
                            Archives of the U.S. Army Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks,
                            Pennsylvania. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from U. S. Army Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1865-01-12">1865-01-12 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Desertion/Leave</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 16th Pa.; 184th Pa. </term>
                    <term>Company: none </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0653T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Metzger writes to his father about the execution of a deserter, recent
                    thunderstorms, and a humorous mistake in the playing of "Reveille."</p>
            </div1>



        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head> Letterhead: CITY OF CINNCINATI.<lb/>City Clerk's Office. <name
                        type="recipient">Father</name>
                </head>
                <opener>


                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1865-01-12">January 12th <unclear>
                                <orig reg="1865">1865</orig>
                            </unclear>
                        </date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Father, </salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Last Friday at 12 O'Clock, Michael Wert was shot for trying to desert to the
                    enemy. eleven balls went through his body, killing him instantly. he <orig
                        reg="leaves">lieves</orig> a wife and five children behind. On Tuesday we
                    had a very heavy Thunder Gust here, it was Lightning and Thundering all day.</p>

                <p><orig reg="Today">To day</orig> our Division <orig reg="is">are</orig> out on
                    review. You would be surprised to see the number of deserters that come in our
                    lines every night. they say that they <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> like the
                        <orig reg="President's">Presidents</orig> call for 300,000 more men. They
                    are on short rations.</p>
                <pb n="2"/>

                <p>Night before last I made a big mistake. about one O'Clock in the morning I got up
                    and looked at my watch to see what time it was. I <orig reg="saw">seene</orig>
                    it was 6 O'Clock, not knowing that the watch had stopped. I picked up the bugle
                    and played with the Reveille. In five <orig reg="minutes">minuits</orig> the
                    drummers and buglers in our whole Brigade were out playing the Reveille. In a
                    short time an <orig reg="orderly">ordely</orig> from Div. Head Quarters arrived
                    at our Regimental <abbr expan="Head  
 Quarters">H.Qrs.</abbr> with a note to
                    our Colonel <orig reg="inquiring">enquiring</orig> the cause of all this fuss so
                    early in the morning. by this time the whole Division <orig reg="was"
                    >were</orig> up, our Col. sent for me and wanted to know what in the Devil I was
                    about in blowing the bugle so early, I <orig reg="saw">seene</orig> that it was
                    all he could do to keep from laughing while the orderly was present. I told him
                    that I thought it was the right time. He says look at your watch once. when I
                    looked I saw that it was still 6 O'Clock. I knew then that the watch had
                        stopped.<pb n="3"/> He drew out his watch and says here I will show you what
                    time it is, fifteen minutes past one. As <orig reg="soon">soone</orig> as the
                        <orig reg="orderly">ordely</orig> had left the Col. rolled and laughed.</p>

                <p>The irons that you sent for my boots I never received. <orig reg="Don't"
                    >Dont</orig> forget to send the Hanover Spectator, and tell Mother or Kate to
                    send me <orig reg="those">them</orig> two books that they will find among my
                    music. one is called the Comet Instructor and the other has 6 or 7 hundred <abbr
                        expan="pieces" cert="no">pcs</abbr> of music in it, with drum and fife calls
                    for the army. it is about 12 <abbr expan="inches">in.</abbr> long and 10 <abbr
                        expan="inches">in.</abbr> wide. both have paper covers. I have not <abbr
                        expan="Received">Recd</abbr> a Spectator since I left home.</p>

                <p>Next year by this time, all that do not enlist in the regular Army, will be at
                    Home. If mother sends a box tell her to put some old dollar Magazines in. we
                    have nothing to read. I am well.</p>

                <p>Give my love to all.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your Son </salute>
                    <signed>Henry C. Metzger </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
