<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0661"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="F0661">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Samuel W. North to his brother,
                    November 20, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county samuel w north to his brother, november 20 1862</title>
        <author>North, Samuel W. </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Sally Henninger </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0661</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/ </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501323</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note>
                    <p>Letterhead: The first page of this letter is printed with an engraving of a
                        bust of <abbr expan="Major   General">Maj. Gen.</abbr> M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Clellan. The writer, North, has crossed out M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Clellan's name and has written above it "Burnside," and North also
                        drew heavy sideburns onto the engraving of M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Clellan.
                    </p>
                </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Samuel W. North to his brother, November 20, 1862</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county samuel w north to his brother, november 20 1862</title>
            <author> </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Samuel W. North Letters, Company C, 126th
                            Pennsylvania Infantry, Civil War Miscellaneous Collection, Archives of
                            the U.S. Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania.
                        </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from U. S. Army Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-11-20">1862-11-20 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>African Americans, Camp Life, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 126th Pa. </term>
                    <term>Company: C </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0661T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>North describes General M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Clellan's and General Porter's
                    farewells to the troops. He also talks about marching on muddy roads and about a
                    disease afflicting horses and mules.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Brother</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-11-20"><abbr expan="November">Novem</abbr> 20<hi
                                rend="super">th</hi>
                            <hi rend="underline">1862</hi>
                        </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp of the 126<hi rend="super">th</hi>
                        </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Brother - </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I received yours of the <unclear>6<hi rend="super">th</hi></unclear> but have not
                    had time to write since as we have been marching for the last week or so. on the
                        10<hi rend="super">th</hi> we were drawn up in line to <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del hand="h1">take</del> hear <abbr expan="General">gen</abbr>
                    <sic corr="McClellan's">Mclellans</sic> farewell it was short and he rode along
                    the lines with his hat off we saluted him at a present arms then gave him three
                    cheers. on the 12<hi rend="super">th</hi> we had <abbr expan="General">Gen</abbr>
                    <orig reg="Porter's">Porters</orig> farewell he too rode past with his hat off
                    and as he shook hands with <abbr expan="General">Gen</abbr> Tyler the tears came
                    into his eyes we marched through Warrenton on the 17<hi rend="super">th</hi>
                    there are some very fine buildings there passed through Warrenton Junction we
                    have been marching pretty hard for the last few days it has been sunny for the
                    last two days and it is raining now the roads are miserable <orig reg="some"
                    >som</orig> places the wheels sink into the hubs <orig reg="some places"
                        >someplaces</orig> the axels scrape the mud<pb n="2"/>the teams often <orig
                        reg="stall">staul</orig> and have to double team it. it is a miserable place
                    on horses and mules there is some kind of a disease got amongst them it is from
                    the shelled corn they get too much of that kind of strong feed and not enough of
                    hay some say it is a contagious disease their feet and mouths get sore some of
                    their feet get fairly rotten and some of them come off so I hear I saw a great
                    many with sore feet and saw a great many condemned ones <orig reg="driven"
                    >drove</orig> back it is supposed they will be taken to washington and sold.
                    tell mother I drew two pairs of government stockings and a pair of new shoes
                    which I will carry with me till my boots <del hand="h1">are given</del> give out
                    that <orig reg="won't">wont</orig> be long. We are <add hand="h1" place="inline"
                        >camped</add> within six miles of <orig reg="Fredericksburg"
                    >Fredricksburg</orig> Va this is a poor country that is, the land is poor but it
                    is level around most of the houses there are lots of<pb n="3"/> shanties for
                    their darkies. the farms and fields are very large. the winter is very bad. I
                    wrote two letters to Mother one at Snickers Gap &amp; the other at White
                    Plains did she get them. we have no regular mails but just get our letters once
                    in a few days. Direct your letters to Washington. it would be useless to write
                    any general news as you have a better chance to get them than I have. if you
                    have a chance to send with anyone coming here you may send my boots but if not
                    do not send them there will be very little chance of my getting them I drew
                    shoes and leggings which will keep my feet comfortable. When you write tell me
                    all the news from home and town tell me <orig reg="everything">every
                    thing</orig> that happens as <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig> from home
                    will interest me. We are in the first Brigade of the third <orig reg="Division"
                        >Divission</orig> of the fifth Army Corps under the command of <abbr
                        expan="General">Gen</abbr> Hooker<pb n="4"/> so you can tell by the papers
                    where we are Hooker has command of two corps, the Second and fifth. write soon
                    &amp; direct to Washington.</p>
                <p>from you Bro</p>
                <p>S.W. North </p>

                <p>#3 21<hi rend="super">st</hi> On half rations <orig reg="today">to day</orig>
                    teams are gone for rations but the roads are bad &amp; the teams are poor.
                    We hope they will be here <orig reg="tonight">to night</orig> the boys some of
                    them traded coffee for flour it is worth $25.00 for <abbr expan="bushel"
                        cert="no">Bbl.</abbr> the same in <orig reg="Richmond">Ritchmond</orig>. Sam
                    Alaman got <del hand="h1">an o</del>
                    <abbr expan="Richmond">Ritch</abbr>-Examiner it quotes flour at $25 to $27
                    &amp; other things in proportion it is Jubilant over the elections in the
                    north. If you have any confederate money you may send it to me as it will pass
                    here for <orig reg="provisions">provissions</orig> among the farmers.</p>

                <p>I thing Charly had a pocket map of the U.S. or of Virginia if you have a chance
                    send me it if it is not about <orig reg="maybe">may be</orig> you can find part
                    of an old atlas I want Virginia or a map of the South. Direct to Washington. S.
                    W. N.</p>

                <p> </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute> </salute>
                    <signed>S.W.N. </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
