<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0667"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="F0667">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Samuel W. North to His Father,
                    [date unknown]</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county samuel w north to his father, date unknown</title>
        <author>North, Samuel W. </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Sally Henninger </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">6</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0667</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501329</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note>
                    <p>A page or more may be missing from the original, starting with the second
                        page.</p>
                </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Samuel W. North to His Father, [date unknown]</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county samuel w north to his father, date unknown</title>
            <author> </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Samuel W. North Letters, Company C, 126th
                            Pennsylvania Infantry, Civil War Miscellaneous Collection, Archives of
                            the U.S. Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania.
                        </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from U. S. Army Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
               
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life </term>
                    <term>Regiment: 126th Pa. </term>
                    <term>Company: C </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0667T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In a discussion of camp life, North talks about the surplus of coffee and the
                    mistreatment of horses.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Father</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                 
                    <salute>Dear Father </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I received your letter of the 4<hi rend="super">th</hi> inst on yesterday morning
                    and one from John dated the 7<hi rend="super">th</hi> which I received yesterday
                    evening and was glad to hear that you are all well. We are still in our old camp
                    although we <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know how soon we may leave it. The
                    weather is unusually fine for the time of the year. it rained some, day before
                    yesterday, <orig reg="and">an</orig> the roads and walks are very muddy. Still
                    it has been an unusually fine winter for camping out. Jacob and I are in our
                    usual good health. the company generally are in good health. We have been living
                    on the best the government has we have been drawing plenty of our regular pork
                    beans crackers coffee &amp; sugar with occasionally extras of potatoes or
                    rice onions or dry Apples and vinegar. We get more coffee than we can make use
                    of we have at least five pounds of it ahead in our mess. it is not exactly pure
                    but still it makes excellent coffee. I wish I had some way of getting some of it
                    home. I hate to see it wasted as it is very dear now at home. but uncle sam pays
                    for it. and his property is destroyed on all occasions. I often see horses which
                    have been condemned and driven off to die hanging round <orig reg="trying"
                    >tryin</orig> to get a <orig reg="mouthful">mouthfull</orig> of hay some of them
                    are <orig reg="really">realy</orig> sound young horses with nothing wrong with
                    them <del hand="h1">but</del> but bad usage and want of feed. they founder a
                    good many of their horses by feeding too much corn. most of the drivers have not
                    as much humanity about them as their horses they drive at a fast trot and I have
                    seen whole trains going at a full run. so you can have some Idea of the wear and
                    tear in that line. We had quite an explosion in front of our camp a few days
                    ago. our <orig reg="division">divission</orig><pb n="2"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <pb n="3"/> affair. I wish I could stop thinking of it but I saw things there
                    which seem to be stamped on my brain. tell John I will answer his letter in a
                    few days tell mother and the girls to write often and if you have the time to
                    spare I would like to hear from you too.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours Affectionately</salute>
                    <signed>
                        <hi rend="underline">S.W. North</hi>
                    </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
