<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0662"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="F0662">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Samuel W. North to His Father,
                    December 1, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county samuel w north to his father, december 1 1862</title>
        <author>North, Samuel W. </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Sally Henninger </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0662</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/ </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501324</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Samuel W. North to His Father, December 1, 1862</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county samuel w north to his father, december 1 1862</title>
            <author> </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Samuel W. North Letters, Company C, 126th
                            Pennsylvania Infantry, Civil War Miscellaneous Collection, Archives of
                            the U.S. Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania.
                        </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from U. S. Army Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="-12-01">xxxx-12-01 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Family, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 126th Pa. </term>
                    <term>Company: C </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0662T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>North predicts an upcoming battle with the rebels across the Rappahannock and
                    observes the poverty of the local Virginia countryside.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Father</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-12-01">Dec <unclear>
                                <orig reg="1st">1<hi rend="super">st</hi></orig>
                            </unclear>
                        </date>
                        <name type="place">Near Falmouth </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Father </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>as it has been some time since I wrote home I take this time to write I suppose
                    there was a letter for me in that <del hand="h1">box</del> package you sent me
                    but through <orig reg="somebody's">some bodies</orig> carelessness it was left
                    behind when Cook &amp; the others came back Peter Cook says he put my boots
                    and all the other things given into his care into a box and had it directed <del
                        hand="h1"/> the same as <abbr expan="Lieutenant">Lieut</abbr>
                    <unclear>Hornbakers</unclear> box which came along safely when they got to
                    Washington it was not along he says &amp; Hornbaker too that the conductor
                    promised to hunt it up and send it on by express. I have been expecting it for
                    the last week but it has not come yet I hope it will still come as it was
                    directed to Capt <unclear>Brownreals</unclear> care. I was waiting until I would
                    get it to write. We are camped within two or three miles of the Rappahannock
                    have been waiting hourly for the report of the first gun to commence the great
                    struggle wich will probably come off here our <orig reg="provisions"
                    >provissions</orig> have been delayed so that they can get but one <orig
                        reg="day's">days</orig> rations at a time. Some think the delay is on that
                    account the rebels from all accounts are <unclear>making</unclear> good use of
                    the delay in fortifying. there is no picket firing I hear that they talk across
                    the river very composedly every <orig reg="day's">days</orig> delay is a great
                    loss to us if we are to cross near <sic corr="Fredericksburg"
                    >Fredricksburg</sic> - which I am beginning to think is not the case - as the
                    enemy are getting their Batteries protected by breast works. I think It will be
                    an artillery fight at first. I have heard that you had an
                    <unclear>accident</unclear> with the team the old mare was killed was
                        <unclear>fan</unclear> hurt or the wagon<pb n="2"/> much broken. write the
                    particulars and whether you supplied <unclear>Dolls</unclear> place. we saw
                    great numbers of condemned mules and horses going back while we were advancing
                    into Virginia I suppose there will be bargains in them although they were very
                    hard stock our regimental teams are pretty hard too but it is not much wonder as
                    the roads are barely passable one of them stalled with two 2 <abbr
                        expan="Bushels">BBS</abbr>
                    <orig reg="mess">mes</orig> pork or not more than six hundred pounds for four
                    mules the artillery goes in the mud until the axles touch it so you may have
                    some idea of the difficulties in the way of moving an army it is not such bad
                    walking but the soil is soft and sandy we can run a bayonet down <orig
                        reg="without">with</orig> touching anything but sand it is the poorest part
                    of the old dominion I have seen the houses are generally old tumble down log
                    concerns with sticks built up for chimneys and plastered with mud some of the
                    worst have no windows they pull up their corn by the roots and hang it across
                    poles to keep for winter some chance places you <orig reg="See">Se</orig> one of
                    the old Southern residences of the <abbr expan="?">F.F.V.</abbr> surrounded by
                    about a dozen negro huts. we saw a good many mares with mule colts there <orig
                        reg="were">was</orig> lots of persimmons when we came but they are all
                    played out now we are very comfortable as regards sleeping and clothing we cut
                    pine bushes for the bottom of our tents at night spread down our overcoats and
                    two sleep together and cover with both blankets. I drew a new pair of
                        <unclear>good</unclear> shoes and a pair of leggings. Mother wants to know
                    where I think we will winter. I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know probably in
                    Richmond I will answer soon</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute> </salute>
                    <signed> </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
