<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0705"?>
<?dlps page-images="color" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;

 <!NOTATION jpg SYSTEM "JPEG">  
 <!ENTITY filename SYSTEM "uva-lib:502950" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 <!ENTITY BitCre6a SYSTEM "uva-lib:502951" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 <!ENTITY BitCre6b SYSTEM "uva-lib:502952" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 <!ENTITY BitCre6c SYSTEM "uva-lib:502953" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 <!ENTITY BitCre6d SYSTEM "uva-lib:502954" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 <!ENTITY BitCre6z SYSTEM "uva-lib:502955" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
   
   
   
 ]>  
<TEI.2 id="F0705">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Alex Cressler to Henry A. Bitner, July 30, 1861</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county alex cressler to henry a bitner, july 30 1861</title>
        <author>Cressler, Alex</author>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Anne Rubin, Valley of the Shadow project, Institute for Advanced Technology in the
      Humanities, University of Virginia </name>
          <resp>Creation of digital images: </resp>
          <name>Anne Rubin, Valley of the Shadow project, Institute for Advanced Technology in the
      Humanities, University of Virginia </name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup: </resp>
          <name>University of Virginia Library Electronic Text Center. </name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">13</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>University of Virginia Library </publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>
        <idno type="VCDH">F0705</idno>
        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly-accessible </p>
     <p>URL: http://etext.lib.virginia.edu/modeng/modengB.browse.html </p>
     <p>Publicly-accessible </p>
     <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.Virginia.EDU/vshadow2/ </p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1998 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1998">1998 </date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501349</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p> </p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>
          <p>Images of the manuscript have been included. This electronic text is a faithful
      transcription of the original manuscript. We have included SGML tags which allow the reader to
      view a modernized version of the text in which the punctuation and the spelling have been
      regularized.</p>
        </note>
        <note> </note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Alex Cressler to Henry A. Bitner, July 30, 1861</title>
            <title level="u"> </title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county alex cressler to henry a bitner, july 30 1861</title>
            <author>Alex Cressler</author>
            <respStmt>
              <resp> </resp>
              <name> </name>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p> </p>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent> </extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher> </publisher>
            <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
            <date value=""> </date>
            <idno type="callno">Manuscript copy consulted: University of Virginia, Alderman Library,
       Special Collections MSS 11395 </idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p> </p>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note> </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Prepared for the University of Virginia Library Electronic Text Center. </p>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Original lineation has been maintained. </p>
        <p>The images exist as archived TIFF images, one or more JPEG versions for general use, and
     thumbnail GIFs. </p>
        <p>Some keywords in the header are a local Electronic Text Center scheme to aid in establishing
     analytical groupings. </p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <refsDecl>
        <p> </p>
      </refsDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy>
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings </title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1861-07-30">1861-07-30 </date>
      </creation>

      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng">English </language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>nonfiction </term>
          <term>prose </term>
          <term>masculine </term>
          <term>American Civil War; Special Collections </term>
          <term>Franklin County </term>
          <term>Chambersburg </term>
          <term>Home Front </term>
          <term>Jefferson Davis </term>
          <term>Slavery </term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
        <keywords>
          <term>LCSH </term>
        </keywords>
        <keywords>
          <term> </term>
          <term> </term>
          <term type="format">72 dpi; 24-bit color </term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="1998-05">May 1998 </date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>corrector </resp>
          <name>Carolyn Fay and Lisa Spiro </name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Added TEI header and tags, corrected transcription errors, and standardized punctuation
     and spelling for the modernized version. </item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text id="F0705T">
  <body id="d2">
   <!-- <page n=1><ID>BitCre61</ID> -->
   <div1 type="envelope" id="d3">
    <figure rend="block" entity="BitCre6z" pid="uva-lib:502955"/>


   </div1>
   <div1 type="letter" n="1861-07-30" id="d4">
    <opener>
     <pb n="1" entity="BitCre6a" pid="uva-lib:502951"/>


     <dateline> Chambersburg, <date value="1861-07-30">July 30<hi rend="super">th</hi>
       <abbr expan="1861">/61</abbr></date>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Friend:-</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>Yours of the 19th <abbr expan="instance">inst.</abbr> was received in due<lb/> time, I was
     sorry to hear that you were not well, but I<lb/> hope that you are now stout and hearty,
     enjoying the<lb/> pleasures of a beautiful country home. I know not<lb/> whether you would
     prefer a town life to one in the<lb/> country, but if you lived in town awhile and had<lb/>
     nothing to do, you would realize the truth of that<lb/> saying, that "nothing to do" is the
     hardest work that<lb/> one can engage in. I hope you will take care of that<lb/> and always
     manage to have something to do, for <orig reg="children">chil-<lb/> dren</orig> learn mischief
     when they learn nothing else.<lb/>
    </p>
    <p> You will excuse me for reminding me of the value<lb/> of health, but my object is to put you
     on your guard<lb/> that you may not, by unnecessary means, <orig reg="impair">impare</orig>
     or<lb/> injure your health, for it is one of the greatest gifts<lb/>
     <orig reg="confered">conferred</orig> upon a man by a bountiful Creator, a gift<lb/> which few
     enjoy, and which a still less number try<lb/> to preserve, how much less suffering would
     there<lb/> be in the world if people would regard their health<lb/>
     <!-- </page> -->
     <!-- <page n=2><ID>BitCre62</ID> -->
     <pb n="2" entity="BitCre6b" pid="uva-lib:502952"/> in the proper light, The only possible excuse<lb/> that could be
     advanced for one's neglecting his health<del rend="none" hand="h1"/><lb/> would, I suppose be, that <abbr
      expan="Doctors">Dr.s.</abbr> must live too,<lb/> He who loses his health, by abusing it, will
     then for<lb/> the first time discover that he has forfeited <del hand="h1">it to</del><lb/> all
     his claims to unalloyed and perfect <orig reg="happiness">happines</orig>.<lb/> Now as you and
     I are yet young and healthy,<lb/> let us resolve <add hand="h1" place="supralinear">that</add>
     our health shall claim its share of<lb/> attention,--that we will ever strive to preserve
     and<lb/> maintain it as long as it is the will of our Maker<lb/> to do so. </p>
    <p>The war is not over yet,--the difficulties remain<lb/> unsettled-- the traitors still live to
     plot our destruction<lb/> yea: it is just beginning to assume its destructive form<lb/> the
     defeat at <name type="place">Manassas Junction</name>, and the cruel manner<lb/> in which our
     wounded heroes were treated will forever<lb/> remain on the pages of history as a living
     testimony against<lb/> the humanity of the slave drivers of the South, when<lb/> the people of
     the North <add hand="h1" place="supralinear">once</add> suffer the cruelties which the<lb/>
     south chooses <add hand="h1" place="supralinear">to</add> inflict--when his life depends on
     the<lb/> sympathy of a southerner, he will say "the half<lb/> was not told us of <add hand="h1"
      place="supralinear">the</add> inhumanity of this people" <!-- </page> -->
     <!-- <page n=3><ID>BitCre63</ID> -->
     <pb n="3" entity="BitCre6c" pid="uva-lib:502953"/> no, the war is not ended yet, we permitted the south<lb/> to
     inflict upon a poor and helpless race of <orig reg="God's">Gods</orig> creatures<lb/> the most
     unjust tortures that was <add hand="h1" place="supralinear">ever</add> heaped upon<lb/> any
     race of human beings, and now we are to be asked to<lb/> do just what rational beings might
     have expected<lb/> to bow down on our knees <add hand="h1" place="supralinear">before
     them</add>, that a like <orig reg="burden">burthen</orig><lb/> may be placed upon <hi
      rend="underline">our</hi> shoulders, but will we do it;<lb/> will we as freeman succumb to
     their unjust demands &amp;<lb/> will we sacrifice ourselves and our children to the<lb/>
     everlasting curse of slavedom? <hi rend="underline">No</hi>, but we will<lb/> cheerfully
     sacrifice our all upon the alter of our Country<lb/> and stand by the Constitution and the laws
     until the<lb/> last drop of our <orig reg="heart's">hear's</orig> blood shall have oozed from
      <add hand="h1" place="supralinear">our</add><lb/> bosoms, not as long as we inherit the spirit
     by which<lb/> our fathers were actuated <add hand="h1" place="supralinear">can we</add> shrink
     from the task<lb/> before us, nor can <add hand="h1" place="supralinear">we,</add> until that
     spirit shall have<lb/> been entirely annihilated, yield to the mandate of<lb/> that <orig
      reg="notorious">notaious</orig> traitor <abbr expan="Jefferson Davis">Jeff.</abbr> not until
     we have<lb/> lost everything that is noble in man, can we<lb/> consent to the destruction of
     the government,<lb/> which would be nothing less than our own destruction.<lb/> No the war is
     not ended yet, the fighting is <!-- </page> -->
     <!-- <page n=4><ID>BitCre64</ID> -->
     <pb n="4" entity="BitCre6d" pid="uva-lib:502954"/> yet to do, and <name type="place">
      <corr sic="virginia">Virginia</corr>
     </name> will become a free<lb/> state, <hi rend="underline">and</hi> slavery will gradually die
     out, and<lb/> how is this to be done? Why I will tell you<lb/> our troops will take <name
      type="place">
      <corr sic="virginia">Virginia</corr>
     </name>-- occupy it, --and then<lb/> the secessionists will have to leave to escape being<lb/>
     imprisoned for treason, and then <name type="place">western Virginia</name> will<lb/> extend
     her government over the whole dominion<lb/> and abolish slavery herself, because the <orig
      reg="non-slaveholders">non-<lb/> slaveholders</orig> will carry the elections, and after <name
      type="place">Virginia</name><lb/> becomes a free state and presents to the other southern<lb/>
     states her advantage gained by freedom and their <orig reg="disadvantaged">dis-<lb/>
     advantage</orig> incured by the curse of <orig reg="slavey">slavery</orig> they will<lb/>
     gradually one after the other become free, and those<lb/> who live to see it will behold the
      <hi rend="underline"> whole union</hi><lb/> cemented together by bonds of common<lb/> interest
     and brotherhood, this is my opinion<lb/> of the result of this war. </p>
    <p> I am getting along with study old fashioned<lb/> and have some hopes of getting home before
     long,<lb/> wishing you success in your efforts to get<lb/> a <orig reg="berth">birth</orig> of
     school teaching. </p>
    <closer>
     <salute> I remain your,<lb/> true friend</salute>
     <signed>Alex Cressler</signed>
    </closer>

   </div1>
   <!-- </page> -->
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
