<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0935"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="F0935">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: William S. Garvin to Simon Cameron, January 24,
     1861</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county william s garvin to simon cameron, january 24 1861</title>
        <author>Garvin, William S.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Susanna Michele Lee</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Susanna Michele Lee</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num>kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">F0935</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501391</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: William S. Garvin to Simon Cameron, January 24, 1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county william s garvin to simon cameron, january 24 1861</title>
            <author>William S. Garvin</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>2 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Simon Cameron Papers, Microfilm reel 7, Collection
       of the Historical Society of Dauphin County, Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission,
       Harrisburg, Pennsylvania.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Historical Society of Dauphin County, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1861-01-24">1861-01-24</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>National Government, State Government</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>


    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="F0935T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>William S. Garvin opposes federal coercion and supports compromise with the South to save the
     Union through Constitutional amendment.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>
  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Simon Cameron</name>
    </head>
    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1861-01-24">Jan. 24. '61</date>
      <name type="place">Mercer</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr>
     </salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I have just <unclear>read</unclear> the debates in the Senate on Monday last. Your course
     gladdens my heart, as it looks as though a way was opening to save this country for your
     children and mine. God grant that you may succeed in staying the torrent of secession. Had the
     great leaders of the abolition wing of your party, risen to the magnitude of the crisis, and
     taken your patriotic position at an earlier day in the session, I think it would have saved us
     from the present peril. Every <pb n="2"/> democrat that I have met to-day, that has been
     advised of your position, is highly rejoiced, and I have heard men that were always opposed to
     you say that now, since you have shown yourself the foremost patriot in the Senate they are
     ready to support you for <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig>. The Republican leaders,
     however, appear to be chagrined at your course.</p>

    <p>But all we want to save the Union, is to let the people of the North have a chance to say to
     the people of the South that they are ready to so amend the constitution as to give the South
     all the guarantees they ask. There are hundreds<pb n="3"/> in this county who voted for
     Lincoln, that will vote for any amendment to the constitution [Crittenden,
     <unclear>Brigler</unclear>, Douglass,] on <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig> else almost
     that has a reasonable face. The small politicians will object, but from every quarter I hear of
     men breaking away from party trammels and avowing themselves ready to compromise to save the
     Union. I have no doubt the same can be said all over the state. If fight we must, it will be
     awful - and will give almost every state in the union trouble. I put it down, for instance,
     that the democrats <orig reg="nowhere">no where</orig> in the north will sustain coercion, and
     if drafted will refuse the requisition. Will<pb n="4"/> Mr. <unclear>Curtin</unclear> and M<hi
      rend="super">c</hi>Clure undertake to compel the democrats of this state to go south to fight
     their brethren. They will have a good time in doing it, I fancy. Coercion will never do -
     better the whole union broke up than coercion attempted in a single state. If we part
     peaceably, we can come together again, when the questions of the day have lost their acrimony,
     and when we realize how necessary to our security, prosperity, and happiness, the Union really
     is - but if we have war, farewell <orig reg="forever">for ever</orig> to any future union. But
     I am writing too much on this subject.</p>

    <p>After offering you an appointment, I do not see how the President can withdraw. In your
     present position, your name <del hand="h1">would</del> in his cabinet would be a
     <unclear>vote</unclear> in his support. If he is wise, he will insist on your acceptance.</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Yours</salute>
     <signed>Wm.S. Garvin</signed>
     <seg type="postscript">
      <name type="recipient"><abbr expan="Senator">Sen.</abbr> Cameron</name>
     </seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
