<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F1119"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F1119">
   <teiHeader type="migrated">

      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Franklin Rosenbery to his family,
               January 3, 1864</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county franklin rosenbery to his family, january 3 1864</title>
        <author>Rosenbery, Franklin</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
               <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
               <name>Matt Speiser</name>
               <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
               <name>Matt Speiser</name>
            </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

         <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

            <idno type="VCDH">F1119</idno>

        <!--
            <availability>
               <p>Publicly accessible </p>
               <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
               <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the University
                  of Virginia</p>
            </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
            <date value="2002">2002</date>
         <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501415</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
         </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note/>
         </notesStmt>

         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Franklin Rosenbery to his family, January 3, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county franklin rosenbery to his family, january 3 1864</title>
            <author>Franklin Rosenbery</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                     <resp/>
                     <name/>
                  </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
               <editionStmt>
                  <p/>
               </editionStmt>
               <extent> pages</extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher/>
                  <pubPlace/>
                  <date value=""/>
                  <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Kittochtinney Historical Society,
                     Chambersburg, PA</idno>
               </publicationStmt>
               <seriesStmt>
                  <p/>
               </seriesStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note/>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Kittochtinney Historical Society, Chambersburg, PA</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

      <profileDesc>
         <creation>
            <date value="1864-01-03">1864-01-03</date>
         </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords>
               <term>Camp Life, Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties, Family, Home Front,
                  Patriotism</term>
               <term>American Civil War</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>

      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date value="2005-07">July, 2005</date>
            <respStmt>
               <resp/>
               <name>Kid W.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
         </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>

   <text id="F1119T">
      <front id="d2">
         <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
            <p>Rosenbery responds to the news of his family, including that of his grandmother's
               death. He offers praise to God and allegiance to country. Rosenbery then forcefully
               writes that his acquantance, John Markey, should return his tools.</p>
         </div1>
      </front>

      <body id="d4">
         <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
            

            <opener>
               <dateline>
                  <date value="1864-01-03">January 3, 1864</date>
                  <name type="place">Army of the Potomac<lb/> Stephensville, <abbr expan="Virginia"
                     >Va.</abbr></name>
               </dateline>
               <salute>Dear Family:</salute>
            </opener>

            <p>Your <orig reg="letters">leters</orig> of December 27th came to hand yetserday
               evening. I was glad to hear that you was well and Brother William and Sister Eliza
               was recovering from their illness. Sorry to hear that Jonas must still be troubled
               with them spells and sorry to hear of Grandmother's death but the Lord giveth and the
               Lord taketh. Blessed by the Lord. I hope she is praising God in Heaven.</p>
            <p>Where there is no war or no trouble to contend with. But all is joy and peace.</p>
            <p>Well, I hope Brother John is well and Solomon I hope is well and obeying his parents
               so that when he has to be away from home he will not have that trouble to think of.
               If this should be his lot but I hope he will enjoy the presence of his parents awhile
               he lives and the rest of my sisters and step mother are well and enjoying health
               which is the richest of God's Blessings.</p>
            <p>This is the Sabbath Morning and finds me in good company while living a soldier's
               life for my country's sake.</p>
            <p>By the help and grace of God I am trying to live a soldier for Jesus. May God keep me
               faithful and all those that desire His Salvation.</p>
            <p>Well, now, concerning John Markey...I would advise him, as a friend, to return them
               tools home and in as good order as I left them. And if they are not all in the chest
               or any of them broke he shall stand good from them. As to selling them-under any
               circumstances whatever I intend using them myself if I live.</p>
            <p>This is not going to last forever and if I never get home the tools will not eat
               anything.</p>
            <p>Now, I ask you to bring them home immediately-no matter where they are and if he does
               not watch I shall sue him for stealing them as he had no orders to move them.</p>
            <p>I could not tell whether the tools was at Stephen Keeffer's. As you had not writ it
               very plain but no matter where they are. You get them home and when you get them. Let
               me know and then if I can see the point I will pay.</p>
            <p>I think that I can see the point. You make some inquiry to this affect and see if I
               can hold his pay till him and Joseph Markey pays you. If I can I will pay him in his
               own <orig reg="coin">coine</orig>. I will try here and name the tools:-<lb/> 1
               joiner<lb/> 1 Face plane<lb/> 1 smoothing plane<lb/> Jack plane<lb/> 2 sets plow and
               grooves<lb/> 1 rabbit <hi rend="super">1/4</hi> head 5/8 head<lb/> Roof <orig
                  reg="bevel">Bevit</orig> Trying Square Steel Square <orig reg="Compasses"
               >Compases</orig> 9 Thuset <orig reg="gauges">guages</orig> hand saw-tenant saw-three
               lurges-chisel- a lot of small chisels. I can't give the number. Saw set-<orig
                  reg="whetstone">whet stone</orig>-Brace and 3 or 4 bits. 2 small gimlets-2
                  <unclear>seniling</unclear> all chalk line-red line-hatchet-hand aue=3 <orig
                  reg="screwdrivers">screw drivers</orig> 1 3/4 auger that you gave me 3/4 auger-<hi
                  rend="super">1/2</hi> auger 5/8 auger- a <orig reg="mallet">malet</orig>-bench
               hook-screw and burr foot luge.</p>
            <p>When you get the chest home, mark on a paper all the tools and what kind. I will tell
               you if they are all there or not. If I had not been merciful my tools would have been
               at home before I left.</p>
            <p>I did not think John (Markey) was so bad up. I shall pay him every cent when it suits
               me and he will take when he gets it..</p>
            <p>No more at this time.</p>

            <closer>
               <salute/>
               <signed>Franklin D. Rosenbery</signed>
            </closer>
         </div1>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>
