<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F1121"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F1121">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Franklin Rosenbery to John Abraham
                    Rosenbery (father), January 10, 1864</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county franklin rosenbery to john abraham rosenbery father , january 10 1864</title>
        <author>Rosenbery, Franklin</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F1121</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501417</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Franklin Rosenbery to John Abraham Rosenbery
                            (father), January 10, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county franklin rosenbery to john abraham rosenbery father , january 10 1864</title>
            <author>Franklin Rosenbery</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent> pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Kittochtinney Historical Society,
                            Chambersburg, PA</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Kittochtinney Historical Society, Chambersburg, PA</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-01-10">1864-01-10</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Family, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-07">July, 2005</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Kid W.</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F1121T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Rosenbery writes about receiving supplies from home and observes that it does,
                    indeed, snow in the South.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
               

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-01-10">January 10, 1864</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Near Stephensville, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Father:</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Your letter of 4th and 5th came to hand yesterday evening. I was truly glad to
                    hear from you. I am well at present-hoping that these few lines may <orig
                        reg="find">finde</orig> you all enjoying the same blessings of health-</p>
                <p>I received Rachel's letter but your others I did not. I was glad to get them awls
                    and Bristles and thread and needle. I intended that you should send me shoemaker
                    threads but one of my <orig reg="messmates">mess mates</orig> got a box sent
                    from home and had shoe thread in it and he had a variety of provisions in it. He
                    shares with us.</p>
                <p>There is 4 of us together-William H. Wolff from Bridgeport, near Loudon, Solomon
                    Dale from Centee County, Ben Bowlesboro and James Deckert. The rest of the mess
                    have sent for stores so that they can share with Solomon Dale while he has
                    shared with us.</p>
                <p>I thought that I could have a small box made up for me as there is a great many
                        <orig reg="boxes">boxs</orig> has come through to our <abbr expan="Regiment"
                        >Regt.</abbr> by express. By being addressed the same as the letter-if you
                    fix me up a small box tell Rachel to put some dry cherries-dry huckleberries, a
                    crock of apple butter and a few pounds of butter. Some fat cakes as they will
                    keep-that is if the fat is not <orig reg="too">to</orig> scarce-about 2 loaves
                    of bread and get a bucket that is like that small one of mine-with the lid
                    on-one that will hold a gallon. Fill it with <orig reg="sauerkraut"
                    >sorkrout</orig> and put in some <orig reg="cucumber">cuccumber</orig> pickles.
                    We would like the bucket to answer for making coffee in. Dale's box weighed
                    about 2 hundred pounds.</p>
                <p>I wish to mention that you must not think that I am starving. I have enough to
                    eat. But the rest have shared with me and I would like to give something in
                    return. If some of the neighbors feel like helping to fix up the box it will be
                    gladly <abbr expan="received">rec'd</abbr>.</p>
                <p>Put in some sausages-some pudding. Dale had roasted chicken sent to him. They
                    were froze over night after they were roasted then packed up. Send some dry
                    beef-some roasted chiken.</p>
                <p>If they wish send some eggs as eggs are worth 60 cents a dozen here. Put them in
                    something to pack them-with some corn meal.</p>
                <p>Tell Rachel to put in some dry beans-that is those that were dried green-put in
                    some apples-send a box weighing about 100 pounds more or less. You may do about
                    this as you please.</p>
                <p>Now at this present time, Aunt Sally Lincoln gives us <orig reg="biscuits"
                        >buisquits</orig>. Only they are pretty <orig reg="hard">harde</orig> on the
                    teeth. It is a good thing to have a change.</p>
                <p>You may send the box when it suits you. I for my part would not ask you to go to
                    any trouble for me. Dale got his box a few days ago. Deckert got his box today.
                    Willim H. Wolrff's box is on the way. They share with me. I feel like sharing
                    with them. If you cannot send such articles as I mentioned...Send anything that
                    is eatable for we are not choicy here or sneaken.</p>
                <p>Now, about the weather. It snowed nearly all day on the 4th of this month as we
                    are South as they call it. It still snows here and the snow is cold here too.</p>
                <p>Tuesday we were sent out on three day picket. On Wednesday night it snowed nearly
                    all night. You may guess how it goes to be out in the snow. 2 hours at a time
                    without fire and when you are off of post and want to lay down to sleep you can
                    lay down and let it snow on you. I tried it but the snow tickled my face <orig
                        reg="too">to</orig> much to sleep.</p>
                <p>We picketed along the Rappahannock River. Every 15th day comes my turn to go out
                    on 3 day picket. It has been very cold for 2 weeks back. I must close for the
                    present.</p>
                <p>I will write soon again.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute><orig reg="Farewell">Farewll</orig> for this time.</salute>
                    <signed><abbr expan="Franklin">F.</abbr> Rosenbery</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">
                        <name type="recipient">To John Rosenbery</name>
                    </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
