<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F1129"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F1129">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Franklin Rosenbery to John Abraham
                    Rosenbery (father), March 21, 1864</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county franklin rosenbery to john abraham rosenbery father , march 21 1864</title>
        <author>Rosenbery, Franklin</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">6</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F1129</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501425</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Franklin Rosenbery to John Abraham Rosenbery
                            (father), March 21, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county franklin rosenbery to john abraham rosenbery father , march 21 1864</title>
            <author>Franklin Rosenbery</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent> pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Kittochtinney Historical Society,
                            Chambersburg, PA</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Kittochtinney Historical Society, Chambersburg, PA</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-03-21">1864-03-21</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties, Desrtion/Leave,
                        Family, Military Authority, Military Strategy, Patriotism, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F1129T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Rosenbery thanks God for his health. He then writes about the army's marching
                    orders and his anticipation of a clash with Confederates. He states his
                    determination to gain victory for the nation, even at the cost of more lives,
                    even though he also longs for home.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
               

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-03-21">March 21, 1864</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Near Stephensburg, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Father-</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I use the present opportunity of informing you that your kind and welcome letter
                    of the 14th came to hand yesterday evening.</p>
                <p>I was truly glad to hear from you all.</p>
                <p>I, this morning, as a traveler to Eternity Thank God that I am well and on my way
                    to the New Jerusalem, hoping and praying that these few lines may find you all
                    enjoying the same blessings of health that I now enjoy.</p>
                <p>It is pretty cold here today and cloudy with the appearance of snow. Everything
                    appears middling quiet at present but we are under marching orders.</p>
                <p>It is rumored through the Camp that the enemy has changed camp or else has
                    started out on their summer Campaign.</p>
                <p>If so they will try to flank us but if they do they will send the boys of the
                    148th somewhere about. They hate our division or rather Corps much. They call it
                    the Butter Fly but I think think it is the Enemy's Fly.</p>
                <p>On last Friday evening at dress parade we were ordered to pack up to march at a
                        <orig reg="moment's">moments</orig> warning. Down at the <orig reg="Rapidan"
                        >Rapiran</orig> they showed a heavy front. I do not doubt but they will try
                    to get in our rear. If they do they will see some fun.</p>
                <p>Although it may cost some of our lives but that is what we are here for to fight
                    for our country and country rights.</p>
                <p>Things look pretty favorable for us conscripts to get home some time in May if we
                    live; According to the Act, They <orig reg="cannot">can not</orig> keep us
                    longer. Although it is kept very quiet, I shall live in hopes.</p>
                <p>I feel very well satisfied here but still if all was peace I would rather be at
                    home.</p>
                <p>Dear Father, make yourself contented and hope for the better. Take care of your
                    health.</p>
                <p>Tell Solomon if Rineman has not got that watch done he shall hand it over. Soon
                    he will ask him for rent for the room that the watch takes up. You need not send
                    the watch till further orders.</p>
                <p>We expect to be <orig reg="paid">paide</orig> off some of these days 'ere long.</p>
                <p>Tell Brother John I would like to see a few lines from him. If he writes to me, I
                    will try and answer his letter. I wrote a letter to John A. Horn <orig
                        reg="some time">sometime</orig> ago but I think the letter got lost as I do
                    not get any answer.</p>
                <p>I have nothing of importance to write. A few days ago, I wrote to you a letter
                    and in it I placed a letter that Brother Abraham had writ to me. You can inform
                    him of the things that he requested of me. I must close for the present.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Write soon so -farewell, Dear Father, for this time.</salute>
                    <signed>Franklin Rosenbery</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
