<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F3522"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="F3522">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Daniel Leedy to Edwin Stanton,
                    October 13, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county daniel leedy to edwin stanton, october 13 1863</title>
        <author>Leedy, Daniel</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">6</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F3522</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2001">2001</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501531</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: MDaniel Leedy to Edwin Stanton, October 13, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county mdaniel leedy to edwin stanton, october 13 1863</title>
            <author>Daniel Leedy </author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Compiled Military Service Records
                            of William Leedy, 126th Pa., Box 36132, Folder 618, National
                        Archives</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-10-13">1863-10-13</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Desertion/Leave, Family</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2001">Fall 2001</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Susanna Michele Lee</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Corrected TEI tagging, proofread for typos, added keywords, and edited
                    summaries.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F3522T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Daniel Leedy requests Edwin Stanton's favorable help in releasing his son,
                    William Leedy, from Fort McHenry, where he had been imprisoned as a deserter. A.
                    K. McClure and Captain Elder endorse Daniel Leedy's letter.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Hon. Edwin Stanton</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-10-13">Oct. 13th, 1863</date>
                        <name type="place">Chambersburg</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Sir,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I beg leave respectfully to submit the following fact for your consideration</p>

                <p>In the month of August 1862, the 126th regiment of the Pennsylvania volunteers
                    was organized at Harrisburg. My Son, Wm. Leedy, was a member of company "H" in
                    this regiment, at the time of enlistment he was not twenty-one years of age. He
                    volunteered in Franklin County, but was not mustered until he reached
                    Harrisburg; Franklin County, had given a bounty of $50 to volunteers. After my
                    son, Wm. Leedy, had been mustered in, the Captain of his company, Capt. Elda,
                    afterwards Colonel, refused to allow him his bounty for the reason that he was
                    in his minority and for fear that he would subsequently be taken out of the
                    service by his parents who were opposed to his enlisting, and he, the Capt., be
                    held responsible for the amount of the bounty by Franklin County. Thinking that
                    his disqualification on account of his minority would prevent him from receiving
                    his pay as well as his bounty he returned home from Harrisburg, where he
                    remained until the latter part of August last, when he was arrested and
                    forwarded to Fort McHenry as a Deserter.</p>

                <p>His regiment was mustered out of service in the month of May preceding. My Son is
                    now confined to Fort McHenry and I respectfully submit in his behalf the facts
                    stated as correct and true, at the same time asking your favorable consideration
                    of his case.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>I am Sir with sentiments of high regard<lb/> Your Obedient Servant</salute>
                    <signed>Daniel Leedy</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">Mr. Daniel Leedy is a respectable citizen of this County,
                        and an earnestly loyal man. His statements are worthy of entire
                        credit.<lb/><lb/> A.K. McClure<lb/> Chambersburg. Oct. 19, 1863<lb/><lb/> I
                        certify that the statements made by Daniel Leedy in regard to his Son is
                        correct and respectfully join in the request that his case be considered
                        favorably.<lb/> James G. Elder<lb/>Capt. Company H<lb/> afterwards Col.
                        126th Penna Vols. </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
