<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F6030"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="F6030">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Lauramann Howe Russell to Ellen
                    Howe, October 23, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county lauramann howe russell to ellen howe, october 23 1862</title>
        <author>Russell, Lauramann Howe</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Julie Beagle</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Julie Beagel</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F6030</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2001">2001</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501609</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Lauramann Howe Russell to Ellen Howe, October 23,
                            1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county lauramann howe russell to ellen howe, october 23 1862</title>
            <author>Lauramann Russell</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Lauramann Howe Russell Papers,
                            Special Collections Department, William R. Perkins Library, Duke
                            University, Durham, North Carolina</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note>
                            <p>We have not included other letters in this collection written from
                                Williamsport, Maryland, Harpers Ferry, (West) Virginia, and
                                Alexandria, Virginia.</p>
                        </note>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Special Collections Department, William R. Perkins Library, Duke University, Durham, North Carolina</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-10-23">1862-10-23</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Home Front, Hospitals, Family</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2001">Summer 2001</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F6030T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In response to a question from his daughter Ellen, Lauramann Howe Russell
                    describes the kind treatment of the people of Chambersburg toward the wounded
                    Union soldiers. He also mentions the layout of the town, its population, and
                    newspaper.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
              

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-10-23"><abbr expan="October">Oct</abbr> 23<hi rend="super">rd</hi> 1862</date>
                        <name type="place"><orig reg="Academy">Acadamy</orig> Hospital<lb/> Chambersburg
                            <abbr expan="Pennsylvania">Penn</abbr>
                        </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Daughter Ellen</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I was agreeably surprised this afternoon to <orig reg="receive">recieve</orig> a
                    letter from you dated the 20<hi rend="super">th</hi>
                    <abbr expan="instant">inst</abbr>. I was right glad I can <orig reg="assure"
                        >ashure</orig> you to know that you were able to write. I had written a
                    letter to you but did not send it for I wished to get my pay and send some money
                    with it but I will write and send the two letters then send the money when I get
                    it I <orig reg="received">recieved</orig> a letter from Charles this forenoon
                    and have answered it. he told me about getting a box from home. He said that he
                    had <orig reg="caught">cought</orig> a rabbit and had saved the <orig reg="fur"
                        >furr</orig> for Frank. He tells me that he likes <orig reg="where"
                    >whare</orig> he lives <orig reg="first-rate">first rate</orig> I am glad of
                    that hope he will stay all winter You say in your letter that you would like<pb
                        n="2"/> to have me tell you how I liked the people of Chambersburg well I
                    like them well thus far <orig reg="although">althoug</orig> I have had but very
                    little to do with them, but I judge of them by their acts. They are so kind to
                    the Soldiers that we <orig reg="cannot">can not</orig> help but think at any
                    rate that they may be very good people. For instance a Mrs Brown sends one of
                    the soldiers his meals regular and has for more than two weeks probably will as
                    long as he stays. Mrs. McCellan brings in a great many things to eat. she most
                    always comes into my ward. there are others who are very much interested in the
                        <orig reg="welfare">willfare</orig> of our soldiers. the names of some of
                    them I mentioned in the other letter. I think that I should like to live in
                    Chambersburg if I had my folks with me. I think that the population of the town
                    is between six and seven thousand that is about the number that there is in
                    Marlboro is it not? The streets all run at right angles and are lighted with gas
                    in the night. The town takes its name from the man who founded it whose name was
                    Chambers. There are three papers printed in town. I directed one to mother the
                    other day over<pb n="3"/> in it you will find an <abbr expan="account"
                    >acct</abbr> of the rebel raid into <abbr expan="Pennsylvania">Penn</abbr>
                    written by <abbr expan="Colonel">Col</abbr> McClure. I will send another soon
                    perhaps they will be interesting for you to read---</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>from your Father</salute>
                    <signed>
                        <abbr expan="Lauramann">L</abbr>
                    </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
