<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F6507"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="F6507">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Eliza R. Stouffer to Catherine and Amos Miller,
     July 10, 1864</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county eliza r stouffer to catherine and amos miller, july 10 1864</title>
        <author>Stouffer, Eliza R.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Edsel Burdge, Jr., Shippensburg, PA</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">F6507</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501635</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Eliza R. Stouffer to Catherine and Amos Miller, July 10, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county eliza r stouffer to catherine and amos miller, july 10 1864</title>
            <author>Eliza R. Stouffer</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: From the private collection of Margaret Binkley
       DuVernet. Photocopies courtesy of the Reformed Mennonite Collection, Mennonite Historical
       Association of the Cumberland Valley, Chambersburg, Pennsylvania.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>We would like to thank Edsel Burdge, Jr. of Shippensburg, PA, for bringing this letter to
        our attention and for sharing with us his transcription.</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from private collection</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1864-07-10">1864-07-10</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>African Americans, Agriculture, Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties, Family, Home
      Front</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""> </date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="F6507T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>In this letter, Eliza Stouffer describes crop harvests within the area, the status of
     education at her son Amos' school, and the recent deaths of friends.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
   

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1864-07-10">July 10th 1864</date>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Children</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>We <abbr expan="received">rec<hi rend="super">d</hi>
     </abbr> both yours &amp; Davids letters yesterday, were very glad to hear from you, and as
     times are, do not Know how long we may have the priviledge of writing together, we are all
     well, hope this may find you all again restored to perfect health, Andrew Henry &amp; <abbr
      expan="colored">col<hi rend="super">d</hi>
     </abbr> Thomas came home with the horses &amp; wagon yesterday evening, he is done cutting
     in the slate land, have quite a small portion to cut here yet, very few persons are done I Know
     of none else, Some are about half done, The news appeared quite <orig reg="favorable"
      >favourable</orig> yesterday, not so much so to day, at least the pickets say so, that stand
     on the pike, on Wednesday the order was given out in town, that when there would be danger and
     they thought it advisable for the farmers to move their stock, the Bells in town should be
     wrung, which was done on wednesday about sun set, then the whole neighborhood cleared off their
     horses, our men were as far as Leesburg, would have came on friday morning<pb n="2"/> But John
     Stouffer. went to town and heard bad news, telegraphed to his men not to come <orig reg="until"
      >untill</orig> he sent further orders. But they had started before the telegram arrived. So
     those that were back <abbr expan="received">re<hi rend="super">cd</hi></abbr> it, and <orig
      reg="stayed">staid</orig>, or else they would <orig reg="likely">likly</orig> all been home a
     day or so sooner, how it will go further, is a mystery yet, But must hope for the best, and put
     our trust in God, There was always a way yet and hope there is yet, Do not trouble yourselves
     about us, and if we should be so situated that we <orig reg="cannot">can not</orig> get
     together or hear from one another, Let us cast our care on him who has all power in Heaven
     &amp; earth, and if we can feel that nearness of him, we shall not be made afraid, we had a
     letter from Amos and a dispatch, enquiring, whether they should stay or come home, we advised
     them to stay, he says they are anxious to get through with their studies, complain they have
     two few teachers for so many <orig reg="Scholars">Schollars</orig>, which is a great drawback
     to them, complains of the heat, perhaps you can write to them <orig reg="sometime">some time</orig>
     <orig reg="particular">perticular</orig> if our mails should be closed and<pb n="3"/> not yours
     which might be the case, &amp; if you want the glass jars he could get them for you Papa
     send him a check for some <orig reg="money">mony</orig> so he could pay them we had meeting
      <orig reg="today">to day</orig>, this <orig reg="afternoon">after noon</orig>, at the School
     house, and had a very fine shower of rain which will freshen up things a little It was very
     dry, and is no ways soaked deep yet,</p>

    <p>The news are as yet not very <orig reg="favorable">favourable</orig> the Rebels are said to
     be moving on towards Baltimore. But we Know nothing and should give all over to God to rule who
     has all in his hands. and power I often feel that I dread the cross too much and would rather
     see it go according to my wish &amp; will. Oh What short sighted creatures are we.</p>

    <p>May the Lord rule my heart. and let me be silent</p>

    <p>Anna Landis was buried last wednesday at 10 Oclock. Stoner &amp; Uncle Daniel were at the
     funeral,</p>

    <p>also Eliza Burkholders son was wounded in battle &amp; has since died,</p>

    <pb n="4"/>

    <p>write <orig reg="whenever">when ever</orig>
     <orig reg="convenient">con venient</orig></p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Let David's see this as I may not answer theirs immediately</salute>
     <signed/>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
