<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F6506"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="F6506">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Jacob Stouffer to Mary R. Stouffer, July 5,
     1863</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county jacob stouffer to mary r stouffer, july 5 1863</title>
        <author>Stouffer, Jacob</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Edsel Burdge, Jr., Shippensburg, PA</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">F6506</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501634</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Jacob Stouffer to Mary R. Stouffer, July 5, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county jacob stouffer to mary r stouffer, july 5 1863</title>
            <author>Jacob Stouffer</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: From the private collection of Margaret Binkley
       DuVernet. Photocopies courtesy of the Reformed Mennonite Collection, Mennonite Historical
       Association of the Cumberland Valley, Chambersburg, Pennsylvania.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>We would like to thank Edsel Burdge, Jr. of Shippensburg, PA, for bringing this letter to
        our attention and for sharing with us his transcription.</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from private collection</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1863-07-05">1863-07-05</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Home Front, Troop Movement</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""> </date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="F6506T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>In this letter to his daughter Mary, Jacob Stouffer describes the health of his brother
     Abraham, the suicide of Abraham Shetter, and the Confederate Army's invasion and emcampment
     within the area.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">


    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1863-07-05">July 5 1863</date>
      <name type="place">Chambersburg</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Mary R. Stouffer<lb/>Dear Daughter, Sister</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>It is a long time Since we had the pleasure of hearing from our Scattered family, little did
     I think when you left home that Such a Scatterment would take place and So long a time elapse
     without an opportunity of hearing from each other-I feel thankful and rejoiced this evening to
     hear that you and the rest of our absentees are Still Spared in life and health and that we can
     Say we enjoy the Same blessing-James Varner came home this evening, and has given us a history
     So far as he could-how you were and they in Cumberland Co- we are all about as well as usual,
     and the friends and <orig reg="neighbors">neighbours</orig> too- brother Abraham is recovering
     a little <orig reg="very">verry</orig> Slowly he has no bodily Suffering but is Still helpless
     in his arms and legs-we have had Some trials, and uneasy times now for nearly three weeks- and
     no doubt you have many reports; and many anxious hours on our account- but thanks be to God,
     who is able to keep and protect all who put their trust in him-we are Still Spared and I trust
     uninjured-our <orig reg="neighborhood">neighbourhood</orig> has Suffered <orig reg="Severely"
      >Severly</orig> in the temporal blessing,the Rebels entered town on monday night the 15<hi
      rend="super">th</hi> June Since then we have been under their rule with the the exception of a
     few days on the 17<hi rend="super">th</hi> they moved toward <pb n="2"/> Hagerstown and
     returned again on the 23<hi rend="super">rd</hi> Since then we have been quite overrun with
     them many thousand, the greater part of <abbr expan="General">Genl.</abbr> Lees army have
     passed by here and have been encamped all around us-they have encamped three different times in
     mine and Shetters woods this day one week we had Some Seven different camp all around us. which
     lay from Saturday noon <orig reg="until">untill</orig> tuesday morning-<abbr expan="General"
      >Genl.</abbr> Lee had his head quarters in A. Shetters woods during this time.-they have
     encamped in and pastured our four grass fields and all of A. Shetters. in most of Daniels-in
     the <unclear>poorhouse</unclear> field by Joseph Ryder in J. Ryder orchard-in Daniel house yard
     or orchard-in Shetters woods between us and Abrahams-in my lot by the School house-in the grass
     lot by J. Bowmans in the lime Kiln lot by Rhodeses &amp; other places-these Camps were
     mostly wagon trains-of Quartermasters- <abbr expan="General's">Genls</abbr> head quarters-
     Commissary departments and Cavalry-we had no heavy encampment of Infantry quite close here-on
     Tuesday June 30 near 700 army wagons passed by here beside the Several encampments which moved
     away from around us also heavy bodies of infantry-21 <orig reg="pieces">peices</orig> of <orig
      reg="artillery">artilery</orig> and many horses and beef Cattle-all were <orig reg="marching"
      >marcing</orig> toward Gettysburg-I am writing more on this Subject than may be proper, and
     hurriedly and confused that you Scarcely read or understand it-you can learn the particulars
     when you get home-I can only Say that these men wanted almost everything-bread-butter
     milk-cheese <orig reg="vegetables">vegeables</orig> &amp; <unclear>C</unclear>- while those
     in authority <pb n="3"/> took from us all the horses they could find-many were not moved far
     away and fell into their hands <abbr expan="George">Geo</abbr> Overcash lost all of his blind
     &amp; all-they took all the horse <unclear>geers</unclear> they could find-the Oats and
     corn-hay when it Suited them flour-and every thing they needed-beef cattle young cattle and
     milk cows-my loss in flour-corn-Oats-hay grass and fences is heavy-all those however are the
     free gifts of a bountiful creator and are merely lent us and with job we can Say the Lord hath
     given-the Lord hath taken away and blessed be the name of the Lord-the hardest of of all I have
     yet to tell you-our friend and neighbour Absolam Shetter was laid into his Silent grave this
     forenoon-he had been in trouble and at times in a State of despondency-this with the troubles
     and Excitements around us-deranged his mind and on yesterday morning ended his existence by
     hanging-this is a hard Stroke on his poor bereaved family-we could not learn until this evening
     where our boys had come to-the following morning after Benjamin- James &amp; David had
     Started Amos Started down too with Some of Jacob Leydigs horses-he would rather not have
     gone-but there was none else to go-he did not find any of the others So he took to the
     mountains to left of newburg-he Started out on Sunday last to hear how things were-when the
     Rebels chased him, he made for the park Valley-was at Joseph Ryders and on his way to M. Ryders
     he was so Surrounded that he could not escape-they took his <pb n="4"/> horse from him and he
     walked home from Loudon-this was hurriedly written by candle light-and now monday morning Jacob
     Lehman is here waiting to take this letter to <orig reg="Carlisle">Carlise</orig> where he is
     going for Mary Stoner-we learned last Evening that Annie Ryder had come home and that they are
     all well-Davids and Amos Millers are also well-Little Annie was not So well-the last weeks-I
     think the boys would best buy two breackbonds down there-or a full Set for the two hind
     horses-not very heavy as they will Scarcely be Supplied here in time unless <orig reg="brought"
      >brot</orig> here from other parts-the front gears we can make up-I think too they will be
     high in price here-I have many things to Say yet but have not time now as Jacob is waiting for
     this-I think too our mails will Soon Run again I think you can all come home Soon-yesterday we
     heard canonading toward <orig reg="Waynesboro">Wanesboro</orig>-they army had hard fighting at
     Gettysburg a few days ago. the Rebels were coming across the mountains with their wagon trains
     and <orig reg="Striking">Strikeing</orig> from Greenwood to Hagerstown-I will close by wishing
     you the blessing of God and his protections to you and all Godfearing Souls-my love to all
      <orig reg="inquiring">enquiring</orig> friends</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>from your father</salute>
     <signed>
      <hi rend="underline">
       <hi rend="underline">J. Stouffer</hi>
      </hi>
     </signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
