<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F6508"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="F6508">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Emma V. Stouffer to Amos Stouffer, August 1,
     1864</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county emma v stouffer to amos stouffer, august 1 1864</title>
        <author>Stouffer, Emma V.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Edsel Burdge, Jr., Shippensburg, PA</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">F6508</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501636</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Emma V. Stouffer to Amos Stouffer, August 1, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county emma v stouffer to amos stouffer, august 1 1864</title>
            <author>Emma V. Stouffer</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>6 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: From the private collection of Margaret Binkley
       DuVernet. Photocopies courtesy of the Reformed Mennonite Collection, Mennonite Historical
       Association of the Cumberland Valley, Chambersburg, Pennsylvania.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>We would like to thank Edsel Burdge, Jr. of Shippensburg, PA, for bringing this letter to
        our attention and for sharing with us his transcription.</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from private collection</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1864-08-01">1864-08-01</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Battle Description, Home Front, Military Authority, Prisons/Prisoners, Troop Movement</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""> </date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="F6508T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>In this letter to her brother, Emma V. Stouffer describes the burning of Chambersburg and the
     extent of the fire's destruction.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     Ford<lb/> Due 3<lb/> Amos Stouffer<lb/>
     <del hand="h1">Petesbough</del><lb/> Chambersburg <abbr expan="Pennsylvania">Pa</abbr><lb/> Box
     951
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1864-08-01">Monday, August 1<hi rend="super">st</hi> 1864</date>
      <name type="place">Home,</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Dear Brother,</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I have no doubt you are very anxious to hear from home, thanks to a kind Providence that we
     still retain our home. I suppose you hear all sorts of news. But hardly much worse than it
     really is. On Saturday morning at four O'clock we heard artillery firing which proved to be the
     rebs on the fair grounds, and a few of our soldiers between them and town. We had two pieces I
     do not know how many the rebels had, Our men then started with the horses, &amp; sheep Abe
     Witmen along. Ben went<pb n="2"/> with a soldier and Noah Sollenberger to town to see if the
     rebels were there, when one fired after them and a ball came within two inches of the soldiers
     head. The rebels were commanded by that old scoundrel M<hi rend="super">c</hi> clausland. they
     first (for an excuse) demanded 500,000 in Greenbacks, or 100,000 in gold which of course could
     not be given them. They then fired the Companies ware house, Court-house-Hall, Academy
      <unclear>V.</unclear> and then carried fire in the private houses. There is nothing but ruins
     from the Depot up <abbr expan="until">till</abbr> D<hi rend="super">r</hi> Sueserott's house
     Eysters mill the paper mill and everything is gone. There is nothing left but the superbs of
     the place. Col. M'clures house and barn and J. Ebys barn are<pb n="3"/> burned. M<hi
      rend="super">rs.</hi> M<hi rend="super">c</hi>lure was sick and they gave her ten minutes time
     to leave, M<hi rend="super">rs.</hi> M<hi rend="super">c</hi>lellan saved her house by very
     hard pleading. Oh Amos, town looks wonderful, Alice Snively has <orig reg="everything">every
      thing</orig> here she owns which is a few of her best dresses. Andrew Snively's property
     consists of one coat, besides what he has on. The D<hi rend="super">r</hi> is in <orig
      reg="Philadelphia">Phila<hi rend="super">d</hi></orig> seeing about his position. he is ready
     to take his place on the field as Surgeon. he has not come home yet, do not know what effect it
     will have on him. I heard of but two families who saved <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig>
     but a few clothes, The Citizens Killed a Rebel Major who was drunk &amp; had straggled back
     and was burning buildings. David &amp; John Miller came up this morning to see whether we
     were burned<pb n="4"/> out. There were two rebels came out to Porters on Saturday Morning and
     while they were busy talking a squad of our men came dashing out the lane there and captured
     them, they say now and it is the opinion of almost <orig reg="everyone">every one</orig> that
     they came out for the purpose of burning the mill, as the rebels said in town that Stouffers
     Mill must come down yet. In a short time <abbr expan="General">Gen</abbr> Averils men came,
     when the rebels, aware of the fact, moved off. Some attach great blame to <abbr
      expan="General's">Gens</abbr> Couch and <orig reg="Averil">Averel</orig>. the former some
     persons say should have rallied the 1500 men who went through here on Friday eve, and the
     latter was so drunk in GreenCastle that he could not write an answer to a dispatch sent him by
      Couch<pb n="5"/> It is hard to tell where the blame rests it surely is a shame that so few
     should come in &amp; do so much damage. No one knows the correct amount of rebs here, Some
     say not more than 3-others 800 &amp; some 1500. Mother &amp; Aunt Leah are still up at
     Grandmothers We have not heard <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig> from there since last
     Thursday, it may likely be that Grandmother is no more. There are a great many persons come to
     town, some from Lancaster, Carlisle Gettysburg <orig reg="etc.">&amp;c.</orig> to see the
     place. I suppose you will be home soon, About that Photograph you need not send any I suppose
     to Leah, as she, I suppose appropriated Abe's to herself. I was in town twice on<pb n="6"/>
     Saturday, Once while the fire was raging and again when it was pretty well over, from the mill
     we could see the Cupola of the Academy, <abbr expan="Benjamin">Benj<hi rend="super"
     >m</hi></abbr> Franklin <orig reg="etc.">&amp;c.</orig> fall over it looked very hard.
     Since I am writing it began to rain but I think it is already pretty well over, I have a great
     deal to tell you and hope to see you soon when I can have the pleasure of again speaking to
     you. I have not time now to write more. Uncle Daniel got a horse some-where and has gone up to
     Loudon. The friends &amp; neighbors are well so far as I know. It is now reported that
     Averell is fighting the rebels at M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Connellsburg but I do not think it is
     correct. Write soon we are very anxious to hear from you</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>from your loving sister</salute>
     <signed>Emma</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
