<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F8534"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F8534">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: E. to Edward McPherson, December
                    21, 1857</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county e to edward mcpherson, december 21 1857</title>
        <author>E.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F8534</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501716</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: E. to Edward McPherson, December 21, 1857</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county e to edward mcpherson, december 21 1857</title>
            <author>E.</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: E. to Edward McPherson 21
                            December 1857, Library of Congress, Edward McPherson Papers, Box 47,
                            Folder 1857</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1857-12-21">1857-12-21</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties, Family, Home Front, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-07">July 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F8534T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>E. refers to the approaching death of a Mr. Ramsey and expresses her concern for
                    Edward McPherson's father's declining health. She also discusses the Gettysburg
                    Presbyterian Church's problem with a Mr. Van Wycke, noting Edward's fondness for
                    the man. </p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
             

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1857-12-21"><abbr expan="December">Dec.</abbr> 21<hi
                                rend="super">st</hi>, 1857</date>
                        <name type="place">Frederick</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear <abbr expan="Edward">Edwd</abbr></salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I have just been sick enough for the last two weeks to make letter writing, too
                    much of a task for me to undertake, &amp; this is the reason you have not
                    heard from me since your last was received. I took cold, but unlike the
                    prevailing influenza, which runs its course in a few days very severely,
                    &amp; then is over, mine has been obstinate, attended by slow fever, loss of
                    appetite &amp;c all symptoms I had four or five years ago, since when, my
                    lungs have never been strong. I feel better for two days just &amp; if there
                    was not so much dampness in the atmosphere would venture out. But I must be very
                    prudent. <pb n="2"/>John is also in the house with a bad cold &amp; our
                    neighbor Dr. Dorsey is very low with pneumonia. Lizzie came last Thursday night
                    &amp; to our great disappointment without Lizzie Law, who wrote she could
                    not possibly get away from Virginia before Christmas.--Her young female friends
                    &amp; all the beaux besides ourselves are filled with consternation. Mr.
                    Williams cannot be here until Thursday night &amp; then must return to
                    Georgetown on Saturday -- business always before pleasure with him -- this is a
                    good sign in these degenerate times, don't you think so? Lizzie will remain
                    until the last day of the year when her Mother &amp; Father expect to go
                    with her; the latter on his way to Annapolis once more to try his fortune. So
                    John &amp; myself will be reigning monarchs. Mr. Ramsey is expected to die
                    every day. For the last five or six weeks there has been a very favorable change
                    in the state of his mind: from being very fretful &amp; rebellious, he has
                    become very <pb n="3"/>gentle &amp; submissive -- peacefully &amp;
                    calmly waiting the great change- his Bible his constant companion. Nannie was
                    just here she desires her love &amp; says she will write soon. She has been
                    suffering with a gathering in her ear. We are truly glad to hear, that Aunt is
                    as well as usual again- but much grieved to hear Uncle is so much more feeble. I
                    have so much desire to see him once more, &amp; hoped at the last, it would
                    be my privilege to assist in ministering to his comfort. But there is no need of
                    me, &amp; there is comfort in that to me, since Providence seems to have
                    tied me down now as regards health, &amp; in other ways. C. Mchaffey, will
                    of course, be on soon &amp; Kate also, if she can leave her little charge,
                    so that, you will not feel so lonely. I often think with sad pleasure of the
                    many little social chats, he &amp; I had the fall I was there, sitting by
                    the light of the fire. No matter how feeble &amp; wearied he was, whenever I
                    entered the room, he always <pb n="4"/> looked up &amp; gave me such a
                    pleasant welcome which made me feel that I <hi rend="underline">could</hi>
                    contribute somewhat to his pleasure when so lonely during your absence. What you
                    mentioned respecting the Winrott's gratified me exceedingly &amp; is just as
                    I expected he would feel &amp; act. In the end, what does all this
                    alienation &amp; bitterness of feeling amount to? It invariably brings
                    sorrow &amp; regret at last, after having caused much that is painful
                    &amp; unpleasant through years that have past, however justifiable the
                    course pursued. I am very glad you like Mr Van Wyck-- There will always be some
                    disaffected ones in a congregation -- yet it is very unfortunate -- at least, so
                    it seems to us-- As to Mr. McClean's step, if only proven that his
                    Presbyterianism was not <hi rend="underline">very deep</hi>, &amp; such are
                    never a very great loss. Tell Aunt I intended to address this letter to her, but
                    did not think of it when I commenced-- We wish we could meet with <orig
                        reg="someone">some one</orig> going over at Christmas to send your <orig
                        reg="father">Father</orig> some <orig reg="jelly">Jelly</orig>-- All join me
                    in much love to you, Uncle &amp; Aunt with all friends.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours ever <abbr expan="affectionately">affecty</abbr></salute>
                    <signed>E</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">Accept the compliments of the season-- We regret so much
                        you cannot be with us at Christmas -- </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
