<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F8539"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F8539">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: E. to H. G. McPherson, October 21,
                    1858</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county e to h g mcpherson, october 21 1858</title>
        <author>E.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F8539</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501721</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: E. to H. G. McPherson, October 21, 1858</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county e to h g mcpherson, october 21 1858</title>
            <author>E.</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: E. to H. G. McPherson, 21 October
                            1858, Library of Congress, Edward McPherson Papers, Box 47, Folder
                        1858</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1858-10-21">1858-10-21</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Death/Casualties, Family, Home Front, National Government, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-07">July 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F8539T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>E. writes to her aunt, Edward McPherson's mother, congratulating her on Edward's
                    election to Congress. She also gives a general report of their circle of friends
                    including Lizzie Law, Nannie, and Mr. Page, and the bad health of Dr. Tyler.
                </p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
              

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1858-10-21"><abbr expan="October">Oct</abbr> 21<hi rend="super"
                                >st</hi>, 1858</date>
                        <name type="place">Frederick</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Aunt</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I returned home on Tuesday last from Baltimore when I received your last letter.
                    For some days before leaving there, I was not very well, or I should have
                    written to Ned to congratulate him on his Election -- it is not too late yet,
                    however &amp; we all beg he will accept our heartiest congratulations on
                    this great event -- I am quite uplifted at the idea of a <hi rend="underline"
                        >Member</hi> of <hi rend="underline">Congress</hi> in the family, &amp;
                    my being a <hi rend="underline">great Aunt</hi>. Cousin was still suffering with
                    her arm when I left. We both felt very much grieved that we missed seeing you
                    when in Baltimore. I had sent to Barnum's a short time before, thinking it was
                    about the time for your return. We are very glad to hear you are so much
                    improved by your visit to Old Point &amp; hope you will pass a comfortable
                    winter. <pb n="2"/>At any rate, we hope you will get to see us while you are
                    enjoying the benefit of it -- you find now by experience that you can bear
                    travelling. I had a letter from Lizzie Law from Marietta -- they were well
                    &amp; expected to leave in a few days. Why do they return to <abbr
                        expan="New">N.</abbr> York if Mr. M. has resigned his office? Thursday of
                    last week we spent at I. Stevenson's to have a jollification over Ned's
                    election, as he expected to hear certainly by that time, of the result -- but we
                    could hear nothing certain, so we rejoiced in anticipating. We found Mrs.
                        <unclear>Luann</unclear> there, &amp; Miss Nancy, the <hi
                        rend="underline">picture</hi> of <hi rend="underline">woe</hi> or <hi
                        rend="underline">dignity</hi>, I could scarcely decide which -- the girls
                    could not get over her looks &amp; manner. It was not so new to me. John
                    &amp; M are so kind &amp; hospitable, we enjoy a visit there very much.
                    Mary Emma &amp; Linnie Williams were in Baltimore a week or ten days, during
                    my stay there-- We passed some very pleasant time together, &amp; I have a
                    very pressing invitation to the wedding. I was very glad to hear through them of
                    Kate &amp; her little family. Nannie Page resides on the Track-- She is to
                    be in town soon, to remain <pb n="3"/>during Lucretia's absence. Nellie is
                    growing almost as fast as Miss Mary. I think she <orig reg="weighs">weigh</orig>
                    160 <abbr expan="pounds">lbs.</abbr>-- Mr. Tyler had made up his mind to try
                    Baltimore as his residence-- of course, we cannot go until he clears his way-
                    living is much more expensive there, than here. Whatever my own feelings may be,
                    I would not throw a straw in the way of his going wherever he may see an opening
                    for a better support for his family. I will not indulge in painful feelings
                    until the time arrives, when they are called for. Lizzie &amp; the babe were
                    well when we heard from them. She had had a good deal of experience already in
                    housekeeping, having had to do her own cooking for some days, but she continues
                    very cheerful &amp; does not complain in the least. I did not know of Mrs.
                    Wallace's death until I saw the Williams! Kitty forgot to tell me after you
                    wrote. I wrote to Mr. W. from <abbr expan="Baltimore">Balt.</abbr> &amp; had
                    a reply since my return. It is a very pretty letter. I do feel truly sorry for
                    him. I think he has made the wisest disposition of the children he could. Excuse
                    a short letter, I have to go down street to see some friends from the North. All
                    join me in much love to you &amp; Ned-- write soon --</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours <abbr expan="affectionately">affecty</abbr></salute>
                    <signed>E</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
