<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F8547"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="F8547">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: E. to Edward McPherson, August 11,
                    1859</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county e to edward mcpherson, august 11 1859</title>
        <author>E.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F8547</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501729</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: E. to Edward McPherson, August 11, 1859</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county e to edward mcpherson, august 11 1859</title>
            <author>E.</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: E. to Edward McPherson, 11 August
                            1859, Library of Congress, Edward McPherson Papers, Box 47, Folder
                        1859</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1859-08-11">1859-08-11</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties, Family, Home Front, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-07">July 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F8547T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>E. tells Edward that Lizzie is sick, that Dr. Ross died, and that Nannie and Mr.
                    Page plan to move to Louisiana. She also mentions the departure of Mr. Van Wycke
                    and the changes in Gettysburg.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
       

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1859-08-11"><abbr expan="August">Aug</abbr> 11<hi rend="super"
                                >th</hi>. 1859</date>
                        <name type="place">Frederick</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear <abbr expan="Edward">Edwd.</abbr></salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I have been wanting to write to you for some time, but until I received your
                    letter yesterday, was entirely ignorant of your whereabouts -- knowing you were
                    absent from Gettysburg, I took it for granted, you would write from whatever
                    place you remained, for any length of time, so waited from day to day, to learn
                    where you were &amp; what about. We rejoice to hear that you feel much
                    improved in health, but sorry, you still postpone your visit to us. I wrote to
                    E. Mchaffey immediately after getting her letter, in hopes, she would write to
                    me again, especially while you were away. We hope Lizzie's sickness is not of a
                    serious character. I should think she would feel Dr. Alexander's death very
                    deeply, for <pb n="2"/>several reasons, for in him she has lost a friend who
                    took a very deep interest in her. His loss to our Church especially, can
                    scarcely be estimated &amp; I know not how his place, to his immediate
                    charge, can ever be supplied. Yet, all things are possible to Him, who loves his
                    church infinitely more than we can do, &amp; I trust he will qualify <orig
                        reg="someone">some one</orig> for that important post. I suppose Mr. Van
                    Wycke has left Gettysburg by this time-- Have you anyone in view? We enjoyed
                    Kate's little visit to us very much, &amp; regret she could not remain
                    longer with us. On leaving, she promised to write in a few days &amp; let us
                    hear if she reached home safely, but not a line have we had from her. About two
                    weeks ago, we were agreeably surprised by Mr Tyler's return home, for the
                    remainder of the summer. Lizzie &amp; her little boy who had not been well
                    came with him -- they will leave in a few days. The house, we expect will not be
                    ready for us before <abbr expan="November">Nov.</abbr> so we shall not leave
                    this before that, I suppose. This is the first summer I have been at home <pb
                        n="3"/> for many years- &amp; now, that Mr Tyler is at home, I am very
                    anxious to go to Thorndale towards the last of this month or first of next, but
                    the old difficulty, of a way to get there, is always present, so, it will
                    probably not be accomplished. Nannie &amp; Mr Page are still here, but
                    really expect to go to Munroe, Louisiana the middle of next month, where Mr. P-
                    expects to take charge of a school, with many flattering inducements. It will be
                    quite an undertaking with a young child, but <orig reg="anything">any
                    thing</orig> is better than a state of absolute dependence. The family are well.
                    If I should ever see Gettysburg again it will be quite a new place to me. But
                    there are many &amp; sad changes <orig reg="everywhere">every where</orig>,
                    even here, it is very striking. It would have gratified me much to have seen the
                    Children once more. How is Mr Wallace now? We did hope E- &amp; Mr Mchaffey
                    would have paid us a visit before they went to Old Point &amp; wrote to urge
                    it, but never heard afterwards. <pb n="4"/>I hope we will be in Georgetown,
                    ready to receive you, when you get there. Mittie &amp; Mr Cassin are there
                    now on a visit, but will soon return to Chicago. I hope you will excuse this
                    dull letter-- I am not well this morning &amp; it is very warm. Let us hear
                    from you soon again. I shall be very glad to have your lecture. All join me in
                    much love to you. What is Tresy going to do when you leave! Remember me to her.
                    Also to all friends.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours ever <abbr expan="affectionately">affect</abbr></salute>
                    <signed>E</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
