<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F8546"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="F8546">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: E. H. B. to Edward McPherson, May
                    31, 1859</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county e h b to edward mcpherson, may 31 1859</title>
        <author>E.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F8546</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501728</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: E. H. B. to Edward McPherson, May 31, 1859</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county e h b to edward mcpherson, may 31 1859</title>
            <author>E</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: E. H. B. to Edward McPherson, 31
                            May 1859, Library of Congress, Edward McPherson Papers, Box 47, Folder
                            1859</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1859-05-31">1859-05-31</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties, Economy, Family, Home Front,
                        Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-07">July 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F8546T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In writing to Edward McPherson, E. tells of Lizzie and her little boy's visit,
                    possible visits, and their future move to Washington. E. also announces the
                    birth of Nannie Page's daughter.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
         

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1859-05-31">May 31<hi rend="super">st</hi>, 1859</date>
                        <name type="place">Frederick</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear <abbr expan="Edward">Edw</abbr><hi rend="super">d</hi></salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I have been trying for two weeks to get a letter written to you, but never could
                    succeed in accomplishing it in time for the mail, &amp; in the evening, the
                    interruptions are more frequent &amp; my eyes not so well qualified to do
                    their part -- besides, all last week, I was suffering from styes. Lizzie
                    &amp; her boy have been here nearly four weeks &amp; that young
                    gentleman makes quite a sensation in this quiet, sober household. He has taken a
                    great fancy to his grandfather. &amp; the regard is mutual, for it is the
                    first child he even noticed. He is a very lovely, engaging little fellow
                    &amp; compels <orig reg="everyone">every one</orig> to notice him. Mr.
                    Williams is expected on Saturday to take them home on Monday. Mr Tyler goes with
                        <pb n="2"/> them- he has been detained here by settling &amp; arranging
                    unfinished business. It is now more than probable that you will find <hi
                        rend="underline">us</hi> settled in Georgetown when you get to Washington.
                    Mr. Tyler has nearly abandoned the idea of leaving us here, He thinks we are
                    both too delicate to be left alone, &amp; he would be always anxious,
                    besides many other things to be considered-- When Lizzie came she told of a
                    delightful house now going up, for rent, two doors from Dr. Grafton Tyler's,
                    &amp; the most desirable locality, in every way, in the place. When he goes
                    down, if rent &amp; all will suit, he will engage it &amp; if ready by
                    that time, we will go in the fall. There are two houses, alike &amp; he
                    desires you will tell Lizzie or <orig reg="Mr.">Mr</orig> Mchaffey about it, for
                    we would love dearly to have them near us &amp; <hi rend="underline"
                    >they</hi> would be so much nearer to Old Point. I suppose you have had your
                    sisters with you &amp; I wish I could have been there too, <orig
                        reg="though">tho'</orig> it would have been a painful pleasure. Your Cousin
                    C- says she is longing to see you, &amp; we have been looking for you so
                    often, that she fears you are going to disappoint us <pb n="3"/> after all. We
                    are truly sorry to hear you have been so unwell--do take care of yourself. I
                    think our air &amp; water will be of service to you. We expect Susan Boggs
                        <orig reg="tonight">to night</orig>, with Lucretia, who has been paying a
                    little visit to <abbr expan="Baltimore">Balt.</abbr> Nannie Page has a daughter
                    a few days old -- she is well -- Mary Newport is just able to sit up a little
                    while during the day. Mr Page is still there, gentleman at large &amp; it is
                    supposed will remain until the Dr. sends him off-for you would suppose he
                    expected business to come to him. Gettysburg must be improving rapidly -- it
                    will look like another place to me, if I ever see it again. As to our leaving
                    here, with all its tender &amp; sad associations, I do not yet realize it --
                    the satisfaction at not being left behind, with your Cousin so delicate
                    &amp; nervous, prevents any other feeling from agitating me just now. <orig
                        reg="Mr.">Mr</orig> Tyler has been brother &amp; <orig reg="everything"
                        >every thing</orig> to me &amp; I would not let him see any reluctance
                    on any part, to do, or go where he thinks it will be best for the interests of
                    all. Lizzie desires her love &amp; says when you <pb n="4"/> go down, she
                    means to take you round &amp; introduce you to some nice ladies. <orig
                        reg="Mr.">Mr</orig>
                    <unclear>F</unclear> too, intends to introduce you, if you have no objections to
                        <abbr expan="Professor">Prof.</abbr> Henry &amp; his family - his
                    daughters are worth knowing. I am truly sorry to hear Mr Wallace is so depressed
                    -- he is greatly to be pitied-- Why does John return home? He is entirely too
                    young for College- &amp; Sarah has a peculiar disposition which none but a
                    judicious mother, I think would know how to manage. They are the children of the
                    Covenant &amp; this is my strong hope for them. Expense haste &amp;
                    write soon to tell <del hand="h1">you</del> us, we may hope to see you before
                    long. All join me in love to you. Mine to all friends. I hope the Great Head of
                    the Church, will overrule all the commotions in your church for his glory
                    &amp; your ultimate good--</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Ever yours truly</salute>
                    <signed>EHB</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">I am glad to hear Maggie H. has married well</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
