<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F8567"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="F8567">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Kate Scott to Edward McPherson,
                    October 2, 1860</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county kate scott to edward mcpherson, october 2 1860</title>
        <author>Scott, Kate</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F8567</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501749</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Kate Scott to Edward McPherson, October 2, 1860</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county kate scott to edward mcpherson, october 2 1860</title>
            <author>Kate Scott</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Kate Scott to Edward McPherson, 2
                            October 1860, Library of Congress, Edward McPherson Papers, Box 47,
                            Folder 1860</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1860-10-02">1860-10-02</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>            
      <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Arts/Leisure, Death/Casualties, Family, Home Front, National Government,
                        Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-07">July 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F8567T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Edward McPherson's sister, Kate Scott, provides him with updates on travel plans,
                    health, and other news of friends and family.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
          

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1860-10-02">Oct 2<hi rend="super">nd</hi>/60.</date>
                        <name type="place">Hagerstown</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Brother.</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I <orig reg="received">recieved</orig> your letter a few days ago, and was very
                    glad to hear from you, it seemed very long indeed since I had heard <orig
                        reg="anything">any thing</orig> of you. I did not know where to address a
                    letter <del hand="h1">to</del> you were moving about all the time. I will be
                    glad when the election is over, we may then hope to hear from you oftener and
                    see you too. you must be sure and come over before you go to <abbr
                        expan="Washington">Wa--</abbr>. I had a letter from sister last week, they
                    are very pleasantly fixed in <abbr expan="Baltimore">Balt.</abbr> and insist
                    upon my making them a visit which I have some idea of doing, they are so very
                    pressing and John and Margaretta Stevenson sent me a very kind invitation
                    through her to <del hand="h1">make them</del> visit them. I have never been to
                        <abbr expan="Baltimore">Balt.</abbr> and have not been from home for some
                    time, I think I would <pb n="2"/>but the principal drawback is the expense, <del
                        hand="h1"/> have been at so much this summer I had thought I would be very
                    economical this winter, <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> building is nearly completed and a
                    tedious <unclear>time</unclear> we have had of it. I am sick of it and feel as
                    though I never wanted to see another workman <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> me, they are so
                    dilatory and disappoint so <unclear>much</unclear> I get out of all patience. I
                    think they are <unclear>worse</unclear> here than any place I know. I suppose it
                    is no use to ask you at this time to meet me in Baltimore, it would be so
                    pleasant all to be together. I may go next week and perhaps not until the week
                    following -- and it might all <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> in talk. We have no special news.
                    The Williams <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> spent Friday with us. Jinnie and Jane have
                        <unclear>been</unclear> there some weeks, the former expected to leave
                        <unclear>today</unclear>, she has a sweet little daughter, Agnes McDonell is
                    her name, Annie and <unclear>Mattie</unclear>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> grown to be very interesting girls, Annie particularly. She is
                    so lovely in disposition. Other <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> is <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> medicine in
                        <abbr expan="Philadelphia">Phil<hi rend="super">a</hi></abbr>.</p>

                <p><unclear>Lizzie</unclear> must have had a dull and sad visit to <abbr
                        expan="Gettysburg">G--.</abbr>
                    <unclear>Not</unclear> one of the family to meet her. I often think <del
                        hand="h1"/> the many changes that <orig reg="have">has</orig> taken place
                    there. <pb n="3"/>I thought I would like to go over this fall for a few days but
                    have given it up. <abbr expan="Baltimore">Balt.</abbr> is as much as I can get
                    through with. The children are well and grown very much. I am sure you would not
                    know Norman, he is such a big fellow. Lillie is learning very fast- and I think
                    is the smartest of the number, she is uncommonly fond of books, and never idle.
                    Mrs. Dunlap is going South to spend the winter, her son is with his Uncle in
                    Misissippi and is very anxious she should come to see him we will all miss her
                    very much. <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> go to <abbr expan="Baltimore">Balt.</abbr> in
                    company with her, she is going with a gentleman from there. write soon again.
                        <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> wish you were done with politics, I think you will wear
                    yourself out we have never yet heard who your opponent is. I suppose you think
                    we take very little interest in Pennsylvania politics, you are all on the wrong
                    side for us. Republicans <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> go down in Maryland. Dr
                    is well and very busy riding all day, did not get home until five O'clock this
                    eve, he has only <unclear>dined</unclear> once with us in the last ten days. I
                    often wonder how he stands it it is so fatiguing, all send their love. <orig
                        reg="Love">love</orig> to Aunt and all other friends. How is Mrs.
                        <unclear>Gilliland</unclear>. I heard she was very ill some time ago <pb
                        n="4"/>Mr. Taylor told me, he had just been there, he is here quite often
                    and is interested in Western Maryland Rail Road. I met him at Mr. Lehley's I was
                    very sorry to hear of Miss Maria's death. How much she must be missed in the
                    family, I imagine Gettysburg looks quite grand lighted with gas, it is certainly
                    a great improvement-- I must close with the hope of hearing from you soon</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>yours affectionately</salute>
                    <signed>Kate -</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
