<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F8575"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F8575">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Alexander K. McClure to Thaddeus
                    Stevens, January 7, 1861</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county alexander k mcclure to thaddeus stevens, january 7 1861</title>
        <author>McClure, Alexander K.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F8575</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501757</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Alexander K. McClure to Thaddeus Stevens, January 7,
                            1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county alexander k mcclure to thaddeus stevens, january 7 1861</title>
            <author>McClure, Alexander K.</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Alexander K. McClure to Thaddeus
                            Stevens, 7 January 1861, Library of Congress, Thaddeus Stevens Compiled
                            Collections, Reel 1, Frame 1118</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-01-07">1861-01-07</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>National Government, State Government</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-06">June 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F8575T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Alexander K. McClure writes Thaddeus Stevens concerning Governor Curtin's
                    possible appointments, including Slifer as Secretary. McClure also mentions that
                    Curtin does not want Cameron in Lincoln's cabinet and that Stevens' Senatorial
                    election is secure.</p>
            </div1>

        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <hi rend="underline">Private</hi>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-01-07"><abbr expan="January">Jn</abbr> 7<hi rend="super">th</hi></date>
                        <name type="place">Chambersburg,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute><orig reg="Dear Sir">DSir</orig> --</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>The conference with Curtin at <abbr expan="Philadelphia">Phila</abbr> developed
                    little beyond demonstrating that he was so <unclear>complicated</unclear> with
                    nearly everybody that he could not move. I finally got him to settle down on
                    Slifer for <abbr expan="Secretary">Secy</abbr> provided I could get a
                    declination from Jordan, to <unclear>show</unclear> me he has <hi
                        rend="underline">positively promised</hi> the <abbr expan="Attorney"
                    >Atty</abbr> Generalship. I accomplished Jordan's withdrawal <orig reg="today"
                        >to-day</orig> &amp; hope that so much is settled. I shall not feel sure
                    of it, however, until Slifer is formally notified &amp; the fact published.
                    Slifer will do well-- indeed under all the circumstances he is the best man in
                    the place. It will be a terrible blow <pb n="2"/> to Cameron, and yet he cannot
                    make men inform the appointment.</p>

                <p>As to <abbr expan="Attorney">Atty</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> the chief difficulty is that Curtin has
                    promised it, to not less than six gentlemen-- or at least they consider it
                    promised to them, and as the law now stands he can appoint but one, If Finney
                    were eligible, he would be the man, but he is not.</p>

                <p>Curtin assured Mann &amp; myself that if it became necessary to keep Cameron
                    out of the Cabinet, for him to write Lincoln protesting against it, he would do
                    so. He has had no communication with Lincoln, but I put him in the way of direct
                    communication with him, &amp; in a manner that cannot fail to be very
                    gratifying to Lincoln.</p>

                <pb n="3"/>

                <p>The electors were afraid to attempt to recommend Cameron. Several were spoiling
                    for a fight; but the Cameron men saw it would not do, &amp; they wished to
                    recommend no one.</p>

                <p>Should I write Lincoln on the subject? I have thought much about it, &amp;
                    scarcely know what to do. I have not written him since the election, &amp;
                    never as to men on this State. <orig reg="Should">Shuld</orig> I do or, I would
                    write in moderation, conceding to Cameron &amp; his friends all they are
                    entitled to, but protesting decidedly against his appointment because of the
                    great wrong it would do the party in the State, not only morally, but in the
                        <unclear>disputation</unclear> of patronage. Had I best do so or not?</p>

                <pb n="4"/>
                <p> You are not considered formidable for Senator, &amp; therein is the only
                    chance you have. If we shall have a row, some one, like yourself who has excited
                    no special animosities in the contest, may be chosen, I need not say that a
                    whenever a awful purpose either to you or the party can be served. I will be
                    with you heart &amp; soul, knowing well as you do that I am committed to a
                        <hi rend="underline">policy</hi> in the election of Senator; I need hardly
                    say that I have not so <unclear>satisfied</unclear> that purpose as to give a
                    pledge to any one. Judging from the present aspect of affairs,
                    <unclear>Cameron</unclear> could be elected more easily than any one else, but I
                    am not fully satisfied that he has not bowed at the <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> shrine. If
                        <abbr expan="not">n.</abbr> he will go overboard. He has been trying hard to
                    convince me that he is right, but I am not yet convinced. Wilmot is for Cameron
                    for Cabinet, at least Meyer, who was sent in to see me, <hi rend="underline"
                        >could</hi> give me no sort of assurance to the contrary.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours</salute>
                    <signed>AKMcClure</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
