<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F8573"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F8573">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: E. to Edward McPherson, May 3, 1859</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county e to edward mcpherson, may 3 1859</title>
        <author>E.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F8573</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501755</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: E. to Edward McPherson, May 3, 1859</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county e to edward mcpherson, may 3 1859</title>
            <author>E.</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>5 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: E. to Edward McPherson, 3 May
                            1859, Library of Congress, Edward McPherson Papers, Box 47, Folder
                        1859</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1859-05-03">1859-05-03</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties, Economy, Family, Home Front,
                        National Government, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-07">July 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F8573T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>E. discusses friends and the Reverend Van Wycke. She also mentions the future
                    move of the Tylers and herself to Washington. She gives McPherson the requested
                    date of her mother's death.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
           

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1859-05-03">May 3<hi rend="super">rd</hi>, 1859</date>
                        <name type="place">Frederick</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear <abbr expan="Edward">Edwd</abbr></salute>
                </opener>

                <p>After receiving your last welcome letter, I was not very well &amp; for that
                    reason concluded to delay writing for a little while, then last week, Cousin
                    Susan B- &amp; my friend Miss Coulson came &amp; spent the week with
                    us-- Of course, my time was entirely devoted to them. Cousin had so recently
                    passed through another great sorrow, that all at home thought a little change
                    would be beneficial, &amp; as Miss C, who is a special friend of hers, was
                    coming, they persuaded her into it &amp; we were very glad to have her come,
                    &amp; she appeared to enjoy it too -- yet it was her greatest pleasure to
                    talk of her precious child, to those who loved her as we all did. It rained the
                    greater part <pb n="2"/>of the week they were here, which I regretted the more,
                    as it was Miss C's first visit, however as she is a very intelligent woman, she
                    enjoyed talking with Mr Tyler on subjects quite too deep for me. He is yet with
                    us, owing to his health, he had been unusually unwell for some weeks, though he
                    goes about as though nothing was the matter -- and as this is not the season for
                    business in Washington, he thinks it best to remain quietly here until he feels
                    better As we are now expecting Lizzie every day, he will wait to see her. He
                    cannot tell what arrangements he will make about <hi rend="underline">us</hi>,
                    until he gets there himself, so that we feel somewhat unsettled. We had hoped to
                    see you before this, &amp; I feel as if this letter may find you gone to
                    Hagerstown. I am glad to hear, there is, at least a suspension of hostilities in
                    your church. Did I not understand you to say Mr Van Wycke was going to leave?
                    But in the account of the meeting of Carlisle Presbytery I should judge he had
                    no idea of it. I really would think more <pb n="3"/>of him, were he to do so
                    &amp; I should think his best friends would feel in the same way. However,
                    as I am not acquainted with all the circumstances, I must not judge rashly.
                    Which of the Elders were so violent in their opposition? Well my greatest
                    comfort under all such discouraging events is, that "The Lord reigneth"
                    &amp; loveth his church infinitely more than we can possibly do, &amp; I
                    trust will overrule all for his own glory &amp; the future good of your
                    church. I like to see a person uphold his pastor in times of difficulty, when it
                    can be done without a sacrifice of principle or duty. And we too often find that
                    these troubles arise from personal feeling caused by some imaginary affront. We
                    had a letter from Lizzie Howe about two weeks ago &amp; were surprised to
                    find her Mother had been with her for five weeks, &amp; not well at the time
                    she wrote. I suppose by this time she had returned to <abbr expan="New"
                    >N.</abbr> York. I cannot understand why they remain there, as E- dislikes it so
                    much &amp; Mr M. has resigned his situation. <pb n="4"/>I was at <abbr
                        expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> McPherson's yesterday. All were well except him,
                    &amp; he has been quite sick &amp; is still in his room. Fanny returned
                    home on <abbr expan="Saturday">Sat.</abbr> after an absence of three months. I
                    saw no one but Mrs. <abbr expan="McPherson">McP</abbr>- Annie was out, &amp;
                    I think you must be a prime <orig reg="favorite">favourite</orig>, as she always
                    talks so much about you in a way, that she is not apt to do, of others, for she
                    is generally reserved in that respect, so that I think you ought to feel highly
                    complimented. I should like very much to pay you a visit this summer &amp; I
                    want to go to Thorndale also, if possible -- but I cannot say decidedly, until I
                    know more of our plans. When you get here, we will talk more about it. Mary
                    Newport is still in bed -- her general health is better, but she has an ulcer
                    that covers the whole stomach &amp; it is a very deep sore, so you may
                    imagine the conditions of one so large &amp; unwieldy as she is-- Poor
                    Lucretia had a hard time of it indeed I do not know what they would do without
                    her. Mr P- is still there, waiting contentedly for business to <hi
                        rend="underline">come</hi> to him. We are very sorry to hear you are not
                    well yourself-- I think if you come &amp; breathe our mountain air &amp;
                    drink our mountain water, you will be better. I rejoice to hear <orig
                        reg="favorable">favourable</orig> accounts of Sarah &amp; John.</p>

                <pb n="5"/>

                <p>I was very near closing, without giving you the information you desired. Mother
                    died last day of <abbr expan="December">Dec.</abbr> 1845- thirteen years ago
                    last <abbr expan="December">Dec.</abbr></p>

                <p>As I did not exactly understand how to direct, I will wait until I hear from you
                    again</p>

                <pb n="1"/>

                <p>[At the top of the first page] I wish you could bring Sarah to see us in some of
                    her vacations. My love to all friends-- Remember me to Tresy-- I suppose she has
                    done all her housecleaning ask her if she does not wish to see me once more? All
                    join me in much love to you. Come soon-</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>yours <abbr expan="affectionately">affecty</abbr></salute>
                    <signed>E</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">I ought to <orig reg="favor">favour</orig> you more than
                        any of my correspondents, as your letters will <hi rend="underline">cost
                            nothing</hi></seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
