<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F8570"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F8570">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: John B. McPherson to Edward
                    McPherson, November 9, 1860</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county john b mcpherson to edward mcpherson, november 9 1860</title>
        <author>McPherson, John B.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F8570</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501752</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: John B. McPherson to Edward McPherson, November 9,
                            1860</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county john b mcpherson to edward mcpherson, november 9 1860</title>
            <author>John B. McPherson</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: John B. McPherson to Edward
                            McPherson, 9 November 1860, Library of Congress, Edward McPherson
                            Papers, Box 47, Folder 1860</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1860-11-09">1860-11-09</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Arts/Leisure, Family, Home Front, National Government, State
                        Government</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-07">July 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F8570T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>John B. McPherson writes to his uncle, Edward McPherson, about politics and local
                    events in Sidney, Ohio, including hunting and school.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
         

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1860-11-09"><abbr expan="November">Nov</abbr> 9, 1860</date>
                        <name type="place">Sidney</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Uncle,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I have often reproached myself for not writing before, but I put it off from day
                    to day until now. Indeed, I have had plenty of time, but had fallen into the
                    habit of Procrastination, and therefore it has remained until to day. Politics
                    appears to be the engrossing topic out here nowadays even after the election.
                    The Republicans however are confident of success and with good reason. The
                    county here has been for years overwhelmingly Democratic, always electing the
                    full unscratched Democratic ticket until this year, when the Republicans elected
                    their candidates for Clerk of the Court and Mayor. This is not much but speaks
                    well for the success of the party here. It is not known yet how the county has
                    voted, too much attention being paid to the returns from the State and Union.
                    One thing is certain, the Republican gain is great, being at least <pb n="2"/>
                    80 or 100. I congratulate you on your election again. I did not know that you
                    were a candidate until lately, when Mr. Hale, a leading lawyer and Republican,
                    asked me if I was <del hand="h1">your</del> a relative of yours. I told him, I
                    was. He then informed me of your election. The Wide Awakes come out on Thursday
                    night provided the more certain election returns prove favorable. The Never
                    Sleeps (Douglas Democrat) have "fizzled". They attempted to have a grand parade
                    last Saturday night, with their paper torches, but "their game was played out".
                    The best joke that has been known here lately (it <orig reg="isn't">isnt</orig>
                    much of a joke, either) is the attempt of the Democratic editor, Mr
                        <unclear>Ragan</unclear>, to vote at the October elections, whilst he was
                    under the requisite age. And then, "although under the full belief and
                    conviction that he was of age, yet he considered it best to write to his father
                    to ask him how old he was". He an editor, and didn't know his own age! But I
                    have often heard that politics is a very dangerous subject for a "Young America"
                    to meddle with. If that be true, I am <hi rend="underline">afraid</hi> I am
                    pretty far gone. But lest it might lead to evil, I will close this subject by
                    saying "Hurrah for Lincoln". The foundry here was burnt down about three or four
                    weeks ago. Nothing was saved and no insurance. The fire was first observed by
                    the passengers of the eastern train. The cars were stopped and the alarm given,
                    but before enough people had arrived to check the flames, they had acquired
                    considerable headway and all that could be done was to save the adjacent shops
                    and buildings. A few more such fires and I think that the need of a fire engine
                    will be felt &amp; <pb n="3"/> one procured. The weather now is very
                    inclement. It has snowed a little twice. It is raining now with every prospect
                    of continuing. Game of all kinds is very plenty. Squirrels, pheasants, quails,
                    wild ducks and geese, wild turkeys, and even deer at a distance of two or three
                    miles, can easily be procured. For see, the distance is not more than 10 or 15
                    miles up north. I <del hand="h1">am</del> was out hunting last Saturday, and
                    killed in a short time at a stream, not far from Sidney a duck and about a dozen
                    other <orig reg="edible">eatable</orig> birds called here yellow hammers. I have
                    never seen any elsewhere. We have a new teacher in our department, Mr. McFarlan,
                    this term. He is a <hi rend="underline">splendid</hi> teacher and knows his
                    business well. Some other time I will <hi rend="underline">write</hi> more about
                    him. I am almost ashamed, after my long silence to request you to answer my
                    letter soon, but I will.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your affectionate nephew</salute>
                    <signed>John B McPherson.</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">P. S. Whenever you leave Gettysburg for any length of
                        time, please notify me, that I may know where to direct my
                        letters.<lb/>John.</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
