<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="FD4507"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="FD4507"> 
<teiHeader type="migrated"> 

    <fileDesc> 
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Diary of Tynes, Achilles James (1864)</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county diary of tynes, achilles james 1864</title>
        <author>Tynes, Achilles</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt> 
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp> 
          <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name> 
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp> 
          <name>Heather Weidner, Virginia Center for Digital History</name> 
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt> 

      <extent>
        <num type="kilobytes"> 13 kilobytes</num>
      </extent> 
      <publicationStmt> 
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher> 
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace> 

        <idno type="VCDH">FD4507</idno> 

        <!--
<availability> 
<p>Publicly accessible </p> 
<p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p> 
<p>copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p> 
</availability>
--> 
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2002">2002</date> 
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500361</idno>
      </publicationStmt> 
      <seriesStmt> 
        <p>Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt> 
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt> 

      <sourceDesc> 
        <biblFull> 
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Diary of Tynes, Achilles James</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county diary of tynes, achilles james</title>
            <author>Tynes, Achilles James</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt> 
          <editionStmt> 
            <p> </p> 
          </editionStmt> 
          <extent>1 pages</extent> 
          <publicationStmt> 
            <publisher/> 
            <pubPlace/> 
            <date value=""/> 
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Achilles James Tynes Papers (#1874) Southern Historical Collection, Manuscripts Department, Wilson Library, The University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</idno> 
          </publicationStmt> 
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt> 
          <notesStmt> 
            <note/>
          </notesStmt> 
        </biblFull> 
      </sourceDesc> 
    </fileDesc> 

    <profileDesc> 
      <creation>
        <dateRange from="1864-07-29" to="1864-08-08">1864-07-29; 1864-08-08</dateRange>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage> 
      <textClass> 
        <keywords> 
          <term>Battle Description, Camp Life, Death / Casualties, Military Authority, Military Strategy,Troop Movement</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords> 
      </textClass> 
    </profileDesc> 

    <revisionDesc> 
      <change> 
        <date value="2006-05">May 2006 </date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Heather Weidner</name>
        </respStmt> 
        <item>Item proofread against original; corrections made.</item> 
      </change> 
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc> 
  </teiHeader> 

<text id="FD4507T">

<front id="d2">
<div1 type="summary" id="d3">
<p>Achilles Tynes writes a running letter to Hattie, his wife or sweetheart.  He describes the burning of Chambersburg and small, subsequent skirmishes.  He is critical of his commanding officers and the men with whom he is working.</p>
<p></p> 
</div1> 
</front>

<body id="d4">

<div1 type="entry" id="d5">
<p>29 July 1864<lb/>

Crossed the river at the McCoys Ferry. Took the road via Clear Spring; reached Mercersburg at six P.M.; found all horses, good <abbr expan="etcetera">&amp;c</abbr> run off or hidden. Had a slight skirmish with about 150 <abbr expan="cavalry">cav.</abbr> who fled. Will leave here tonight, route not yet designated. At Mercersburg the proprietorship of the old Mansion house gave us supper of beefsteak, butter, coffee, milk, bread and <unclear>Comet.</unclear> I champagne - was tolerably merry. </p><lb/>

<p> At dark moved east upon Chambersburg. Marched all night - skirmishing. Appeared before the place about 4 A.M. Slight resistance. At half past 5 o'clock we entered the town. Levied a contribution of 100,000 Gold or 500,000 <abbr expan="Green Backs">G. Backs</abbr> or in case of failure the town would be burnt. Three hours run out. City fired about noon. Saddest spectacle I ever witnessed to see the women and children.  This inaugurates a terrible system of retalliation, devastation and rapine. From <abbr expan="Chambersburg">C.</abbr> took the great Pittsburg <abbr expan="Road">R.</abbr> to McConnellsburg across the <abbr expan="Mountain">Mt.</abbr> Reached that place at dark. Rested all night.</p><lb/>

<p>Set off at sunrise, taking the road to Hancock, on the Potomac <abbr expan="River">R</abbr> &amp; <abbr expan="Baltimore and Ohio Railroad">B&amp;O RR</abbr> - reached about 4 P.M. Made a levy on the town of five thousand rations and 30,000 dollars, to be paid in 4 hours. Averill came up ere the time expired. Had a little bout with him, lasting until nearly sundown, when we left him and set off for Cumberland across the Allegheny range and after one of the most fatiguing marches of nearly <orig reg="all night">allnight</orig> and a part of today (<hi rend="underline">first</hi> of August, I think it is) I have ever endured and under one of the hottest suns I ever felt, reached the vicinity of this place, at about 3 P.M., on the Great National Pike. We found the enemy very strongly posted upon a range of hills some 2 miles East of the town when a severe artillery duel was commenced, mingled occasionally with musketry at long range. <abbr expan="It is">'Tis</abbr> just now sunset and as yet neither party seems to have gained any real advantage. The casualties on our side are very slight, only about two or three men slightly hurt and two horses killed and two or three wounded. Just now there is a lull. What <abbr expan="Generals">Genls</abbr> <abbr expan="McCausland">McC.</abbr> &amp; <abbr expan="Johnson">J.</abbr> are going to do I can't say. The enemy's force is unknown but from the best data is supposed to be from 2400 to 3000. Their artillery practice is tolerable. This county is a perfect succession of mountains. I would give more than you could imagine to be by Hattie's side this evening.</p><lb/>

<p><hi rend="underline"><abbr expan="August">Aug.</abbr> 2nd.</hi> <hi rend="underline">Old Tavern Potomac River.</hi> Fell back from Cumberland during the night. A toilsome, tedious march. Find the enemy here. The Bridges across the Canal burned and the Ford over the river guarded. Enemy in front and rear and on both flanks. Prospects quite gloomy for escape. Wish I was by your side. Construct a pontoon across the canal and make a road down to it. As part of the <abbr expan="command">comd.</abbr> fighting an ironclad <abbr expan="Railroad">RR</abbr> train all the time as well as a block house guarding the river ford. The canal is to be crossed first, then an island, then the river on the <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> side of which is the <abbr expan="Railroad">RR</abbr> and Blockhouse. Kelly coming down from Cumberland by rail and by the road we had marched and Averill coming up the tow-path and the main and the main road from Hancock. All this was but partially seen in the early dawn and through a thick fog and to add to the interest of the whole we had the dull heavy boom of the cannon and the whizzing sound of bursting shells from the Iron clads and the dull thud of rifles whose sound was deadened by the dense atmosphere. This was rather dispiriting to say the least of it, to worn-out and starved-out men, but we must get out of this and at it we went. I can give you no particulars here. I shall be one of the party who crosses to the old <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, if there is any, and as McCausland's <abbr expan="Brigade">Brigd</abbr> seems to be wasting time to construct a bridge I will go down where Johnson is fighting to join a bridge across the canal and find the passage of the river and if anybody crosses I and Clark have determined to be of the party. <abbr expan="It is">'Tis</abbr> now light. One piece of the Baltimore Light artillery is in position and opens on the Iron Clad Train. Eureka, the very first shot at a distance of 800 yards goes crashing right in the Boiler of the Engine and she is helpless.</p><lb/>

<p><hi rend="underline">At 5 o'clock A.M.</hi> You ought to see the Yanks leave the train! <hi rend="underline">Shade of Cicero</hi>, how they run as the shells burst around them! I ought to have said that Sweeny's and Dun's Battalions charged them on the Island simultaneously with the opening of the gun and drowned them. This gives us the island. Another train comes in sight but seeing the fate of the Ironclad runs away. We commence pouring across the river, but as we ascend the bank a withering fire from the Fort drives us under cover of the bank. We flank them quickly, under cover, bring a piece across, unlimber, shove it to the top of the bank, showing its frowning mouth to the enemy about two hundred <abbr expan="yards">yds</abbr> distant. They shoot but hurt nobody. A flag is sent in. They meet it and surrender at once (the <abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> having already been deserted by all but 81 men) thus relieving us of a very difficult position. And here let me say that it is about the first time I felt like we were about to be caught.</p><lb/>

<p><hi rend="underline">8 A.M.</hi> We have burned and destroyed everything and are fast setting off for Romney, Hampshire <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr>, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></p><lb/>

<p><hi rend="underline">6 P.M.</hi> Have just gone into camp. The prospect here is gloomy for hungry men, especially for me. I am worn out and unwell and my horse has been broken down for several days. I left Maud with Spence, riding an old broken down mare of his to exchange off for a better one in <abbr expan="Pennsylvania">Pa.</abbr> but have had no chance as our coming has been anticipated. We leave here day after tomorrow for Moorfield, Hardy <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr>, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>.</p><lb/>

<p><hi rend="underline"><abbr expan="August">Aug.</abbr> 3rd. 3 P.M.</hi> Got into a scrape today. Johnson's CS had gone in the night and put guards at two mills we had grinding for the <abbr expan="command">comd.</abbr>, one of which was for <hi rend="underline">my</hi> <abbr expan="Brigade">Brigd</abbr>. I sent guards next morning and retook one of them which was grinding for me, and of course took what flour was ground. His C.S. complained and he addressed a very impertinent letter to <hi rend="underline"><abbr expan="McCausland">McC.</abbr></hi>, who is in command of the whole, asking that I be put under close arrest until a court martial commits to me the punishment I deserve for my outrageous and lawless conduct. <abbr expan="McCausland">McC.</abbr> sent for me, handed me Bradley's letter and asked me the particulars. I told him and he merely laughed; and that is all I have heard of it. For several days I have noticed that there is a want of cordial cooperation between our <abbr expan="Generals">Genls.</abbr> I think Johnson is jealous and <hi rend="underline"><abbr expan="McCausland">McC.</abbr> selfish</hi>. Something will happen to bring them to their senses.</p><lb/>

<p><hi rend="underline"><abbr expan="August">Aug.</abbr> 5th.</hi> We camp tonight here three to 5 miles <abbr expan="North West">NW</abbr> of Romney. Shall move upon New Creek on the River and <abbr expan="Railroad">RR</abbr> tomorrow at daylight. <hi rend="underline">Near Moorfield, <abbr expan="August">Aug.</abbr> 6.</hi> Our <abbr expan="Brigade">Brigd</abbr> leading the advance reached New Creek (the strongest place along this road from Parkersburg to Harpers Ferry) <hi rend="underline">about one P.M. 6th</hi>, and attacked the fortifications at once upon the left for the purpose of capturing and holding an high hill that seems to command their main and central work and the <abbr expan="Railroad">RR</abbr> below as well as the Maryland <orig reg="cliffs">clifts</orig>. There were wide bottoms in front swept every inch by their artillery. Across these fields, in the corn and behind the fences, the 14th was deployed as skirmishers, two cos. only holding their ridges on the left (our left) until Johnson should come up. The 22nd, 17th and 16th under <abbr expan="Lieutenant Colonel">Lt.Col.</abbr> Radford, <abbr expan="Commanding">Comdg.</abbr> 22d, and <abbr expan="Major">Maj</abbr>. Nounan 16th, and <abbr expan="Captain">Capt</abbr>, Crawford the 17th - the whole under Radford - proceeded to carry the height mentioned and right gallantly did they do so, against a large force and up an almost perpendicular ascent. You will remember that all this was on our right. Johnson was to come up on the left and carry a high ridge, on the right extremity of which the Fort was situated, but owing to some unaccountable and as yet unexplained reason he failed to come up until about 4 o'clock when he was so slow in bringing his men in on the ground assigned him that all our work was for nothing and we had the mortification to withdraw with severe loss from the field. I told you that something would happen. We returned to this place and from the looks of the clouds we will get a perfect drowning tonight.</p><lb/> 

<p><hi rend="underline">Aug. 8th.</hi> It has come. I was almost drowned last night. Our <abbr expan="Brigade">Brigd.</abbr> is camped on the South and <abbr expan="Johnson's">J's</abbr> on the <abbr expan="North">N.</abbr> side of the <abbr expan="South">S.</abbr> branch of the Potomac. This is a beautiful country. It seems that our officers mean to rest here. From the careless manner about camp it seems that they think no enemy is near.</p><lb/>

<p>The difficulty seems, whatever the cause, to be getting more serious between our bridgadiers. It will end disastrously I fear. We have marching orders for daylight tomorrow on the Winchester Road from this place. I presume for the present the raid is over and if God will forgive me for this I shall try and keep out of all future raids under the same officers for let me tell you darling this command under the present management is as far superior in all the characteristics that make up a band of robbers and bandits to Averill's as <abbr expan="it is">'tis</abbr> possible for any set to be. <abbr expan="It is">'Tis</abbr> the first and I hope it will be the last time I shall have to blush for <abbr expan="Confederate States">CS</abbr> soldiers.</p><lb/>

<p>Adieu for tonight dear.</p>

</div1>
</body>
</text>
</TEI.2>