<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="FD4501"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="FD4501">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Diary of J. Kelly Bennette, (1864)</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county diary of j kelly bennette, 1864</title>
        <author>Bennette, J. Kelly</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Heather Weidner, Virginia Center for Digital History</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>
        <num type="kilobytes"> 9 kilobytes</num>
      </extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">FD4501</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
                    Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500355</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>: Diary of Bennette, J. Kelly</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">diary of bennette, j kelly</title>
            <author>Bennette, J. Kelly</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p> </p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>8 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: J. Kelly Bennette Papers #886,
                            Southern Historical Collection, Manuscripts Department, Wilson Library,
                            The University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Southern Historical Collection, Wilson Library, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-07-30">1864-07-30</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Women, Troop Movement, Military Stategy</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2006-05">May 2006</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Heather Weidner</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="FD4501T">

        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>J. Kelly Bennette writes in his diary about the burning of Chambersburg and
                    describes the different attitudes in the armies toward private property, women,
                    and children.</p>
                <p/>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
<div1 type="entry" id="d5">

            <p>30th. Scarcely had we time for our hungry horses to satisfy their hunger on
                Pennsylvania corn &amp; we <pb n="2"/> to snatch a hasty bite for ourselves when
                the bugle sounded "to horse" &amp; we are again on the dusty road. We have been
                driving before us all day a small body of yankees &amp; tonight concealed by the
                darkness they stop at every turn in the road &amp; fire on our advance guard
                &amp; although they did no hurt to anyone yet it made it very unpleasant to the
                advance guard. Arrived at within a mile of Chambersburg a little before day light.
                The first thing I knew of being in its vicinity was a dull "Boom"! &amp; a
                charge of grape came flying over us like a flock of pigeons. At this place the 36th
                    <abbr expan="Battalion">Batt</abbr> lost another man killed. The yankees moved
                their position &amp; we went into line of battle &amp; waited for the other
                    <pb n="3"/>
                <abbr expan="Brigade">Brig.</abbr> to come up. While waiting I went to sleep
                &amp; when I awoke the town was in our hands &amp; on fire. A levy was made
                on the town <abbr expan="through">thro'</abbr>
                <abbr expan="General McCauseland">Gen McC.</abbr> by order of <abbr expan="General"
                    >Gen.</abbr> Early for $100,000 in specie of 500,000 in <abbr
                    expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> currency toward paying for private property
                burned by Hunter. The Mayor being absent the demand was made known to fifteen of the
                most prominent citizens who replied that we as rebels against the General Government
                had no right to make such a demand; and moreover that <abbr expan="General"
                >Gen.</abbr> Averill had telegraphed that he would be there in time to save them.
                    <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> McCauseland immedi[ately] ordered the
                destruction of the town giving the women &amp; children two hours to leave
                &amp; remove what they could <pb n="4"/> but many of them made no improvement of
                the time thus afforded &amp; when our men urged them to save what they could
                they replied that we dared not burn it, nor would they believe that <abbr
                    expan="General McCauseland">Gen. McC.</abbr> meant what he said 'till the fire
                was in their homes.</p>

            <p>The burning of Chambersburg was generally condemned by our <abbr expan="Regiment"
                    >Regt.</abbr>
                <hi rend="underline">at first</hi> when all the sympathies were all aroused, but
                when reason had time to regain her seat I believe that they all thought as I thought
                at first; that it was Justice &amp; Justice tempered with Mercy. That <hi
                    rend="underline">burning per se</hi> is wrong no one can deny; and the bare idea
                of turning out of doors upon the cold charities of the world unprotected women
                &amp; unoffending children is sufficient to cause the feelings to rebel. But
                there may be circumstances under which it is <pb n="5"/> not only <hi
                    rend="underline">justifiable</hi> but becomes a duty, - stern it is true but
                nevertheless binding. <abbr expan="Through">Thru</abbr> several times since the
                beginning of this war we have had opportunities of laying waste northern cities
                &amp; private property generally. But instead of this we have pursued toward
                them a course uniformally conciliatory hoping by this means to set the war on a
                civilized footing &amp; thus protect our defenceless ones at home. Orders were
                issued that private property must be respected as we came not to pillage &amp;
                destroy but to conquer a Peace. Not what has been the consiquence of this
                conciliatory policy? From Princeton for 30 miles toward Raleigh <abbr
                    expan="Court House">C. H.</abbr> you do not see a house, the blackened <pb n="6"
                /> chimnies alone marking where once the farm-house stood. From Memphis Norfolk
                &amp; <abbr expan="New">N.</abbr> Orleans women without number have been sent
                    <abbr expan="through">thro'</abbr> the lines not knowing where they were to find
                a home. Jackson <abbr expan="Mississippi">Miss.</abbr> Washington <abbr
                    expan="North Carolina">N.C.</abbr> Guyandotte <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>
                a large portion of Lexington Buchanon, Fredericksburg Wytheville <abbr
                    expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, Newbern <abbr expan="North Carolina">N.C.</abbr>
                Winchester <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> &amp; hundreds of other towns
                &amp; cities have been laid in ashes &amp; often not giving the women
                &amp; children five minutes notice. Private farm houses of which there are
                thousands are not mentioned. In Wytheville for instance when David St. Clair carried
                his sick child from his burning house &amp; took up its cloak to wrap about it
                he was cursed as a d--n'd <hi rend="underline">rebel</hi> &amp; bid to lay it
                down, &amp; as <pb n="7"/> he passed <abbr expan="through">thro'</abbr> he had
                to <hi rend="underline">steal from his own porch the sheep-skin on which his
                dog</hi> slept to shield his child from the cold night air. We are in this war to
                defend the <hi rend="underline">women</hi> - if we try one expedient &amp; it
                fails we are recreant to our duty if we persevere in that expedient instead of
                changing the prescription. Now everyone knows that the conciliatory policy has
                failed - utterly failed - &amp; we are driven nolens volens to the opposite mode
                of proceedure. Instead of snatching from the hands of the ladies what they had saved
                from their burning houses &amp; throwing it back into the flames as the yankees
                did in K. Valley, or stealing &amp; destroying it as they did Mrs. Anderson in
                the Valley of <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> our men could be seen all over the
                city <pb n="8"/> checking the fire or carrying trunks, bundles <abbr
                    expan="etcetera">&amp;c.</abbr> for the ladies. How beautiful the contrast!
                It must be acknowledged that there were some who having become drunk seemed to glory
                in spreading destruction but it must also be remembered that many of them have had
                strong provocation.</p>

            <p>Leave what remains of <abbr expan="Chambersburg">C.burg</abbr> &amp; retrace our
                steps through St. Thomas &amp; after a march of 31 <abbr expan="miles"
                >mls</abbr> find ourselves at McConelsburg <abbr expan="Pennsylvania">Penn.</abbr>
                where we go into camp. 1220+25+31=1276</p>

        </div1></body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
