<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="FD7001"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="FD7001">
  <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title id="VShadow" type="main">Franklin County: Diary of Eliza R. Stouffer (1863)</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county diary of eliza r stouffer 1863</title>
        <author>Stouffer, Eliza R.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Edsel Burdge, Jr., Shippensburg, Pennsylvania</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Jaime Henshaw, Virginia Center for Digital History, Virginia Center for Digital
            History</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>
        <num type="kilobytes"> 14 kilobytes</num>
      </extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">FD7001</idno>

        <!--
<availability> 
<p>Publicly accessible </p> 
<p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p> 
<p>copyright 2003, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p> 
</availability>
-->
        <availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2003 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
            Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2003">2003</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500365</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Diary of Eliza R. Stouffer</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county diary of eliza r stouffer</title>
            <author>Eliza R. Stouffer</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p> </p>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: From the private collection of Margaret
              Binkley DuVernet. Photocopies courtesy of the Reformed Mennonite Collection, Mennonite
              Historical Association of the Cumberland Valley, Chambersburg, Pennsylvania</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>We would like to thank Edsel Burdge, Jr. of Shippensburg, Pennsylvania, for
                bringing this diary to our attention and for sharing with us his transcription.</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Private Collection</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <dateRange from="1863-06-12" to="1863-07-10">1863-06-12-1863-07-10</dateRange>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term/>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""> </date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia
            Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD
          (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>

  <text id="FD7001T">

    <front id="d2">
      <div1 id="d3" type="section">
        <head>Biography <!-- <ref>FD7001bio</ref> -->
        </head>
        <p/>
      </div1>
    </front>

    <body id="d4">

      <div1 id="FD7001int" type="introduction">
        <head>Introduction <!-- <ref>FD7001int</ref> -->
        </head>
        <div2 id="d6" type="section">

          <!-- <ref>Home Front</ref> -->


          <p>Account of My Visit in Lancaster County</p>

        </div2>
      </div1>
      <div1 id="FD70011863" n="1863" type="part">
        <head>1863 <!-- <ref>FD70011863</ref> -->
        </head>
        <div2 id="d8" n="1863-06" type="section">
          <head>June 1863 <!-- <ref>Home Front, Church/Religious Activity, Women</ref> -->
          </head>
          <div3 id="d9" n="1863-06-12" type="entry">
            <head>June 12<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1863</head>
            <p>I Started from home on the Morning of 12<hi rend="super">th</hi> June in company with
              Daniel Musser and wife, Aunt Leah-Catharine Snyder-Amanda Herr-and Maria Stouffer-the
              three last named and Myself stopped at Middlesex. also brother Benjamin-We took dinner
              at David Millers. went out to Amos Miller's in the evening there over night, </p>
          </div3>
          <div3 id="d10" n="1863-06-13" type="entry">
            <head>Saturday Morning the 13<hi rend="super">th</hi>
            </head>
            <p>started to Darry station in Dauphin County Stopped at Harrisburg <orig reg="until"
                >untill</orig> 2. Oclock-we walked out to the Capitol and around the place
              awhile-got to the Aunt Hersheys in the afternoon took supper with them. The
              examination Meeting was over a great had been <orig reg="together">togather</orig>. We
              went to Martin Hersheys in the evening there over night they had a house full of
              Strangers, thirty four over night. </p>
          </div3>
          <div3 id="d11" n="1863-06-14" type="entry">
            <head>Sunday Morning the 14<hi rend="super">th</hi>
            </head>
            <p>all went to Meeting at the church. C Whitmer and D Musser spoke, the house full did
              not near all get in. fourteen were received by baptism. We went back to Hersheys took
              dinner and started to Mt Joy in Carriage; went to John Snyders, there over night. </p>
          </div3>
          <div3 id="d12" n="1863-06-15" type="entry">
            <head>Monday 15<hi rend="super">th</hi>
            </head>
            <p>all at Pap Snyders over dinner. Aunt Leah started for home in the afternoon A great
              excitement there. reports the Rebels are coming to Chambersburg. Emma Snyder went
              along in the afternoon to Samuel Hersheys there overnight. </p>
          </div3>
          <div3 id="d13" n="1863-06-16" type="entry">
            <head>Tuesday morning 16<hi rend="super">th</hi>
            </head>
            <p>went to Hersts there for dinner. They took us back to Snyders. Aunt Leah came back
              could not get home. in the evening went to see Polly Rohrer in Mt Joy-at J Snyder over
              night. </p>
          </div3>
          <div3 id="d14" n="1863-06-17" type="entry">
            <head>In the afternoon of the 17<hi rend="super">th</hi>
            </head>
            <p>Aunt, Maria and Myself took the Cars to Lancaster and the Hack to Lampeter to Dr
              Musser's. the excitement <orig reg="still">stile</orig> getting greater-at Musser's
              over night. </p>
          </div3>

          <div3 id="d15" n="1863-06-18" type="entry">
            <head>on Thursday afternoon</head>
            <p>Sister Musser took Maria and I to see Lydia Hebble <pb n="2"/> took supper with her
              in the evening went with Annie Miller home there over night. </p>
          </div3>
          <div3 id="d16" n="1863-06-19" type="entry">
            <head>Friday 19<hi rend="super">th</hi>
            </head>
            <p>Dr Musser took us over to Jacob Weavers there over dinner. Annie Lantz went along to
              Gabrial Whingerts there a few hours, and back to John Weavers for Supper. Jacob took
              us and Annie Lantz to the Widow Herr. in the evening went to the Meeting house and
                <orig reg="graveyard">grave yard</orig>, at Herr's over night.</p>
          </div3>
          <div3 id="d17" n="1863-06-20" type="entry">
            <head>Saturday 20<hi rend="super">th</hi>
            </head>
            <p>to Franks awhile in the morning. Fanny took us to Daniel Musser's, took dinner at
              Daniel Herrs and supper at Abram Herr's. Went to Dr Mussers again in the evening went
              to see Henry Herr's, Yitzels, and Crooks-over night at Mussers. </p>
          </div3>
          <div3 id="d18" n="1863-06-21" type="entry">
            <head>Sunday morning 21<hi rend="super">st</hi>
            </head>
            <p>Abram Herr took us to Manor Meeting. two were received by baptism a cloudy wet
              morning; went through Petersville and along the Conestoga creek. took dinner at Jacob
              Frantzes came by Millersville. Lizzie Frantz took us along home, came through a little
              town called Eden and the War banks and Lancaster City. There over night. </p>
          </div3>
          <div3 id="d19" n="1863-06-22" type="entry">
            <head>Monday 22</head>
            <p>Frantzes two girls went along to Andrew Frantzes there awhile took dinner at David
              Shirks Mary went along to Dochertys there a few hours, and then to Jacob Fricks. there
              over night. </p>
          </div3>
          <div3 id="d20" n="1863-06-23" type="entry">
            <head>Tuesday 23<hi rend="super">rd</hi>
            </head>
            <p>Salinda and her Mother went along to Lydia Landis took dinner with her. in the
              afternoon to Amos Hoover's and in the evening to John Kohr's there over night. </p>
          </div3>
          <div3 id="d21" n="1863-06-24" type="entry">
            <head>Wednesday 24<hi rend="super">th</hi>
            </head>
            <p>Maria and I took the Cars at Dillerville to Landisville took dinner and supper at the
              Widow Lehman's in the evening Emma went along to Widow Longs there over night. </p>
          </div3>
          <div3 id="d22" n="1863-06-25" type="entry">
            <head>Thursday morning</head>
            <p>Maria Long went along to Jacob Hoovers there awhile, went back to Lehmans for dinner.
              Emma went along to Christian Swartleys there over night. At Joseph Swartleys in the
              evening awhile. </p>
          </div3>
          <div3 id="d23" n="1863-06-26" type="entry">
            <head>Friday morning</head>
            <p>Lizzie Swartley took us to Hostetters there a few hours, then to George Trouts there
              for dinner. Susan went along to Swarrs there over supper, Trouts came for us in the
              evening, this was a wet rainy day. in the evening <pb n="3"/> John and Frank Lantz
              came, with several others. brought 25 head of horses along, great excitement among the
              people. (We cannot hear from home. at Trouts over night.</p>
          </div3>
          <div3 id="d24" n="1863-06-27" type="entry">
            <head>Saturday 27<hi rend="super">th</hi>
            </head>
            <p>Susan took us to Jacob Swartleys there over dinner in the after noon they took us to
              Lancaster. We took the Hack to Lampete to Abram Herrs, there over night. </p>
          </div3>
          <div3 id="d25" n="1863-06-28" type="entry">
            <head>Sunday 28<hi rend="super">th</hi>
            </head>
            <p>Annie Miller took us to the Meeting house. Jacob Bowman and D Musser spoke. We all
              took dinner at Abram Whitmers. <orig reg="Met">Meet</orig> Bennie, Adam, David and
              some of Millers men at meeting, very unexpected brought horses down-in the afternoon
              went to see Old Betsy Weaver, To Joseph Weavers in the evening there over night. </p>
          </div3>
          <div3 id="d26" n="1863-06-29" type="entry">

            <p>Barbara went along to Isaac Weavers in the afternoon. there I <orig reg="met"
              >meet</orig> Andy and James, In the evening Mary Weaver took us to Benjamin
              Buckwalters there over night. </p>
          </div3>
          <div3 id="d27" n="1863-06-30" type="entry">
            <head>Tuesday morning</head>
            <p>Tuesday morning Kate and Mary Buckwalters went along to Jacob Bowmans took dinner
              there and supper at Widow Neffs, overnight at Eshlemans, (<orig reg="Met">Meet</orig>
              Christ Miller there) heard very bad news about the rebels; how they are destroying
              things, and abusing the people. </p>
          </div3>
        </div2>
        <div2 id="d28" n="1863-07" type="section">
          <head>July 1863 <!-- <ref>Death/Casualties, Home Front, Women</ref> -->
          </head>
          <div3 id="d29" n="1863-07-01" type="entry">
            <head>Wednesday morning 1<hi rend="super">st</hi> July</head>
            <p>We went to the funeral of Henry Herr at Myser's. Amanda went along to Henry Landis'es
              there for dinner, took supper with Aunty Anne. in the evening went to Joseph Weavers
              there over night. </p>
          </div3>
          <div3 id="d30" n="1863-07-02" type="entry">
            <head>Thursday afternoon</head>
            <p>Barbara and Annie Weaver went along to Samuel Weavers, not there long <orig
                reg="until">untile</orig> they sent for us. Aunt <orig reg="Leah">Leeh</orig> and
              Betsy Musser came. </p>
          </div3>
          <div3 id="d31" n="1863-07-03" type="entry">
            <head>Friday morning</head>
            <p>took Uncles carriage and our horse Annie Weaver along went to Widow Herrs there for
              dinner Amanda went along in the after noon to Amos Herrs there for supper; in the
              evening all went to Hannah Armits, at Franks in the evening awhile, over night at
              Herrs.</p>
          </div3>
          <div3 id="d32" n="1863-07-04" type="entry">
            <head>Saturday 4<hi rend="super">th</hi>
            </head>
            <p>Amanda went along to Mary Kriders was not at home. stopped at Abram Weaver's awhile,
              went back to Joseph Weavers there for dinner, Amanda and Barbara went along to Jacob
              Musser's took supper there, Maria and I stopped at Isaac Weavers there over night. </p>

          </div3>

          <pb n="4"/>

          <div3 id="d33" n="1863-07-05" type="entry">
            <head>Sunday July 5<hi rend="super">th</hi>
            </head>
            <p>raining fast all day intended going to meeting to Strasburg but did not go. In the
              afternoon Susan Weaver went along to Lampeter. I was at Mussers over night.</p>
          </div3>
          <div3 id="d34" n="1863-07-06" type="entry">
            <head>next morning</head>
            <p>went to John Herrs-We all took dinner at Mussers-this was a wet unpleasant day,
              cleared off in the afternoon. Andy, David, Maria, and I went to Mt Joy at John Snyders
              over night. </p>
          </div3>
          <div3 id="d35" n="1863-07-07" type="entry">
            <head>next Morning</head>
            <p>went to Paps there for dinner. In the afternoon went back to Lampeter Stayed at
              Musser over night. </p>
          </div3>
          <div3 id="d36" n="1863-07-08" type="entry">
            <head>Wednesday Morning,</head>
            <p>raining fast. the boys all started for home took the horses and wagons along. Maria
              and Myself went to Cassels there over dinner, went to Carpenters awhile, and took
              supper at Sister Housers, back to Mussers in the evening there over night </p>
          </div3>
          <div3 id="d37" n="1863-07-09" type="entry">

            <p>the Dr took us to Lancaster in the morning. at Widow Eckmans awhile. took the Cars
              for home about 11.Oclock. got to Middlesex in the evening took supper at Davids, over
              night at Amos'es</p>
          </div3>
          <div3 id="d38" n="1863-07-10" type="entry">
            <head>Friday 10<hi rend="super">th</hi>
            </head>
            <p>started in the Carriage for home, took dinner at a farm house. got in with a regiment
              of Union Soldiers, were pressed to haul some. a very warm and tiresome Journey. got
              home about 9.Oclock in the evening July 10<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1863-</p>
          </div3>
        </div2>
      </div1>





    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
