<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="FN0002"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="FN0002">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: A Soldier to the Pennsylvania Daily
                    Telegraph, April 30, 1861</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county a soldier to the pennsylvania daily telegraph, april 30 1861</title>
        <author>Unknown </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>David Samuel Freed </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">FN0002 </idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2 </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1998">1998 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501767</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War. </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note>
                    <p>Transcription from a photocopy.</p>
                </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: A Soldier to the Pennsylvania Daily Telegraph, April
                            30, 1861</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county a soldier to the pennsylvania daily telegraph, april 30 1861</title>
            <author> </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Letter of a Soldier, published in the <hi rend="underline">Pennsylvania Daily Telegraph</hi>, May 1, 1861, p.
                            2, under the headline, "From Camp Slifer." </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Daily Telegraph</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-04-30">1861-04-30 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Home Front, Church/Religious Activity, Women, Enlistment,
                        Military Authority </term>
                    <term>Regiment: none </term>
                    <term>Company: none </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="FN0002T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>A soldier from Camp Slifer, near Chambersburg, PA, shares his thoughts with the
                    editor of the Daily Telegraph. He discusses the organization of the soldiers in
                    camp and mentions his officers' solemn promise that the soldiers will observe
                    the Sabbath. His letter also praises the camp's commanding officer, General
                    Williams and talks about residents of Chambersburg.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Editor, Pennsylvania Daily Telegraph</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-04-30">April 30, 1861</date>
                        <name type="place">CHAMBERSBURG</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>MR. EDITOR -</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>This usually quiet town now presents a very animated and soldier like appearance,
                    as the sound of the drum, the running to and fro of soldiers, and all the pomp
                    and circumstance of glorius war, are the distinguishing features of our streets.
                    Camp Slifer is situated near this place, on the Baltimore road, on level
                    grounds, having a beautiful stream of spring water running through the camp.
                        <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Williams and Staff arrived here on last
                    Thursday, and at once proceeded to organize the camp. Two regiments were here,
                    stationed at the Fair grounds and hotels, but in one day the sheds in the new
                    camp were erected, and all the troops removed on Thursday evening. The energy
                    and order with which these movements were directed soon made it evident that
                    there was a master spirit at the head of affairs. The officers and men soon
                    partook of the spirit of the chief, and each joined cheerfully in bringing order
                    out of confusion. <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Williams issued general
                    orders for the government of the camp, which are very explicit, and force the
                    officers and men to the strict line of duty; and already we witness the result
                    of such a discipline, as in a few days order has taken the place of disorder,
                    and well drilled soldiers are now seen on parade instead of raw recruits.
                    Spectators all express surprise at the rapid improvement in the drill of the
                    men. You see no straggling soldiers about town, but every one is compelled to
                    attend closely to duty -- a state of things which I have failed to see in other
                    camps I have visited in the State. <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Williams
                    requires the men to be occupied constantly, at either company or squad drill,
                    except of course the time requisite for recreation and preparing meals. While
                    some may complain of the severe discipline, yet all must admit that constant
                    drill alone secures efficiency, and we therefore hear constant praise awarded
                    the General Commanding for his firmness and ambition in making the regiments
                    under his command a credit to the service. <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr>
                    Williams is ably assisted by his aid de camp, Captain Patterson, Brigade
                    Inspector Major Knipe, and Brigade Quatermaster <abbr expan="Captain"
                    >Capt.</abbr> Osterlough. </p>

                <p>The citizens of Chambersburg have been generous in their contributions, and
                    profuse in their kindness to the soldiers and officers; while the ladies, God
                    bless them, smile upon us so sweetly as almost to captivate us all. Their
                    kindness will be a theme of praise among the soldiers now in Camp Curtin in
                    future years. Although not in secret, I fear some of the fair damsels have "laid
                    seige" to the hearts of the gallant beaux in our <abbr expan="company"
                    >comp.</abbr>, and may furnish a romance or a reality for the future novelist.
                    They no doubt pity the noble fellows; but they should remember the poet says
                    "pity is akin to love." We expect another regiment shortly, and have quarters
                    provided for them. If the Government wish soldiers made out of raw recruits in
                    double quick time let them send them to Camp Sifer under the command of <abbr
                        expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Williams and it will be done. </p>

                <p>I read in your Saturday's paper, an article headed "No Sabbath in War." Your
                    remarks were very proper, and should command the attention of the officers of
                    the volunteers now being organized. <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Twiggs
                    once issued an order on the Rio Grande that Sunday would be dispensed with
                    hereafter until further order. Such an order could only be issued by a man
                    within whose breast beat the heart of a traitor. </p>

                <p>The following is an order issued by General Williams on last Saturday, which I
                    hope you will publish to gratify the parents and friends of the officers and
                    soldiers now under the command of <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> W., as it
                    will show them that while he is the soldier and strict disciplinarian, yet he is
                    mindful of their duty as Christians as well as patriots. </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute> </salute>
                    <signed>HEAD QUARTERS, CAMP SLIFER April 27, 1861. </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
