<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1868/va.au.rv.1868.10.02">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/28/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-10-02">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day norm="">2</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1868.10.02.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1868.10.02.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our attention has lately been called to the condition of our county roads by
                        several of our farmer friends. Some time ago the improvement of our roads
                        was agitated in a communication in our columns, and we then made it the
                        subject of an editorial. We desire again to call the attention of our people
                        to the importance of this subject. Next in importance to railroad
                        communication is the improvement of our county roads. We are now destined to
                        have superior railroad advantages by the early completion of the Chesapeake
                        &amp; Ohio Railroad and the then imperative necessity of the extension
                        of the Valley Railroad--in fact, the then almost absolute certainty of its
                        extension to Salem.</p>
                    <p>Can we take the full advantage of our Railroad communications without our
                        county roads are improved? We can not. Is our present system of working our
                        roads efficient and calculated to place our roads in proper condition? We
                        think not. Therefore, it behooves our people to look to their interest and
                        set on foot, at once, some plan by which our county roads can be put and
                        kept in thorough repair. There is no county in the State more capable of
                        making good county roads and keeping them in good condition than the county
                        of Augusta. We should then, by all means, take the matter in hand and set to
                        work to place our roads in the best possible condition.</p>
                    <p>With good roads our farmers can haul larger loads, with greater ease and less
                        wear and tear of vehicles and teams, their lands will be appreciated in
                        value thereby and they generally can reap almost the same advantage from our
                        railroads as those whose lands lie in close proximity to despots.--Whether
                        the present plan of working roads be retained, or a special tax be levied to
                        keep regular sets of hands on the roads, or some other method is adopted to
                        put and keep our county roads in good condition, the matter is important and
                        should be attended to at once. The roads leading to the county seat and the
                        various depots should meet with the earliest attention. Then in turn the
                        next in importance and so on until every road in the county is put in
                        complete repair. Money expended in this way will return the largest possible
                        revenue to all.--It is not what is made by what is saved that adds to our
                        wealth and in no way can as much be saved to all as by having good roads.</p>
                    <p>Other counties are turning their attention to this subject. Our energetic
                        neighbors of Rockingham are improving their roads, laying out air line roads
                        to their county seat, erecting bridges &amp;c., &amp;c. They are
                        alive to their immediate and prospective interests. Let us exhibit the same
                        zeal and liberality in improving our county roads and the result will amply
                        repay. We therefore call upon our citizens generally to take an interest in
                        the matter and let us make old Augusta as famous for her good roads as she
                        is for the energy and go ahead spirit of her people.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Advocates improving the roads in Augusta county for better transportation.
                    Lists the ways that everyone will benefit, cites other counties that are already
                    at work on a similar project.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that the increase in the public debt for the month of
                    September stands at $2,500,000. "Thus the debt continues to increase, in time of
                    peace, under the follies of Radicalism."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Future of Virginia</head>
                <origin>Norfolk Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The last three years have fully justified our undoubting confidence in
                        Virginians, and we can proudly boast that the whole State, poor and desolate
                        as it is, has sprung forward with a power and energy that has astonished
                        even ourselves. We have no fears for the future--onwards! onwards! is the
                        motto of Virginia. If she has done so much when more than one-half of her
                        territory has been swept with the besom of destruction, what will, in coming
                        years, be her wealth and glory!--There rises before our eye of faith a
                        boundless vista of her future prosperity. We see, before the close of this
                        century, Old Virginia covered over with railroads and crowded with
                        population; with noble cities at every fall of her river, manufacturing for
                        the Union, with her mills developing the infinite wealth now hidden in the
                        bowels of the earth. This picture of the future is no opium dream; but it is
                        what must come to pass.--<emph rend="italic">Norfolk Journal</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Quotes an article from a Norfolk paper extolling Virginians for their
                    boundless energy in rebuilding their state over the last 3 years. Does not give
                    any specifics, just broad praise.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1868.10.02.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Britt</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George W. Britt has been appointed Flour Inspector for Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Polmer</ln>
                        <fn>P. O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. P. O. Polmer, a "practical citizen" of Staunton, invented a
                    water-wheel called "Polmer's Triple Turbine Water-wheel." It is claimed to be an
                    improvement on existing wheels. "It is simple in construction, durable and has
                    three sets of buckets, securing a rotary effect from every drop of water which
                    passes through the wheel."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>French</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prof. French in manufacturing in Staunton his celebrated "King of Pain."
                    "It cures Rheumatism, Neuralgia, Dyspepsia, and various other diseases." Many
                    local citizens offer testimony to the effectiveness of the remedy. Prof. French
                    promises to refund the money of dissatisfied customers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The County Court met on Monday last, J. Marshall McCue, Presiding Justice.</p>
                    <p>Wm. Chapman and Geo W. McCutchen renewed their bonds as Notaries Public.</p>
                    <p>E.L. Houff and Jno. M. Kinney were appointed Surveyors of roads.</p>
                    <p>Ordered that Jas. Bumgardner be instructed to examine and report whose duty
                        it is to keep in repair the road between the Railroad bridge and the U.S.
                        National Cemetery.</p>
                    <p>License was granted to John Stoner to keep private entertainment at Buffalo
                        Gap, and also to Elias Pirkey, at the Cave of the Fountains.</p>
                    <p>Petition of J.D. Craig and others for change of the road near Weyer's Cave
                        was granted.</p>
                    <p>According to report of Commissioners and Surveyors, the road running through
                        the lands of Judge Jno. Kenney and Mrs. Margaret D. Lyman was ordered to be
                        made of lawful width.</p>
                    <p>About 47 cases were disposed of on the motion docket.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J. Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chapman</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCutchen</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houff</ln>
                        <fn>E. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pirkey</ln>
                        <fn>Elias</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kenney</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lyman</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports on business done at the County Court, mainly local appointments and
                    reports from Road Surveyors.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>R. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shelton</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donaghe</ln>
                        <fn>B. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mauzy</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bayley</ln>
                        <fn>E. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Larew</ln>
                        <fn>John J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>George E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Absalom</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McChesney</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walters</ln>
                        <fn>William L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>M. W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maupin</ln>
                        <fn>Logan J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Withrow</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patrick</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>J. Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eskridge</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A meeting was held at the Court House to appoint delegates to an upcoming
                    Commercial Convention at Norfolk.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Bryan's Circus and Menagerie performed on Friday to some of the largest
                    crowds ever gathered under one tent in Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lightner</ln>
                        <fn>William T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lightner</ln>
                        <fn>Dora M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lightner</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Canter</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William T. Lightner of Augusta and Miss Dora M. Lightner, daughter of
                    William Lightner of Highland were married at the residence of the bride's father
                    on September 17th by the Rev. J. W. Canter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hollingsworth</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finks</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Catharine R. Hollingsworth died at the Waynesboro residence of her
                    son-in-law Capt. J. B. Finks on September 23rd. She was 72 years old. "The
                    subject of the notice connected herself with the Baptist Church over 30 years
                    ago, lived a consistent christian, and died in the full hope of eternal
                    happiness in the world to come."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stanard</ln>
                        <fn>Phillip B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss A. H. Christian died near Goshen Bridge at the residence of her
                    brother-in-law Maj. Phillip B. Stanard on August 22nd. She was 27 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Porterfield Kinney</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Porterfield Kinney Bell, infant son of Maj. H. M. Bell, died in Staunton on
                    September 18th. He was 5 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelley</ln>
                        <fn>Louis Borromeo</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelley</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelley</ln>
                        <fn>K. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Louis Borromeo Kelley, son of John and K. M. Kelley, died in Staunton on
                    September 25th. He was 2 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1868.10.02.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
