<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1868/va.au.rv.1868.11.20">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/04/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-11-20">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day norm="">20</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1868.11.20.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1868.11.20.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The spirit of the age demands increased facilities for reaching the great
                        centres of trade. Countries and sections which were accessible, in the past,
                        only by long and arduous journeys, are now, by the potent agency of steam,
                        opened up to the traffic of the world. Others are anxiously looking to and
                        preparing for the time when steam communication will bear their productions
                        speedily to the great marts.</p>
                    <p>In the recollection of the youngest man, the vast prairies of the West were
                        more inaccessible than trans-Atlantic countries, but to-day the
                        steam-whistle is heard in every part of them, cities have arisen almost by
                        magic, and are now the most progressive and prosperous on this
                        continent--populous and powerful States have taken the place of the prairie
                        and the wilderness, and surpass in prosperity their older sisters of the
                        Union, while the productions of this comparatively new land now control the
                        markets of the world. All this has been done by opening up rapid systems of
                        communication with the world--in a degree annihilating time and space.
                        Without steam communication, the great West would to-day be the abode of the
                        wild Indian alone. The older States, especially the Southern states, might
                        learn a lesson from this. Virginia would, particularly, be benefitted by
                        adopting the progressive spirit of her Western daughters. Her rich mineral
                        deposites will never be developed nor her fertile fields cultivated to their
                        full extent, until emulating the example of her children, steam
                        communication is extended into every available portion of her rich domain.
                        Without it, the prairies of the past are nearer the markets of the world
                        than some of her most fertile sections. Give us but the spirit of progress
                        of the West and Virginia's prosperity will, in a few years, rival that of
                        any State of our once proud Union.</p>
                    <p>While we look at the advantages of steam inter-communication, we should not
                        forget that our common roads must be improved. Railroads can not run to the
                        barns and granaries of every one, but our common roads can be so improved as
                        to greatly expedite the transportation of productions. Both of these
                        subjects are of direct interest to the people of this section and it
                        behooves them to look well to them.</p>
                    <p>Thus much because our people to reflect and reason among themselves on this
                        subject. Reflection and reasoning beget action and action is the only
                        Aladdin's Lamp we need to convert the rich productions and resources of the
                        "Old Dominion" into the yellowest of gold.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises the virtues of steam and railroad technology and urges all
                    Virginians to expand both in the state in order to reestablish Virginia's past
                    glory. Notes how both technologies transformed the West and so would provide
                    unlimited prosperity for Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper gloats that Radical Republicans are already turning criticism
                    upon General Grant.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Old Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A subject now fitly commanding much attention in "the Old Dominion" and her
                        promising young daughter, West Virginia, is the opening of direct railway
                        communication between the Ohio river and Chesapeake bay. A good portion of
                        the distance was long since traversed by the Virginia Central while much
                        grading has been done, but (we believe) no rails laid, on the Covington and
                        Ohio railroad, in West Virginia. Acts have passed the Legislatures of both
                        Virginia and West Virginia providing for a consolidation of the existing
                        corporations and completion of a through line on the route up the Kanawha
                        and down the James, which, since the day of George Washington, has been
                        regarded by Virginians as not only the shortest and most direct, but the
                        easiest and most natural channel of artificial communication between the
                        Atlantic and the Great Valley.</p>
                    <p>Negotiations looking to the legal consolidation of the existing companies
                        into one, which shall be charged with the completion and operation of the
                        "Chesapeake and Ohio railroad," are now in progress, and some divergences of
                        views or of interests have been developed. One party proposes to cut the
                        knot by the sword. General Stoneman, commanding the military department
                        which includes Virginia, is solicited to issue an edict deciding that the
                        required consolidation shalt be effected in a certain way and under certain
                        auspices, and not otherwise. We presume him incapable of such an abuse of
                        authority; but we shall nevertheless, record our protest against it. Civil
                        authority was rightful conferred by Congress on the military arm for no such
                        purpose as that here contemplated, but for the protection of personal rights
                        and the preservation of order and peace. We trust all necessity for such
                        authority will soon cease; meantime, let it not be discredited by glaring
                        abuse. We understand that northern capital stands ready to supply the
                        missing links in the proposed and much-needed chain so soon as the
                        differences now existing shall be finally adjusted. Leave business
                        arrangements to business men, and let the military power be satisfied with
                        doing its whole duty in protecting personal rights and preserving the public
                        peace.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Favors an expansion of railroads in the state but deeply opposes conditions
                    set down by military authorities. Insists only civil authority should have power
                    in the state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1868.11.20.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The revival in Staunton's M. E. Church is still in progress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>T. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The boarding house and residence of Prof. T. J. White, Principal of the
                    Mossy Creek Academy, was destroyed by fire. Most of the furniture on the ground
                    floor was saved, but nothing from the top floor. "The loss to Mr. White is heavy
                    and very embarrassing, considering the large number of students attending his
                    school this session. We learn that the school will be continued, as though this
                    unfortunate accident had not occurred."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Staunton Lyceum</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ranson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latane</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Staunton Lyceum will discuss whether or not laws are binding on the
                    conscience. They will also discuss whether or not Staunton should subscribe
                    $100,000 to the stock of the Valley Railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Staunton Musical Association</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The association has been re-organized with a large number of new members.
                    Membership costs $3 and entitles the holder to free admission to rehearsals,
                    soirees, and concerts. "Nothing is so calculated to raise the standard of music
                    in a community as just such an association. Staunton has been much benefitted by
                    it."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scheffer</ln>
                        <fn>Fred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Ed H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper expresses little surprise that a correspondent of the Register
                    has praised Staunton's Virginia Hotel. The proprietor Fred Scheffer is
                    first-class, and Mr. Ed. H. Fisher, general manager, runs everything very
                    smoothly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fultz</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A number of prominent citizens will address the people of Augusta at the
                    Court House on the proposed subscription of stock to the Valley Railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ross</ln>
                        <fn>William O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmore</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. William O. Ross and Mrs. Sarah A. Whitmore, both of Augusta, were
                    married at the residence of the bride's mother on November 12th by the Rev. J.
                    J. Engle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lambert</ln>
                        <fn>Charles P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burdette</ln>
                        <fn>S. Belle</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burdette</ln>
                        <fn>Harvey</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles P. Lambert of Alexandria and Miss S. Belle Burdette, daughter of
                    Harvey Burdette of Staunton, were married on November 17th by the Rev. William
                    E. Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1868.11.20.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
