<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1868/va.au.rv.1868.09.25">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/28/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1868-09-25">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="">25</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1868.09.25.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Two Inventions</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article profiles two promising new inventions: the velocipede and the
                    steam carriage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1868.09.25.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Radicals raise the hue and cry that if Grant and Colfax are elected peace
                        will ensue but if Seymour and Blair are elected the rebellion will be
                        re-opened and war will be inevitable. The response to each individual cry,
                        that if war then ensues the Radicals, themselves, must of necessity
                        inaugurate it, since the Democracy will have attained their ends, is a
                        virtual estoppel, yet the general cry of "Seymour, Blair and War" continues
                        for buncombe. In the event of an untrammeled and fair election, there is not
                        the slightest probability of war whether Grant and Colfax or Seymour and
                        Blair be elected. But is there a probability of peace in either event? If
                        Seymour and Blair be elected, we hope and expect to see that peace which
                        will follow the restoration of the Constitution, the restriction of the
                        privileges, prerogatives and powers of each department within their
                        constitutional spheres, the removal of military Governments in the South,
                        the reduction of taxes and restoration of the Union in fact and in truth.
                        Then will follow that confidence, prosperity and progress throughout the
                        land which are the only sure indicators of positive peace.</p>
                    <p>Should Grant and Colfax be elected the peace which will follow is that which
                        we of the South enjoy (?) to-day, viz: military Governments and trials by
                        military commissions, suspension of the <emph rend="italic">habeas
                        corpus</emph> and revocation of judicial decrees, whenever it suits the whim
                        of a military satrap, continued disfranchisement of our best and wisest men,
                        the general sway of ignorance and vice, enormous taxation and a consequent
                        continued stagnation of business and prosperity throughout the whole
                        country. This is the peace that the Democracy not only believe and predict,
                        from the election of Grant and Colfax, but which we are promised by high
                        Radical authority. They promise us that the re-construction acts of Congress
                        shall be maintained and enforced, with their white subordination to
                        ignorance and vice, taxation to support a host of useless officers, and
                        defray the expenses of an unnecessary standing army, &amp;c.
                        &amp;c., and if any, North, South, East or West, presume to raise an
                        objection to this kind of peace, a little triangular "piece of steel" is to
                        be the quietus. This is no fancy sketch. It emanates from one who stands
                        high in Radical estimation, Gen. Garfield, member of Congress from Ohio.</p>
                    <p>In a late speech he said: "General Grant will be elected the next President
                        of the United States. When thus elected, he intends, with the aid of the
                        Radical majority in Congress, to rule the country by the help of <emph
                            rend="italic">a little triangular piece of steel called a
                        bayonet</emph>."</p>
                    <p>This "little triangular piece of steel" is to rule the <emph rend="italic"
                            >whole country</emph>, says Gen. Garfield. We of the South are not
                        disturbed in the least at the threat of this "little triangular piece of
                        steel," since it is now held aloft every day in our midst, but will it be
                        received with the same equanimity North? The experience of the South under
                        the rule of the bayonet should suffice for any people, who really love
                        liberty regulated by law. We cannot therefore believe that the northern
                        people will willingly, unresistingly yield to the rule of the bayonet.</p>
                    <p>They have the choice. Civil government or the rule of the sword and bayonet.
                        Peace like unto that of the past or the peace which Gen. Grant wants and
                        which Gen. Garfield offers. Constitutional Government with Seymour and
                        Blair, or Military rule with Grant and Colfax.</p>
                    <p>How they will exercise it remains to be seen but, with the issue patent, we
                        can not believe they will consign themselves to a tyranny like that which
                        broods over the South, sapping its vital energy and prostrating the business
                        interests of the whole country.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Warns voters in both the South and the North of the brutal consequences
                    should Grant be elected. Quotes a speech from Garfield showing how Radicals
                    intend to rule the whole country with military force. Appealing mainly to
                    Northerners to get Seymour elected.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1868.09.25.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Augusta County Fair will be held October 27th-29th. Railroads will be
                    offering special rates for transportation to the fair.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that Staunton's schools are filling with pupils from all
                    over the South. Their success stands as a testimony to the town's excellence in
                    education.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Staunton Lyceum will resume meeting on October 2nd. The Rev. Long of
                    Charlottesville will speak.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Bryan's Menagerie and Circus will visit Staunton today. They could not find
                    a town lot big enough for their show, so they will be setting up in Mr. Ayres'
                    meadow.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Risk</ln>
                        <fn>Harvey</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Harvey Risk has volunteered to take a census of Staunton if the town
                    provides him free books.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that "two gentlemen of color" had a fight after one
                    called the other the "offspring of a feminine canine." The tussle drew a small
                    crowd at the edge of town.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Ladies' Memorial Association will hold a dinner in the Town Hall to
                    raise money for improving the soldiers' cemetery. Donations are accepted.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shultz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. Shultz has opened the Lee Hotel, Greenville, and has received
                    satisfied reviews.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>David K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Masincup</ln>
                        <fn>Cynthia K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bushong</ln>
                        <fn>A. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David K. Hoover and Cynthia K. Masincup were married on September 17th at
                    the residence of the bride's father by the Rev. A. A. Bushong.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuffin</ln>
                        <fn>John V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitesel</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John V. McGuffin and Miss Virginia Whitesel, both of Augusta, were married
                    on August 27th by the Rev. C. Beard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1868.09.25.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
