<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1866/va.au.rv.1866.06.29">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/15/01</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-06-29">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>29</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1866.06.29.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>Hark Ye Girls!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It is nigh time that somebody told you a little plain truth. You have been
                        watched for a long time; certain class of you; and it is plain enough you
                        are laying plans to cheat somebody. You intend to sell chaff for wheat, and
                        there is danger that some of the foolish "gudgeons" will be sadly taken in.</p>
                    <p>It may not be your fault that you belong to the "one idea party"-that the
                        single idea of getting a husband is the only one which engrosses much of
                        your time or attention.-Your venerable mother of Eden memory, was called a
                        "help for man, and you are looking for a man to help you; to help you to
                        live in the half idle, half silly way which you have commenced. Men who are
                        worth having, want women for wives. A bundle of gew-gaws with a string of
                        flats and quavers, sprinkled with cologne and set in a carmine saucer-this
                        is no help for a man who expects to raise a family of boys and girls and
                        veritable bread and meat.</p>
                    <p>The piano and the lace frame are well in their places, and so are ribbons and
                        frills and tinsels-but you can't make a dinner of the former, nor a
                        bed-blanket of the latter. And awful as the idea may seem to you, both
                        dinner and bed blanket are necessary to domestic enjoyment. Life has its
                        realities as well as its fancies but you make it all a matter of decoration,
                        remembering the tassels and curtains, forgetting the bed-stead. Suppose a
                        young man of good sense and of course of good prospects to be looking for a
                        wife, what chance have you to be chosen?-You may cap him, or trap him, to
                        catch him, but how much better to make it an object for him to catch you!
                        Render yourself worth catching, and you will need no shrewd mother or
                        managing brothers to help you to find a market.-<emph rend="italic"
                            >Lancaster Intelligencer</emph>. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges women to remember that men want wives who can perform important
                    domestic chores, explaining that one cannot make a dinner from a piano. Women
                    who know how to cook and keep a house, the author contends, will make themselves
                    "worth catching."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1866.06.29.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We publish in another column the earnest protest of the people of Augusta,
                        assembled in their Court House, on the 25th inst., (Court day,) against the
                        abominable 'concurrent resolution,' "so-called," proposed as an amendment to
                        the Constitution. Thus has spoken the people of "old Augusta" and right
                        nobly do they speak. They will have nothing to do with the ratification of
                        this miserable subterfuge as an amendment tot the Constitution, involving as
                        it would an entire loss of their self respect, and, by their own act, the
                        sanctioning their own degradation and dishonor.</p>
                    <p>We commend these resolutions and proceedings to our confreres in the South,
                        and as the citizens of "old Augusta, in their meeting on Thursday last, have
                        done, call upon our fellow citizens of Virginia and other Southern States to
                        hold public meetings and place the seal of their condemnation on this
                        iniquitous radical scheme, and thus show the people of the North, many of
                        whom are led to suppose that we would accept anything to secure
                        representation, that, though having suffered severely, and compelled to bear
                        the burdens of, without enjoying the privileges in the Union, we are not
                        willing, by our own acts and deeds, to consign ourselves and our posterity
                        to everlasting infamy.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Referring to the resolutions produced by a meeting of white citizens, held
                    at the Court House on June 25 and found in another column of the Vindicator, the
                    editor calls on other citizens of "Virginia and other Southern States to hold
                    public meetings and place the seal of their condemnation on this iniquitous
                    radical scheme."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Public Meeting in Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Resolutions propounded by a public meeting at the court house on June 26,
                    denouncing the course of Congress, praising President Johnson, and vowing that
                    Virginia will never "be placed in the position of a political prostitute, by
                    giving consent to her own degradation and dishonor." For the full text of the
                    resolutions, see the Staunton Spectator, 7/3/66.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Negro Congressmen</head>
                <origin>Mobile Tribune</origin>
                <commentary>"The Mobile Tribune, speaking of the prospects of Congressional
                    Representatives says:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"Let us get fifty or sixty of the ugliest, dirtiest, greasiest, raggediest,
                        lou--, yes, and most ignorant cornfield darkies, that can be caught in the
                        country-let us cram their moths full of iron-clad oaths, and send them as
                        our members elect to Congress.</p>
                    <p>"The Radical members could not deny them their seats without stultifying
                        themselves before the world. They have giving the negro his civil rights,
                        let them have the first benefit of it. Now would not a Congress so
                        composed-made so as the just result of Radical legislation-present a
                        beautiful spectacle? Such a spectacle, indeed, that neither army nor navy
                        would obey their behests.-They would in a very short time, be as dead as the
                        Southern Confederacy."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the South should send "fifty or sixty of the ugliest, dirtiest,
                    greasiest, . . . most ignorant cornfield darkies" to Congress and soon, the
                    author predicts, "the spectacle" would guarantee that "neither army or navy
                    would obey their behests."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1866.06.29.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>PROCEEDINGS of the term of the County Court, held Monday last, J. Marshall
                        McCue presiding.</p>
                    <p>The Commonwealth vs George Hawkins, colored, for felony, dismissed.</p>
                    <p>The County levy was laid at $3 on each titheable, making total levy $15,627,
                        of which sum $6,500 was appropriated for the support of the poor, and for
                        the building of additional houses at the Poor House for freedmen.</p>
                    <p>The Constables of the County qualified.</p>
                    <p>Dr. John W. Gillespie qualified as Notary Public.</p>
                    <p>A number of licenses for Hotels were granted.</p>
                    <p>W. J. Dews was required to give counter security on his official bond as
                        Notary Public.</p>
                    <p>Thomas S. Hogshead was appointed Road Commissioner, vice, J. G. Fulton, and
                        John Wilson, vice, W. F. Smith.</p>
                    <p>A. L. Turk was also appointed Road Commissioner.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J. Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawkins</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillespie</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dews</ln>
                        <fn>W. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulton</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pilson</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>W. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn>A. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A summary of the proceedings of the June term of the County Court, presided
                    over by J. Marshall McCue.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>THE work at the Cemetery, as far as digging graves and arranging for setting
                        out trees &amp;c. is concerned was completed on Thursday of last week.
                        There was a general turn out, the places of business, as far as practicable,
                        being closed, and the citizens of town and country, repairing to the cemetry
                        either in person or by substitute, worked with a will, and left nothing
                        undone to receive our Confederate dead, now lying in uncared for graves on
                        many battlefields. When the bodies of our soldiers are removed to the
                        cemetery, we hope to see these grounds handsomely adorned and an appropiate
                        monument rise to commemorate their many virtues and gallant bearing.</p>
                    <p>In conclusion we take pleasure in mentioning the fact that Colin Scott, John
                        Christian, Jno. Bumgardner, Fleming Burnett, Alex. Patterson, Rich. H.
                        Brown, Jno. Bridges and Deaf and Dumb George (colored) voluntarily presented
                        themselves or sent substitutes to aid in this work.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scott</ln>
                        <fn>Colin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>Jno.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burnett</ln>
                        <fn>Fleming</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>Alex.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Rich. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bridges</ln>
                        <fn>Jno.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that there was "a general turn out" at the cemetery last Thursday,
                    where "the citizens of town and country" assembled to prepare the grounds for
                    the soldiers "now lying in uncared for graves on many battlefields."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>PROCEEDINGS of the Town Council, at their meeting held June 23rd.</p>
                    <p>The water Committee, having considered complaints against the Superintendent
                        of Water Works, and fined him $30, upon an appeal to the Council the fine
                        was reduced to $20.</p>
                    <p>Robt. Knightly was awarded the contract to clean Lewis' Creek, from the
                        Beverly Street to the west side of the bridge on Lewis Street, for the
                        amount of $650.</p>
                    <p>Several unimportant resolutions were adopted and the Council adjourned.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knightly</ln>
                        <fn>Robt.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Summarizes the proceedings of the Town Council at their June 23 meeting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. William Harman will open a boarding and day school at her residence in
                    Staunton, where "every attention will be paid to the morals and manners of the
                    young ladies committed to her charge."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Davis died last Saturday, "aged nearly 100 years." Davis was
                    discharged from the military in the War of 1812 because he was over 45 years of
                    age.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Lutheran Sunday School had a picnic near Staunton last Tuesday, where
                    "the children enjoyed themselves exceedingly, and the Teachers and others
                    present were much delighted with their innocent pleasures."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A difficulty occurred at the Depot on Wednesday evening last, by Mr. Madison
                        Doom striking one of the Virginia Hotel porters, whom he alleges was
                        portering against the rules, on the platform, into which Mr. Bernard Peyton
                        was drawn. Some harsh wods passed when pistols and knives were drawn, but by
                        the interposition of bystanders a collision was prevented. The case was
                        investigated before Mayor Trout and Mr. Wm. B. Kayser, Recorder, who decided
                        to bind Messrs. Peyton and Doom over the sum of $500 each to keep the peace
                        for three months. They also bound Mr. Doom over in the sum of $100 to answer
                        an indictment to be preferred by the Grand Jury for assault and battery.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doom</ln>
                        <fn>Madison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Bernard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mayor</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A "difficulty" occurred at the Depot last Wednesday when Madison Doom and
                    Bernard Peyton drew pistols and knives but "by the interposition of bystanders a
                    collision was prevented."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Ladies of the Methodist Episcopal Church South made $300 dollars from a
                    fair held at the Town Hall last Monday and Tuesday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawkins</ln>
                        <fn>Lou W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawkins</ln>
                        <fn>James P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lou Hawkins, wife of James Hawkins and formerly of Augusta, died in
                    Danville on June 25. She was 49.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1866.06.29.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
