<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1866/va.au.rv.1866.05.04">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/01/01</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-05-04">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>04</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1866.05.04.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>What the South has Lost</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mathew F. Maury, ex-director of the National Observatory at Washington, and
                        present colonizer in Mexico, has written a letter to the London <emph
                            rend="italic">Morning Herald </emph>, in which he gives the following
                        estimate of the losses of the South, caused by the war: </p>
                    <p>"I estimate the amount of the pecuniary losses incurred by the people of the
                        Southern Confederacy, in their late attempt at independence, to be not less
                        than $7,000,000,000 (seven thousand millions of dollars,) viz</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>By emancipation</cell>
                            <cell>$3,000,000,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Expenses of the war</cell>
                            <cell>2,000,000,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Destruction of private property</cell>
                            <cell>1,000,000,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>additional taxation imposed by the victor for payment of Federal
                                war debt, say $10,000,000 per annum, equal to six per cent. interest
                                on</cell>
                            <cell>1,000,0000,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Total</cell>
                            <cell>$7,000,000,000</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>"This loss falls upon less than eight millions of whites, who have, moreover,
                        in addition to contribute largely towards the support of the four millions
                        of blacks who <emph rend="italic">have </emph> been suddenly turned loose
                        among them and who, for the present at least, are incapable of earning for
                        themselves. </p>
                    <p>"This $7,000,000,000 of money was the accumulated wealth of centuries; it
                        constituted nearly the whole industrial plant and capital of the South."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Matthew Maury, former director of the National Observatory, estimates the
                    total cost of the war to the people of the South at seven billion dollars.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1866.05.04.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In another column will be found the result of the labors of the
                        Reconstruction Committee, and a more nefarious and reckless scheme for party
                        aggrandizement and power never disgraced the history of any country or age.
                        It is divided into three parts. The first is a Constitutional amendment,
                        which would ingraft into the Constitution the features of the Civil Rights
                        Bill, force negro suffrage upon us, or cut down the basis of representation,
                        disfranchise those who sympathize with secession, as far as voting for
                        members of Congress and electors for President and Vice-President is
                        concerned, until July 4th 1870, (a most disgraceful attempt to secure the
                        election of Stevens, Sumner, or some other radical to the next Presidency,)
                        prohibits the payment by the United States, or any State, of any obligation
                        incurred in aid of secession, or any claim to compensation for slaves
                        emancipated, and gives Congress absolute power and control over the whole
                        subject.</p>
                    <p>The second part refers to the restoration of the Southern States to their
                        full (?) political rights in the Union. The conditions of which are, that,
                        the amendment having become a part of the Constitution, any Southern State
                        adopting it and modifying its Constitution in accordance therewith, and
                        electing duly qualified Senators and Representatives, who can take the test
                        oath, shall be admitted, and offers a bribe in the shape of a postponement
                        of the payment of the direct tax, assumed by such State, for a period not
                        exceeding ten years from the passage of the proposed act.</p>
                    <p>The third part declares ineligible to any office under the United States
                        Government those who have aided the Confederate States, occupying certain
                        positions under it and under the State Governments. This latter part would
                        deprive us of the services of the ablest statesmen among us, in a Federal
                        capacity, and force us to elect a set of incapacitated upstarts, who could
                        be manipulated at will by the vile tricksters who now disgrace our National
                        Legislature.</p>
                    <p>We, it seems, are to have no hand in making or refusing to make the proposed
                        amendment a part of the Constitution. When three-fourths of the States now
                        represented shall ratify it and make it a part of that instrument, we may
                        adopt it and thereby secure the postponement of the payment of the unpaid
                        direct tax for a period not exceeding ten years. Most generous Congress!
                        Tremendous bribe!</p>
                    <p>For the privilege of representation in Congress by men who would fail in
                        every particular to represent us, we mist disfranchise our best citizens,
                        and lose the service of many [MISSING LINES] capacity, and the payment of
                        the direct tax of 27 cents on every one hundred dollars' worth of taxable
                        property will be postponed for ten years. Our people have already paid a
                        vast portion of this direct tax, and supposing the other States have been
                        treated like Virginia, the remainder unpaid, judging from this particular
                        community, would not exceed one-twenty-seventh of the direct tax, or one
                        cent on every $100, for the postponement of the payment of which we are to
                        barter away your constitutional and "full political rights."</p>
                    <p>The amendment may be made a part of the Constitution yet we doubt that 19 of
                        the 20 States represented will ratify it, but we are not so lost to
                        manliness, that, for the sake of being relieved for a time of the payment of
                        the remaining direct tax of 1 cent on every $100, we would adopt this
                        abominable production of the Reconstruction Committee. Better be
                        unrepresented forever. Those who claim all the rights may do as they will
                        and we are powerless to prevent it, but we can at least have the proud
                        satisfaction of knowing that we had no hand in riveting on ourselves this
                        diabolical scheme.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summarizes, and disparages, the recent report of the Reconstruction
                    Committee, arguing that it would be better to be "unrepresented forever" and
                    "have the proud satisfaction of knowing that we had no hand in riveting on
                    ourselves this diabolical scheme."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In this day of recuperation an earnest desire is shown to throw aside the old
                        Fogyism of the past and take advantage of every thing nature has placed in
                        our midst.</p>
                    <p>Left without a dollar at the close of hostilities our people have addressed
                        themselves to the work before them with an energy equal to their
                        undertakings and to the wants of the time, which is noticeable to the merest
                        observer who drops into our community, and has been heralded by more than
                        one of our cotemporaries elsewhere as a stimulus to their communities.</p>
                    <p>Our Stores have been refitted and opened with goods admirably suited to the
                        wants of our people, our workshops are again sending forth the pleasant
                        sounds of busy industry, and the main spring of all, the plain, plodding and
                        patient husbandman, with half the labor of the past, boldly prepares his
                        land for the coming seed time, and carefully plants his crop in the hope of
                        an abundant harvest, with which to supply his wants and keep in active
                        motion the vast business machine of our community.</p>
                    <p>As we have before intimated, not content wich the old combination of wheels
                        in this business machine, which we have run for so many years, new wheels
                        have been added and we notice builders' establishments and Iron works in
                        active operation and with a prospects of brilliant success.</p>
                    <p>Situated in the midst of an iron district, and in direct communication with
                        many portions of the State by the Virginia Central and connecting roads, and
                        to be made more accessible to others by the Valley Railroad, Staunton must
                        develop her advantages in the manufacturing line, and being at a point
                        adapted to supply readily the wants of the country North West, West and
                        South West of this, will ultimately be the centre of a considerable
                        wholesale business, which must necessarily build her up to a position not
                        secondary to any in the State. While we write, [UNCLEAR], are preparing to
                        open [UNCLEAR], and others in [UNCLEAR] will follow suit.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises local residents' desire "to throw aside the Fogyism of the past and
                    take advantage of everything nature has placed in our midst" and urges Staunton
                    to "develop her advantages in the manufacturing line."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We noticed in the proceedings of Congress on May 1st, that Senator Trumbull
                        presented a petition of 146 "<emph rend="italic">citizens</emph>" of <emph
                            rend="italic">Staunton, Va</emph>., representing that, the troops being
                        recently withdrawn from that place, the "Union" men are being persecuted by
                        the "rebels" and praying that the troops be returned for the protection of
                        loyal men. </p>
                    <p>That 146 <emph rend="italic">citizens </emph> of Staunton ever signed such a
                        petition is a falsehood, and we desire to brand it as such before our
                        cotemporaries by publishing it, give it credence elsewhere [UNCLEAR] "Union"
                        men are not and have not been persecuted by any person here, and we
                        unhesitatingly assert that no one in Staunton, who claims to have been a
                        "union" man is in danger of or really fears any such persecution, or desires
                        the return of troops to this place for his better protection. We believe
                        that Mr. Tukey, Asst. Sup't of the "Bureau of Freedmen, refugees and
                        Abandoned Lands," whose duty it is to see that "Union" men are protected,
                        will bear us out in the above assertion. </p>
                    <p>This is doubtless the same petition which was originated and <emph
                            rend="italic">secretly </emph> circulated in the country by Wm. J. Dews,
                        which we mentioned at the time, and heard denounced, as was Dews himself, by
                        sever of the "union" men of Staunton. Its assertions are without the shadow
                        of truth, and it was only intended by its originator to harass our people.
                    </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dews</ln>
                        <fn>W. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Referring to a petition presented in Congress on May 1 by Senator Trumbull
                    from citizens of Staunton, the author denounces the man who circulated the
                    petition, W. J. Dews. The article claims the petition "was only intended by its
                    originator to harass our people."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Report of the Reconstruction Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Contains the report of the Joint Committee on Reconstruction, which
                    includes the proposed Fourteenth Amendment and bills declaring former
                    Confederates ineligible to hold office and providing for the restoration of the
                    Southern states when they meet the prescribed requirements.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1866.05.04.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>IN noticing the many improvements in our town, the visitor is particularly
                        struck with the neat and comfortable appearance of our hotels.</p>
                    <p>The Virginia, during the past week has been re-opened by its worthy
                        proprietors, Messrs Geo. L. Peyton &amp; Co. Being remodeled and
                        refurnished, from top to bottom, in the latest style, the proprietors, by
                        prompt attention to the wants of their guests, hope it will attain a greater
                        degree of popularity than it enjoyed in former times. From the dinners
                        served up on several occasions, at which we were present, we can truly say
                        that, in the eating line, the well deserved reputation of the proprietors is
                        fully sustained, and that the traveler, either on business or pleasure, will
                        be well cared for at the Virginia.</p>
                    <p>Col. C. T. O'Ferrall, the indefatigable proprietor of the American, not
                        willing to be in the rear in improvements, has, with his accustomed energy,
                        papered, painted and refurnished the American with new and elegant
                        furniture, and is now ready to entertain, in good style, all who may favor
                        him with a call.</p>
                    <p>Staunton can now boast of two as good hotels as can be found in the State,
                        and being easy of access from the Cities, North and South, and located in
                        the healthful region of our beautiful Valley, offers great inducements, as a
                        stopping place, to those visiting the mountains in quest of health or
                        pleasure.</p>
                    <p>We trust that the worthy proprietors of our hotels will receive from a
                        discerning public that patronage, which, in their efforts to please, they so
                        richly deserve.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Geo. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Ferrall</ln>
                        <fn>C. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Praises the "neat and clean appearance" of Staunton's two hotels, each
                    recently remodeled, and "as good hotels as can be found in the State."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>IT has been proposed to appoint some day on which the ladies of the South
                        might unite, annually, in an ovation to our departed heroes, by strewing
                        flowers on their graves planting evergreens &amp;c., and otherwise
                        showing their regard for those who fell in the late war in defence of our
                        cause. The 10th day of May, the anniversary of the death of our beloved
                        "Stonewall Jackson" has been suggested, and, as we deem it most appropriate,
                        we invite our ladies to unite on that day in paying homage to our
                        Confederate dead.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Suggests that "the ladies of the South might unite" to mourn the
                    Confederate dead on May 10, the anniversary of the death of Stonewall Jackson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1866.05.04.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
