<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1866/va.au.vs.1866.11.16">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>3/11</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-11-16">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day>16</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vs.1866.11.16.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>From the Spectator</head>
                <origin>Staunton Spectator</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article includes a letter from John B. Baldwin and a copy of his bill to
                    establish and incorporate the Augusta County Fair.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Exhibit of Whites and Blacks in Six of the Southern States</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>With statistics drawn from the 1860 Census, the article notes that blacks
                    outnumber whites in Mississippi, Louisiana, and South Carolina, the last two
                    with black majorities in over half of the respective states' counties.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vs.1866.11.16.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Lexington Gazette and Banner</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We observe in the last issue of the Lexington <emph rend="italic"
                        >Gazette</emph> and <emph rend="italic">Banner</emph> that the vote taken in
                        Rockbridge County, on the 3rd inst., on the question of that County
                        subscribing $100,000 to the Valley Railroad Stock, resulted almost
                        unanimously in favor of said subscription, the vote being 497 for 36 against
                        it.</p>
                    <p>Rockbridge County was the first to lead off on the question of County
                        subscriptions to the Valley Railroad stock and well has she acted. This
                        road, which all acknowledge will vastly benefit our section, can only be
                        built by the conjoint action of the people and communities along its route.
                        If they fail to rise equal to the occasion, the Valley Railroad scheme fails
                        or lies for a time dormant. There is not in the history of railroad
                        construction an instance, we believe, in which they have not increased the
                        material prosperity of the sections and States in which they were built.
                        With the advantages, so often stated of the Valley Railroad to our section
                        and county, it seems wonderful to us that our people should allow a fear of
                        increased taxation in this great work. If a man's taxes are $50 and his
                        actual profit only $500, it would be hard indeed to double the income, but
                        if by increasing his taxes slightly, you enhance his income in a greater
                        proportion then the matter assumes a different aspect. This will be the case
                        with the Valley Railroad--once built better prices for our products, reduced
                        rates for transportation, increased value to our possessions, influx of
                        money, &amp;c., and in a short time our incomes will greatly enhanced
                        while taxation has been but slightly increased. This matter has been dwelt
                        upon and so thoroughly discussed in the papers in the past that we do not
                        desire to weary our readers by its discussion at present, but simply desire
                        them to reflect upon this subject without prejudice, and we are satisfied
                        that they will not suffer to pass by, much less voluntarily thrust aside, a
                        scheme destined evidently to benefit them so much, but eagerly await the
                        time when they can cast their votes for the county contribution, thus making
                        the great step towards the rapid recuperation of our section and return to
                        its former prosperity.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors commend the residents of Rockbridge County, who voted
                    overwhelmingly in favor of subscribing $100,000 to the Valley Railroad Stock.
                    The tally was 497 for and 36 against.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Laments the results of the late election, which will give the Radicals even
                    greater power in the Fortieth Congress than they had in the Thirty-Ninth. With
                    the exception of Maryland, Delaware, and Kentucky, the article asserts, the
                    "fanaticism of the past few years is still as rabid as ever in the North."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gen. Howard, reports the article, is seeking the cooperation of black
                    religious leaders in Washington to help convince "surplus freedmen" in the
                    capital to leave the city. The problem, Howard asserts, is that there is only
                    enough work for 15,000 of the 22,000 living there.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vs.1866.11.16.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Informs readers that the outbreak of "fatal" diarrhea that struck Staunton
                    residents in recent weeks has subsided.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Booze</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Relates that J. W. Booze, a native of Augusta, has purchased the Chapman
                    Hotel in Salem, Roanoke County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gifford</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Board of Visitors of the Deaf, Dumb, and Blind has decided to divide
                    the institution's music department in two, reports the article; Prof. A. J.
                    Turner will head the Male Department while Mrs. Gifford will lead the Female
                    Department.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>O. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that O. P. Baldwin is scheduled to deliver a lecture on "'Fighting
                    considered one of the Fine Arts'" at the Staunton Lyceum next Monday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the stairway leading to Town Hall collapsed last week.
                    Fortunately, no one was injured in the accident.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Medicus</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Medicus" calls on local authorities to appoint a board of inspections to
                    examine conditions in Staunton and make recommendations to avoid future
                    outbreaks of diarrhea or any other cholera-like illnesses.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Tabitha G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 8, John W. Reed, of Frederick County, and Tabitha G. Myers were
                    married by Rev. C. Beard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bosworth</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dold</ln>
                        <fn>Mattie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stringer</ln>
                        <fn>W. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. John W. Bosworth, of Randolph County, W. Va., and Mattie E. Dold were
                    married by Rev. W. R. Stringer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arnold</ln>
                        <fn>Abner A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitesell</ln>
                        <fn>Amanda V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>J. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 8, Abner A. Arnold and Amanda V. Whitesell were married by Rev. J.
                    E. Armstrong.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tribbet</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuffey</ln>
                        <fn>Sue</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flournoy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 8, John Tribbet, of Rockbridge, and Sue McGuffey were married by
                    Rev. Flournoy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vs.1866.11.16.04">
            <pageNote>Page contains advertisements and news briefs.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
