<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1866/va.au.rv.1866.03.02">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/30/01</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-03-02">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>02</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1866.03.02.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Freedmen's Bureau Bill--Veto Message of the President</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A transcript of President Johnson's veto message of the Freedmen's Bureau
                    Bill. For the full text of the message, see the Valley Spirit, February 28,
                    1866.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1866.03.02.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Great Speech of President Johnson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A transcript of a speech given by President Johnson at Grover's Theater in
                    Washington. Johnson distinguishes himself from the Radicals by arguing that the
                    Southern states should be readmitted to the Union "when they have given
                    sufficient evidence of their loyalty and that they can be trusted, when they
                    yield obedience to the law." Johnson told the audience that "though vituperation
                    may come in its most violent character, I will be found standing by the
                    Constitution as the chief rock of our safety."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1866.03.02.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>ON Monday last, Court Day, Samuel Paul Esq., qualified as sheriff, and Messrs
                        John Towherman, A. B. Lightner, Wm. Mowry, Wm. H. Gamble and Geo. Harlan
                        qualified as deputies.</p>
                    <p>THE County Court caused to be entered on its records the flowing important
                        order:</p>
                    <p>VIRGINIA:--In Augusta County Court February 26th 1866.</p>
                    <p>It having been suggested to the Court, that the officers of the Freedmen's
                        Bureau have found some difficulty, in having their process executed, within
                        the limits of this County, and this Court, feeling a strong desire to
                        co-operate with the officers of the Bureau in the preservation of order, the
                        enforcement of the laws, and the protection of freedmen and refugees in all
                        their rights.</p>
                    <p>It is thereby ordered, to be entered on the records of this Court, that the
                        Court the Magistrates in their respective districts, and the Sheriff and
                        other officers of the Court, are ready and willing, at all times, to render
                        every necessary assistance in the officers of the Bureau in the discharge of
                        their duties, and that the Sheriff and Constables be and they are hereby
                        instructed to serve promptly, all process which may be placed in their hands
                        by the officers of the Bureau and to enjoin on the people the necessity of a
                        ready obedient thereto, and in other respects to render all the aid in their
                        power, in the executive of the laws of the United States.</p>
                    <p>Copy Teste.</p>
                    <p>WM. A. BURNETT, Clerk.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paul</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Towberman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lightner</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowry</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gamble</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harlan</ln>
                        <fn>Geo.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burnett</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists appointments to local offices and includes a copy of an order from
                    the county court, pledging to cooperate with the Freedmen's Bureau "in the
                    preservation of order, the enforcement of the laws, and the protection of
                    freedmen and refugees in all their rights."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Booth</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Last week a boy was seen attempting to fire the carpenter shop of Smith
                    &amp; Booth. The article reports that "it is not known whether he was white
                    or colored."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Levell</ln>
                        <fn>Jas.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Hare</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jas. Levell, jailed for passing a counterfeit bill to John O'Hare, was
                    tried and acquitted on February 22.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Jno. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jno. Brown, "a highly esteemed and worthy citizen of Augusta," died last
                    Sunday at his home near Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1866.03.02.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
