<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1867/va.au.ss.1867.01.01">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/10/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-01-01">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>01</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1867.01.01.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1867.01.01.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The New Year</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>This is the first day of the year 1867. We have all entered upon the duties
                        and responsibilities of another year, having just bidden a final adieu to
                        the year 1866, which, with all its hopes and fears, joys and sorrows,
                        triumphs and defeats, tribulations and blessings, is buried in the tomb of
                        the irrevocable past. We hope that our people will be more blessed in the
                        present than in the past year. For several years their trials have been
                        great-their cross has been heavy. We would console them with the christian
                        reflection that, "the heavier the cross the brighter the crown."</p>
                    <p>Though they have been of property, friends and liberty bereft, we would
                        counsel them not to yield to the suggestion of Despair, but to draw fresh
                        inspirations of Hope and "learn to labor and to wait." Nothing can be
                        accomplished by folding the arms in listlessness, and reposing supinely upon
                        the couch of indolence. We should have faith that better times are coming
                        and that better fortunes await us, but it should not be the faith that is
                        barren of works-our faith should be exemplified by works.-Faith,
                        unaccompanied by works, never "removed mountains," and never will. The
                        mountains of oppression now heaped, like Pelion upon Ossa; upon the bending
                        necks of our people will, never be removed by faith unaccompanied by
                        appropriate works. A calm, serene, steady, unswerving faith, accompanied by
                        firm resolves and persistent, active energy, will in time, "redeem,
                        regenerate and disenthrall" our people from the bonds by which they are at
                        present bound-it will yet make them a free and happy and prosperous people.
                        Turn a deaf ear to the counsels of Despair, and listen not to the siren
                        voice of Despondency, which lures to betray, and betrays to ruin.</p>
                    <p>Patriotism calls upon you to be hopeful, if not cheerful. Commence the New
                        Year with a hopeful spirit, and resolve to do your whole duty to your God,
                        your country, your friends, and yourself, throughout this, and all future
                        years.</p>
                    <p>This life is called "a vale of tears," but it is also a valley of happiness.
                        In this life, pleasure and pain, joy and sorrow, hope and fear are blended
                        like the different colors in a piece of tapestry-light and shade are
                        beautifully and wisely intermingled. In the language of another, on the year
                        which has just passed, and which was so full of shadows, "have we not
                        gathered, here and there, clusters of pleasant fruit by the way in which we
                        journeyed: Have we not bound leaves of healing with the cypress wreath and
                        sometimes found pearls in the bottom of our cups of sorrows?</p>
                    <p>Ah, yes! no life is wholly dark-there are flowers as well as brambles in
                        every garden-there are joys and victories as well as griefs and defeats in
                        every experience. And to-day, looking backward, though we see desolate
                        places here and there, we see also pleasant nooks where we have loitered,
                        and "golden epochs" whose glory crowned us with a halo. Therefore let us be
                        content.</p>
                    <p>The days pass-we grow old-threads of russet hue are woven into the woof of
                        life-silvery hairlines upon our foreheads-staff and crutch become familiar
                        companions-our eyes grow dim and we see but a little way ahead; but the days
                        in passing ripen us for heaven; the russet thread and silver hair win for us
                        homage and respect-the crutch and staff help us, weary pilgrims, to the home
                        that awaits us; and on our dim eyes we know a new light shall come, and
                        behind the narrowing sky there is a Better Land, where staff and crutch, and
                        ills of age, and the soiled vesture, wherein the immortal soul was wrapped
                        for a brief day, shall all be put away forever."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Encourages readers to "have faith that better times are coming, and that
                    better fortunes await us," and suggests that faith and "persistent, active
                    energy" will yet make them "a free and happy and prosperous people."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Richmond Enquirer</origin>
                <commentary>"The Richmond Enquirer says:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Supreme Court contains a majority of the same party that dominates in
                        Congress. It was supposed that sympathy in the objects was supposed that
                        sympathy in the objects sought, would beget an assent to the means employed,
                        and that the Congressional usurpation would be acquiesced in by the
                        co-partisans of the bench. The Chief Justice had been a high priest of
                        radicalism, and as a cabinet officer, had shared the responsibility of the
                        most irregular proceedings. The surprise therefore was general, when the
                        Supreme Court lately evinced a purpose to bring all laws and proceedings to
                        the test of the Constitution. If they shall adhere to this purpose, the
                        revolution is arrested, and the country is saved! The threats with which the
                        South is harassed, and her recuperation delayed will become impotent;
                        terrible indeed in sound, but only the roaring of a chained lion.</p>
                    <p>The pressure brought to bear on the members of the Supreme Court, is now
                        tremendous. Reproached as enemies, if not traitors, to their
                        party,--threatened with reconstruction,--threatened with
                        demolition,--insulted, abused, defied,--it remains to be seen whether they
                        will <emph rend="italic">stand firm</emph> to their office and their oaths.
                        Here lies the turning-point of the fight, the key of the battle-field. If
                        the authority of the Constitution shall be vindicated, the South is safe,
                        and the end of her troubles approached. Reconstruction with then come, not
                        through vain and humiliating abasements, but by appealing to the remedies of
                        the Constitution. "While this cardinal problem is receiving its solution,
                        the South has additional reason for an attitude of silence and firmness. Let
                        us wait and see whether or not we have indeed a constitution which
                        determines inter-State relations, or whether they are to be dictated by the
                        absolute will and whims of the men whose caprices and demands vary with the
                        passions and supposed party interests. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the Supreme Court is now "the turning-point of the fight, the
                    key of the battlefield," claiming that if the Court will "bring all laws and
                    proceedings to the test of the Constitution" then "the revolution is arrested,
                    and the country is saved."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Could Not Change the Decree of God</head>
                <origin>Washington Union</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Washington Union</emph> states that on Christmas
                        morning a colored woman walked into one of our churches and took a seat
                        among white people. The sexton asked her to take a seat in the part of the
                        church set apart for her color. She went to the minister and complained
                        saying she did not think there should be any distinction. The minister
                        replied: "My dear woman, God has made the distinction, and I cannot change
                        His decrees."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A "colored woman" who attempted to take a seat in the white section of a
                    church and told the minister she did not believe there should be a distinction
                    was told by the minister that God made the distinction, and he could not change
                    the decree of God.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1867.01.01.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Colonel James M. Lilley has been appointed Notary Public. At the last Court
                        he was qualified and gave the necessary bonds. Colonel Lilley is so well
                        known in this county that it is useless to speak of his qualifications for
                        the performance of the duties of this office. He is a County Surveyor and
                        travels over great portions of the county, and persons will thus have
                        opportunities to get the benefit of his services as Notary Public as well as
                        Surveyor.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Colonel James M. Lilley has been appointed Notary Public, and will continue
                    to serve as Surveyor as well.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Furnace for the Jail</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A furnace will be placed in the local jail in the next few days in response
                    to a recent attempted escape by a prisoner who set the floor on fire.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Local News--Distressing Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We are called upon, this week, to chronicle one of the most painful and
                        distressing accidents that has ever occurred in this community. Mrs. Ann
                        Eliza Matheny, wife of Mr. Wm. M. Matheny, of this place, was so badly
                        burned, on Christmas night, as to cause her death on last Thursday, about 1
                        o'clock. The circumstances connected with this sad affair, are about as
                        follows:--At a late hour on the night of the 25th ult. Mrs. M. was called
                        upon to get up to attend the wants of a sick child, and having succeeded in
                        quieting the child, and putting it to sleep in its crib, she laid down on a
                        lounge near the fire, and being fatigued, fell asleep. After being asleep
                        for some time, her clothes were set on fire by means of a spark, and by the
                        time she awoke and succeeded, by her screams, in arousing her husband, her
                        clothes were all in a light blaze and were nearly consumed. Her husband ran
                        to her relief, and with the aid of his brother, who was sleeping in a room
                        in the upstairs of the house, succeeded in extinguishing the flames-not,
                        however, until she was so badly burned as to render her recovery beyond the
                        reach of the most skillful physicians.-She lingered until last Thursday, the
                        27th ultimo, when the last messenger-death-put an end to her sufferings. Mr.
                        Matheny was also badly burned, in his endeavors to save the life of the
                        companion of his bosom, and will be laid up for several months, and, it is
                        fear will loose the use of his left hand entirely. Mrs. M. was about 44
                        years of age, and leaves three children and a helpless husband to mourn
                        their loss. They have our most heartfelt condolence.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Matheny</ln>
                        <fn>Ann Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Matheny</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Ann Eliza Matheny died from burns she received on Christmas Night when a
                    spark from the fire ignited her clothes while she slept.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>County Court--December Term</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">December Term</emph>.-Court met on Monday, December 24th,
                        J. Marshall McCue presiding, five Justices present. Robert G. Bickle and H.
                        H. Peck, were appointed a committee to purchase a furnace to heat the cells
                        of the Jail by steam. Thos. A. Bledoe and Wm. C. Eskridge renewed their
                        bonds as Notaries' Public. Col. James M. Lilly, qualified and gave bonds as
                        Notary Public. Ervin Reid, colored, was exempted from payment of County and
                        Parish Levies, on account of bodily infirmities. W. T. Lightner, qualified
                        as Deputy Sheriff. G. W. Bateman was appointed Surveyor of public roads,
                        vice, Smith Bateman, deceased. In case of Commonwealth <emph rend="italic"
                            >vs</emph> Martin H. Lotts, charged with attempting to fire the Jail,
                        remanded to Circuit Court for trial. The following Tribute to the memory of
                        Jefferson Kinney, Esq., was ordered to be published. </p>
                    <p>IN AUGUSTA COUNTY COURT, DECEMBER 26th 1866.-It having been made known to the
                        Court that Jefferson Kinney, Esq., who held the office of Clerk of this
                        Court for many years, departed this life on Friday, the 21st, inst., and the
                        Court being desirous of testifying their respect to his memory-it is ordered
                        to be entered on the Record.</p>
                    <p>That this Court has heard with deep sensibility, the news of the death of
                        Jefferson Kinney, Esq., who for 30 years filled the office of the Clerk of
                        this Court, during all which time he fulfilled every duty of his position
                        with singular fidelity and ability. The Court also desires to bear their
                        unanimous testimony to the high character of Mr. Kinney, as a gentleman of
                        integrity and upright deportment in all the relations of life, and their
                        sense of the loss which the community have sustained in his death, and to
                        express their deep sympathy with his family in their bereavement.</p>
                    <p>It is therefore further ordered that the Clerk of this Court cause a copy of
                        this order to be transmitted to the family of the deceased, and to assure
                        them of the condolence of each member of the Court with the family in their
                        affliction, and that this order be published in the Newspapers of Staunton.</p>
                    <p>Copy-Teste.</p>
                    <p>W. A. BURNETT, Clerk</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>W. A. Burnett</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J. Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>Robert G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bledsoe</ln>
                        <fn>Thos. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eskridge</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilly</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reid</ln>
                        <fn>Ervin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lightner</ln>
                        <fn>W. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bateman</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bateman</ln>
                        <fn>Smith</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lotts</ln>
                        <fn>Martin H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Jefferson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burnett</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A summary of recent proceedings of the county court, including a tribute to
                    the memory of the recently deceased Jefferson Kinney.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>MR. EDITOR:--Where were all "Ye Local Reporters" the night of the Cantata at
                        Augusta Female Seminary? I see only a brief notice of it-a very brief one in
                        any of the Papers.-Surely such a thing-so well gotten up and so happily
                        performed, should not be permitted to pass into oblivion with such a meager
                        notice and the <emph rend="italic">prime</emph> movers in it, why so richly
                        deserve the greatest amount of praise for their indefatigable exertions in
                        getting it up, are not even mentioned. I know full well the amount of time
                        they sacrificed and the interest they showed to make it an unexceptionable
                        performance.-Great credit is due Dr. J. L. Brown and his estimable daughter
                        (whose musical abilities are so well known and appreciated in this
                        community,) who labored so zealously and willingly for several weeks, to
                        make it no ordinary affair, and with the material they had to operate on-the
                        pliant minds-quick perceptions and intelligence of the young Ladies, it was
                        undoubtedly a brilliant affair. To attempt a description of the Cantata I am
                        unqualified, but that the character of Queen by Miss M. Hawkins and that of
                        Teacher by Dr. Brown were personated to perfection is beyond all question.
                        Their Solos were capitally performed and elicited great admiration: indeed
                        the Solos of those who personated Spring, Sunshine, Rainbow and Spray were
                        beautifully rendered and the choruses were truly admirable. But the most
                        interesting feature of the performance was the singing of the Little Ones,
                        who took the part of Dew Drops, among whom I noticed Mary Crawford, Emma
                        Wills and others, who sang like nightingales and acted their part to
                        perfection. </p>
                    <p>Too much praise cannot be awarded to Miss Brown for her unwearied exertions
                        in training the Pupils and it must, indeed, to be gratifying to her to see
                        that her efforts have been crowned with such complete success, and here let
                        me say that Dr. Brown who has lately cast his lot with us and who took so
                        lively an interest in getting up the Cantata is a gentleman well worthy the
                        confidence of the community.</p>
                    <p>As hundreds were unable to witness this delightful exhibition-being unable to
                        get into the crowded School Room-I hope to see it repeated at a future day,
                        in a larger Room, or in the Seminary Yard, and with a Stage, better adapted
                        to represent a Forest Scene, and large enough to give freedom of motion to
                        the Performers, when I hope, Mr. Editor, you may have the pleasure of
                        witnessing it.</p>
                    <p>Till then adieu. A WITNESS</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>A Witness</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawkins</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wills</ln>
                        <fn>Emma</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Praises a recent concert at the Augusta Female Seminary where the young
                    ladies "sang like nightingales and acted their part to perfection."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Read</ln>
                        <fn>C. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coleman</ln>
                        <fn>Talbot B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>Marcia A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Marcia Gordon, of New Kent, and Talbot Coleman, of Staunton, were married
                    at the home of the bride's father in New Kent on December 25 by Rev. C. H. Read.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaws</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stringer</ln>
                        <fn>W. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bailey</ln>
                        <fn>Geo. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaw</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rebecca Shaw and George Bailey were married near Sherando on December 27 by
                    Rev. W. R. Stringer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaws</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stringer</ln>
                        <fn>W. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bridge</ln>
                        <fn>Jesse R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trevy</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elizabeth Trevy and Jesse Bridge were married near Sherando on December 27
                    by Rev. W. R. Stringer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaws</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stringer</ln>
                        <fn>W. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Falls</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lunsford</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elizabeth Lunsford and Jeremiah Falls were married near Sherando on
                    December 27 by Rev. W. R. Stringer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richards</ln>
                        <fn>John E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trusler</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stringer</ln>
                        <fn>W. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Trusler and John Richards were married at South River on December 17
                    by Rev. W. R. Stringer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stringer</ln>
                        <fn>W. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>John E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitesell</ln>
                        <fn>Martha J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Martha Whitesell and John Harris were married on December 20 by Rev. W. R.
                    Stringer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stringer</ln>
                        <fn>W. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pannell</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shomo</ln>
                        <fn>Lucy Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lucy Jane Shomo and Adam Pannell were married on December 24 by Rev. W. R.
                    Stringer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1867.01.01.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
