<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1867/va.au.ss.1867.05.14">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/28/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-05-14">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>14</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1867.05.14.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1867.05.14.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Jeff. Davis in Richmond</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Jefferson Davis arrived in Richmond last Saturday where he was
                    greeted by a large crowd of onlookers. He looked "older and rather haggard and
                    feeble" compared to the last time the Richmond public saw him, and offered no
                    comment on his imprisonment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Negroes and Street Cars</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The New York Sun says that a great deal of indignation has lately been wasted
                        upon the people of Richmond because they dislike the ideas of having negroes
                        ride in the street cars. It is a foolish prejudice, of course, and one which
                        disappeared in this city several years ago But why do not the special
                        champions of the Freedmen direct a little of their surplus indignation
                        toward Northern cities in which the same prejudice exists. The people of
                        Philadelphia have persistently refused to allow negroes in their street
                        cars, and it as only by coercion on the part of the late Legislature that
                        they were finally obliged to sacrifice their prejudice. It is somewhat
                        singular that the self-constituted defenders of the negroes give their
                        attention exclusively to fault-finding in the South paying, no attention to
                        the colored people of the North.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Refers to the conflicts in Richmond over allowing blacks to ride the
                    streetcars as "a foolish prejudice" and encourages the Northerners who dislike
                    the practice to address the prejudice in their own cities.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Another Street Car Difficulty</head>
                <origin>Richmond Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that another conflict has occurred in Richmond over access to
                    street cars. The compromise proposed by Gen. Schofield, which called for four of
                    the six cars to be open to all patrons and the other two reserved for whites
                    only, has, according to the article, not given blacks "satisfaction, and they
                    now express their intention of riding in any car which they like."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1867.05.14.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that General Lee will be in Staunton this week for the Episcopal
                    Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On yesterday, the scaffolding to the Freedmen's Church, which is in course of
                        erection, fell, whilst Mr. Lewis Peaco, Mr. -------- Hughes, and one or two
                        others, were on it. None were hurt, we understand, except Mr. --------
                        Hughes. He was considerably hurt, but not seriously injured.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peaco</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hughes</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Scaffolding collapsed yesterday at the Freedmen's Church, which is
                    currently under construction. No serious injuries are reported.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Local News--Memorial Day</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The fourth anniversary of the death of "Stonewall" Jackson-10th May, 1863-was
                        appropriately celebrated in this place on Friday last. The ceremonies were
                        inaugurated at the Methodist Church, and presented a most interesting
                        spectacle.</p>
                    <p>The Augusta Fire Company, Capt. Waters, and the Deaf and Dumb and Blind Fire
                        Company, Capt. Frion, turned out in their beautiful uniforms. The
                        "Stonewall" Band and the Blind Band, of this place, were both present to add
                        interest to the occasion.</p>
                    <p>At the church, which was crowded to overflowing, the Rev. Wm. E. Baker, of
                        the Presbyterian Church, offered up a fervent prayer for our country, and
                        for the uplifting of the hand which is laid so heavily upon our late chief
                        magistrate, Jefferson Davis.</p>
                    <p>Col. Bolivar Christian, in introducing the orator of the day, made some
                        brief, but eloquent and appropriate remarks, and read with great effect, the
                        following touching poem, written for the Memorial Association of
                        Fredericksburg, but Father Ryan of Knoxville, the author of the "Conquered
                        Banner," and the "Sword of Lee:" <lb/></p>
                    <p>Gather the sacred dust</p>
                    <p>Of the warriors tried and true,</p>
                    <p>Who bore the flag of our Nation's trust,</p>
                    <p>And fell in the cause, though Lost, still Just,</p>
                    <p>And died for me and you. <lb/></p>
                    <p>Gather them each and all!</p>
                    <p>From the Private to the Chief,</p>
                    <p>Come they from hovel or princely hall,</p>
                    <p>They fell for us, and for them should fall '</p>
                    <p>The tear of Nation's grief. <lb/></p>
                    <p>Gather the corpses strewn</p>
                    <p>O'er many a battle plain,</p>
                    <p>From many a grave that lies so lone,</p>
                    <p>Without a name and without a stone</p>
                    <p>Gather the Southern slain. <lb/></p>
                    <p>We care not whence they came,</p>
                    <p>Dear is their lifeless clay!</p>
                    <p>Whether unknown or known to fame,</p>
                    <p>Their cause and country still the same-</p>
                    <p>They died-and wore the Gray. <lb/></p>
                    <p>Whenever the brave have died,</p>
                    <p>They should not rest apart;</p>
                    <p>Living they struggled side by side-</p>
                    <p>Why should the hand of Death divide</p>
                    <p>A single heart from heart! <lb/></p>
                    <p>Gather their scattered clay,</p>
                    <p>Wherever it may rest;</p>
                    <p>Just as they marched to the bloody fray,</p>
                    <p>Just as they fell on the battle day,</p>
                    <p>Bury them breast to breast. <lb/></p>
                    <p>The foeman need not dread</p>
                    <p>This gathering of the brave;</p>
                    <p>Without sword or flag, and without soundless tread,</p>
                    <p>We muster once more our deathless dead-</p>
                    <p>Out of each lonely grave. <lb/></p>
                    <p>The foeman need not frown;</p>
                    <p>They are all powerless now-</p>
                    <p>We gather them here, and we lay them down,</p>
                    <p>And tears and prayers are the only crown</p>
                    <p>We bring to wreathe each brow. <lb/></p>
                    <p>And the dead thus meet the dead,</p>
                    <p>While the living o'er them weep;</p>
                    <p>And the men whom Lee and "Stonewall" led,</p>
                    <p>And the hearts that once together bled,</p>
                    <p>Together still shall sleep. <lb/></p>
                    <p>Col. C. T. O'Ferrall, the selected orator of the occasion, then delivered the
                        anniversary oration-marked with beautiful thoughts and language and touched
                        the hearts of many of those present, causing the tear of affection and
                        sorrow to flow down the cheek of many a heart-stricken one. He referred to a
                        number of the "bravest and best" men of our town and county who fell in
                        defence of their homes and firesides-whose memories will ever be cherished
                        and whose memories will ever be cherished and whose graves will be kept
                        green by the tears and consecrated by the prayers of their loved ones in
                        their now bereaved and desolated homes. An allusion to the self-exiled
                        Early, the latest commander of the forlorn hope in the Valley drew forth
                        irrepressible tribute of applause.</p>
                    <p>At the close of Col. O'Ferrall's address, the Rev. Jno. L. Clarke, pastor of
                        the Methodist Church, pronounced the benediction. The order of procession to
                        the Cemetery was then announced by Col. Baldwin, the chief Marshall, as
                        follows:</p>
                    <p>1. Stonewall Band, Maj.</p>
                    <p>2. Band of D. &amp; D. &amp; B. Institution, Garber,</p>
                    <p>3. Clergy, Marshall.</p>
                    <p>4. Press.</p>
                    <p>5. Confederate Soldiers, Maj. Hall, Marshal.</p>
                    <p>6. Fire Companies, Capt. Waters, Marshal.</p>
                    <p>7. Female Schools, Col. Christian and Captain Berkeley, Marshals</p>
                    <p>8. Ladies, Maj. Hanger and Capt. Harrison, Marshals.</p>
                    <p>9. Male Schools, Capt. Bumbgardner, Marshal.</p>
                    <p>10. Citizens, Capt. Balthis, and Capt. Arnall Marshals.</p>
                    <p>The long procession of near a mile in length was a scene of touching
                        interest; and , arriving at the Cemetery, the gentlemen stood reverently
                        with uncovered heads, while the ladies in tender silence spread wreaths of
                        evergreens and flowers of early spring upon the graves of the loved and
                        lost. Amid these sacred scenes-the solemn precincts of the dead-only the
                        magnanimous feelings of our common nature had place-any emotions of
                        hostility which may have survived the civil strife, were suppressed; for it
                        was observed in the evening that the graves of the federal soldiers, killed
                        in battle and temporarily buried there, were all religiously respected and
                        garnished.</p>
                    <p>The ceremonies of the Cemetery being concluded, the procession returned in
                        order to the town and was dismissed by the chief Marshall. The events of the
                        day can but impress upon the ladies of the Memorial Association how truly
                        their labors of love are appreciated by our people.</p>
                    <p>The distant friends of the dead may well feel comforted in knowing from the
                        spirit of this occasion, that these hallowed graves will ever be tenderly
                        cherished-</p>
                    <p>"The sunshine of the Southern sky</p>
                    <p>Smiles sweetly on them here,</p>
                    <p>And loving hearts and hands watch by</p>
                    <p>Each hero's sepulchre."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Ferrall</ln>
                        <fn>C. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>Jno. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>Maj.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waters</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berkely</ln>
                        <fn>Capt.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Maj.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrison</ln>
                        <fn>Capt.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>Capt.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Balthis</ln>
                        <fn>Capt.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Friou</ln>
                        <fn>Capt.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arnall</ln>
                        <fn>Capt.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Summarizes the local Memorial Day proceedings, which included addresses and
                    a procession to the Soldiers' Cemetery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>John L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cupp</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cupp</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Cupp and Mary Jane Cupp were married on May 13 in the Augusta County
                    Clerk's Office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCadden</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry McCadden died near Greenville on February 13 at the age of 79.
                    McCadden was a veteran of the War of 1812.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1867.05.14.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
