<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1867/va.au.ss.1867.03.05">
	<header>
		<title>Staunton Spectator</title>
		<tagger>
			<taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
			<tagDate>07/24/00</tagDate>
			<tagNote/>
		</tagger>
		<address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
		<date n="1867-03-05">
			<year>1867</year>
			<month norm="03">March</month>
			<day>05</day>
			<weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
		</date>
		<frequency>weekly</frequency>
		<extent>04</extent>
		<editionNote/>
	</header>
	<paperBody>
		<page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1867.03.05.01">
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1867.03.05.02">
			<div type="e">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>Our Mother, Virginia</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>Our good old mother, Virginia, being about to be outraged, some have, it is
						said, doubted whether or not they should advise her, to yield her <emph
							rend="italic">consent </emph>, to avoid , as they supposed, rougher
						treatment in the act. The honor of a State like the virtue of a woman,
						cannot be robbed or taken by violence-it can only be <emph rend="italic"
							>given </emph> away or lost by the <emph rend="italic">consent </emph>
						of the party ruined. </p>
					<p>Virginia has lost all but her <emph rend="italic">honor </emph>, and <emph
							rend="italic">that </emph> she should prize as dearly, and guard as
						jealously, as a woman the jewel of her virtue.-Grievous and oppressive
						wrongs may be inflicted upon her, vials of infuriate wrath, as hot as fused
						lava, may be poured upon her head-these she can bear; because they do not
						affect her good name and reputation; but the sacrifice of her <emph
							rend="italic">honor </emph>, she cannot bear, because that links her
						name with infamy. Good bless Virginia, and may none of her sons ever do any
						act inconsistent with her cherished honor. </p>
					<p>The honor of Virginia forbids the acknowledgement of the validity of the
						unconstitutional act of Congress by calling a Convention in accordance with
						its provisions; or the adoption of the Constitutional amendment, which she
						so emphatically rejected on the ground <emph rend="italic">that her honor
							forbade it</emph>. </p>
					<p>We may add that not only honor, but sound policy, also, forbids the adoption
						of either of these propositions. If these outrages be forced upon us as
							<emph rend="italic">against our consent</emph>, all the odium justly
						attaching to them belongs to the perpetrators and they would be delighted if
						we would relieve them of that odium by <emph rend="italic">consenting
						</emph> to their perpetration. By consenting, we become parties to the act,
						and change its character from a gross outrage forced upon us to a
						self-imposed abasement. </p>
					<p>Honor and sound policy demand that Virginia, and the other Southern States,
						should stand firmly by their rights, and resolve to bear with heroic
						fortitude whatever may be forced upon them. Their motto, so far as
						oppressive Federal legislation is concerned, should be:-- "<emph
							rend="italic">Masterly inactivity and heroic fortitude.</emph>" </p>
					<p>The South should not suffer her equanimity to be disturbed-she should be as
						calm as the sleeping ocean and as firm as the rock-ribbed mountains.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Uses a highly sexualized comparison of "the honor of a State" and "the
					virtue of a woman" to advocate the rejection of the constitutional amendment.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>The People of Augusta</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>We think we know the character of the citizens of their county, and , if we
						be not egregiously mistaken, no degree of oppression will induce them to do
						any act, or yield their voluntary consent to any act, which would directly
						or indirectly derogate from their character, as an honest, high-minded and
						patriotic community, faithful and true to the constitutional liberties of
						the people, and will, therefore, not consent to reorganize the validity of
						any unconstitutional act passed by Congress.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Expresses the belief that the people of the county would not allow their
					character as "an honest, high-minded and patriotic community" to be sullied by
					recognizing "the validity of any unconstitutional act passed by Congress."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>Moral and Political Conscience</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>A State has a moral as well as a political conscience-the former considers
						what is right, the latter what is expedient. At Athens these were
						represented respectively by Aristides and Themistocles, when the former
						said, in substance, what Themistocles recommends would promote the interest
						of Athens, but it would not be <emph rend="italic">right </emph>. </p>
					<p>Both the moral and political conscience of Virginia would be violated, in our
						opinion, by either the adoption of the constitutional amendment, or the
						recognition of the validity of the force bill by calling a Convention in
						accordance with its provisions, as the adoption of either course would be
						both wrong and inexpedient. A State, like an individual, cannot afford to
						violate its moral conscience.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Argues that to adopt the constitutional amendment or recognize the validity
					of the Force Bill by calling a convention would violate both the moral and
					political conscience of Virginia.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>01</column>
				<head/>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The Sherman-Shellabarger bill, known as the Force Bill, passed over
					presidential veto last week, by votes of 145 to 67 in the House and 38 to 10 in
					the Senate.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>02</column>
				<head>The Proper View</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>In discussing, with what we conceive to be the proper spirit, whether the
						Legislature should do anything by which they would recognize the validity of
						the unconstitutional and oppressive measures of Congress, the Lynchburg
							<emph rend="italic">News </emph>, asks: Shall we tamely surrender every
						constitutional right, acknowledge ourselves without the pale of law, and
						admit that our political privileges, our property, our liberty and our
						lives, are held at the mercy or caprice of the Radicals in Congress? </p>
					<p>We concur with the <emph rend="italic">News </emph> that if we are determined
						to find relief at all from the tyrannical oppressions of the Radical party,
						it can only be had through the reaction of the popular mind at the North. If
						this be granted it follows, as a matter of course, that the more flagrant
						the usurpations, the more palpable the violations of the Constitution, the
						more tyrannical the outrages enacted by this party, the more certainly and
						speedily will this reaction occur. In this light, then, the very indignities
						which we suffer, and the additional wrongs with which we are threatened, may
						under Heaven, prove the most efficient means for bringing about the
						destruction of that party which was perpetuated these enormities. </p>
					<p>Let us never accept as valid a bill which abrogates every night we ever
						enjoyed; let us never renounce every attribute of manhood; surrender
						unconditionally every legal safe-guard thrown around our property and our
						lives by virtue of the Constitution, and cravenly acknowledge our own
						unworthiness to live, except at the mercy of such men as Stevens and his
						myrmidons.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Argues that if relief "from the tyrannical oppressions of the Radical
					party" will only occur when sentiment in the North changes, the current
					suffering of the South may "prove the most efficient means for bringing about
					the destruction of that party which has perpetrated these enormities."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>02</column>
				<head>Confiscation</head>
				<origin>Baltimore Gazette</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>A Washington letter in the Baltimore Gazette says that a bill has been
						prepared providing for extensive confiscations of southern landed estates.
						The idea that the "military bill" is the crowning enormity, that it contains
						the ultimatum of the Radicals, that it is as intended as a finality, is
						openly derided by all prominent members of the dominant party, adds the same
						letter. They say they have applied the "entering wedge"--their ultimate
						design is to seize upon every inch of southern soil. I understand that the
						confiscation bill I have alluded to was seen by Mr. Johnson, your Senator,
						and that this knowledge of the existence of such project is alleged by him
						in palliation of his vote upon the military bill.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>A letter found in the Baltimore Gazette claims that a bill "providing for
					extensive confiscation of Southern landed estates has been prepared" and claims
					that the Radicals' "ultimate design is to seize upon every inch of southern
					soil."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>05</column>
				<head>Kansas and Female Suffrage</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The following is the joint resolution on the suffrage question, which passed
						the Kansas Legislature: <emph rend="italic">Resolved </emph>, That the
						proposition to strike the word "male" from section one of article five of
						the constitution of the State is hereby submitted to the electors of the
						State for ratification or rejection, in compliance with section one of
						article fourteen of the constitution. </p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>The resolution to strike the word "male" from the Constitution has been
					submitted to the electors of Kansas for ratification or rejection.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1867.03.05.03">
			<div type="a">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>Local News--Another Attempt to Escape</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The prisoner, Martin H. Lotts, who attempted some time since to effect his
						escape by burning through the floor of his cell, was about to make his
						escape on Saturday night last, when it was discovered by his fellow
						prisoner, Alex W. Greaver, who made him desist. By means of knives and a
						file furnished by his wife, concealed between the soles of shoes presented
						to him by her, Lotts had severed his hobbles and a bar of the window, and
						was about attaching a rope by which to effect his escape, when he was
						discovered by Greaver. A flight ensued between these prisoners, in which we
						believe, both were considerably hurt.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Lotts</ln>
						<fn>Martin H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Greaver</ln>
						<fn>Alex W.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Martin Lotts made a second attempt to escape from the local jail. His plans
					were foiled by another prisoner, Alex W. Greaver.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>Local News--Fair and Dinner</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>We have several times called attention to the fact that the Ladies' Memorial
						Association of this place will hold a Fair and give a Dinner on the 4th
						Monday of this month, to provide means to prosecute the work on the Soldiers
						Cemetery which the ladies have undertaken with such laudable spirit. We hope
						that liberal contributions will be sent in from all parts of the country and
						from adjoining counties. The contributions will be sent in from all parts of
						the county and from adjoining counties. The contributions should be
						deposited with Capt. Chas. Arnall at the Va. Central R. R. Depot. We have
						been informed that the Stage lines and R. R. will not charge for
						contributions of provisions carried by them for the benefit of the Fair.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Arnall</ln>
						<fn>Chas.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Capt.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>The Ladies' Memorial Association will hold a fair and dinner to raise money
					for work on the Soldiers' Cemetery.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>02</column>
				<head>Local News--In Council for the Town of Staunton</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>March 2nd 1867</p>
					<p>Wm. B. Kaysor, James A. Piper, John M. Hardy, A. M. Bruce and F. M. Young
						were appointed Commissioners to Superintend, and Wm. Craig of the officer to
						conduct the election to be held at the Court House on the Wednesday after
						the first Monday in April next, for a Mayor, a Sergeant, and eleven persons
						to serve as Recorder, Alderman and Commissioners.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Kayser</ln>
						<fn>Wm. B.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Piper</ln>
						<fn>James A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hardy</ln>
						<fn>John A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Bruce</ln>
						<fn>A. M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Young</ln>
						<fn>F. M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Craig</ln>
						<fn>Wm.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Lists the officer and superintendents appointed for the April elections.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>04</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Dice</ln>
						<fn>J. C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Evans</ln>
						<fn>Jacob</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Ramer</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Mrs.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Evans</ln>
						<fn>Hannah</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Jacob Evans and Hannah Evans, of the Bean settlement, were married at the
					residence of Mrs. Ramer, of Moorefield, by Rev. J. C. Dice.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>04</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Beard</ln>
						<fn>C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Alexander</ln>
						<fn>Robert C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Jordan</ln>
						<fn>Mary Susan</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Mary Susan Jordan and Robert Alexander were married on February 21 by Rev.
					C. Beard.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>04</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Farran</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev. Father</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Wholey</ln>
						<fn>William</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Collins</ln>
						<fn>Hannah</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Hannah Collins and William Wholey, of the Stonewall Brigade, were married
					at St. Francis' Church on February 27 by Rev. Father Farran.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>04</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Armstrong</ln>
						<fn>J. E.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Allen</ln>
						<fn>Tipten W.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Patterson</ln>
						<fn>Mary B.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>McCoy</ln>
						<fn>Judson</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Mary Patterson and Tipten Allen, of Shenandoah county, were married on
					February 21 by Rev. J. E. Armstrong.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>04</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Helmick</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Cease</ln>
						<fn>N. K.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Johnson</ln>
						<fn>Helen T.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Helen T. Johnson, recently of Holmes county, Miss., and N. K. Cease, of
					Staunton, were married in Harrison county, West Virginia on January 8 by Rev.
					Helmick.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>04</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Thompson</ln>
						<fn>Horatio</fn>
						<sf>D. D.</sf>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Heizer</ln>
						<fn>J. Frank</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>McCormick</ln>
						<fn>Phebe Ann</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>McCormick</ln>
						<fn>Robert</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>J. Frank Heizer and Phebe Ann McCormick were married at the home of the
					bride's father on February 21 by Rev. Horatio Thompson.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>04</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Thompson</ln>
						<fn>Horatio</fn>
						<sf>D. D.</sf>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Ballew</ln>
						<fn>John Dorsey</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Lotts</ln>
						<fn>Catherine</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Lotts</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Catherine Lotts and John Dorsey Ballew were married near Old Providence
					Church on February 28 by Rev. Horatio Thompson.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1867.03.05.04">
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
	</paperBody>
</hwp>
