<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1867/va.au.ss.1867.11.19">
	<header>
		<title>Staunton Spectator</title>
		<tagger>
			<taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
			<tagDate>01/09/01</tagDate>
			<tagNote/>
		</tagger>
		<address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
		<date n="1867-11-19">
			<year>1867</year>
			<month norm="11">November</month>
			<day>19</day>
			<weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
		</date>
		<frequency>weekly</frequency>
		<extent>04</extent>
		<editionNote/>
	</header>
	<paperBody>
		<page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1867.11.19.01">
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1867.11.19.02">
			<div type="e">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>Meeting on Monday Next</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>We hope that the good citizens of this great and noble and patriotic and
						liberty-loving and Constitution loving county will turn out, <emph
							rend="italic">en masse</emph>, on Monday next-Court day-to attend the
						meeting which will be held in the Court house on that day to appoint
						delegates to the Conservative Convention which will meet in Richmond on
						Wednesday, the 11th of December, for the purpose of organizing of the
						Conservative party of the State that this grand "Old Commonwealth" may be
						saved from the dire calamity of Radical rule and negro domination. This
						noble old State is on the verge of the abyss of ruin. None should fail to
						rush to her rescue. Our mother is threatened with a fate more to be dreaded
						than death. Can any of her sons refuse to fly to her relief? Liberty is
						threatened with violence and overthrow. Can any refuse to adopt the only
						means to preserve it? The son of Virginia who fails to do his duty in this
						hour of peril is undeserving of his parentage-he should have been the child
						of some other mother. </p>
					<p>We hope that the citizens of this county will show by turning out next Monday
						that the appreciate the perils which threaten-that they know their duty, and
						are resolved to perform it. We wish to see the Court house crowded with
						intelligent and patriotic citizens-we wish to feel the strong, healthy
						pulsations of their hearts, and to witness their faces radiant with
						expressions of patriotic emotions. We wish them to demonstrate that they are
						the friends of liberty, and worthy sons of their good Old mother-Virginia.</p>
					<p>We hope that the Court will allow the meeting to be held at an early hour-not
						later than 12 o'clock-that all from the country who may be present may be
						enabled to stay till the meeting be concluded.</p>
					<p>We wish as many as possible to participate in its proceedings. We hope that
						the meeting will appoint the best men to be found in the various parts of
						the county, and that those who may be thus honored will feel it incumbent
						upon them to attend the Convention. To be appointed a delegate to that
						Convention will not be an empty honor. It is not necessary to appoint many,
						but they should be men of ability, character, wisdom, and reliability, and
						such as will attend.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Urges the "good citizens" of Augusta to attend a meeting at the Courthouse
					next Monday to appoint delegates to the upcoming Conservative Convention in
					Richmond. Asserts that it is their duty to help save Virginia "from the dire
					calamity of Radical rule and negro domination."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>01</column>
				<head/>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>WE would remind our readers that the Court has postponed the day of election
						on the question of subscription of the sum of $300,000 to the stock of the
						Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad till the third Thursday in December, the 19th
						of that month. We would again request such as are able to argue the
						propriety of voting this subscription, to send their communications to us
						for publication in the <emph rend="italic">Spectator</emph>. One side has
						been presented in these columns, and we would like for our readers to see
						the other side argued with the same degree of ability.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Reports that the Court has postponed the vote on a subscription for the
					Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad until December 19 and urges those who support the
					subscription to submit their arguments to the Spectator.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>03</column>
				<head>Hunnicuttism and Negroism</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>"Hunnicutt and his set" are terrified, not by their excesses, but by the
						discovery of them, and all sorts of disclaimers and explanations are being
						made. We should have heard no such disclaimers and explanations but for the
						publicity given by the press to the incendiary speeches of these white and
						black Jacobins.-Public sentiment was so shocked here, and will be so shocked
						at the North by the disclosure made that it becomes of the first importance
						to speak out of their dilemma as well as they can. To this end the effort is
						being made to produce the impression that Hunnicutt's negro associate on the
						Convention ticket, Lindsey, did not say what he is reported as saying, and
						that what he actually did say was disapproved of by the meeting. As some of
						our readers probably failed to see what he did say, we re-produce it-as
						follows: "<emph rend="italic">That before any of his children should suffer
							for food, the streets of Richmond should run knee-deep in blood; and he
							thanked God the negroes had learned to use guns, pistols and
						ramrods.</emph>" The reporter says this seditious language received "<emph
							rend="italic">the smiling approval Hunnicutt and the cheers of the
							ignorant masses</emph>." </p>
					<p>The disclaimers and explanations hypocritically and falsely made were thus
						met and refuted by our neighbor, the <emph rend="italic">Dispatch</emph>,
						yesterday: </p>
					<p>The report which appeared in the <emph rend="italic">Dispatch</emph> on
						yesterday of the Radical meeting on Friday night last was made by a leading
						radical of this city, who was present on the occasion, and who says every
						word reported is true. The attempt now made by Lindsey and his friends to
						break the force of his language is altogether an afterthought. They did not
						know when his remarks were uttered that they would be published, nor did
						they know that the grand jury of the Hustings Court of this city would, on
						yesterday, take steps to bring these black conspirators against the peace of
						society to trial for their treasonable and bloodthirsty doctrines.-But,
						taking the alarm, they now seek to retreat from the position which they
						assumed in their secret conclave. The resolutions above adopted virtually
						admit the correctness of our report of the Friday night meeting. </p>
					<p>A card, signed by John Oliver, Matthew Hopes, Fields Cooke, R. C. Hobson, R.
						W. Johnson (colored men,) which appeared yesterday in one of the city
						papers, admits that the speech was delivered as reported, and protests
						against "both Mr. Lindsey and his "speech." But in doing so, they use this
						very singular language: "That it was not sympathy "with Mr. Lindsey which
						caused the meeting "to applaud him on the above occasion, but <emph
							rend="italic">the ludicrousness of his ideas!</emph>" <emph
							rend="italic">Ludicrous</emph>-that "the streets of Richmond should run
						knee "deep in blood!" Very funny, this-a capital joke. The white people
						whose lives are thus threatened cannot be brought to view it in the light.
						They are deficient, perhaps, in that acute sense of the ludicrous which
						belongs to the sacred race. </p>
					<p>"Hunnicutt and his set" cannot gloss over or back down from this affair. It
						will forever stand against them.</p>
					<p>But it is not in Richmond alone that the fruits of their diabolical teachings
						are seen.-We hear of threats, plots and incendiary demonstrations from
						various parts of the State.-Almost simultaneously with this Richmond affair
						we hear of a meeting of fifty negroes in Campbell county, called to devise
						an effectual mode of shooting and hanging the different white people and the
						few black Conservatives in the neighborhood. We hear also, from King William
						county, of an attempt at the Court house on Court day by sixty or seventy
						negroes under the leadership of the white delegate elect to the convention,
						E. W. Massey, to mob Major Frank A. Butts, a former agent of the Freedmen's
						Bureau. A letter to the <emph rend="italic">Enquirer</emph> says: </p>
					<p>"Major Butts was quietly playing backgammon with a friend in the parlor of
						the hotel when he heard furious yells and shouts from the negroes, daring
						him to come out, threaten the negroes, daring him to come out, threatening
						to take his life-"we will have his heart's blood: we will kill the d-d rebel
						on sight," &amp;c., they cried. The Major was only dissuaded from
						meeting them, pistol in hand, by the entreaties of his friends who did not
						wish to see him uselessly sacrifice himself. The negroes marched around
						awhile with drum and fife, and finally dispersed after this bravado.</p>
					<p>"But now for the more serious and ugly part of this business: Major Butts
						went before a magistrate and sued out a warrant for the arrest of the ring
						leaders, but the officer who went to execute it was defied by the negroes,
						who were banded together, and refused to be arrested, as they said, "by a
						rebel officer, or tried before a rebel court."</p>
					<p>The same letter says:</p>
					<p>Under the administration of Major Butts, of New York, Lieutenant Choice of
						Pennsylvania, and their predecessors in the Bureau-all of whom have been
						conservative officers and gentlemen-the relations of the races in this
						county had been very harmonious. But ever since the advent of Lieutenant C.
						Goodyear, a Radical, as I learn, from Connecticut, as agent of the Bureau,
						trouble has been brewing. The negroes have been permitted to form military
						organizations, and to drill openly at public places, in defiance of the laws
						of Congress and the orders of General Schofield; and this was the case even
						after Lieutenant Colonel Ayres, a military commissioner, was sent down here
						to investigate and take testimony touching the facts I have detailed.</p>
					<p>What do all these things mean? The same design pervades them all-vengeance
						against the whites-all whites, Southerners, Northerners and foreigners-and a
						few mean white monsters are at the bottom of them. Is there no remedy? We
						are under the exclusive control of the Federal Government and the remedy
						must be found by the authorities of the Government. There is much to
						exasperate us all in the state of things to which we refer, but we advise
						calmness and entire abstinence from all retaliatory measures, not only from
						violent acts, but from menaces and angry words. It will be time enough for
						our citizens to think of devising means for the protection of their lives
						and their homes and their firesides when the Government authorities show
						either inability or unwillingness to interpose in their behalf. Negroism is
						now culminating in Virginia, and its excesses and our moderation will stand
						out in such contrast as to make it hateful throughout the whole country.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Drawing on a speech delivered at the Constitutional Convention, and other
					rumors from throughout the state, the author contends that blacks are consumed
					by the desire for "vengeance against the whites--all whites, Southerners,
					Northerners and foreigners." As a result, the article suggests that "citizens"
					begin "devising means for the protection of their lives and homes."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>04</column>
				<head>Virginia Conservative Press Convention</head>
				<origin>Richmond Enquirer and Examiner; Richmond Whig; Lynchburg News</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>We have received a circular from Messrs. R. Mauzy, W. H. H. Lynn and A. M.
						Garber, Jr., the editors, respectively of three papers published in
						Staunton, proposing a convention of the Conservative editors of the State,
						to assemble in this city on the 11th of December, for the purpose of
						adopting some hue of policy to be pursued by all in order to secure the
						rejection of the constitution which will be framed by the Mongrel
						Convention.</p>
					<p>Most heartily do we concur in the measure, and thank our Staunton
						cotemporaries for making the proposition. The Conservative Convention to be
						composed by the ablest and wisest men in the State, will meet here at the
						same time, and the two bodies will be able, we doubt not, to effect such a
						work as will save this grand Old Commonwealth from Radical rule and negro
						domination.</p>
					<p>The circular adds another important proposition in a modest postscript,
						suggesting that "any matter of general interest to the press might be
						considered at the same time."</p>
					<p>The entire proposition has our cordial approbation, and we hope it will be
						agreed to by the entire press of Virginia. every editor in the State, who
						has the true interests of the Commonwealth at heart, should be
							present.-<emph rend="italic">Enquirer and Examiner</emph></p>
					<p>CONVENTION OF EDITORS.-The editors of the three Staunton papers are out in a
						circular to their brethren of the Press, recommending and requisition them
						to meet in the city of Richmond, on the 11th of December proximo, for the
						purpose of adopting a uniform policy for their guidance in the coming
						contest on the question of adopting or rejecting the Constitution. They also
						propose to consider any other matters of general interest to the Press,
						which may be suggested at that time.</p>
					<p>We heartily endorse the suggestion, and expecting to be present ourselves,
						hope to greet all our Conservative co-laborers at the time and place
							indicated-<emph rend="italic">Lynchburg News</emph>. </p>
					<p>THE CONSERVATIVE CONVENTION.-The suggestion that reaches us by circular from
						our Staunton contemporaries meets our entire and cordial approval. We shall
						be very happy to meet them and all our brethren of the press on the occasion
						referred to.-<emph rend="italic">Rich. Whig</emph>. </p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Mauzy</ln>
						<fn>R.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Lynn</ln>
						<fn>W. H. H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Garber</ln>
						<fn>A. M.</fn>
						<sf>Jr.</sf>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Articles from Lynchburg and Richmond papers praise the proposed
					Conservative Convention, which was originally suggested by the editors of
					Staunton's three newspapers.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="l">
				<column>04</column>
				<head/>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>MT. SIDNEY, Nov. 12th, 1867.</p>
					<p>MR EDITOR.-The impression exists. I am told, with many of my old company, (E
						of the 1st Va. Cavalry.) that I deserted our ranks and "refugeed" to the
						lines of the enemy. In justice to myself, I ask a space in your columns for
						a brief statement in defence of my honor. I was returning to my command in
						October, 1863, after the expiration of a furlough given to me for the
						purpose of enabling me to procure a fresh horse, when I unexpectedly ran
						into a raiding party of the enemy at Jack's Shop, Madison county, Va., and
						was made prisoner, and, as such, was detained at "Point Lookout" until
						February, 1865. I will add that I was on my way to rejoin my company when
						the surrender of our army reached my ears. For the truth of this statement,
						I can refer to my Captain, and also to many reliable gentlemen of the county
						who were incarcerated with me. My apology for taking this public method of
						refuting this slanders and disgraceful charge, is that a soldier's honor is
						sensitive, when assailed even by a suspicion.</p>
					<p>JUNIUS F. ROOT.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer>Junius F. Root</trailer>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Root</ln>
						<fn>Junius F.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Junius Root disputes rumors that he deserted his company during the war.
					Root explains that he was in fact taken prisoner.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1867.11.19.03">
			<div type="a">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>Local News</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The circular issued by the Press of this place and addressed to the
						Conservative Editors of the State requisition them to meet in Richmond on
						the 11th of December to agree upon concerted action has been responded to in
						the proper spirit, and we doubt not that the Press will do its duty and hope
						that they will be the means of getting the people to do theirs.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Reports that the circular issued by the Staunton editors has been warmly
					received by the conservative press of the state and hopes that the press will be
					able to get "the people" to do their duty.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>Local News</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Praises the Town Council for the recent improvements in the streets and
					sidewalks of Staunton as evidence of their "energetic, practical and
					progressive" nature.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>Local News</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Hogshead</ln>
						<fn>M. W. D.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>M. W. D. Hogshead was thrown from his horse while on his way to report for
					jury duty. He is believed to have broken his leg.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>Staunton Lyceum</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>On Monday night, the 11th instant, the following question was discussed:</p>
					<p>"<emph rend="italic">Should the Government prohibit the transportation and
							distribution of the mails on Sunday?</emph>" </p>
					<p>It was discussed in the affirmative by Rev. J. A. Latane, R. Mauzy, Y. Howe
						Peyton, Bolivar Christian, Rev. W. A. Harris and Rev. Geo. B. Taylor, and in
						the negative by Col. J. H. Skinner and Dr. C. R. Harris.</p>
					<p>The question was decided in the affirmative by the vote of 16 to 6.</p>
					<p>The question selected for discussion on next Monday night, the 25th instant,
						reads as follows:</p>
					<p>"<emph rend="italic">Is a lawyer justifiable in defending and laboring to
							acquit a man whom he believes guilty?</emph>" </p>
					<p>The following were appointed to discuss the question In the affirmative,
						Capt. James Bumgardner, and Dr. Wm. W. McChesney, in the negative, H. M.
						Bell and Dr. Atkinson.</p>
					<p>The hour of meeting has been changed from 7 ½ to 7 o'clock. The roll will be
						called at that hour, and members absent will be fined unless they assign
						satisfactory reasons for their failure to be present.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Latane</ln>
						<fn>J. A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Mauzy</ln>
						<fn>R.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Peyton</ln>
						<fn>Y. Howe</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Christian</ln>
						<fn>Bolivar</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Harris</ln>
						<fn>W. A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Taylor</ln>
						<fn>Geo. B.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Skinner</ln>
						<fn>J. H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Col.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Harris</ln>
						<fn>C. R.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Dr.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Bumgardner</ln>
						<fn>James</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Capt.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>McChesney</ln>
						<fn>Wm. S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Dr.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Bell</ln>
						<fn>H. M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Atkinson</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Dr.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>The Staunton Lyceum met last Monday to discuss the question, "'Should the
					Government prohibit the transportation and distribution of the mails on
					Sunday?'" After debate, the question was decided in the affirmative by a vote of
					16 to 6.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>02</column>
				<head>Local News</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Echols</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Bell</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Catlett</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Sheffey</ln>
						<fn>H. W.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Judge</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Haile</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Judge H. W. Sheffey recently sold his 440 acre farm to Mr. Haile, formerly
					of Alabama, for the sum of $25,000.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>04</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Latane</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Opie</ln>
						<fn>Thomas</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Dr.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Harman</ln>
						<fn>Sallie</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Harman</ln>
						<fn>M. G.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Col.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Dr. Thomas Opie, of Baltimore, and Sallie Harman, of Staunton, were married
					at Trinity Church on November 13 by Rev. Latane.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>04</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Schreckhise</ln>
						<fn>J. M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Clemmer</ln>
						<fn>Henry C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Arehart</ln>
						<fn>Mary M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Mary Arehart and Henry Clemmer were married near Middlebrook on November 7
					by Rev. J. M. Schreckhise.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>04</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Neel</ln>
						<fn>A. A. P.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Masincup</ln>
						<fn>David V.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Fall</ln>
						<fn>Mary M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Mary Fall and David Masincup were married near Churchville on November 14
					by A. A. P. Neel.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>04</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Stevenson</ln>
						<fn>G.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Dice</ln>
						<fn>P. H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Rivercomb</ln>
						<fn>R. A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Rivercomb</ln>
						<fn>John C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>P. H. Dice, of Rockingham, and R. A. Rivercomb, of Sangersville, were
					married at the home of the bride's father on October 14 by Rev. G. Stevenson.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1867.11.19.04">
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
	</paperBody>
</hwp>
