<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1867/va.au.ss.1867.07.02">
	<header>
		<title>Staunton Spectator</title>
		<tagger>
			<taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
			<tagDate>09/14/00</tagDate>
			<tagNote/>
		</tagger>
		<address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
		<date n="1867-07-02">
			<year>1867</year>
			<month norm="07"/>
			<day>02</day>
			<weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
		</date>
		<frequency>weekly</frequency>
		<extent>04</extent>
		<editionNote/>
	</header>
	<paperBody>
		<page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1867.07.02.01">
			<div type="a">
				<column>06</column>
				<head>No One Like a Mother</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>A poor old woman lay upon her sick bed in a close uncomfortable room, with a
						daughter and little grandchild to take care of her. But whom do you think
						this aged woman called for all the time, and longed to have come and nurse
						her?</p>
					<p>It was 'mother'-her own mother.</p>
					<p>"O, there's nobody like mother to take care of you when you are sick," she
						said.</p>
					<p>A person present asked how long her mother had been dead.</p>
					<p>"About fifty years, I reckon," she answered.</p>
					<p>Do you think you will remember your mother's loving care for fifty years? No
						doubt you will, if God spares your life. You may think but little of it now
						but you will think a great deal of it then. This woman's children and
						grandchildren had grown up about her, but her heart reached back over all
						that waste of years to the time when she was a child at her mother's side.</p>
					<p>It was for "mother," "mother," that our poor boys, in tent and hospital,
						called and prayed when sick and wounded they were laid down to die.</p>
					<p>O, there is nobody like a mother in love and care for us. What return are you
						making her every day for all she does for you? Do your feet run willingly to
						do her bidding, as soon as it is known? Do you try to save her trouble and
						lighten all her burdens? O, nothing in this world can do it so effectually
						as to know that her children are growing up good, and noble, and useful in
						the world.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Encourages readers to consider how much they appreciate their mothers and
					asks "Do you try to save her trouble and lighten her burdens?"</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1867.07.02.02">
			<div type="a">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>Augusta County Fair</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The County Court at its last term chose ten citizens of the county to be
						Directors of the Augusta County Fair, as provided by the Act of Assembly
						passed last winter, and proceeded to divide them by lot into five classes to
						go out of office annually as follows:</p>
					<p>1. John B. Baldwin and Asher W. Harman.</p>
					<p>2. James Henderson and George T. Antrim.</p>
					<p>3. J. Marshall McCue and Philip O. Palmer.</p>
					<p>4. Saml. B. Finley and James Walker.</p>
					<p>5. Wm. A. Burke and Wm. M. Tate.</p>
					<p>We learn that a meeting of the Directory was held on Saturday last; at which
						Col. John B. Baldwin was elected President of the Fair and Maj. Jed.
						Hotchkiss, Secretary; and that committees were appointed and other steps
						taken to put the enterprise at once in active operation.</p>
					<p>We understand that a committee was been appointed to select and report a
						suitable place at which to hold the County Fair, and we shall probably have
						some competition among the different neighborhoods as we presume the
						location will to a large extent depend upon the advantages offered in the
						way of suitable grounds and reasonable prices. The neighborhood of Staunton
						would naturally be preferred, as the most central and convenient-but other
						advantages may be offered which will go far to overcome the claims of
						Staunton, and it becomes the inhabitants of the <emph rend="italic"
							>Metropolis</emph> to be on the look out! </p>
					<p>The charter provides that where there shall be one hundred and forty
						corporators contributing one hundred dollars each to the permanent endowment
						of the Fair-the whole management and control of it shall be taken from the
						County Court, and given to the corporators. The Directory have made
						arrangements to allow five or even ten years credit upon the amount required
						upon payment of the interest and a portion of the principal each year, and
						we have no doubt that the number of corporators required will be promptly
						found, so that the first annual Fair will be held under the auspices and
						control of the corporators.</p>
					<p>It will be remembered that this is not merely an <emph rend="italic"
							>Agricultural Society</emph>. It is by the terms of the charter "a
						corporation <emph rend="italic">for the purpose of establishing and
							conducting fairs and other examinations of the natural and industrial
							products of Augusta County, as a means of developing the resources of
							the County, and of promoting enterprizes, industry, economy and thrift
							among the people</emph>." </p>
					<p>We cannot doubt that such an enterprize will meet with universal favor among
						our people, and we anticipate such an active co-operation of all industrial
						classes among us as will soon make the Augusta County Fair a matter of
						interest pride and profit to the whole community.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Baldwin</ln>
						<fn>John B.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Harman</ln>
						<fn>Asher W.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Henderson</ln>
						<fn>James</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Antrim</ln>
						<fn>George T.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>McCue</ln>
						<fn>J. Marshall</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Palmer</ln>
						<fn>Philip O.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Finley</ln>
						<fn>Saml. B.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Walker</ln>
						<fn>James</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Burke</ln>
						<fn>Wm. A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Tate</ln>
						<fn>Wm. M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
						<fn>Jed.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Major</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Reports that the County Court last week chose ten citizens to be Directors
					of the Augusta County Fair, which the article predicts will become "a matter of
					interest, pride and profit to the whole community."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>Home Manufactures</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>There were many years ago several trades carried on Staunton, that have
						entirely ceased to exist. There were two or three manufacturers of hats;
						[UNCLEAR] -tree maker, one or two fueling mills; and a paper mill: Coopering
						was carried on much more extensively, than at present, so also we believe
						was the cabinet making business-that is the <emph rend="italic"
							>manufacturing of</emph> furniture; wagon maker too, had much more to do
						than now. A lottery used to be regularly carried on here, but for many years
						past, there has been none. </p>
					<p>Now, why is it, that so many of these trades have ceased to exist, and why
						have others greatly fallen off in the amount of work done by them, and this
						too, when the population of the town has increased fourfold? Some persons
						tell us, that all these articles manufactured by the trades mentioned above
						are now brought from the North; and sold much cheaper than they can be
						manufactured here.</p>
					<p>Should this be so? Have we not all the material here for carrying on the
						various manufactures, in as great plenty, and of as good quality, as they
						have anywhere in the North? We can also raise here in the Valley of Virginia
						(this garden spot of the State,) everything in the greatest profusion, to
						feed both man and beast. In this we certainly have a great advantage over
						New England, and in point of climate, we have a still greater advantage. In
						New England and in many other portions of the North, the winters are at
						least twice as long as here, and very much colder. Besides all this, we have
						untold treasures in the earth, in mineral; and we have too, fine water
						power; and the best of timber, in abundance. Our wagons, carriages, ploughs,
						wooden ware, and in fact everything that we use, made either from iron or
						wood, or of the two, combined, should be made <emph rend="italic">out and
							out and entirely</emph> at home.--Why should we send abroad for hats,
						when we might have them manufactured at home, just as good and as cheap. Of
						many other things we might say the same. </p>
					<p>We are told, that, it will be a long while before there will be much
						manufacturing carried on in this part of the country; that we have no money
						here to start factories with. We admit the fact, that money is scarce in
						this community, and our people generally poor; but still we believe, from
						the quantity of <emph rend="italic">fashionable finery</emph>; for men and
						women-sold throughout this region of the country, that there must be much
						more money here than is generally supposed. </p>
					<p>Now suppose each family in the counties of Rockbridge, Augusta and
						Rockingham, who are what are called "<emph rend="italic">good
						livers!</emph>-were to curtail their expenses in the purchase of wearing
						apparel <emph rend="italic">one-tenth</emph>, which we doubt not they could
						way conveniently do, and invest it in manufacturing establishments, we think
						it would probably be sufficient to start several such enterprises. We hear
						the remark, often made, that "our people are too extravagant, that they
						dress finer now than they did before the war." [UNCLEAR]we fear is too true
						with regard to a great many persons, not only in the towns, but throughout
						the country generally. During the war most of the people could get so little
						finery to wear, that we suppose now, they are somewhat like persons that
						have been nearly starved for want of food, being suddenly placed where they
						could get plenty to eat, not knowing when to stop eating; [UNCLEAR] Southern
						people, don't know when to stop buying. </p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Laments the fact that there is actually less local manufacturing than
					before the war and suggests that if the local families, those "called 'good
					livers,'" were willing to curtail their spending by one-tenth and invest that
					money in local manufactures, new enterprises would quickly spring forth.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>02</column>
				<head>"Union Prayer Meeting"</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>A union prayer meeting of all the Christian denominations of this place in
						the Presbyterian Church last Sunday evening, at 5 o'clock. The committee,
						appointed at a meeting on last Sunday week, submitted the following report,
						which was adopted: STAUNTON, VA., June 28th, '67.</p>
					<p>The committee appointed at first meeting of the Union Prayer Meeting on
						Sunday, June 22nd, 1867, met at the store of Mr. P. B. Hoge, a quorum,
						Messrs. Hoge, Strasburg and Baker being present. They respectfully submit
						for adoption by this meeting the following, as the order of exercises
						&amp;c., viz:</p>
					<p>1. Open with prayer of not more than 5 minutes in length.</p>
					<p>2. Sing 2 or 3 verses of a hymn.</p>
					<p>3. Read a brief lesson from the Scriptures.</p>
					<p>4. Invite requests for special prayer to be handed in the Leader-to be read
						by him to the meeting.</p>
					<p>5. Special prayer of not more than 5 minutes.</p>
					<p>6. Exhortation or address from any one who desires, not exceeding 10 minutes
						in length.</p>
					<p>7. Sing 2 or 3verses of a hymn.</p>
					<p>8. Prayer of not more than 5 minutes.</p>
					<p>9. Doxology.</p>
					<p>Meetings are to be held in the different Churches-on successive Sabbaths, in
						the following order, viz:</p>
					<p>Presbyterian, Lutheran, Methodist, Episcopal, and Baptist. Meetings to be
						held at 5 o'clock P. M. , and to hold not over one hour.</p>
					<p>We respectfully suggest that this meeting appoint an executive committee of
						one member from each Church whose duty it shall be to visit the streets and
						homes of the town-say half an hour before the meeting, and invite loungers,
						and others, to attend our meetings and spend an hour with us in worship. The
						committee shall also select the leader for our meetings, who shall lead 5
						Sabbaths in succession; also give the names of those who will lead in prayer
						in public-having a list for the use of leader.</p>
					<p>The committee also respectfully present, the following gentlemen as the
						Executive committee, viz:</p>
					<p>JNO. K. WOODS,</p>
					<p>C. W. HUNTER,</p>
					<p>DR. ATKINSON,</p>
					<p>JNO. B. HOGE,</p>
					<p>DAVID DRAKE.</p>
					<p>Jed. Hotchkiss was selected as the leader of the meeting for the first five
						Sabbaths.</p>
					<p>We are pleased to see this spirit of unity manifest by the christian people
						of Staunton, and we trust this meeting may be the means of doing much for
						the advancement of the Redeemer's kingdom and to the breaking down of the
						strongholds of sin.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Hoge</ln>
						<fn>P. B.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Strasburg</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Baker</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Woods</ln>
						<fn>Jno. K.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hunter</ln>
						<fn>C. W.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Atkinson</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Dr.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hoge</ln>
						<fn>Jno. B.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Drake</ln>
						<fn>David</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
						<fn>Jed.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Reports that all the local Christian denominations held the first in what
					will be a series of "union prayer meetings." The article praises "the spirit of
					unity manifested by the christian people of Staunton."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1867.07.02.03">
			<div type="a">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>Local News--Registration Returns</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The Poll of Registration in the two districts of Staunton, which closed on
						last Saturday, stands as follows:</p>
					<table>
						<row>
							<cell>1st District-whites</cell>
							<cell>380</cell>
						</row>
						<row>
							<cell>2nd " "</cell>
							<cell>366</cell>
						</row>
						<row>
							<cell>1st " blacks</cell>
							<cell>184</cell>
						</row>
						<row>
							<cell>2nd " "</cell>
							<cell>258</cell>
						</row>
						<row>
							<cell>Total number of whites</cell>
							<cell>746</cell>
						</row>
						<row>
							<cell>" " blacks</cell>
							<cell>442</cell>
						</row>
						<row>
							<cell>White majority</cell>
							<cell>304</cell>
						</row>
						<row>
							<cell>Total number of whites and blacks</cell>
							<cell>1188</cell>
						</row>
					</table>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Voter registration ended last Saturday in the two districts of Staunton
					with 746 whites and 442 blacks registered.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>Local News--Concert By the Blind at the D. D. &amp; B. Institution</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Turner</ln>
						<fn>A. J.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Prof.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>The students of the Deaf, Dumb, and Blind Institution gave a concert last
					Tuesday, where, according to the article, they displayed "much musical talent."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>02</column>
				<head>Local News--Wesleyan Female Institute</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The closing exercises of this Institution, an adjunct to the Methodist
						Church-South, took place on Monday and Tuesday last, at the Church in this
						town.</p>
					<p>On Monday night, every corner of the Church was crowded there being a public
						exhibition of Prof. Hewitt's music class. A full choir was, also in
						attendance, and opened the exercises with an original <emph rend="italic"
							>Ode to Science</emph>, composed, for the occasion, by Mr. Hewitt. At
						the conclusion of the Ode, the Professor made a short and neat speech in
						behalf of his pupils, and, then, introduced Misses Waters and Harris, who
						executed a very pleasing duet, on the piano forte with considerable ability.
						Miss Annie Walton, the <emph rend="italic">prima donna</emph> of the
						evening, sang "Eve's Lamentation" with touching effect. Then, followed a
						brilliant Mazurka, by Miss Kat Trotter, and a vocal duet "O'er the hills" by
						Misses Waters and Walton; then came, in order, "Les voix des ondes," a neat
						piano solo, by Miss Walton; L'harpe Eoleanne," by Miss Maggie Harris; "La
						Reve," by Miss Fannie Waters-winding up with a comic duet, admirably sung,
						by Miss Walton and Mr. Hewitt. </p>
					<p>The crowning attraction of the evening, however was the neat little Cantata
						of "Flora's Festival," which brought into action the vocal powers of the
						entire class, from the flashy voice of Flora down to the tiny warblings of
						the little Zephyr of four years. The poem is divided into three
						parts-Morning, Noon and Night, and is also interspersed with poetic
						dialogues.</p>
					<p>Miss Annie Walton represented the mythological queen of the realm of flowers,
						with much ease and grace. Some of her solos were well calculated to show off
						her fine voice. We have space only to instance, "Hail, holy light," and "Ye
						burning stars." The other characters personified were Aurora, Miss L. R.
						Payne; the Queen Zephyr, Miss Mattie Harris; the Nyriad, Miss Fannie
						Blackburn; Diana, Miss Cynthia Balthis; Sunbeam, Miss Marietta Moore; Pea
						Blossom, Miss Fannie Waferk. These were all <emph rend="italic"
						>immortals</emph>; the <emph rend="italic">mortals</emph> were the Queen,
						Miss Kate Pitzer, and the first, second and third Maids of Honour, Misses
						Henrietta McMullen, Kate Trotter, and Mary Bruce. We must, also, mention
						Prof. Hewitt who, as the Storm spirit, seemed to glory in the war of the
						elements. </p>
					<p>Many of the choruses were admirably sung, for a class which has been but a
						few months in training; and, though the practised ear might have detected
						faults, yet the merits largely predominated, and every one of the audience
						seemed disposed to award the meed of praise to the fairy band who could
						discourse so eloquently through the medium of sweet sounds.</p>
					<p>On Tuesday morning, the building was again crowded to witness the
						distribution of the awards, and listen to the address of the Rev. W. E.
						Munsey. The exercises were opened by a stirring Anthem, "Wake the song of
						Jubilee," sung with effect by the choir, followed by a prayer by Rev. George
						B. Taylor, of the Baptist Church. The Rev. Mr. Miller, of the Lutheran
						Church, read the report of the committee on examinations.-The Rev. W. A.
						Harris, President of the Institute, then gave an explanation of the plan
						adopted, and the degrees of proficiency required for receiving Certificates
						of Graduation or Diplomas in the several departments. To the following
						graduates in the different schools Certificates were awarded by the Rev. Mr.
						Harris and Prof. Leonidas Points:</p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">School of Natural Philosophy</emph>.-Misses Fannie
						Blackburn of Rockingham; Maggie a. Harris, of Augusta; Bettie C. Shafer of
						Augusta; Kate Pitzer, of Covington, West Va.; L. Rebecca Payne, of
						Frederick; Annie D. Fletcher, of Accomac. </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">School of Chemistry</emph>.-Misses L. R. Payne, A. D.
						Fletcher; Cynthia Bathis, of Staunton; Fannie Waters, of Maryland; Annie E.
						Walton, of Shenandoah; Henrietta McMullen, of Green. </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">School of English Literature</emph>.-Misses L. R. Payne,
						A. D. Fletcher, Cynthia Balthis, Fannie Waters, a. E. Walton, H. McMullen. </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">School of French</emph>.-H. McMullen. </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">School of Latin</emph>.-H. McMullen. </p>
					<p>Certificates of proficiency in the Junior Course of Physiology and Hygeian
						Anatomy were awarded to the following young ladies:</p>
					<p>Misses Fannie Blackburn, Marietta Moore, Annie D. Fletcher, Maggie A. Harris,
						Cynthia Balthis, Kate Pitzer, Henrietta McMullen, Annie E. Walton, Fannie
						Waters, Bettie C. Shafer and L. R. Payne.</p>
					<p>At the conclusion of the ceremony of distributing the honors of the different
						schools, the Rev. Mr. Munsey addressed the young ladies in a strain of pure
						eloquence, which riveted the attention of the audience for more than an
						hour. He selected <emph rend="italic">Music</emph> for his subject-its
						origin and progress, not only as an art-but, as a mysterious agent of the
						Creator, working through every department of nature. To those who never had
						heard this eloquent gentleman before, the treat was a rare one-yet, the
						effort fell short, of his usual pulpit discourses; his forte is theology,
						and the grandeur of his eloquence displays itself in praise of the majesty
						and goodness of God. </p>
					<p>At the conclusion of the address, Miss Ruth, a charming amateur cantatrice,
						from Richmond, aided by the members of the choir, sang with much pathos the
						following song, written expressly for the occasion by Prof. Hewitt. It is
						adapted to the fine old air of "Auld Lang Syne":</p>
					<p>THE PARTING SONG.</p>
					<p>The parting song-the parting song</p>
					<p>Harmonious let us sing,</p>
					<p>That angels, as they sweep along,</p>
					<p>May bear it on the wing.</p>
					<p>There's sorrow in the word "Farewell,"</p>
					<p>That lingers on the tongue;</p>
					<p>And fond remembrance loves to dwell</p>
					<p>The vanish'd seems among,</p>
					<p>The parting song-the parting song,</p>
					<p>Let our full voices raise,</p>
					<p>To that old tune our fathers sung</p>
					<p>With pride in other days.</p>
					<p>The parting song-the parting song,</p>
					<p>The strain of olden times,</p>
					<p>When love was pure and friendship strong,</p>
					<p>And joy rang merry chimes.</p>
					<p>The soul is wing'd in every note,</p>
					<p>While truth hangs on the lips,</p>
					<p>Like dew upon the rose's leaf</p>
					<p>That smiles although it weeps.</p>
					<p>The parting song, &amp;c. <lb/></p>
					<p>The parting song-the parting song</p>
					<p>That wakes the harp's sad strings,</p>
					<p>When round the heart sweet mem'ries throng</p>
					<p>And poise upon their wings.</p>
					<p>Go where we man, the said, sad strain,</p>
					<p>Will fall upon the ear;</p>
					<p>Forgotten scenes loom up again</p>
					<p>Through sorrow's crystal tear,</p>
					<p>The parting song, &amp;c. <lb/></p>
					<p>The Rev. Wm. A. Harris, whose fine reputation as an educator has been richly
						earned in the South management of the first colleges in Virginia sustained
						that reputation in the decided success of this institution during the past
						year. He took charge of it under rather unfavorable circumstances, but with
						his characteristic energy and perseverance, he has placed it among the first
						institutions in Virginia. Its highly improved thorough system of
						teaching-the character of the able and experienced gentlemen, who assisted
						the President-Professors Hewitt, Points, Dr. C. R. Harris and others, render
						it worthy of the cordial support of the people of the South. The school is
						under the patronage of the Episcopal Methodist Church-South, and, therefore,
						should receive the united and hearty support of all that denomination. We
						predict for this institution a prosperous and brilliant future.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Hewitt</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Prof.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Waters</ln>
						<fn>Fannie</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Harris</ln>
						<fn>Maggie</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Walton</ln>
						<fn>Annie</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Trotter</ln>
						<fn>Kate</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Payne</ln>
						<fn>L. R.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Harris</ln>
						<fn>Mattie</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Blackburn</ln>
						<fn>Fannie</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Balthis</ln>
						<fn>Cynthia</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Moore</ln>
						<fn>Marietta</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Fletcher</ln>
						<fn>A. D.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>McMullen</ln>
						<fn>Henrietta</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Bruce</ln>
						<fn>Mary</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Munsey</ln>
						<fn>W. E.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Taylor</ln>
						<fn>George B.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Miller</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Harris</ln>
						<fn>W. A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Points</ln>
						<fn>Leonidas</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Prof.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Shafer</ln>
						<fn>Bettie C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Walton</ln>
						<fn>A. E.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Harris</ln>
						<fn>C. R.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Dr.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Offers an account of the closing exercises at the Wesleyan Female Institute
					and a list of those who received certificates of graduation.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>02</column>
				<head>Commencement Exercises of the Virginia Female Institute</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Kinney</ln>
						<fn>R. P.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Miss</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Phillips</ln>
						<fn>E. Florence</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Sheffey</ln>
						<fn>Louise</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>The commencement exercises at the Virginia Female Institute included
					praiseworthy musical performances and the presentation of degrees and gold
					medals. Staunton residents E. Florence Phillips and Louise Sheffey graduated and
					R. P. Kinney received a gold medal for scholarship.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>04</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Miller</ln>
						<fn>J. I.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Stoneburner</ln>
						<fn>Charles D.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Trenary</ln>
						<fn>Blanche L.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Blanche Trenary and Charles Stoneburner, the foreman of the Staunton
					Vindicator, were married on June 25 by Rev. J. I. Miller.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>04</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Clarke</ln>
						<fn>John L.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Bartley</ln>
						<fn>Henry B.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Layton</ln>
						<fn>Jane</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Jane Layton and Henry Bartley were married at the Virginia Hotel on June 19
					by Rev. John L. Clarke.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1867.07.02.04">
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
	</paperBody>
</hwp>
