<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1867/va.au.ss.1867.06.11">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/06/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-06-11">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>11</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1867.06.11.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Radical Address to the People of the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Radical Congressional Committee have issued an address to the people of
                        the South. The intention of the Reconstruction acts, and the policy of
                        Congress are defined. It declares that the Radical party will exact
                        compliance with condition making renewal of civil war impossible, and that
                        it will secure the freedmen the full and equal rights of citizens. It asks
                        the freedmen to sustain with their votes, this policy and all the people of
                        the South to freely accept universal suffrage, to unite in the establishment
                        of public schools, and to favor the distribution of lands. It affirms that
                        "if the people of the States lately in rebellion shall cheerfully and in
                        good faith reorganize their governments upon the principles of the laws
                        passed by Congress, there will then remain no causes of difference between
                        the various sections of the country."</p>
                    <p>This is a brief abstract of the address; and the following is an extract. It
                        will be seen that the finality is not <emph rend="italic">yet</emph>,
                        according to this: </p>
                    <p>"Congress reserves to itself the full and unrestricted right of judgment
                        whenever a State presents itself for admission into the Union.-That right
                        will be exercised fairly and generously. But yet in the interest of peace
                        and loyalty certain conditions an precedents are laid in laws. These must be
                        met. But beyond these conditions Congress must be satisfied also that the
                        people of the proposed States respectively are, and are likely to be, loyal
                        to the Union, by decisive and trustworthy majorities; that the institutions
                        are framed upon the basis of equality, and that they will, from year to
                        year, and from age to age, contribute to the peace, progress and prosperity
                        of the States and of the country."</p>
                    <p>The amount of all this is, says the Lynchburg <emph rend="italic"
                        >Republican</emph>, that when the people of the South obey all the
                        requirements of he military bills, and then elect a Radical delegation to
                        Congress, and then do any thing else that may be required of them, they may,
                        perhaps, be admitted to the Union. This is what we have predicted all along
                        would be the case, and, therefore, we are not surprised at the new demand.
                        If our people can see anything encouraging in this we confess we can't. We
                        see nothing but fresh humiliation, outrage and final ruin so long as the
                        Radicals rule. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that "fresh humiliation, outrage and final ruin" will be the lot of
                    the South as long as the Radicals maintain power.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1867.06.11.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Registration in Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that voter registration will begin in Augusta on June 22 and
                    encourages all who have not taken an oath of loyalty to the Constitution to do
                    so at once.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Live Men Wanted!!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>During the June term of court, the Justices of Augusta will choose six men
                    to serve as directors of the upcoming Augusta County Fair.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Register! Register!!</head>
                <origin>Richmond Times</origin>
                <commentary>"The Richmond Times, in an article on the supreme duty of the hour,
                    says:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"We sincerely trust that the people of Virginia will take care that not a
                        vote be lost by their failure to register. We do not advise them to neglect
                        their agricultural pursuits, to meet at the cross-road ground, and upon the
                        court greens to listen to gaseous orators, but we do implore them to
                        register in their magisterial districts without delay. The white race cannot
                        lose the ascendancy which it has enjoyed in Virginia since the settlement at
                        Jamestown, unless our people are criminally indifferent or apathetic. The
                        stake which they have in the approaching elections is not one of those empty
                        political triumphs which, before the war used to excite such intense
                        interest among all classes. Their political rights, and the safety of life,
                        liberty and property are all involved in the issues which have been thrust
                        upon us by the military act. Every white man who fails to register will
                        deserve to be execrated as an enemy of his race, and as an unnatural husband
                        and father, whose name should be held in reproach by his descendants as one
                        who failed to defend his birthright when it was in jeopardy. The rich and
                        the poor, the great and the bumble, are alike interested in the registration
                        of every white voter in the State."</p>
                    <p>The triumph of a party like <emph rend="italic">that</emph>, which has made a
                        terrestrial Inferno of Tennessee, would crush the mechanic by completely
                        paralysing the energy of the capitalist, and drive the wealthy from the
                        State by the wolfish agrarianism which it would inaugurate. We do not ask
                        every Virginian to aid us with all the force of talents, energy, public
                        spirit and mans which God has blessed him in making the registration as
                        complete as possible, for the purpose of denying to the negro a single right
                        which can be claimed for him as [UNCLEAR] of his liberty. By no means. <emph
                            rend="italic">But we wish, when a complete and thorough registration has
                            revealed the strength of the white men in this State to teach the
                            blacks, by our liberality towards them, that their best friends are
                            their former masters</emph>. When we have demonstrated to the deluded
                        negro followers of the demoralized white men who have poisoned their minds
                        against us, that we are master of the situation, we can afford to make the
                        lesson of our magnanimity and justice impressive. </p>
                    <p>"If the white men of this State, who have not been disfranchised, will take
                        care to register and vote, they will not only secure, beyond the possibility
                        of danger, their political rights and property, but they will be in
                        condition to aid in the work of speedy reconstruction upon terms not as
                        disadvantageous as they would be made by the triumph of Radicalism."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Encourages all white men to register and vote, declaring that "every white
                    man who fails to register will deserve to be execrated as an enemy of his race,
                    and as an unnatural husband and father." After victory, though, the article
                    argues that whites can "afford to make the lesson of our magnanimity and justice
                    impressive" upon the "deluded negroes."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Mutual Protection Company</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>WHEREAS Larceny of horses in this community having become a common and crying
                        evil, bringing great loss of property and the depredators, in most
                        instances, escaping arrest and punishment; and, whereas, in order to remedy
                        the matter as far as in our power by effecting an organization, we have</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That we who hereunto subscribe our names
                        hereby associate ourselves into an organization to be called the "Mt.
                        Meridian League to prevent and punish horses stealing," That whenever, we
                        have notice that a horse has been stolen from any of our body, we will
                        immediately aid in the pursuit and capture of the property and thief, That
                        we offer a standing reward of One Hundred and Fifty Dollars for the arrest
                        and conviction of the thief who may steal a horse from any member of this
                        association, and that members be obliged to brand their horses with the
                        letter "O," on the right side of the neck under the mane.</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>R. S. Harnsberger</cell>
                            <cell>G. C. Patterson</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>S. D. Craig</cell>
                            <cell>J. L. Bowcock</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>C. M. Kimpse</cell>
                            <cell>J. H. Nuckols</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>W. R. Foster</cell>
                            <cell>J. J. Wonderluck</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Thos. P. Crawford</cell>
                            <cell>Dan. V. Weast</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>J. A. Patterson, sr.</cell>
                            <cell>Henry Hahn</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Col. S. D. Craford</cell>
                            <cell>Benj. Byerly</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>S. H. Walker</cell>
                            <cell>John Ruebush</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>L. J. Maupin</cell>
                            <cell>T. R. Mohler</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Henry Weast</cell>
                            <cell>Frank McClung</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>David Pleeker</cell>
                            <cell>R.L. Johnson</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>John Werner</cell>
                            <cell>B. J. Craig</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Dr. W. J. Bell</cell>
                            <cell>A. W. Diehl</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Henry Tutwiler</cell>
                            <cell>Noah Spitzer</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>J. H. Diehl</cell>
                            <cell>Elias Porky</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Dan'l Landis</cell>
                            <cell>G. W. Putzler</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>C. S. Patterson</cell>
                            <cell>S. H. Kaylor</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Wm. Patterson</cell>
                            <cell>J. G. Patterson</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>June11-3t*</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harnsberger</ln>
                        <fn>R. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>S. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimpse</ln>
                        <fn>C. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foster</ln>
                        <fn>W. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Thos. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>S. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>S. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maupin</ln>
                        <fn>L. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weast</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plecker</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Werner</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>W. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tutwiler</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Diehl</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Landis</ln>
                        <fn>Dan'l</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>C. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>G. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowcock</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nuckols</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wonderlick</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weast</ln>
                        <fn>Dan. V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hahn</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byerly</ln>
                        <fn>Benj.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruebush</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mohler</ln>
                        <fn>T. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClung</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>R. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>B. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Diehl</ln>
                        <fn>A. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spitzer</ln>
                        <fn>Noah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Porky</ln>
                        <fn>Elias</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Putzler</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kaylor</ln>
                        <fn>S. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the formation of a mutual protection society to respond to the
                    frequency of horse theft in the area. The members will aid in the pursuit and
                    capture of any one who steals a horse from another member and will offer a
                    reward of 150 dollars for the arrest and conviction of a horse thief.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1867.06.11.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Staunton Lyceum</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> On the 3rd inst, the Lyceum discussed the question "<emph rend="italic">Is
                            there any truth in spiritual manifestations or witchcraft</emph>."
                        Debated in the affirmative by Rev. J. L. Clarke and Prof. Powers; in the
                        negative by Prof. Hewitt and Y. H. Peyton, Esq. The vote stood affirmative
                        4, negative 14. The same question was selected for the meeting on the 10th
                        inst. The term "spiritual manifestations" was construed to comprehend all
                        kinds of spiritual influences, angelic or otherwise. The question for the
                        17th inst. Is "<emph rend="italic">Do labor-saving devices benefit the
                            laboring classes</emph>."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powers</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hewitt</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Y. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 3 the Staunton Lyceum discuss the question "Is there any truth in
                    spiritual manifestations or witchcraft?" After debate the question was decided
                    in the negative by a vote of 14 to 4.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Impartial Justice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Of three negroes tried for this term of the Circuit Court for the detestable
                        offence of houseburning, two were acquitted and one sentenced to the mildest
                        penalty allowed by the law. The circumstantial evidence indicated that each
                        was guilty, and it was obviously the sympathy felt for the ignorance and
                        helplessness of the negro that induced the benefit of the doubt in his
                        favor. If they had been white men, on the same evidence, they would have
                        "gone up," sure. Our people do what they think right, and will never punish
                        prisoners in defence to "public sentiment," much less to political
                        prejudice.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that of the three black men tried for arson in the local Circuit
                    Court, two were acquitted and the third lightly sentenced, claiming that it was
                    sympathy for their "ignorance and helplessness" that exonerated them.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neel</ln>
                        <fn>A. A. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>William T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burgess</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sarah Burgess and William Wright were married at Parnassus on May 30 by
                    Rev. A. A. P. Neel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kiracofe</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houff</ln>
                        <fn>John F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neff</ln>
                        <fn>Mary V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Neff and John Houff were married on May 30 at the home of the bride's
                    father near Spring Hill by Rev. J. W. Kiracofe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latane</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powell</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stribling</ln>
                        <fn>Ella</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stribling</ln>
                        <fn>F. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Ella Stribling and Hugh Powell, of New York City, were married at Trinity
                    Church in Staunton on June 5 by Rev. J. A. Latane.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jordan</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craun</ln>
                        <fn>Marie E. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Marie E. Craun and Joseph M. Jordan were married on May 30 by Rev. C.
                    Beard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McNutt</ln>
                        <fn>Robt.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert McNutt died at his home near Moffett's Creek on April 24. He was 79
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1867.06.11.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
