<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1867/va.au.ss.1867.01.08">
	<header>
		<title>Staunton Spectator</title>
		<tagger>
			<taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
			<tagDate>07/10/00</tagDate>
			<tagNote/>
		</tagger>
		<address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
		<date n="1867-01-08">
			<year>1867</year>
			<month norm="01">January</month>
			<day>08</day>
			<weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
		</date>
		<frequency>weekly</frequency>
		<extent>04</extent>
		<editionNote/>
	</header>
	<paperBody>
		<page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1867.01.08.01">
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1867.01.08.02">
			<div type="e">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>Our True Policy</head>
				<origin>Richmond Enquirer</origin>
				<commentary>"We have so frequently presented our views of what we believe to be the
					true policy of the South that they cannot be misunderstood. It is, in brief, to
					avoid giving unnecessary offence to the people of the North; to stand calmly
					though firmly by all our constitutional rights; to rely upon ourselves; to
					develop the rich resources of our section; to establish factories of all kinds;
					to buy as little abroad as possible; to live within ourselves, and encourage in
					every possible way every branch of industry in the Southern States; to labor and
					not to idle; to hope and not to despond. In an able article, the Richmond
					Enquirer has so well expressed our views that we publish a lengthy extract from
					it in lieu of expressing them more elaborately ourselves. It says that:"</commentary>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>We have so frequently presented our views of what we believe to be the true
						policy of the South that they cannot be misunderstood. It is, in brief, to
						avoid giving unnecessary offence to the people of the North; to stand calmly
						though firmly by all our constitutional rights; to rely upon ourselves; to
						develop the rich resources of our section; to establish factories of all
						kinds; to buy as little abroad as possible; to live within ourselves, and
						encourage in every possible way every branch of industry in the Southern
						States; to labor and not to idle; to hope and not to despond. In an able
						article, the Richmond <emph rend="italic"> Enquirer</emph> has so well
						expressed our views that we publish a lengthy extract from it lieu of
						expressing them more elaborately ourselves. It says that "our first aim
						should be to undermine that organized hostility of superior numbers, which,
						while it exists, will render alike vain, all appeals to reason to covenanted
						faith. To preach to passion is to preach to boreas-and never were a people
						so wholly under the influence of passion as is the dominant party of the
						North to-day. We must therefore avoid as far as possible all direct
						collisions with Northern sentiment. We must refuse to accept sectional
						issues. The effort will be to draw us into these, for then our ruin is
						assured. We must beware such stratagems. We must avoid giving the
						evil-disposed material wherewith to irritate the Northern mind;--there is
						nothing which those who most hate us at the North so desiringly look for and
						so eagerly publish, as taunts and sarcasms uttered here. It is hard indeed
						to endure in silence the volleys of vituperation so ceaselessly poured upon
						us; but we must learn the virtue of endurance. It is no mark of cowardice in
						a soldier-it is rather the highest test of his courage and discipline-to
						receive in silence a fire which he may not effectually return. It is hard to
						bear insults and arrogances such as the coarsest and most brutal slaveholder
						would have been ashamed to utter the meanest slave; but the disgrace is not
						ours. </p>
					<p>While refusing to scold and quarrel, and to give an overpowering multitude
						excuse for passion,--we must carefully watch and maintain all our existing
						constitutional defences, and make them as available as possible. We must
						test in the courts how far this is indeed a government of constitution and
						laws; whether the obedience demanded of us does not imply protection;
						whether taxation does not imply representation; whether the duties of States
						do not imply rights of States.</p>
					<p>Not only must we disarm passion by moderation, and restrain aggression within
						the narrowest practicable bounds, but we must seek to avert hostile
						discriminations by removing the opportunities for them. So long as our
						social composition differs from that of the North, we shall be dogged by
						fanatics and harassed by hostile legislation. To obviate this we must <emph
							rend="italic">diffuse the negroes</emph>. It will be fatal to keep them
						all here. Send as many as possible North. Scatter them over the whole
						country, and they will no longer disturb its politics. Concentrated here, we
						shall <emph rend="italic">never have peace</emph>. </p>
					<p>Again: We must conform <emph rend="italic">our industry</emph> to that of the
						North. So long as we produce cotton and New England spins it all, the cotton
						grower will be taxed for the benefit of the cotton-spinner. So long as we
						plant and the North manufactures, the planter will be taxed for the
						manufacturer. We must remove the opportunities for discrimination. We must
						grow no more cotton than we can spin. We must provide our own boots and
						shoes and cloths, and mechanical implements, as well as our meat and bread. </p>
					<p>It will not avail us to inquire in what way our industry, if unmolested,
						would be most profitable. It will not be unmolested. It is not our natural
						interest, not political economy, but political exigency that we have to
						study.-We must conform our lines to those that confront us. We must present
						no salient points of attack. We must invite no adverse discriminations by
						prominent peculiarities. Better fish for cod and share the bounty, than grow
						cotton under heavy tax for Northern spinners. We must spin too. We must
						manufacture ourselves. Thus we shall share in legislative "protection," and
						escape legislative discrimination. It will indeed be worse for the country
						to have its production thus uniform instead of diversified,--articificial
						instead of natural; but it will be better for us. If not the best that
						nature intended for us, it will be the best that man permits to us."</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Lays out the "true policy" of the South. The author recommends emulating
					Northern industry and argues that Southerners needs to "diffuse the negroes"
					because, with them "concentrated here, we shall never have peace."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>02</column>
				<head>The Whites and Blacks</head>
				<origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The chief complaint on the part of the Radicals against the South is, says
						the Richmond <emph rend="italic">Whig </emph>, that we will not, as they
						allege, do the negroes justice. From this, as a starting point, they launch
						out into many charges against us, and, by mingling much of falsehood with
						some little of truth, they have made out such a case against us as to alarm
						the whole North for the safety of the negroes. This is just what the Radical
						leaders wanted to do. They don't care a straw for the negroes-their aim is
						to preserve to the North the ascendancy which the war gave it; to retain
						power in their own hands long enough to remodel the Constitution in the
						interests of the North; to reconstruct the Supreme Court in the same manner,
						and to launch the new Government-for new it will be-under the auspices of a
						President of their own choice. Some great predominant sentiment and sympathy
						had to be enlisted to give success to their scheme, and they found this
						powerful ally in the morbid humanitarianism of the Northern masses. The
						argument was, the negro is oppressed; he must have relief and the power of
						self-protection; indemnity for the past and security for the future. The
						object of the Radical leaders is one thing, the object of the Northern
						masses another thing. But both being jealous of and inimical to the Southern
						people, and being thus turned into common channels of thought and sympathy,
						have become identified in sentiment and purpose. </p>
					<p>While all this is going on at the North there is uninterrupted harmony at the
						South between the whites and blacks. Both classes know perfectly well that
						the basis of the proposed legislation of Congress in regard to the South is
						a false basis. If the Southern whites are wise the will conform as
						cheerfully as may be to the new relations that exist between them and the
						blacks. While nature-the instinct of both races-interposes an insuperable
						bar to social equality, there is no obstacle to the most friendly relations.
						Let Congress fix the political status of the freedman as it may, their
						position will ever be that of laborers. The land of the South belongs and
						ever will belong to the whites; and to the proprietors of the soil the bulk
						of the freedmen must look for employment. There, of course, will be
						exceptional cases.-Some colored people of superior intelligence and thrift
						will become land owners. The more intelligent and industrious the whole
						class, the better it will be for both races. We should do all we can to help
						them on to the highest development of which they are capable. The more we
						voluntarily do to assist and improve them, the more profit we will reap from
						their labor, and the stronger will be our hold upon their confidence and
						affection in the political changes which Federal legislation contemplates.
						If we play our cards skillfully the Radicals will, perhaps, one day awake to
						the unpleasing consciousness that in making the freedmen suffragans they
						have only added to Southern representation and Southern power.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Claims that Radicals are antagonizing otherwise amicable relations between
					the races in the South when in fact "they don't care a straw for the
					negroes--their aim is to preserve to the North the ascendancy which the war gave
					it." The article argues that the role of blacks in the South "will ever be that
					of laborers" while whites will continue to monopolize land and wealth. But it
					also encourages whites to help blacks obtain "the highest development of which
					they are capable," allowing that "some colored people of superior intelligence
					and thrift will become land owners." It even suggests that one day Radicals will
					find that "in making the freedmen suffragans they have only added to Southern
					representation and Southern power."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>02</column>
				<head/>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Reports that, in his annual message, the Governor of Delaware expressed
					opposition to the constitutional amendment and approval "of the selling of
					negroes into slavery as the best punishment for crime."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>04</column>
				<head>Contracts with Freedmen</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>As this is the period when most employers are renewing their engagements with
						laborers, we reproduce the act of the General Assembly bearing upon the
						subject:</p>
					<p>1. <emph rend="italic">Be it enacted by the General Assembly</emph>, That no
						contract between a white person and a colored person, for the labor of
						service of the latter for a longer period than two months, shall be binding
						on such colored person unless the contract be in writing, signed by such
						white person, or his agent, and by such colored person, and duly
						acknowledged before a justice or notary public, or clerk of the county or
						corporation court, or overseer of the poor, or two, or more credible
						witnesses, in the county or corporation in which the white person may
						reside, or in which the labor or service is to be performed. And it shall be
						the duty of the justice, notary, clerk or overseer of the poor, or the
						witnesses, to read and explain the contract to the colored person, before
						taking his acknowledgement thereof, and to state that this has been done in
						the certificate of the acknowledgement of the contract. </p>
					<p>2. If any person shall entice away, from the service of another, any laborer
						employed by him under a contract, as provided by this act, knowing of the
						existence of such contract, or shall knowingly employ a laborer bound to
						service to another under such contract, he shall forfeit to the party
						aggrieved not less than ten nor more than twenty dollars for every such
						offence; to be recovered by warrant before any justice of the peace.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Reproduces the acts of the General Assembly pertaining to contracts
					"between a white person and a colored person, for the labor or service of the
					latter."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1867.01.08.03">
			<div type="o">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>Local News--Jefferson Kinney, Deceased</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>Died, at his residence near Staunton, on the 21st day of December 1866, after
						a long and useful life, JEFFERSON KINNEY, aged 61 years, 8 months, and 17
						days, leaving a disconsolate wife, and numerous descendants to mourn their
						great loss.</p>
					<p>The subject of this notice was no ordinary man, and few in this community,
						where he was born and died, have rendered to it such important, faithful,
						and long continued services; modest, retiring and unobtrusive, he never
						claimed promotion as a right, yet such was his fidelity, his ability, and
						zeal in the performance of all duties devolved upon him, that, from an earl
						period of his life, he was placed by his fellow-citizens in the most
						responsible and arduous positions, where he was always acquitted himself
						with credit. From about the year 1820, he was engaged as a deputy clerk in
						the County Court of Augusta, where he performed the heavy and responsible
						duties of that office in so satisfactory a manner, that in June, 1831, he
						was appointed by the Justices, Clerk of that Court, and held the office
						under their appointment until the new Constitution of Virginia went into
						operation, when, in 1852, he was again elected by the people, and held the
						office till the 1st of July, 1858. During his tenure, the onerous and
						important duties of the Clerkship were preformed in the most exemplary and
						able manner.</p>
					<p>In the meantime, being then a resident of Staunton, the people of that town
						called him five times to the office of their Mayor, in which capacity he
						served them faithfully during the years 1839, 1842, 1848, 1849 and 1850.</p>
					<p>For many years he was a director in the Va. Central Railroad Company, and
						also a director in the Valley Bank at Staunton. He was a man of great public
						spirit, and whenever the question was to promote the interests of his
						beloved State or county, he was always found a zealous and efficient
						co-operator.</p>
					<p>Mr. Kinney's friendships were warm, unwavering and true; his companionship
						genial, intelligent and very pleasant; his principles patriotic, honest and
						unbending.</p>
					<p>His private and social virtues were as pure and spotless as his public career
						was upright and worthy of emulation. For some years past the state of his
						health had been feeble and declining, and his friends had watched with
						anxious solicitude the approach of that sad result which has now deprived
						them of his presence among them. At last it came suddenly, and without a
						struggle or a groan he died as peacefully as a weary child who would go to
						rest.</p>
					<p>His remains were committed to the silent tomb on Sunday, the 23rd of
						December, followed by a large concourse of sympathizing friends and
						neighbors.</p>
					<p>May he rest in peace, and in that better country to which he has gone may he
						reap the rich reward of his well spent life.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Kinney</ln>
						<fn>Jefferson</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>An extended and glowing obituary for Jefferson Kinney, who had a long
					career in public service including five terms as mayor of Staunton. Kinney died
					on December 21 at the age of 61.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>03</column>
				<head>Aim of the Radical Party</head>
				<origin>Richmond Times</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The negro is our labor. If the fanatics will only cease their baleful
						interference, capital and labor in the South will regulate its relations, as
						in every other country. The former master feels an interest in his former
						slave and dependent-the recent slave cannot but help looking up to his
						former owner, who for many years past treated him in the great majority of
						cases with kindness, and furnished him with all that most men labor for, his
						food and his clothes. The negroes, if left to themselves, have no unkind
						feelings to the whites, and by mutual dependency, the most friendly
						relations could be established on a permanent footing, and their sentiments
						would soon be in unison and sympathy with our own.</p>
					<p>It is this that the Radicals fear. They do not wish any union between the
						whites and blacks of the South. It is their aim to sow discord between the
						two races and keep them apart-One would naturally infer from their course
						and their speeches, that were a negro insurrection to spring up in the
						Southern States they would not only rejoice, but if in their power aid it.
						In Virginia no such out-break could ever occur; in the first place, because
						of the superior intelligence of our negroes; and in the second, from their
						inferiority to the whites in numbers; but along the coast of North Carolina,
						in South Carolina and Southern Georgia, if the Radicals and their emissaries
						are permitted to carry out their plans they must eventually bring about a
						conflict of races.</p>
					<p>We are well aware that the great mass of the rank and file of the Republican
						party at the North would shrink with horror if they could look into futurity
						and see the natural result of the acts and teachings of their leaders, and
						that they apprehend no such fruit; but we tell them it will come as
						certainly as the sun will rise tomorrow if the Radical plans are carried
						out, and further more, that their leaders are anxious to bring it
							about.-<emph rend="italic">Rich. Times</emph>. </p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Claims that "friendly relations" between whites and blacks "could soon be
					established on a permanent footing," if not for the "baleful influence" of the
					Radicals who seek to "bring about a conflict of races."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>04</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Baker</ln>
						<fn>Wm. E.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Collins</ln>
						<fn>James</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Reynolds</ln>
						<fn>Virginia M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Virginia Reynolds and James Collins were married in Staunton on January 3
					by Rev. William Baker.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>04</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Blain</ln>
						<fn>J. S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Guy</ln>
						<fn>John S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Glendy</ln>
						<fn>Belle Martin</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Glendy</ln>
						<fn>R. J.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Belle Martin Glendy and John S. Guy, of Augusta, were married in Bath
					county on January 1 by Rev. J. S. Blain.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>04</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Bratton</ln>
						<fn>Andrew S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Guy</ln>
						<fn>Mary Moore</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Guy</ln>
						<fn>William</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Blain</ln>
						<fn>J. S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Mary Moore Guy, of Augusta, and Andrew Bratton, of Bath, were married in
					Bath on January 1 by Rev. J. S. Blain.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>04</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Blain</ln>
						<fn>John S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>McClintic</ln>
						<fn>Wm. S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Montgomery</ln>
						<fn>Hettie</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Montgomery</ln>
						<fn>Edwin</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Hettie Montgomery, of Augusta, and William McClintic, of Bath, were married
					on October 18 by Rev. John S. Blain.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1867.01.08.04">
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
	</paperBody>
</hwp>
