<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1867/va.au.ss.1867.07.16">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/02/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-07-16">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="07"/>
            <day>16</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1867.07.16.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1867.07.16.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Another Voice From Albemarle</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A counter-meeting was held in Albemarle last week to refute the
                    "co-operation" meeting which was castigated in the Spectator last week. They
                    issued resolutions denouncing the cooperationists, arguing that "abject
                    behaviour will rob misfortune of its dignity," and claimed to speak for
                    "nine-tenths of our citizens."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1867.07.16.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sears</ln>
                        <fn>Barnas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Dr. Barnas Sears, the former president of Brown University,
                    will soon make Staunton his permanent home.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Madison</ln>
                        <fn>R. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Local doctor R. L. Madison will be leaving the community to resume his
                    chair at the Virginia Military Institute.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News-Women's Rights</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Under this heading we advise all good husbands to call on Messrs. Kayser
                        &amp; Young, whose advertisement appears in today's papers and buy their
                        wives the greatest of all labor-saving machines, a good sewing machine.
                        "Singer's new family Sewing Machine" is pronounced "incomparably the best in
                        existence," and no more acceptable and useful gift can be presented to any
                        household than such a machine. If you love your wife, call and get her
                    one.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Encourages "good husbands" to visit a local store "and buy their wives the
                    greatest of all labor-saving machines, a good sewing machine."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Registration in Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Boards of Registration for the districts of Churchville, Mt. Solon and
                        Mt. Sidney, Augusta county, met yesterday, and will continue for six days.
                        The following is a statement of the number of persons already registered in
                        six districts of this country, which gives a majority of 1408 for the
                        whites:</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>District</cell>
                            <cell>Whites</cell>
                            <cell>Colored</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Staunton No. 1</cell>
                            <cell>380</cell>
                            <cell>184</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>" " 2</cell>
                            <cell>367</cell>
                            <cell>258</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Middlebrook " 3</cell>
                            <cell>407</cell>
                            <cell>124</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Greenville, " 4</cell>
                            <cell>428</cell>
                            <cell>123</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Wayensboro, 5</cell>
                            <cell>470</cell>
                            <cell>224</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>New Hope, 6</cell>
                            <cell>376</cell>
                            <cell>102</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>2428</cell>
                            <cell>1015</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists registration totals for the six districts composing Augusta county.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>WE are pleased to learn that the Friends of Temperance in this place are in a
                        prosperous condition, and are constantly growing in strength.-We are truly
                        glad to see our young men becoming interested in the cause of temperance and
                        enlisting in the ranks of the cold water army, whose object and aim are to
                        conquer that demon of destruction who is daily and hourly bringing thousands
                        to the drunkard's grave, and stealing the last morsel of bread from the
                        mouths of many poor children. They installed, on the first of July, the
                        following list of officers, for the ensuing term of six months:</p>
                    <p>H. F. Lushbaugh, President; Geo. W. Long, Associate; Thomas E. Fuller,
                        Secretary; John H. Lushbaugh, Financial Secretary; John T. Long, Treasurer;
                        J. S. Dull, Conductor; Wm. Southward, Assistant Conductor; C. M. Fuller, I.
                        S.; James Gregory, O. S.; Wm. D. Candler, Chaplain.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lushbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>H. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>Geo. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fuller</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lushbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>John T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dull</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Southard</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fuller</ln>
                        <fn>C. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gregory</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Candler</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Praises the organization of the local Friends of Temperance, whose members
                    selected officers at a meeting last week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Tributes of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Died of paralysis, near Versailles, Morgan county, Mo. Mrs. CHRISTIANA
                        ARGENBRIGHT, on the 19th of June, 1867.</p>
                    <p>The subject of this notice was born near Staunton, Va., August 23rd, 1776,
                        and at the time of her death was near 91 years old. She resided in Augusta,
                        until the Fall of 1855, when she emigrated to Missouri with her eldest son.</p>
                    <p>For a number of years previous to her removal to Missouri, she had been a
                        member of the Lutheran church, and died as tranquil as a summer's sun sinks
                        to rest.</p>
                    <p>"Peaceful be thy silent slumber-</p>
                    <p>Peaceful in the grave so low:</p>
                    <p>Thou no more wilt join our number;</p>
                    <p>Thou no more our songs shalt know. <lb/></p>
                    <p>Yet again we hope to meet thee,</p>
                    <p>When the day of life is fled;</p>
                    <p>Then in heaven with joy to greet thee,</p>
                    <p>Where no farewell tear is shed.</p>
                    <p>Died on last Thursday night, the 11th, instant, Mrs. Elizabeth Carroll, in
                        the 72nd year of her age.</p>
                    <p>Mrs Carroll was one of the oldest inhabitants of Staunton, and was known as a
                        good and kindhearted woman-beloved by all who knew her. She had only to be
                        known to be loved. Under many years of suffering, from general debility, she
                        exhibited the highest degree of christan fortitude and patience-never
                        murmuring or complaining. In her last moments, while surrounded by all her
                        children and a number of relatives and friends, she expressed a willingness
                        to "depart and be with Christ, which is far better"-thus leaving the bright
                        testimony behind that she enjoyed the comforts and consolation of an
                        unwavering faith in God, her spirit took its everlasting flight, and now
                        rests in the bosom of her savior. "Blessed are the dead which die in the
                        Lord: yea, saith the spirit, that they may rest from their labors; and their
                        works do follow them."</p>
                    <p>She leaves a large circle of relatives and friends to mourn their irreparable
                        loss</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Argenbright</ln>
                        <fn>Christiana</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carroll</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Offers "tributes of respect" for two women who died recently. Christina
                    Argenbright was born in 1776 and lived in Augusta until 1855. She died on June
                    19. Elizabeth Carroll was "beloved by all who knew her" and was 72 when she died
                    on July 11.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dobbins</ln>
                        <fn>Josephine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Frank Montgomery, of Mint Spring, Augusta, and Josephine Dobbins were
                    married in Charlottesville on July 9 by Rev. J. C. Bowman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1867.07.16.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
