<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1867/va.au.ss.1867.05.28">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/31/00</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-05-28">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day norm="00">28</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1867.05.28.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1867.05.28.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Registering Officers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following persons have been appointed registering officers for Augusta
                        county:--Geo. W. McCutchen, at large; Thomas Leahay, late officer
                        volunteers, at large; John Yates, at large; Fred. S. Tukey, first district;
                        A. T. Maupin, second district; George Rubush, third district; William
                        Gibson, fourth district; Jacob Stover, fifth district; Charles Bates, sixth
                        district; Samuel Landis, seventh district; Abraham Huffman, eighth district;
                        George A. Shuey, ninth district.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCutchen</ln>
                        <fn>Geo. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leahay</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yates</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tukey</ln>
                        <fn>Fred. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maupin</ln>
                        <fn>A. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rubush</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bates</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Landis</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huffman</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuey</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the men appointed registration officers throughout the county.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>National Intelligencer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The National Intelligencer thinks that the ultras at the North, have sent
                        sundry violent Radical emissaries to the South, to stir up the passions of
                        the people, and provoke riots and tumults; they hoping, that if this plan is
                        successful; it will be made a pretext for the getting up of a furious
                        crusade of public opinion in the North, the reassembling of Congress in
                        July, the impeachment and deposition of the President without delay, and the
                        passage of bills of confiscation of Southern lands, and perhaps the seizure
                        and execution of individuals. The Intelligencer, therefore, cautions the
                        Southern people to say nothing and do nothing which can give an excuse for
                        the proposed new plan of operations-"to keep their temper and maintain their
                        dignity."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that "ultras" in the North have sent emissaries to the South with
                    the hope of provoking riots as a pretext to galvanize Northern sentiment against
                    the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1867.05.28.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the town was crowded yesterday and many appeared "more
                    cheerful than they have been for some time, owing, no doubt, to the fine
                    prospects of a fruitful harvest." The article expresses "hope that our oppressed
                    and heavily taxed farmers will all be blessed with plenteous crops and cheerful
                    hearts."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local News--Philomathesian</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Philmathesians met on last Saturday night, with open doors, and the
                        fertile question-"Is the assassination of tyrants justifiable?" was
                        discussed before quite a crowd of ladies and gentlemen, by Messrs. Chewning
                        and Effinger in the affirmative, and Messrs. Moore and O'Ferrall in the
                        negative. The discussion was quite animated and interesting, and the <emph
                            rend="italic">young </emph> orators displayed a high degree of moral
                        courage and considerable historical research. The vote on the question
                        stood:--affirmative,4; negative, 13. </p>
                    <p>They also elected a new corps of officers for the ensuing term of two months,
                        as follows: C. A. Richardson, President; Howard Wayt, Vice President; Ned.
                        Kinney, Secretary, and W. Ker, Treasurer.</p>
                    <p>The question for net Saturday night reads:--"Ought Southerners, who are
                        entitled to vote, avail themselves of it?"</p>
                    <p>The question for next Saturday night week is:--"Ought a person ever advocate
                        what he believes to be wrong?"</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chewning</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Effinger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Ferrall</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn>C. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wayt</ln>
                        <fn>Howard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Ned.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ker</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>At their meeting last Saturday the Philomathesian society elected officers
                    and debated the question, "Is the assassination of tyrants justifiable?" After
                    discussion, the final vote was decided in the negative by a vote of 13 to 4.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>New York Herald</origin>
                <commentary>"The New York Herald, describing the effects of the "electioneering" to
                    which the South is at present treated, says:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"Radical threats of confiscation, and appeals to the negro-to bad passions
                        and violent crimes-are already forcing the people to believe that any other
                        party must be better and safer for them than the Republican party. The
                        present state of parties in Virginia is significant. Already the blacks have
                        taken an extreme position around the more violent Radical leaders-a position
                        that will render it impossible for the white voters there to join them, and
                        will, consequently, drive these white voters into the arms of any
                        opposition.</p>
                    <p>"Mr. Botts who favors such action as will render it possible for whites and
                        blacks to act together as Union men and republicans is denounced by the
                        negroes as the enemy of republicanism. This is the legitimate result of the
                        recent radical campaigning and this will go much further. It will force all
                        men in the South who are not in favor of the policy of the extravagant few
                        to oppose the republican orators in the South to-day are building up the
                        democratic party far more efficiently than the democrats themselves could do
                        it."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the most radical Republicans have polarized the races
                    politically throughout the South, with blacks supporting "the more violent
                    Radical leaders," driving whites to the Democratic party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flournoy</ln>
                        <fn>P. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morgan</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Morgan and John hanger were married in Middlebrook at the home of the
                    bride's father on May 16 by Rev. P. P. Flournoy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>R. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latane</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>Reuben T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tams</ln>
                        <fn>Fannie S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tams</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Fannie Tams and Reuben Phillips were married in Trinity Church on May 21 by
                    Rev. R. H. Phillips, assisted by Rev. J. S. Latane.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibson</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibson</ln>
                        <fn>John St. Pierre</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>Mary S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>Joel S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Wallace and Dr. John St. Pierre Gibson were married at the residence
                    of the bride's father on May 16 by Rev. Isaac Gibson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Mary F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Smith died at the residence of her mother in Staunton on April 24. She
                    was 18 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heizer</ln>
                        <fn>Cicero H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Cicero Heizer died at his father's residence in Greenville on May 18. He
                    was 20 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sarah Wilson died at the home of her husband on Buffalo Creek on April 19.
                    She was 62 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1867.05.28.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
