<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1867/va.au.ss.1867.10.22">
	<header>
		<title>Staunton Spectator</title>
		<tagger>
			<taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
			<tagDate>12/11/00</tagDate>
			<tagNote/>
		</tagger>
		<address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
		<date n="1867-10-22">
			<year>1867</year>
			<month norm="10">October</month>
			<day>22</day>
			<weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
		</date>
		<frequency>weekly</frequency>
		<extent>04</extent>
		<editionNote/>
	</header>
	<paperBody>
		<page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1867.10.22.01">
			<div type="l">
				<column>06</column>
				<head>Rail Road Subscription</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>I learn from a communication in a <emph rend="italic">Spectator </emph> of
						recent date over the signature of "X," that the County Court at its last
						term made an order submitting to the voters of the county, the question of a
						subscription of three hundred thousand (300,000) dollars, to the Chesapeake
						and Ohio Railroad. I have not a copy of the act of the Legislature
						conferring this authority upon the Court, and am therefore unacquainted with
						its terms, or the date of its passage.-But whatever may be the provisions of
						the act, or whenever it may have been enacted, it is obvious that a state of
						things exists at this time in Va. neither contemplated nor foreseen by the
						Legislature. </p>
					<p>The law under which this proceeding is to take place, doubtless authorizes
						the Court to submit the question to the qualified voters of the country. At
						the passage of this act of the Assembly, "the qualified voters" were a
						portion of the citizens of the State clearly ascertained and accurately
						distinguished, by the Constitution, as possessing certain qualifications
						which entitled them to the exercise of the elective franchise. And to the
						citizens of the State, resident in the county, possessing these
						qualifications, and to none others, was the Court authorized to submit such
						questions. An act of the Legislature authorizing the Court to submit a
						certain question to the vote of one class of citizens, can confer no
						authority upon it to submit the question to an entirely different class.
						And, this question of subscription will be submitted to, and decided by, the
						votes of persons to whom the Legislature never designed to grant such
						authority; whilst a large number of the persons by whose votes the law
						intended this question to be determined will be excluded from any voice or
						influence in its decision. It is perfectly evident that the Legislature
						never intended the decision of such persons except those authorized by the
						Constitution and laws of the State. It, therefore seems to me that the legal
						authority of the Court to submit this question to the represents voters of
						the county is extremely doubtful.-This order of the Court will, however,
						afford an opportunity to a large number of persons to bind heavy burdens for
						other people's shoulders, whilst they will not touch them, with so much as
						one of their fingers.</p>
					<p>If this subscription should be carried, I hope there will be found a goodly
						number of the people possessing enough of that manly fortitude, heroic
						patriotism and enlightened regard to legal rights which animated John
						Hampden, to make them resist its collection by every lawful means. A tax
						imposed in this way is as much in contravention of justice and the
						constitutional rights of the citizen, as was the imposition of "ship money"
						by Charles the First.</p>
					<p>It is incumbent upon the advocates oft his subscription to show, that the
						county has some special and peculiar interest to be advance by the
						completion of this railroad. Will it open a new market for its surplus
						products? It certainly will not. Because it penetrates a country having a
						large surplus of just such products as Augusta county wishes to sell. The
						State of Ohio will not want to purchase our wheat, corn, hay, apples,
						whiskey or pork, for the reason that these are the very products she has for
						sale. The road, however, will accomplish one result, it will bring Ohio
						products into direct competition with us at our very doors.-But, if it will
						open to us no new market it will, doubtless, increase our facilities for
						reaching our present one. It will be borne in mind that the Chesapeake and
						Ohio Railroad is merely an extension of the Central. We will, therefore only
						have our present facilities of getting our surplus to market, burdened with
						all the increased transportation consequent upon the extension of the road
						to the Ohio river. Those persons who live along the line of a railroad can
						tell whether the transportation of the <emph rend="italic">way
						freight</emph> is ever postponed to <emph rend="italic">through </emph>. Or
						if they cannot at present, perhaps they will be able to do so when the
						Central cars are flying "onward to Richmond," freighted with Ohio what and
						flour, whilst theirs moulds and rots in the depots, and the tax collector
						sells milch cows and plough horses, to meet the county subscription of
						$300.000. </p>
					<p>But if it will not increase the facilities of getting to market, perhaps it
						will cheapen the cost. It may do so, but I can see no reason why it should.
						When the Central reaches the Ohio river it will have to compete for freight
						and travel with the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad. And to do this successfully
						the charges upon through freight and travel will have to be reduced to the
						lowest figure, which is the mere cost of transportation to the
						Railroad.-This will obviously be a great advantage to Ohio. But wherein will
						it ensue to the benefit of Augusta? I can see but one advantage she can
						derive from it, and that is one highly honorable to her disinterested and
						enlarged liberality. The already high charges upon her surplus products will
						have to be kept up, if not increased, in order to enable the road to carry
						Ohio products at a low rate. Noble, generous, magnanimous Augusta!!</p>
					<p>But if it will not cheapen, immediately, the cost of transportation, perhaps
						it will establish a rival line, the natural competition between which and
						the Central will eventually reduce freights to a reasonable amount.
						Certainly it will not, for being a mere extension of the Central, it will
						only enlarge the sphere and lengthen the field for the display of the
						admirable administrative and executive abilities of the present Directory.</p>
					<p>But if the completion of the road to the Ohio river will neither increase our
						facilities of getting to market, nor reduce the cost, the subscription of
						$300,000 will surely so <emph rend="italic">reduce </emph> our taxes, and
						make the payment so <emph rend="italic">facile </emph>, that it will be a
						real pleasure to meet Towberman and Lightner with their ticket bags. And
						even if this <emph rend="italic">small </emph> subscription should
						unexpectedly increase our taxes, the prospects ahead, both politically and
						financially, are so bright and encouraging, that we ought not to hesitate at
						increased pecuniary undertakings. The advocates of this subscription can
						safely assure the people that the "clouds," which, at present, hang so
						portentously over their heads are "big with mercies," and to guarantee that
						they shall "burst in blessings on their heads." </p>
					<p>Some hundreds of years hence, as some antiquarian son of "old Augusta"
						examines her must records, how his heart will swell and exult, as he reads
						her history, and learns that whilst she paid <emph rend="italic">twenty
							thousand dollars</emph> for bringing the railroad to her county seat and
						geographical centre, with a generosity and magnanimity unparalleled, she
						taxed herself <emph rend="italic">three hundred thousand dollars</emph> to
						make a road for the benefit of the people of Ohio! </p>
					<p>FARMER.</p>
					<p>October, 12.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer>Farmer</trailer>
				<names/>
				<summary>"Farmer" decries the subscription of $300,000 for the Chesapeake and Ohio
					Railroad that will soon be submitted to the voters of Augusta. He urges readers
					to vote against it, arguing that it will benefit Ohio but not Augusta. If it
					does pass, the author expresses his hope that those with "manly fortitude,
					heroic patriotism, and enlightened regard" will "resist its collection by every
					lawful means."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1867.10.22.02">
			<div type="e">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>Be Sure to Vote</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>We regret exceedingly that the election occurs on the day of our issue, for
						we would like to appeal to every subscriber to turn out and vote AGAINST the
						Convention, and for the Conservative candidates-WADDELL, HARRISON, and
						SOUTHALL. This is an important election, and we regret that there is not
						time to impress upon the voters the importance of seeing that every
						Conservative voter be induced to go to the polls and to cast his vote for
						the Conservative ticket. No voter should split up his ticket, but vote the
						Conservative ticket SOLID. As most of our readers cannot receive this issue
						till after the election, an appeal to them now to RALLY to the polls, would
						be like sounding the bugle note to charge after the battle was fought.</p>
					<p>Were it not for this, we would write a stirring appeal, such as the
						importance of the election demands. Every white voter in the county should
						vote the whole of the following</p>
					<p>CONSERVATIVE TICKET!</p>
					<p>
						<emph rend="italic">AGAINST A CONVENTION!!</emph>
					</p>
					<p>Delegates for Augusta count,</p>
					<p>JOSEPH A. WADDELL,</p>
					<p>POWELL HARRISON.</p>
					<p>Delegate for District composed of Augusta,</p>
					<p>Albemarle and Louisa Counties</p>
					<p>JAMES C. SOUTHALL.</p>
					<p>Those who vote for a convention vote for <emph rend="italic">universal negro
							suffrage</emph>. </p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Waddell</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Harrison</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Urges "every white voter" to vote the Conservative ticket solidly while
					also voting against the Convention.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>01</column>
				<head/>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Urges "voters in town" to vote early and then "see that all other white
					voters are brought to the polls."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>Wm. F. Gordon's Speech</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>On Friday night last, W. F. Gordon, Jr., the Radical candidate for the
						Convention to represent this District, delivered a long, tedious and
						disjointed speech in the Court House of this place. His chief effort seemed
						to be to secure the negro vote. He charged that his opposing candidate,
						James C. Southall, was inconsistent, and in doing so proved himself equally
						inconsistent. He said he would get the negro vote of Albemarle and Louisa,
						and expected to get the negro vote of this county.</p>
					<p>PETER INDEPENDENCE KURTZ arose to reply, and soon Gordon, esteeming
						"discretion the better part of valor," vamosed.</p>
					<p>A full report of Mr. Kurtz' remarks will be found on the fourth page</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>William Gordon, a candidate for the proposed Convention, addressed an
					audience at the Court House last Friday. The article reports that he "delivered
					a long, tedious and disjointed speech" and that "his chief effort seemed to be
					to secure the negro vote."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>02</column>
				<head>Reaction Against a Convention</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>Nearly all the papers in this State, except avowed Radical ones, are now
						earnestly calling upon the voters to vote <emph rend="italic">against
						</emph> the Convention. For many months the <emph rend="italic">Spectator
						</emph> occupied this position "solitary and alone." The policy advocated by
						the <emph rend="italic">Spectator </emph> from the beginning, without
						"variableness or shadow of turning," is now endorsed by a large majority of
						the white voters of the State, and if the election were postponed a month
						longer, the Convention would be voted down, notwithstanding the negro vote
						in favor of it. The course of the Spectator has been satisfactorily
						vindicated. </p>
					<p>This is but another illustration of great truth that principle should never
						be discarded, and that the <emph rend="italic">right </emph>, if
						persistently maintained, will ultimately triumph. The people should never
						cease to cling to the right, and to hope for its success. In the language of
						Buckle, whom we have several times quoted recently, "in any country which
						pretends to be free let no one be disheartened by the temporary overthrow of
						the Right. Weak, vain, and vicious theories soon perish when brought forth
						into that strong current which makes Truth only the more robust. There is no
						device nor cunning which can long delay the march of Public Opinion-and
						Experience <emph rend="italic">soon tears to pieces and tramples under her
							feet those flimsy disguises and stratagems by which bold and bad men
							seek to pervert or mould to their own benefit the destinies of a great,
							free and enlightened people.</emph>" </p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Expresses satisfaction that most newspapers in the state, "except avowed
					Radical ones," have now joined the Spectator's opinion, urging their readers to
					vote against the Convention. The author also argues that if the election were
					postponed for a month while public opinion continues to shift, the Convention
					would be defeated "notwithstanding the negro vote in favor of it."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>02</column>
				<head>Against a Convention</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>Our readers will remember what a cold reception greeted us when, about a
						month since, the <emph rend="italic">Index </emph> was fairly and squarely
						committed to the opposition to the calling of a Convention. </p>
					<p>* * * * * * *</p>
					<p>Promptly in response to our call upon the press answered the Lynchburg <emph
							rend="italic">Republican </emph>, the Norfolk <emph rend="italic"
							>Virginian </emph>, the Winchester <emph rend="italic">News </emph> the
						Warrenton <emph rend="italic">Index </emph>, the Staunton <emph
							rend="italic">Spectator </emph>, the Fredericksburg <emph rend="italic"
							>News </emph> and <emph rend="italic">Herald </emph>, and in fact all
						the papers of Northern Virginia against a Convention.-<emph rend="italic"
							>Petersburg Index, Oct</emph> 17<emph rend="italic">th</emph>. </p>
					<p>The complacent assumption of the Index that the Staunton <emph rend="italic"
							>Spectator responded</emph> to <emph rend="italic">its </emph> call to
						oppose a convention, made "about a month since," will excite the
						responsibilities of the readers of the <emph rend="italic">Spectator </emph>
						who know that it has been opposing the Convention not only "about a month"
						but for about <emph rend="italic">seven </emph> months-ever since it has
						been presented for the action of the people. </p>
					<p>Since we commenced our opposition to the call of the Convention, the editor
						of the <emph rend="italic">Index </emph> constructed what is known as the
						Petersburg Platform, mounted it, and earnestly called upon the people to
						rally upon it. </p>
					<p>If there be any credit due to the journal which was first to oppose the call
						for a Convention, that credit is <emph rend="italic">certainly </emph> due
						to the <emph rend="italic">Spectator </emph>, for it did not hesitate at
						all, but took that position as soon as the bill was passed, (four or five
						months in advance of any other paper) and has maintained it earnestly and
						consistently to the present time. If all the other papers had been as
						prompt, decided, and earnest in opposition to it, the call for a Convention
						would have been defeated. The <emph rend="italic">Spectator </emph> has done
						its duty faithfully. </p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Disparages the Petersburg Index's "complacent assumption" that they were
					the first paper to urge readers to vote against the Convention. If credit is to
					be given to the journal that began the call, the author argues, "that credit is
					certainly due to the Spectator."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>03</column>
				<head/>
				<origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
				<commentary>The Richmond Whig says:</commentary>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The Richmond Whig says: "Radicalism, it is believed, has received its
						death-blow at the North, and Conservatism is to be installed in its place.
						We have now our part of the general task to perform at the South. Here a
						vulgar and ignorant and vindictive Radicalism has reared its head, which is
						the more despicable and would be the more dangerous from these qualities of
						vulgarity and ignorance. It must be strangled in its infancy. If it once
						seize upon power it will hold it for years. If we stifle it now it will not
						annoy us again. Here, too, as in the North, conservative men, whether
						Unionists or Confederates, white or black, must get together and work
						together and vote together. There are but two tickets, in fact, before the
						people of this city, the one representing Conservatism and the other
						Radicalism of the vilest description. There is nothing between. One or the
						other must be chosen. If any one is content to be considered a Radical or
						the character represented by the Radical ticket, there is no doubt how he
						will vote. But those who make the least pretension to moderation and
						conservatism cannot escape the obligation to vote for the ticket the
						Conservatives have put out."</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Argues that recent elections in Northern states indicate that Radicalism is
					on the wane there and that now the South must do its part. The "vulgar and
					ignorant and vindictive Radicalism" that has appeared in the South "must be
					strangled in its infancy."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>03</column>
				<head>What Will be the Effect?</head>
				<origin>New York World</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Argues that the recent Democratic gains in the North will have far-reaching
					effects, causing "the white citizens of the South to stand resolutely aloof from
					the bastard governments thrust upon them at the end of a bayonet." Ultimately,
					the author predicts, the Republicans will crumble since "great majorities in
					Congress amount to little, when great majorities of the people are of a contrary
					way of thinking."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1867.10.22.03">
			<div type="a">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>Local News</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Spitler</ln>
						<fn>J. Wayne</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>An unnamed black man was arrested and committed to jail, charged with
					assaulting J. Wayne Spitler, "a white man."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>Local News</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Trout</ln>
						<fn>E. Stribling</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Lieut.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Trout</ln>
						<fn>N. K.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Lieut. E. Stribling Trout, the eldest son of N. K. Trout, died on Sunday
					night at his father's home. His funeral will take place today at 11 a.m. at the
					Episcopal Church.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>Local News</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Mason</ln>
						<fn>C. R.</fn>
						<sf>Jr.</sf>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Tate</ln>
						<fn>Jas.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Gilliam</ln>
						<fn>Wm. H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Harrison</ln>
						<fn>J.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Berry</ln>
						<fn>C. B.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Reports that five men from Augusta "are progressing finely" at the Medical
					School at the University of Virginia.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>01</column>
				<head>Local News--Bold Rogues</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>A short time since, a colored person, in the day time, went into the house of
						Hon. A. H. H. Stuart and picked up some cut-glass goblets and walked off
						with them. Mr. Stuart met him with the goblets in his hands, but supposed he
						had been sent for them.</p>
					<p>A few days since, an overcoat was stolen from the hat-rack in the hall of Mr.
						J. a Waddell's house. Our citizens should be on their guard against
					thieves.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Stuart</ln>
						<fn>A. H. H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Waddell</ln>
						<fn>J. A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Reports that acts of daytime theft have occurred recently at the homes of
					two of the county's most prominent citizens, A. H. H. Stuart and J. A. Waddell.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>02</column>
				<head>A Word to Freedmen</head>
				<origin>Fredericksburg News</origin>
				<commentary>"We published an editorial last week, containing some wholesome counsel
					to the colored population. The Fredericksburg News of the 14th contained a
					communication upon the same subject and with similar views written by R. R.
					Collier, from which we extract the following:"</commentary>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>"The whites of the South need <emph rend="italic">labor </emph>, and will
						have it. It is with us, as with all people, that the well-to-do in the
						world, will have others who are not well off to do their work.--The country
						must have laborers. The question is: <emph rend="italic">are they to be
							white or black in these States?</emph> The question opens a wider field
						than I have time just now to explore, or your paper space to spread out in
						print. I will state two facts. The negroes know that the white people with
						whom they have been raised, prefer black servants to white ones. Then, we
						whites desire the negroes to remain amongst us. The white people of the
						North desire these broad acres to dwell on and to cultivate. If the negroes
						will not gratify our tastes to have them for our servants, white laborers
						from the North and all Europe will come in and take their places.-That is
						not only certain to be so, unless negroes make and keep us their friends by
						taking sides with us, but it was avowed twelve years ago by leading men of
						the North, that the poor white men of the North and of the world want this
						fertile region and will occupy it, if they have to exterminate the negro to
						get it. And that is the other fact. We prefer the negro, <emph rend="italic"
							>and </emph> the poor of the North say they will come and take his
						place. Who is the friend of the negro? We, who prefer his presence, or they
						who would exclude him? Every negro has sense enough to see how it is, and if
						they are not cheated by the Yankees, they will have an eye single to their
						won interest which is to stay with us as friends." </p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Argues that the white men of the South want "the negroes" to remain among
					them as their servants while "the poor white men of the North and of the world
					want this fertile region and will occupy it, if they have to exterminate the
					negro to get it." From these assertions, the author argues, blacks should look
					"to their own interest which is to stay with us as friends."</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>04</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Hawes</ln>
						<fn>H. H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Wright</ln>
						<fn>J. F.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Bunch</ln>
						<fn>Martha J.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Martha Bunch and J. F. Wright were married at the residence of the bride's
					father on October 8 by Rev. H. H. Hawes.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>04</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Hawes</ln>
						<fn>H. H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Patterson</ln>
						<fn>George C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Bell</ln>
						<fn>Wm. J.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Dr.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Patterson</ln>
						<fn>Mary A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>McClung</ln>
						<fn>J. F.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Patterson</ln>
						<fn>Maria Va.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Rev. H. H. Hawes conducted a double wedding ceremony on October 16 at the
					home of George Patterson, where William Bell was married to Mary Patterson and
					J. F. McClung to Maria Patterson.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>04</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>See</ln>
						<fn>C. S. M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Fishburne</ln>
						<fn>E. G.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Van Lear</ln>
						<fn>Ella L.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Ella Van Lear and E. G. Fishburne were married on October 10 by Rev. C. S.
					M. See.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>04</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Shriver</ln>
						<fn>Louis</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Father</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>O'Rork</ln>
						<fn>J. Colin</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Capt.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Murphy</ln>
						<fn>Mollie E.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Murphy</ln>
						<fn>Thomas</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>J. Colin O'Rork, formerly of Staunton, and Mollie Murphy, of Brown, Ohio,
					were married in Ripley, Ohio on July 4 by Rev. Father Louis Shriver.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>04</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Madison</ln>
						<fn>L. B.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Spears</ln>
						<fn>James A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Tate</ln>
						<fn>James T.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Shaver</ln>
						<fn>Margaret S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>James Tate and Margaret Shaver, formerly of Augusta, were married in
					Faquier County on October 17 by Rev. L. B. Madison.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>04</column>
				<head>Marriages</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Bowman</ln>
						<fn>F. H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Thrift</ln>
						<fn>George N.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>McCue</ln>
						<fn>Bettie K.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>McCue</ln>
						<fn>Thomas W.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>George Thrift, of Madison, and Bettie McCue were married at Belvidere,
					Augusta county, on October 15 by Rev. F. H. Bowman.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="o">
				<column>04</column>
				<head>Deaths</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Scott</ln>
						<fn>Margaret C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Margaret Scott died at her home on September 28. She was 64 years old.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1867.10.22.04">
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
	</paperBody>
</hwp>
