<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1868/pa.fr.vs.1868.10.07">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/12/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1868-10-07">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day norm="">7</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.10.07.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Horrible Outrages by Negroes. White Men, Look on this Picture. Shall the
                    Freedmen's Bureau Continue to Feed These Savage Beasts? Shall These Monsters
                    Govern the South? Shall Their Voice Weigh Against You in the Election of your
                    Rulers?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A collection of articles highlighting black crime in the South. Included is
                    an alleged rape and murder in Tennessee, an alleged rape and murder in North
                    Carolina, and an alleged murder of a family in Kentucky.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.10.07.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Deserter Vote</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There are certain men residing in almost every election district in this
                        County to whom the Election Boards have refused the privilege of voting. We
                        refer to those who have been marked as deserters upon the records of Provost
                        Marshals and upon their Company rolls. All such persons, whether they are
                        Radicals or Democrats, have a clear right to vote <emph rend="italic">unless
                            they have been convicted by a Court Martial</emph>. This is the law as
                        it stands <sic>to day</sic>, as <sic>interpretted</sic> by the Supreme Court
                        of Pennsylvania. That Court has passed upon the Act of Congress and the Act
                        of our State Legislature, which were intended to disfranchised these men,
                        and it has decided that unless the men classed as deserters have been <emph
                            rend="italic">convicted</emph> of the crime of desertion by a court of
                        competent jurisdiction, <emph rend="italic">they must be allowed to
                        vote</emph>. We call upon honest men who compose the Boards of Election in
                        the several districts of this County to observe the rulings of the Supreme
                        Court upon this question.</p>
                    <p>In the South Ward of this Borough there is a Radical deserter who votes
                        regularly at every election, and that vote is received by a <emph
                            rend="italic">Democratic</emph> Board, for the reason that the men
                        constituting that Board know he has a clear right to vote. In Green township
                        there is a <emph rend="italic">Radical</emph> deserter who will offer to
                        vote next Tuesday, and whose vote will be received by a <emph rend="italic"
                            >Radical Board</emph>, for the reason that the Radicals there claim,
                        with justice, that he has a clear right to vote. Let there be uniformity of
                        action in this matter. Let Democratic Judges and Inspectors and Radical
                        Judges and Inspectors unite in a strict observance of the law, and receive
                        the votes of all such persons, unless the record of a conviction by a Court
                        Martial is produced against them.</p>
                    <p>With the light that has been thrown upon this subject by the decisions of our
                        Supreme Court, the men who refuse to receive the ballots of this class of
                        men most assuredly render themselves liable to a criminal prosecution.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Denounces the court decisions banning deserters from voting. Asserts that
                    every man has a right to vote and no one, Democratic or Republican, should stand
                    in the way of that. Targets Radicals as the worst offenders.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Room for the Leper</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Gov. Curtin is said to be coming here along with Col. McClure, to make a
                        strong effort to carry Franklin county. He will, of course, endeavor to make
                        the Radicals believe that his motives in coming are very patriotic and
                        disinterested, when in truth they are utterly selfish. There is a United
                        States Senator to be elected next winter and Curtin wants the place. He did
                        not come here last fall, because there was no Senator to be made last
                        winter. He left the Radicals of this county "in the lurch" a year ago. He
                        did not lift a finger to save them from the defeat they sustained. They did
                        not care what became of their legislative candidates or their candidates for
                        county offices. But now, when the United States Senatorship is at stake, he
                        comes here to <emph rend="italic">blarney</emph> the Radicals of Franklin
                        county with "assurances of his distinguished consideration." Are they <emph
                            rend="italic">green</emph> enough to believe that he cares a fig for
                        them, or that he would come here at all if he did not want to secure a vote
                        for Senator? The only man on the Radical ticket for whose success he cares a
                        pinch of snuff is Capt. Walker. He wants the Captain elected because he
                        wants his vote for United States Senator. This it is, and this alone, that
                        brings him here.</p>
                    <p>Is it not time for the Radicals of Franklin county to cease to be fooled by
                        such leprous demagogues as Andrew G. Curtin? Are they content to let it be
                        understood (as it seems to be) all over the State that they are owned by the
                        political firm of Curtin &amp; McClure? How long do they intend it to
                        remain a standing joke in other parts of the State that "when Curtin and
                        McClure take snuff the Radicals of Franklin county sneeze?"</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper ridicules Andrew Curtin for stirring up Radicals in Franklin
                    County, and claims the only reason he's doing it is to gather for a Senatorial
                    bid in a year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Radical Extravagance</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper criticizes Republicans for the financial management of
                    government. The editors assert that the government expenses for September
                    amounted to $28,485,839, and that yearly spending totals $341,824,068. The
                    present administration has spent almost 4 times more than Buchanan's.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Shooting of Lechrone</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In our issue of September 23d, referring to the melancholy death of young
                        Lechrone, we contented ourselves with saying that he had been shot by
                        Benner. As the case was a very serious one, and one upon which a Franklin
                        county jury would have to render a verdict, we refrained from indulging in
                        any comments upon it, though the testimony taken before the Coroner's Jury
                        (which we published) might have justified us in saying something unfavorable
                        to the accused.</p>
                    <p>We regret to say that the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> of the same
                        date did not follow our example. It undertook to state the circumstances
                        connected with the unfortunate affair, and it strayed far away from the
                        truth in order to make out a case in favor of the person who fired the fatal
                        shot. It found itself able to look only with partisan eyes upon a matter
                        involving the lives of two men.</p>
                    <p>Nor did it content itself with the misstatements contained in its issue of
                        the 23d. On the 30th it announced that an inquest had been held "on the body
                        of young Lechrone, who was <emph rend="italic">accidentally</emph> shot on
                        the Greencastle turnpike, near Waynesboro'." If the testimony taken before
                        the Coroner's Jury established anything beyond the simple fact that Lechrone
                        was killed, (and we think it did,) it established that his killing was <emph
                            rend="italic">not</emph> accidental. It is plain that Benner shot to
                            <emph rend="italic">hit</emph>, and as the shot proved instantaneously
                        fatal, it is fair to infer that he shot to <emph rend="italic">kill</emph>.
                        Whether the shooting was justifiable or excusable, is a question upon which
                        we do not wish to express an opinion at present. We regret that the criminal
                        misconduct of the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> in relation to this
                        matter, has made it necessary for us to say what we have said above.</p>
                    <p>Mr. S.W. Hays, one of the editors of the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Repository</emph>, is supposed to be desirous of filling the office of
                        District Attorney. He is the Radical candidate for that office. If elected,
                        it might fall to his lot to conduct the prosecution against Benner. He
                        qualifies himself for this important duty by defending Benner in his paper!
                        He lets the people see how impartially he would perform the duties of the
                        office by giving in his paper a partial, one sided, untruthful account of
                        the affair in which young Lechrone lost his life.</p>
                    <p>We put it to every fair-minded member of the Radical party whether such a man
                        is fit to act as public prosecutor. If his sense of propriety and of duty is
                        so dull that he cannot refrain from permitting his political prejudices to
                        sway him in this case, what security have the public that he will not
                        deviate from a right line in the event of his becoming District Attorney? If
                        he discriminates between Radicals and Democrats in this way, would he not
                        also discriminate between Radicals who were his own personal friends and
                        those who were not? What a farce the administration of justice would become,
                        so far as the District Attorney was concerned, if Mr. S.W. Hays, being
                        elected, should labor in his paper for the acquittal of persons accused of
                        crime, at the same time that he pretended to labor for their conviction in
                        court! Let sober minded members of the Radical party look at this matter in
                        its true light, and let them vote to keep the fountain of justice pure and
                        undefiled.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes a local Republican paper's reporting of a murder which took
                    place a few weeks before. Notes the editor of that paper is running for district
                    attorney and asks how justice can be fairly meted out under such an unscrupulous
                    man.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Jesse on Ulysses</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints testimony from Grant's father that the office of the
                    Presidency would not suit his character and abilities.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyle</ln>
                        <fn>Charles E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hartranft</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Endorsement of Charles E. Boyle for Auditor General. Charges that
                    Hartranft, the present Republican incumbent, has "permitted the State Treasury
                    to be plundered." Boyle will administer his office honestly and "stop the
                    stealing."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ent</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barr</ln>
                        <fn>James P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Endorsement of Gen. W. H. Ent for Surveyor General. The paper charges that
                    Campbell, the present Republican incumbent, has doubled the expenses of the
                    office that now amount to $68,172.46. Ent will bring down costs and allow voters
                    to "save your money."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn>Francis M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cessna</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Endorsement of Francis M. Kimmell for Congress. He will bring peace, Union,
                    and "economy in administration." "The Radical Congress is robbing the people.
                    Cessna would dip into the public pap with as big a spoon as Butler's."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>Calvin M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McConaughy</ln>
                        <fn>Dave</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Endorsement of Calvin M. Duncan for State Senate. His election will "wipe
                    out the disgrace inflicted upon this district by Dave McConaughy's admission to
                    the State Senate." The Republican McConaughy won a challenge that overturned
                    election results that appeared to have favored Duncan.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shively</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Endorsement of B. F. Winger and John Shively for State Legislature. They
                    will end rule by "shoddyites and oil speculators."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baer</ln>
                        <fn>William J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Endorsement of William J. Baer for Law Judge. The paper declares him a
                    model judge and citizen whose moral character is deeply rooted in the
                    "principles of the Christian religion."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zollinger</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Endorsement of Frederick Zollinger for Sheriff. The paper declares him a
                    "man of the people" and an "old style" Sheriff who has not "spent a life in
                    political trickery."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Endorsement of William S. Stenger for District Attorney.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAllen</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Endorsement of William S. McAllen for Commissioner. The paper declares
                    McAllen an "active and sagacious business man" who will never "lose sight of the
                    interests of the tax payers."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Endorsement of Jacob R. Smith for Director of the Poor. The paper argues
                    that Smith, who "conducts his own business economically and well" will "strive
                    to make the Poor House as light a burden as possible to the tax-payers of the
                    county."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Auld</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Endorsement of Hugh Auld for County Surveyor. He is an experienced
                    surveyor, a good citizen, and a staunch Democrat.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Kinstry</ln>
                        <fn>William D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Endorsement of William D. M'Kinstry for Auditor. The paper declares him
                    perfectly suited to the needs of the office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>A Radical's Opinion of Democrats</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>CHAMBERSBURG, Pa., Oct. 6th, 1868.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Messrs. Editors.</emph>--We have in our Borough a few
                        Radicals who seem to have a very high opinion of <emph rend="italic"
                        >white</emph> men. On the day of the Democratic Mass Meeting, the following
                        conversation occurred within my hearing. One of the leading lights of the
                        Radical party in our borough, a man noted for his strict integrity and high
                        Christian character, chanced to meet a lady upon one of our street corners
                        as the large procession was passing by. Said he, "Madam, are you not afraid
                        to be out this morning? Don't you know that the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Rebels</emph> are in town to-day?" "Oh no," said the lady, in reply, "I am
                        not afraid. These men are Democrats, and will not disturb anyone." At this,
                        the pious Radical became very indignant, and exclaimed, "Why, Madam, <emph
                            rend="italic">it takes ten Democrats, and large ones too, to make as
                            good a man as a nigger."</emph> Let us have peace. Yours truly.<lb/>
                        H.C.K.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates an incident, possibly fictional, where a Radical equates Democrats
                    with rebels and as less worthy than black men.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>A Radical Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>GREENCASTLE, Sept. 5 1868.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Messrs. Editors:</emph>--I cannot restrain a desire to
                        tell you about a Radical fizzled demonstration which was had in our town on
                        last Saturday night. You remember, gentlemen, how these truth-concealing,
                        falsehood-telling enemies to our country and her weal were eclipsed by a
                        public meeting of the Democracy only a short time since in this place, and
                        you also remember how an unseasonable <emph rend="italic">rising of Buck
                            Creek</emph> made the rebel Mass Meeting in Chambersburg a failure. In
                        order then to regain the ground lost by these two abortive attempts at
                        public pow-wows, it was determined by "The Ring" to make another effort in
                        the same direction, on Saturday night. Having failed before, all the Radical
                        energy and Radical money of the county were demanded by formal requisition
                        of those in authority to make this a success. A corps of twenty riders was
                        employed one week in advance, at five dollars a day each, whose duty it was
                        to visit every town and hamlet and Republican home, and beg if they could,
                        but buy if they must, every one to turn out.--Here is a literal copy of
                        their instructions; "Tell every one you meet to come. Urge them to come.
                        Plead with them to come. If business prevents their coming, buy them to
                        come. Give them as much as their business will profit them. Tell them they
                        must come. Tell them that the Democrats have beaten us twice in the way of
                        meetings, and that if we do not bestir ourselves they will beat us in the
                        way of elections in October and November. Ride day and night and use all the
                        means within your power to secure a general turn-out."</p>
                    <p>Now, Messrs. Editors, all these extreme means were actually resorted to, in
                        order to make a display in this ancient town on Saturday night. The result
                        of it all was two hundred and twenty cavalry men from Mercersburg, Upton,
                        Waynesboro', Quincy, Shady Grove, Marion, Leitersburg, Md., Greencastle and
                        other places inclusive; and twenty five footmen from town, headed by Geo. W.
                        Zeigler and the rest of "the family," and footed by John Carl. In the ranks
                        we noticed "Elick" Shafhirt and Dave Hess, "Tip" Fletcher and Boggs Byers,
                        Sam. Ilginfritz and Ike Newman (col'd), and others whom it is not necessary
                        here to individualize--all under the command of the hero of the Mexican war,
                        Capt. Miller. As they marched along, Mr. Zeigler, who was mimicked by all
                        his followers, called to the by-standers to "fall in." Those who obeyed were
                        few as angels' visits however. The procession was less when it halted at the
                        speakers' stand than when it started at Prospect school house.</p>
                    <p>The first orator announced by the President was Geo. Chambers, Esq. This
                        youthful orator acquitted himself handsomely.--He must have studied
                        Demosthenes: he was all "action." He told the old, hackneyed story of
                        "Rebels, Rebels', over again and then sat down. He was followed by Col.
                        Black, of Frederick, Md. The Col. commenced by apologizing for his intention
                        to say something <emph rend="italic">new</emph>. This was his exordium--"I
                        am rather a neat specimen of humanity, an I not? You have heard a great deal
                        about carpet-baggers; but I suppose you never saw one. Well there is one
                        before you now. <emph rend="italic">I</emph> am a veritable carpet-bagger."
                        At this juncture Mr. Zeigler, his <emph rend="italic">uncle</emph>, proposed
                        "three cheers for the carpet-bagger." It was <emph rend="italic"
                        >answered</emph> in <emph rend="italic">one</emph>, by himself, the Col's.
                            <emph rend="italic">uncle</emph>, "Tip" Fletcher, the Col's. <emph
                            rend="italic">cousin</emph>, and Moses Anderson, (col'd) the Col's.
                            <emph rend="italic">friend</emph>. After the applause died away, the
                        Col. resumed; but he seemed to have forgotten his promised <emph
                            rend="italic">new</emph> story, and he told the old one, too. He said
                        the financial question was an important one, but he would not discuss it
                        then. He preferred to talk about the poor, oppressed negro of the South, and
                        his sufferings at the hands of the rebels and their sympathizers at the
                        North!!! The Col. disappointed his friends here. They expected a better
                        speech from him.</p>
                    <p>Geo. Eyster, late Capt. and Provost Marshal, was the next orator. He held in
                        his hand a statement of Mr. McLellan's concerning the probable result of the
                        October election in this county. It was to the author's own hand writing.
                        How the gentleman got it I do not know. Possibly in the way Butler did his
                        spoons. Mr. Eyster tried to show us where Mr. McLellan was wrong in his
                        predictions. Instead of three hundred Democratic majority stated by the
                        letter, it would be just one hundred and fifty Republican, even. To do this
                        he said that it would be necessary to get two hundred at Mercersburg and
                        fifty at Greencastle. Now we can tell Mr. Eyster that they will do no such
                        thing--that he must not count on more than one hundred at Mercersburg and
                        none here. Messrs. Editors, it was amusing to hear Mr. Eyster. He and his
                        whole audience were fearfully frightened.</p>
                    <p>But we will not string this letter out too long. I wish only to add that the
                        Republican citizens of this place complained of there being so much
                        drunkenness here at the time of the Democratic meeting. You will not be
                        surprised to learn that it was all laid quite in the shade by the confusion
                        here on Saturday night. You could hear their drunken songs all over town.</p>
                    <p>There is one thing about this meeting which must not be forgotten. It is the
                        only instance within my recollection where the Chairman of the County
                        Committee appointed <emph rend="italic">two</emph> meetings at the same
                        place during a State campaign. Of course there is often more than one
                        irregular meeting held; but never appointed by the committee. This fact only
                        shows how they are frightened, and how they have been out-stripped in the
                        way of meetings by the Democracy.<lb/> LOOKER-ON.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zeigler</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carl</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shafhirt</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hess</ln>
                        <fn>Dave</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>Tip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>Boggs</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ilginfritz</ln>
                        <fn>Sam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newman</ln>
                        <fn>Ike</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>Moses</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prints a letter sent in by a Democrat describing a Radical rally in
                    Greencastle. Heavily emphasizes the lack of turnout, repetitive speeches, and
                    general nervousness on the part of the organizers. Delights at the weakness of
                    Radical support in comparison to Democratic gatherings.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.10.07.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Sherry's Theatre opened with a performance of "Peep O'Day" in Repository
                    Hall. The "Irish Dance" was especially enjoyable and succeeded in "bringing down
                    the house."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Military Company</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Franklin County's new Zouave Company drilled and marched at the fair. They
                    were outfitted in blue uniforms and red pants. Most of the members "saw much
                    service during the war." A poll will be taken during the fair to choose the name
                    of the new company.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Democratic Mass Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>TREMENDOUS OUTPOURING OF THE PEOPLE<lb/> Great Speech of Mayor Hoffman.</p>
                    <p>We believe we speak the literal truth when we say that the Democratic Mass
                        Meeting held in Chambersburg on Wednesday last, was the grandest political
                        demonstration that ever took place in the Cumberland Valley. We have been at
                        nearly all the great meetings held in this valley from 1840 down to the
                        present time, and we do not hesitate to put the meeting of Wednesday last at
                        the head of them all. We expected a good turn out, but the overwhelming
                        numbers in which our friends swarmed all the roads leading to town, and
                        their enthusiasm, took us by surprise. The immensity of the gathering is the
                        more to be wondered at as the meeting took place in the height of seed-time,
                        when our agricultural population were busy putting in their fall crops. In
                        response to our expressions of astonishment at the fullness of the turn out,
                        we received but one answer from every delegation: "This is nothing to what
                        it would have been if our farmers had not been busy seeding."</p>
                    <p>The town was decorated with flags in the Diamond and at appropriate places on
                        the principal streets, and a very large number of houses were handsomely
                        embellished. The delegations from the various districts brought with them a
                        multitude of banners, some of which <sic>mere</sic> handsomely trimmed and
                        all of which bore appropriate emblems or inscriptions. Our Fayetteville
                        friends made a decided hit with their illustration of the "Freedmen's
                        Bureau." But we cannot undertake even a brief description of the various
                        striking features of this grand display. The job is too big for us. Those
                        who witnessed it will agree that no written description, however elaborate,
                        could convey to the reader a just conception of its magnificence. We can
                        only say to those who were not here, that they missed a sight such as they
                        may live fifty years without having another chance to see.</p>
                    <p>About 11 o'clock a Grand Procession was formed, with its right resting on
                        Centre Square. It was marshaled by the following officers in addition to the
                        Marshals of the respective delegations:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Chief Marshal</emph>--COL. B.F. WINGER.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Assistants</emph>--Alex Martin, P. Henry Peiffer, John
                        King, Martin Ludwig, Wm. E. McKinstry, Samuel J. Snyder, Edward Senseny,
                        Christian Fredrick, Geo. W. Gassel, Dr. John H. Montgomery, Capt Geo. W.
                        Skinner, David Hyasong, William Finney, J. Logan Kennedy, H.C. Koontz, Capt.
                        Thomas Cook, Dr. J.M. Gelwix, Milton Embick.</p>
                    <p>The following Bands of Music were in attendance: The Silver Cornet Band of
                        Chambersburg, the Citizens' Band of Chambersburg, the Greencastle Band, the
                        Keedysville (Md.) Band, the State Line Band and the Fayetteville Band. There
                        was also a Drum Corps from Greencastle, which, we believe, accompanied the
                        Mercersburg delegation. The Keedysville Band came with the delegation from
                        Hagerstown, which numbered several hundred.</p>
                    <p>It had been announced that speaking would commence at the Fair grounds at one
                        o'clock, but notwithstanding the number and capacity of our public houses,
                        it was a full hour later before all who wanted dinner could be served. About
                        2 o'clock a large crowd assembled around the stand on the Fair grounds. John
                        R. Orr, Esq., Chairman of the Democratic County Committee, called the
                        meeting to order, and on his motion it organized by electing the following
                        officers:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">President</emph>--Hon. Geo. W. Brewer, of Chambersburg.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Vice Presidents</emph>--Col. James B. Orr, of Orrstown;
                        Samuel Holliday, of Dry Run; Joseph Gilmore, of Letterkenny; James Mullen,
                        of Loudon, J.B. Crowell, of Greencastle, and Henry Besore, of Washington.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Secretaries</emph>--Dr. J.M. Gelwix, of Strasburg, and
                        Fullerton Richey, of Fayetteville.</p>
                    <p>The President, after a few remarks appropriate to the occasion, introduced
                        the Hon. JOHN T. HOFFMAN, the Democratic candidate for governor of the State
                        of New York, who proceeded to address the meeting. We will not attempt a
                        sketch of Mayor Hoffman's speech. It would be unjust to him to give anything
                        short of a full report of it, which we are not prepared to do. We have met
                        no one who pretends to have heard an abler argument at any time or in any
                        place. It was solid argument from beginning to end, and utterly devoid of
                        anything savoring of an appeal to passion or prejudice. He grappled the
                        living issues of the day and made them plain to every man before him. We
                        know that he made a deep impression upon several intelligent Republicans who
                        were present. As for the thousands of Democrats who stood around him, we
                        know that every one of them was delighted. The Democracy of Franklin will
                        long remember Mayor Hoffman, and they will make the welkin ring with joyful
                        shouts when the news of his triumphant election as Governor of New York
                        comes down to them on the night of the 3d of November.</p>
                    <p>After Mayor Hoffman had concluded, a call was made for Wm. S. Stenger, Esq.,
                        who responded in a ten-minute speech. We think we speak the opinion of all
                        who heard it when we pronounce it a pattern of neatness.</p>
                    <p>The vast assemblage then quietly dispersed; and thus ended the largest and
                        most orderly meeting ever held in Chambersburg.</p>
                    <p>Mayor Hoffman was accompanied by his wife. During their brief sojourn here
                        they were the guests of Hon. Geo. W. Brewer. In the evening the Mayor was
                        serenaded at Mr. Brewer's residence, where he was also called upon by a
                        large number of our prominent citizens. He left for Harrisburg in a special
                        train at 8 o'clock on Wednesday evening, having engaged to address a meeting
                        at Pittsburg on Thursday.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peiffer</ln>
                        <fn>P. Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ludwig</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKinstry</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Senseny</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fredrick</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cassel</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hyssong</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finney</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>J. Logan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koontz</ln>
                        <fn>H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwix</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Embick</ln>
                        <fn>Milton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>James B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holliday</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mullen</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crowell</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Besore</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwix</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richey</ln>
                        <fn>Fullerton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoffman</ln>
                        <fn>John T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Describes in vivid detail a large Democratic rally in Chambersburg. Names
                    all the key officers, reports on the proceedings in glowing terms, and praises
                    every speaker. Partly an effort to contrast this meeting with the Republican one
                    reported in a separate article in this edition.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>An Old Citizen Dead</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Uglow</ln>
                        <fn>Nicholas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Nicholas Uglow died in his Hamilton residence on September 28th. An 81 year
                    old native of England, he had lived in Franklin county for over 50 years. Mr.
                    Uglow was a leading brick-maker, but lately had been pursuing agriculture. Last
                    year he made a return trip to England and was reunited with a sister and two
                    brothers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Female College</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Board of Trustees of the proposed Presbyterian Female College met in
                    Chambersburg to decide upon a location for the institution. They will meet next
                    in Greencastle. Chambersburg has pledged $14,500, including a donation of
                    $10,000 from Miss Sarah Wilson of St. Thomas, to build the school in the city.
                    Greencastle has already pledged $15,000. "Is it possible that Chambersburg will
                    permit this magnificent enterprise to be snatched from her by Greencastle? If
                    so, we can only say, all honor to our neighbors and all shame to ourselves!"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brinley</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stitt</ln>
                        <fn>Agnes N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stitt</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. John Brinley of Spring Run and Miss Agnes N. Stitt, daughter of John W.
                    Stitt of Dry Run, were married on September 29th by the Rev. William A. West.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolff</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shearer</ln>
                        <fn>Sue A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel Wolff and Miss Sue A. Shearer, both of Spring Run, were married on
                    September 29th by the Rev. William A. West.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hackdorn</ln>
                        <fn>David A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Emma H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David A. Hackdorn of Ontario and Mrs. Emma H. Wilson of Dry Run were
                    married on September 30th the Rev. William A. West.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuman</ln>
                        <fn>Mary C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. Keller</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. W. Craig of Indiana County and Miss Mary C. Shuman of St. Thomas were
                    married on October 1st at the residence of the bride's father by the Rev. J.
                    Keller Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.10.07.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote>Advertisements and agricultural information appear on this page.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
