<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1868/pa.fr.vs.1868.11.04">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/14/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1868-11-04">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day norm="">4</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.11.04.01" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Vote to Save Your Country</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We hope that every Democrat, and every conservative Republican who believes
                        with us that a change is needed in the administration of national affairs,
                        will turn out on Tuesday next and vote for Seymour and Blair.</p>
                    <p>Times are hard and getting harder; money is scarce and getting scarcer; taxes
                        are high and getting higher; the government expenses are enormous and
                        growing worse; the public debt is fearful and being augmented every month;
                        the Radical Congress is squandering the people's money and Radical
                        office-holders are stealing half the revenues they collect.</p>
                    <p>The public welfare demands a change. Honest Republicans who vote with the
                        dishonest crew who are plundering the people will regret the act all the
                        days of their life. Their eyes will ere long be opened to their error. Those
                        who vote for Seymour and Blair--for the immediate restoration of the
                        Union--for the reduction of government expenditures and the consequent
                        reduction of the public debt--for the lightening of taxation--for the more
                        equal distribution of currency and revival of business that would result
                        therefrom--these will have no cause to reproach themselves, let matters go
                        as they will. They can rest in the consciousness that they performed their
                        duty. If evil ensues, the fault will not be theirs.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls on both Democrats and Republicans to correct the errors of the past
                    and vote for Seymour. Lists the issues Democrats championed for the past few
                    months and promises a return to prosperity.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>No Money for White Men</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Radical Congress refused to vote one dollar for the relief of the
                        citizens of Chambersburg whose property was carried away or burned by the
                        Rebels. The same Congress has voted twelve million dollars a year to the
                        negroes of the South, which is distributed to them by the Freedmen's Bureau.</p>
                    <p>Nearly everybody in Chambersburg is pinched for money. Our business men have
                        a terrible struggle to sustain themselves. If the Radical Congress had given
                        to the sufferers here just one million of the twelve millions it has given
                            <emph rend="italic">every year</emph> to the Southern Negroes who did
                        not suffer at all, everything would go easy with the people of Chambersburg.</p>
                    <p>Can any Radical give a good reason why millions should be appropriated every
                        year for the Southern Negroes, while not one dollar is given to the White
                        sufferers of Chambersburg? We would like to know the reason, if one exists.
                        Can the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> give it? Can any of the
                        Radical orators give it?</p>
                    <p>A memorial, it will be remembered, was sent from this place to Congress,
                        setting forth the sufferings of our people and praying for relief. Gen.
                        Koontz presented it and endeavored to get a favorable report upon it from
                        the committee to which it was referred. John A. Bingham, of Ohio, and other
                        leading Radical members of Congress, were on that committee. They refused to
                        report in its favor. Bingham was strongly against it. With his big fee in
                        one pocket for prosecuting Mrs. Surratt to the gallows, and his $5,000 for
                        one year's service in Congress in the other, he felt too comfortable to
                        concern himself about the poor White people of Chambersburg. But his bowels
                        of compassion were deeply moved when the appropriation for the Freedmen's
                        Bureau came up, and he voted to invest twelve millions more of the people's
                        money for the benefit of the Southern Negroes, just after he had refused to
                        vote one dollar to us.</p>
                    <p>Do the people of Chambersburg really want indemnity for their losses? Do the
                        people of the rest of Franklin county want indemnity for theirs? If so,
                            <emph rend="italic">how should they vote</emph> in order to get it?</p>
                    <p>John A. Bingham is regarded by his friends as a great lawyer. If Grant should
                        be elected to the Presidency, Bingham would be urged upon him for Attorney
                        General, and in all probability he would be appointed. What advice would he
                        give the President upon the indemnity question? After going against us in
                        Congress, would he be likely to go for us in the Cabinet? And if the
                        Radicals in Congress care so little about us as to give us nothing when a
                        Presidential election is coming on, notwithstanding all their anxiety to
                        obtain votes, what have we to expect from them after they get another four
                        year lease of power?</p>
                    <p>It is very probable that what we are saying on this subject will be
                        disregarded by every Radical voter in Chambersburg and throughout the
                        county. It is to be feared that party prejudice and party drill will blind
                        them to their own vital interests. We perform our duty, however, in warning
                        them against voting for the candidates of the party which, through its
                        representatives in Congress, has refused them indemnity for their losses,
                        whilst it has squandered millions upon Negroes who had no claim to one cent
                        from the National treasury. If they would rather vote for Grant and give
                        twelve millions a year to the Negroes, than vote for Seymour and secure a
                        million or two for themselves, there is no help for it. But what a sight it
                        is to see intelligent white men voting so directly against their own
                        interests.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses astonishment and anger that Congress appropriated money for the
                    Freedmen's Bureau and not for the damages Chambersburg suffered in the war.
                    Blames Radicals for this, especially John Bingham. Claims Democrats, if elected,
                    would fix the problem.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>Are Florida Negroes Better Than White Pennsylvanians?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The negro has not yet been admitted to the ballot box in Pennsylvania. Fully
                        one-half of the Republicans in the State, if interrogated to-day, would say
                        that they would never consent to his admission to it. Yet these same
                        Republicans will vote for Grant, and so vote to sustain the Radical
                        reconstruction policy, whereby the negroes in the Southern States have been
                        admitted to the ballot box. The negroes in those States have not merely been
                        put upon an equality with the white people and given the power to contend
                        with them at the polls upon equal terms. They have been given the entire
                        control of the ballot box and it expresses their will alone.</p>
                    <p>Do the Republicans of Pennsylvania flatter themselves that because the negro
                        does not vote in this State he does not stand upon terms of equality with
                            <emph rend="italic">them?</emph> True, he does not elbow them at their
                        voting places. He does not spread his perfume around their polls. His
                        ivories do not shine like a polished steel trap through the window where
                        their ballots are taken in. But in those places where the destinies of the
                        nation are decided, he meets them on terms of equality and speaks in a voice
                        as potential as theirs.</p>
                    <p>There will be Senators in the United States Senate on the fourth of March
                        next, who were elected by negro members of the Legislatures of Southern
                        States. There will be members of the House who were elected by direct votes
                        of negroes at the ballot box. Each Senator thus elected by negroes in the
                        Legislature, and each member thus elected by negroes at the polls, will have
                        a voice and vote equal to each Senator and each member elected by the white
                        people of Pennsylvania.</p>
                    <p>To this position of political equality with the intelligent white men of the
                        North have the ignorant negroes of the South been elevated by the
                        reconstruction policy of the Radicals. Every Northern man who votes for
                        Grant votes to weigh a Southern negro in the scale against himself. And what
                        is worse, he gives the negro a chance to outweigh him. In one of the
                        Southern States, the negro population does not equal the population of a
                        single county in Pennsylvania. And yet those few thousand negroes will have
                        two Senators of the United States, the same as the three million whites of
                        Pennsylvania or the four million whites of New York. One Florida negro will
                        balance the power of forty or fifty white Pennsylvanians in the United
                        States Senate under Radical reconstruction.</p>
                    <p>Many Republicans look upon this elevation of the Southern negroes merely as a
                        deserved degradation of the Rebels. They overlook the fact that it is also a
                        degradation of the white people of the North. We confess our fear that they
                        will continue to look at it in a wrong light, and only awake to a true view
                        of it when they find Negro Equality fastened upon the country beyond their
                        power to shake it off. Negro Equality did we say? Let us say Negro
                        Superiority, for that is what it amounts to when a few thousand Florida
                        negroes can stifle the voice of three million white Pennsylvanians in the
                        United States Senate.</p>
                    <p>All who are in favor of Negro Superiority will vote for Grant; and let no one
                        who votes for Grant forget <emph rend="italic">what</emph> he is voting
                    for.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Attacks Republican Reconstruction policy by pointing out how it gives
                    political equality to blacks. Gives an example of blacks in Florida having more
                    representation in the Senate than white Pennsylvanians. Charges that anyone who
                    votes Republican is voting for racial equality.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>08</column>
                <head>Times Hard and Money Scarce</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper laments the difficult financial situation in the country.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.11.04.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Duty of Democrats</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The time for vigorous action is at hand. Lethargy and inactivity must give
                        place to vigilance and work. It is no time to sleep when the foe is
                        advancing. He who would fight well must prepare himself for the fight. The
                        party that would win a triumph must "organize victory." There must be no
                        shirking of duty. There must be no skulking from the ranks. Let cowards,
                        frightened at the first charge of the enemy, go to the rear, or join the
                        ranks of the foe, if they choose. But let brave men gird on their armor for
                        the final battle, and struggle valiantly for the right. Victory rightfully
                        belongs to those who labor to achieve it.</p>
                    <p>Democrats, you have a great duty to perform. It is a duty which you owe to
                        yourselves. A duty to yourselves, so as to maintain the integrity and
                        reputation of your time honored organization. A duty to yourselves so as to
                        guard your most sacred rights and preserve your blood-bought liberties.</p>
                    <p>It is a duty which you owe to your country. This fair land, dedicated by our
                        forefathers to freedom, is overshadowed by a huge solitary despotism. The
                        General of the armies, who holds under his iron heel ten States of the
                        Union, asks you to sanction his purpose to govern the other States in the
                        same way. It is your duty to prevent the consummation of that purpose.</p>
                    <p>Corruption holds high carnival in every department of the Federal
                        Government.--Extravagances unprecedented in our history are indulged in by
                        the Radical Congress.--Honesty is no longer considered necessary. It has
                        even lost its respectability. The public money is squandered, instead of
                        being applied to the payment of the public debt. The money wrung from the
                        people by taxation is expended upon the negro, and for the support of
                        innumerable officials who grow fat upon the Freedmen's Bureau and by the
                        collection of the Internal Revenue taxes. <emph rend="italic">Large sums of
                            the people's money are used to buy votes for General
                        Grant.</emph>--Bribery upon an enormous scale is practiced in order that
                        Radicalism may bloat itself still more with the spoils of office. <emph
                            rend="italic">You must make a clean sweep of these corrupt officials,
                            and break the power of this extravagant, reckless party, or your farms
                            and little lots of ground will soon be mortgaged to the last farthing of
                            their value.</emph> Your national debt will be a huge load under which
                        you will stagger to your graves and from the burden of which generation
                        after generation of American citizens will struggle in vain to be relieved.
                        Stagnation will continue to pervade every department of business. Trade will
                        remain paralyzed. Your commerce will be swept entirely from the seas. It
                        will no longer be your pride to be called an American citizen. The National
                        credit will be forever impaired.</p>
                    <p>Democrats, keep these facts in mind, and perform your duty earnestly and
                        fearlessly. <emph rend="italic">That duty is to vote</emph>. Let no alight
                        excuse keep you from the polls. Stir yourselves and "<del/> you like men."
                        Be not discouraged because you were not successful in October. You can carry
                        this County if you do but go to the polls and cast the same number of votes
                        that you cast at the last election. <emph rend="italic">Let every man who
                            voted then vote next Tuesday</emph>.</p>
                    <p>You know, too, the men who stayed away from the last election. Visit them.
                        Induce to go to the polls. <emph rend="italic">Get them to vote</emph>. Let
                        us make "a long pull, a strong pull, and a pull all together," and we will
                        carry Franklin County by a handsome majority for Seymour and Blair.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges all Democrats to go to the polls to vote for Seymour. Tells them they
                    can still end the corrupt government of the Radicals by getting out the vote.
                    Pleads with them not to be discouraged by the October election results.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Fraudulent Assessments in Green Township</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that three names of individuals in Fayetteville have been
                    illegally added to the voter registry for Green Township. The paper has the
                    names, and will ask Democratic supporters to object to their votes and prosecute
                    the assessor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The National Seesaw</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper mocks John Cessna as the "National Seesaw." If Grant is known as
                    the "National Cigar" for his smoking habits, Cessna should be called "seesaw"
                    for his wavering on temperance issues.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Freedman's Bureau</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper argues that the Freedmen's Bureau is in no danger of being
                    disbanded. In fact, rumors of its demise existed only as a political ploy used
                    by the Republicans. The editors lament that the "wards of the nation" will
                    continue to receive "charity."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Cessna's "Ten Strike"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper mocks John Cessna for receiving 10 fewer votes than the
                    Republican candidate for Bedford County Surveyor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Treasury Bled Again</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes Grant and the government for meeting Massachusetts's war claims
                    with money while doing nothing to aid southern Pennsylvania.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Seymour to the Rescue</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following was Gov. Seymour's telegram to Gov. Curtin, in answer to the
                        latter's call for assistance when Lee was marching into Pennsylvania in
                        1863:</p>
                    <p>ALBANY, June 16, 1863.</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">Governor Curtin, Harrisburg:</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>I am pushing forward troops as fast as possible; regiments will leave New
                        York tonight. All will be ordered to report to General Couch. HORATIO
                        SEYMOUR.</p>
                    <p>It was through Franklin county that the legions of Gen. Lee poured into
                        Pennsylvania, and it was to defend the homes of the people of Franklin
                        county that Gov. Seymour was "pushing forward troops as fast as possible" at
                        the date of the above telegram. Seymour's troops were posted in the
                        fortifications on this side of the Susquehanna, while the "shoddy" officers
                        who responded to our own Governor's call were quarreling in Camp Curtin
                        about their pay!</p>
                    <p>If a man of Seymour's sagacity, energy and promptness of action had been
                        Governor of Pennsylvania, Gen. Couch would not have been left here without a
                        single company, nor would Chambersburg have been burned and Franklin county
                        plundered. Our people ought to remember the man who came to their rescue
                        when their homes were in danger.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints Seymour's telegram to Curtin promising more troops to defend
                    Pennsylvania in 1863. Praises Seymour's actions, urges Franklin county voters to
                    vote for the man who rescued them in a time of need. Insults Pennsylvania
                    veterans in the process, ironically.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Bad Effects of the Radical Financial Policy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper criticizes Republican financial policy for encouraging
                    speculation and causing concentration of money in large eastern cities.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.11.04.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A Democratic meeting will be held in the Chambersburg Court House. Speeches
                    will be made.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Female College</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Col. McClure's mansion and grounds have been purchased for the Female
                    College.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Teacher's Institute</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wickersham</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The annual meeting of the Franklin County Teacher's Institute will be held
                    in the Court House in Chambersburg. Many notable teachers will be present to
                    lecture on a variety of topics. Area teachers are invited to attend.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Courts continued in session until Friday afternoon. The following cases
                        were disposed of:</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Samuel Evey. Surety of the Peace. Jacob S. Funk, Prosecutor. Deft.
                        sentenced to pay costs. Stenger for Com; Stumbaugh and Gehr for Deft.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Edward Lewis. Larceny of a watch belonging to Charles Lewis,
                        Prosecutor. Verdict, guilty. Sentenced to Eastern Penitentiary for one year.
                        Stenger for Com; Brewer for Deft.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Columbus Green, Larceny of Wheat and Rye. Martin Heintzelman,
                        Prosecutor. Verdict, not guilty. Stenger for Com; McGowan for Deft.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. John Wolff. Malicious trespass. Simon Bitner, Prosecutor. Verdict,
                        not guilty, but Deft to pay costs. Kimmell and Stenger for Com; Sharpe and
                        Stumbaugh for Deft.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Elijah W. Wallace. Larceny. Jacob Shafer, Prosecutor. Verdict,
                        guilty. Sentenced to 12 months imprisonment in County jail. Stenger for
                        Com.; Kimmell and Sharpe for Deft.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Peter Plowden. Assault and Battery. Martin Hoover, Prosecutor.
                        Verdict, guilty. Sentenced to pay costs. Sharpe and Stenger for Com.;
                        McGowan for Deft.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Frederick Myers. Surety of the Peace. Margaret Kyle, Prosecutrix.
                        Complaint dismissed. Deft. to pay costs. Stenger and Kimmell for Com.;
                        McCauley and Orr for Deft.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Mary Myers. Surety of the Peace. Margaret Kyle, Prosecutrix. Same
                        action as above and same counsel.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Hannah Holland. Surety of the Peace. Margaret Kyle. Prosecutrix.
                        Same action as above and same counsel.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Charles Jones. Assault and Battery on Peter Dorte, Prosecutor.
                        Verdict, guilty. Sentenced to pay costs. Stenger and Kimmell for Com.;
                        Douglas for Deft.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Jacob Hite. Surety of Peace. Adam Vanderan, Prosecutor.
                        Dismissed--each party to pay his own costs. Stenger and Kimmell for Com.;
                        Brewer for Deft.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. William Hance. Larceny of a watch. Isaac Kuhn, Prosecutor. Verdict,
                        guilty. Sentenced to 18 months imprisonment in the Eastern Penitentiary.
                        Brewer and Stewart and Stenger for Com.; McGowan for Deft.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Jacob Golden. Obstructing a public road by running a fence out upon
                        it. Supervisors of Southampton township were the Prosecutors. Verdict, not
                        guilty, and the County to pay the costs. Sharpe and Stenger for Com.;
                        Kimmell and Orr for Deft.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. David Overcash. Assault and Battery. Daniel Harmon,
                        Prosecutor.--Verdict, not guilty, and the costs equally divided between
                        Prosecutor and Defendant. Stumbaugh and Stenger for Com.; Kimmell and Brewer
                        for Deft.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Harrison Newman, Surety of the Peace, John H. Adams,
                        Prosecutor.--Deft. sentenced to pay the costs and give security to keep the
                        peace in bond of $100. Stenger for Com.; Brewer for Deft.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. E. P. Acker. Larceny. Daniel Miller, Prosecutor. Verdict, not
                        guilty,--Stenger and Gehr for Com; McCauley for Deft.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Thomas Morgan. Assault and Battery. Eveline Howard,
                        Prosecutrix.--Verdict, guilty. Sentenced to pay costs,--Stenger for Com.;
                        Kimmell for Deft.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. John W. Miller. Forgery.--Solomon Sentman, Prosecutor. Verdict,
                        guilty. Sentenced to pay costs and be imprisoned in County jail 6 months.
                        McCauley and Stenger for Com; Sharpe and Orr for Deft.</p>
                    <p>Cases in which a nolle prosequi was entered:</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Frederick Hoffman--Desertion.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. John Bergner--Fornication and Bastardy.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Wm. Butler--Fornication and Bastardy.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Geo. A. Cole--Larceny.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Skinner, Devor and McNaspey, Supervisors of Fannett township.
                        Refusing to lay out a public road.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Willis Weaver--Malicious trespass.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Jacob Salhimer--Fornication and Bastardy.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. J. M. McPherson--Larceny.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. David Neff--Surety of the peace.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Luther Fisher--Assault and Battery.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. George W. Corwell--Assault and Battery.</p>
                    <p>Bills Ignored.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Samuel Campbell--Larceny.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. S. D. Jones and W. Hockenberry--Receiving stolen property.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Wm. McKain--Assault and Battery.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Bishop Meade--Assault and Battery.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Wm. McKain--Assault and Battery.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Eliz. Williams--Assault and Battery.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Isadore Stumbaugh--Assault and Battery.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Robert Lane--Assault and Battery.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. George Kyle--Assault and Battery.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Susan Bricker--Assault and Battery.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Peter Dorte--Assault and Battery.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Margaret Johnston--Assault and Battery.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Rebecca Barnes--Assault and Battery.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Edward Harmon--Assault and Battery.</p>
                    <p>Com. vs. Martin Hoover--Assault and Battery.</p>
                    <p>A considerable number of cases in which true bills were found, were continued
                        to the next term of Court. No civil causes were tried.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evey</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gehr</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lewis</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lewis</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Green</ln>
                        <fn>Columbus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heintzleman</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGowan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolff</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bitner</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>Elijah W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shafer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plowden</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyle</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holland</ln>
                        <fn>Hannah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dorte</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hite</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanderan</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hance</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Golden</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Overcash</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harmon</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newman</ln>
                        <fn>Harrison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Adams</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Acker</ln>
                        <fn>E. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morgan</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howard</ln>
                        <fn>Eveline</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sentman</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoffman</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bergner</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Butler</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cole</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Devor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McNaspey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weaver</ln>
                        <fn>Willis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sallhimer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McPherson</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neff</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Luther</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Corwell</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>S. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hockenberry</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKain</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Isadore</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyle</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bricker</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dorte</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harmon</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Proceedings of Franklin County Court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dansberg</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zaboke</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houck</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. W. Dansberg of Jackson Hall and Susan Zaboke of Stoufferstown, Franklin
                    County, were married in Shippensburg on October 22nd by the Rev. W. A. Houck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heckman</ln>
                        <fn>David A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flack</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flack</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. Keller</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David A. Heckman and Miss Eliza A. Flack, daughter of George Flack of
                    Hamilton, were married on October 28th by the Rev. J. Keller Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.11.04.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote>Advertisements and agricultural information appear on this page.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
