<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1868/pa.fr.vs.1868.07.29">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/07/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1868-07-29">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="">29</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.07.29.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.07.29.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Constitutional Amendments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>President Johnson sent recommendations to Congress for amendments to the
                    constitution. He proposed a 6 year presidential term, assumption of presidential
                    duties by the Secretary of State in the event of death of both the president and
                    vice president, direct election of Senators, and judicial term limits. The paper
                    supports the ideas, and also suggests that each house of Congress should not be
                    final judge of the qualifications of its own members. Instead, an impartial body
                    should make such decisions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Radical Squabble for Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports divisions within Franklin's Republican Party. Factions are divided
                    between Koontz, Cessna, and Wiestling for Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.07.29.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Delegates Meetings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>North Ward Democrats will meet at the Montgomery Hotel to select convention
                    delegates. South Ward Democrats will meet at the hotel of Samuel R. Boyd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Democratic Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Democrats and Conservatives of Chambersburg will meet in the Court
                    House to ratify the nominations of the County Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Seymour and Blair Club Organized</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>C. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Democrats of Chambersburg met in the Court House to organize a club to
                    support Seymour and Blair for president and vice president. "The Democrats are
                    wide awake and intend to charge fiercely upon the enemy and 'rout him, horse
                    foot, and dragoons.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Eight Hour Law</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>CHAMBERSBURG, JULY 20, 1868.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Messrs. Editors:</emph>--I, in common with a number of
                        others, wish to be informed when the Eight Hour law of Pennsylvania came
                        into operation, because one cannot walk the streets of our principal towns
                        or cities at any hour of the day or night without hearing the din and
                        clatter of machinery in operation.</p>
                    <p>It is high time that our law makers should stop fooling. The working men,
                        women and children of this as well as other States, need laws to protect
                        them from being ground to dust by the iron heel of capital. No Nation, I
                        believe, in the whole civilized world, pays less regard to the pleasures and
                        enjoyments of the laboring class than the well to do people of the United
                        States. Our Legislatures, it is true, have enacted 8 and 10 hour laws time
                        and again, but as yet such laws have always been allowed to remain a dead
                        letter on the Statute books. A law, to be of service, must be enforced. It
                        is all moonshine to talk about the people "enforcing the law themselves, if
                        they really want it." Such laws are made, or ought to be made, to do for
                        individuals what individuals cannot do for themselves in their individual
                        capacity. Should all the laws that are made be enforced, or rather not
                        enforced, according to the 8 and 10 hour pattern, we should be a lawless
                        people indeed. If every one were allowed to pay taxes or let it alone, very
                        few taxes would be paid. The government knows this; hence laws for the
                        collection of taxes are enforced as a general thing. Why not enforce labor
                        laws then? Are the laborers such an unworthy and degraded class of human
                        beings that they have got no right to the common lot of enjoyments which
                        belong to all? Or rather, is not the laboring man the man of all others who
                        has got an exclusive right to the good things of this world? That's the way
                        to put it. Workingmen have been through necessity compelled, not only to
                        work long hours, but to say nothing loud about it--else their props would
                        speedily have been knocked from under them.</p>
                    <p>But to work long hours in a country like this, with the mercury at 100 and
                        over, is more incomprehensible still. It proves to me that there is
                        something "rotten in Denmark." Either the working classes are very ignorant,
                        or else times are mighty bad. An investigation ought to be made as to which
                        is the cause.</p>
                    <p>However I am of the opinion that the incompetent lawmakers at Harrisburg did
                        wrong in wasting time and the public money in framing an 8 hour law when
                        they had never as yet enforced the 10 hour law.--Why was this? How did it
                        come to pass? An investigation ought to be had here also. Enlightened people
                        do not allow their lawmakers to place mock laws upon the Statute books. But
                        it appears that anything may be crowded upon the backs of the sovereign (!)
                        people of America by their so-called representatives.<lb/> OBSERVER.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An opinion writer criticizes the lack of enforcement of an 8 hour law
                    passed by the legislature. Says laws are useless without enforcement, gives an
                    example of why the national government enforces tax collecting. Comes out for
                    the working class, calls the legislature incompetent.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>Ephia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William E. Gillan and Miss Ephia Keefer, both of St. Thomas, were married
                    in Chambersburg on July 21st by the Rev. P. S. Davis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Overcash</ln>
                        <fn>Hiram</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Hiram Overcash died near Chambersburg on July 14th. He was 40 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn>Lydia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Lydia Etter died in Chambersburg on July 20th. She was 74 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Ida May</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Emaline</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Ida May Myers, daughter of John and Emaline Myers, died in Greenwood on
                    July 21st. She was 10 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spidel</ln>
                        <fn>Harvey Dowd</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spidel</ln>
                        <fn>A. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Harvey Dowd Spidel, infant son of A. G. Spidel, died on July 16th in Alto
                    Dale. He was 3 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cort</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cort</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Lizzie Cort, daughter of the Rev. C. Cort died of cholera infantum on
                    July 22nd in Alto Dale. She was 1 year old. "The Lord gave and the Lord hath
                    taken away; blessed be the name of the Lord."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.07.29.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote>Advertisements and agricultural information appears on this page.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
