<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1868/pa.fr.vs.1868.03.04">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/17/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1868-03-04">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="">4</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.03.04.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>She is a Working Girl</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have frequently heard the above remark, and it always excites in our mind
                        a sentiment of ineffable contempt for the worthless piece of humanity that
                        uttered it. It is a source of deep regret to us that it may ever be our duty
                        to deal harshly with any portion of the fair sex who maintain a reputable
                        standing in society, but there are some, and not a few either, who, though
                        their fame be unspotted, are so filled with envy, jealousy, hatred toward
                        their sex, who happened to be less favored by fortune, but more perfectly
                        moulded and finished by nature than themselves, that their hearts are gall,
                        their souls are wormwood, their breath is pestilence, whenever they can make
                        it convenient to speak of them.</p>
                    <p>These are they who, with a sarcastic leer, and scornful turn of the nose,
                        stigmatize as "nothing but working girls," such young females as have the
                        moral courage and virtue to work with their hands for an honest livelihood,
                        rather than be dependent, destitute or disreputable.</p>
                    <p>It is sometimes applied opprobriously to married ladies, after the following
                        manner: "Did you ever see the like, how Mrs.------- dresses herself and
                        children of late? I knew her when she was a working girl, and her husband a
                        poor working mechanic and when he worked for my father. Now they have got a
                        little something in the world, and they stick themselves up as somebodies.
                        It is always just so with such creatures, as soon as they get a little in
                        the world, they forget the poverty they sprang from, and then begin to put
                        on airs of gentility. I can't bear them, for my part!"</p>
                    <p>Reader, if you are a young man, and should hear anything like the above
                        sentiment uttered by a young lady to whom you are paying your addresses, let
                        that be your last visit. Even if you are under promise of marriage, it would
                        be better to break off and incur the penalty of breach of promise, than to
                        be united to one so utterly devoid of kind hearted sympathy for those of her
                        sex thus virtuously struggling with adversity, and who holds it as
                        disreputable in a young lady without a fortune or able friends to draw upon
                        and relies on her own physical faculties for support, in an honest, useful
                        vocation.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Opposes those who say it is undignified for a woman to work. Believes women
                    suffering from adversity should have the right to work to stave off poverty
                    regardless of decorum.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.03.04.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Impeachment a Fact</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The work of impeachment has been begun. The nation is doomed to undergo the
                        intense anxiety with which the most important trial in American experience
                        must necessarily be attended. A president of the United States is about to
                        be arraigned for the first time at the bar of the Senate, charged with the
                        commission of high crimes and misdemeanors. It becomes every citizen to ask,
                        and not to rest until he has satisfactorily answered, the question. <emph
                            rend="italic">Why is this?</emph> How comes it that such an effort is
                        being made to drag President Johnson from the Executive Chair? The answer is
                        simple, plain and truthful. Because he has sought to defend the Constitution
                        from the assaults of partisan fanatics. Because he has interposed his
                        influence and constitutional authority to preserve the dignity of his great
                        office. Because he has thus far successfully thwarted the revolutionary
                        designs of Congress, which were intended to establish military despotisms,
                        in the interest of the Radical party, over the States lately in rebellion.</p>
                    <p>Up to the issuing of the order removing Stanton from the War Office, and
                        appointing General Thomas Secretary of war <emph rend="italic">ad
                        interim</emph>, there was, confessedly, no ground for impeachment. Congress
                        distinctly acknowledged this, by twice deliberately resolving that they
                        would not undertake this work. The issuing of the order referred to, is now
                        laid as proper ground for impeachment. It is contended that it is such an
                        open, wilful violation of the Tenure-of-Office-Bill as admits of no <orig
                            reg="defense">defence</orig>, and the Radical papers are asserting, with
                        an assurance that smacks of positive knowledge on the subject, that the
                        Radical Senators will, without doubt, convict the President, and remove him
                        from office.</p>
                    <p>The impeachment of a President is a very serious matter. It ought to be
                        resorted to only where the <orig reg="offense">offence</orig> is, not only
                        heinous in its nature, but where it can be so clearly made out as to leave
                        no doubt as to its character, and the certainty of its commission. Surely it
                        ought not to be attempted when the Chief Executive has only been guilty of
                        "peccadilloes," which the New York <emph rend="italic">Tribune</emph>
                        asserted but a week ago, was all that could be charged and proven against
                        Andrew Johnson. If the process of impeachment, as intended by the framers of
                        the Constitution, is to be used as a means of getting rid of a President
                            <emph rend="italic">obnoxious to a party</emph>, then we may safely
                        predict that our Republic is destined to undergo frequent disturbances of
                        this kind, because, whenever a Congress <unclear>had</unclear> its will
                        opposed, and its laws vetoed by a resident who dares to have an opinion of
                        his own different from theirs, <del/> soon remove the obstacle by <del/> him
                        to a Senate two-thirds of which are men who are known to entertain opinions
                        in direct antagonism to those entertained by him, and who will cheerfully
                        become the instrument <emph rend="italic">to remake the President, whom the
                            will of the Sovereign people of the United States has placed in the
                            chair of the Chief Executive</emph>. Shall Congress, on trivial charges
                        out of pure partisan malignity, with indecent <unclear>hate</unclear>, be
                        permitted to erect itself into a tyrannical Directory, assuming to itself
                        absolute power, and undertaking to rob both the Executive and Judicial
                        Departments of the government of the <unclear>debts</unclear> vested in them
                        by the Federal Constitution? This is a question which every man should, and
                        must ponder upon, and decide for himself. It is not only whether Andrew
                        Johnson shall be impeached and removed from office on such a frivolous,
                        groundless charge, but whether his impeachment and removal of Andrew Johnson
                        once become an accomplished fact, and republican government in America will
                        be a thing of the past. The Republic will die amid the general scramble for
                        political power, in which everybody will claim the privilege of acting
                        "outside the Constitution."</p>
                    <p>And now, for what is the President to be impeached? For removing Edwin M.
                        Stanton from his position as Secretary of War. It is claimed that this
                        action is a palpable violation of the Tenure-of-Office-Bill, which the last
                        Congress enacted for the purpose of tying the hands of Andrew Johnson. In
                        the first place, every unprejudiced mind will see from the message of the
                        President, which we publish to-day, that Stanton's case is not within the
                        act of 1867, regulating the tenure of certain civil officers, and known as
                        the Tenure-of-Office-Bill. By this act, the tenure of officers is limited
                            <emph rend="italic">"for and during the term of the President by whom
                            they may have been appointed, and for one month thereafter</emph>."
                        Stanton was the appointee of President Lincoln. He was never re-appointed by
                        President Johnson. He was, therefore, subject to removal at anytime,
                        provided there was no previous law upon the subject which defined the term
                        of his office. It is conceded on all hands that no such law existed.
                        Consequently, the President, in removing Stanton, is not guilty of a
                        violation of this act of 1867. So far, the President has met the Radicals
                        upon their own ground, and shown that there is no shadow of excuse for the
                        impeachment project.</p>
                    <p>But there is a higher ground than this.--<emph rend="italic">It is Edwin M.
                            Stanton's own ground</emph>, namely, that even if the action of the
                        President should be decided to come within the provisions of the
                        Tenure-of-office bill, still the President is guilty of no <orig
                            reg="offense">offence</orig>, for the reason that the Tenure-of-office
                        bill is unconstitutional, and, therefore, absolutely null and void. It is
                        true that the power to <emph rend="italic">appoint</emph> certain officers
                        of the Government can not be exercised by the President except "by and with
                        the advice and consent of the Senate," but his power to <emph rend="italic"
                            >remove</emph> the same officers has never been called in question. The
                        right to remove has been claimed and exercised by every former
                        President.--It has been sanctioned by Congress. It has been affirmed by the
                        Supreme Court. The Constitution has been always construed to clothe the
                        President with this power. Nobody ever dreamed before of attempting to
                        impeach the Chief Executive for the exercise of this right. His orders of
                        removal have been always obeyed by those to whom they were directed, and
                        acquiesced in by the people. When Congress first proposed to put this
                        limitation upon the President's power, Stanton was a member of the Cabinet.
                        He attended its meetings regularly.--His opinion was asked for, and given in
                        regard to this very bill. <emph rend="italic">He pronounced it
                            unconstitutional.</emph> He suggested to the President the points of
                        objection which were made in the message vetoing the bill. The act was
                        passed over the President's veto. And now, <emph rend="italic">Stanton seeks
                            to retain possession of the War Department by virtue of this very bill
                            which he advised the President to veto on the ground of its
                            unconstitutionality</emph>. Nay more, he goes before the Chief Justice
                        of the District of Columbia, <emph rend="italic">and takes his solemn
                        oath</emph>, that Adjutant General Lorenzo Thomas, in accepting the position
                        of Secretary of War <emph rend="italic">ad interim</emph>, has violated the
                        Constitution and laws of the United States, and thus subjected himself to
                        the <sic>palns</sic> and penalties of the Tenure-of-office-Bill, when
                        Stanton himself, according to the opinion given to the President, actually
                        believed that the Tenure-of-office-Bill <emph rend="italic">was not then a
                            law binding upon Gen. Thomas because it was in violation of the
                            Constitution</emph>. Does not this look like perjury in Mr. Stanton?
                        Certainly no less tenable ground was ever put forth upon which to punish any
                        one. It will be an eternal disgrace to the American nation to allow the
                        removal of its Chief Executive on such flimsy pretexts. But the Radicals
                        have resolve to impeach the President nevertheless. <emph rend="italic">They
                            care nothing for the honor of the nation</emph>. They are simply in
                        search of power as a means of procuring the spoils.--The public mind is
                        anxious upon the subject. When will the trial begin? Will Chief Justice
                        Chase be ready to proceed as soon as the Senate is ready? Will Andrew
                        Johnson plead to the jurisdiction? Will he refuse to be judged by such an
                        irregular and fragmentary body? If so, will the country be deluged with the
                        blood of another civil war? If not, will indecent haste mark the
                        proceedings? Have the Senators, who are to sit as judges, constituting a
                        hight Court of impeachment, prejudged the case? Is the trial to be a mere
                        farce? And how will it end? All these questions are in men's mouths, and
                        various opinions in regard to them are entertained and uttered.</p>
                    <p>Our own mind is clear, <emph rend="italic">that the Senate of the United
                            States as at present constituted is utterly incompetent to try the
                            President</emph>.--The constitution never contemplated a trial by a body
                        which excludes from its deliberations, twenty one Senators who are as
                        clearly entitled to their seats as any one of the Senators who intends to
                        sit in judgement upon the President. The constitution of the United States
                        runs thus, <emph rend="italic">"The Senate of the United States shall be
                            composed of two Senators from each State,"</emph> &amp;c, and again,
                            "<emph rend="italic">the Senate</emph> shall have the sole power to try
                        all the impeachments." What Senate? Why, the Senate of the United States
                            <emph rend="italic">composed of two Senators from each
                        State</emph>.--And so, we say, whenever the states of Alabama, Arkansas,
                        Florida, Georgia, Louisiana, Maryland, Mississippi, North Carolina, South
                        Carolina, Texas, and Virginia are accorded their full representation of two
                        Senators from each State, to which they are con-constitutionally entitled,
                        Andrew Johnson ought to appear to answer, at the bar of the Senate, to any
                        articles which may be preferred against him, <emph rend="italic">but no
                            sooner</emph>. But, he ought to be prepared for the consequences of such
                        a refusal. If he intends to demur to the jurisdiction, and has not arranged
                        appropriate measures and means of <orig reg="defense">defence</orig>, he
                        will find himself in a fort, and another man in his place within twenty four
                        hours after his demurrer is entered.</p>
                    <p>If however, he concludes to recognize the legality of the tribunal which will
                        undertake to try him, he should guard against any effort to suspend him
                        during trial. Besides, he ought to take every possible step to procure a
                        decision of the highest judicial tribunal in the mind upon the
                        constitutionality of the Tenure-of-office-Bill, before the Senate is ready
                        to take a vote upon the question of his guilt.</p>
                    <p>The fight between the President and Stanton is not our fight. Andrew Johnson
                        does not hold his office by Democratic votes. He was made President by the
                        support of the Republican party. As to the personal issues involved,
                        Democrats might afford to sit in silence, and witness the progress of the
                        contest. But far higher interests are at stake. A question of principle is
                        involved. The hitherto unquestioned constitutional right of the President to
                        remove a Cabinet officer at his pleasure is assailed. An effort is being
                        made to restrain the Executive in the sphere of his legitimate action, so as
                        to make him utterly powerless. Nay more, the design is to remove the
                        President from office, so as to get rid of the greatest obstacle in the way
                        of delivering the Southern States over to negro supremacy, and thus securing
                        the perpetuation of Radical power in the nation. Let Democrats prepare
                        themselves for any contingency that may arise. No man knows now what a day
                        may bring forth. Republican institutions are now undergoing their severest
                        trial.--Through all the gloomy period of our bloody civil war,
                        constitutional liberty was never exposed to such fearful perils as those
                        which now threaten it. Let it be our business to watch and be ready always.
                        If forcible resistance must be made to the lawless proceedings of Congress,
                        we must act like men who "know their rights, and knowing, dare maintain
                        them."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gives a very negative view of the impending impeachment of President
                    Johnson. Details many legal reasons why impeachment against him is ludicrous.
                    The editors show particular distaste for the actions of Stanton. Ends by warning
                    of the dangers impeachment implies for the rest of the nation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Few Words to Radicals</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Isn't it a little strange that the Radicals should be so greatly enraged at
                        President Johnson? Consider, for a moment, what he has done. He has removed,
                        or attempted to remove, Edwin M. Stanton from the office of Secretary of
                        War. He has also nominated Thomas Ewing to fill Stanton's place. Now what is
                        there in this that ought to excite any member of the Radical party? Edwin M.
                        Stanton used to be, or at least professed to be, a Democrat; and it is
                        beyond question that, when secession was ripening, he told Senator Brown, of
                        Mississippi, a far more bitter secessionist than Jeff Davis, that he was
                        right, and advised him to go home and rebel against the Lincoln government.
                        Thomas Ewing used to be a Whig, and on the dissolution of that party he
                        became a Republican. The Whigs of Ohio thought him worthy to represent that
                        State in the United States Senate. Gen. Harrison thought him worthy of a
                        seat in his Cabinet. President Fillmore also gave him a seat in the Cabinet.
                        He is the father of the gallant Union General Thomas Ewing Jr., as well as
                        the father-in-law of General Sherman. He never was a Democrat and never
                        advised anybody to rebel against the government. Too old to take the field
                        himself, he put the war-harness on his son's back and sent him forth from
                        the paternal roof to fight for the Union.</p>
                    <p>Now, gentlemen of the Radical party, nearly all of you who were voters a
                        dozens years ago were Whigs, and all of you profess to be Union men. Why is
                        it, then, that you prefer Stanton, a renegade Democrat, who advised Senator
                        Brown to go home and fight against Lincoln, to Thomas Ewing, an old Whig and
                        Republican, who stood by Lincoln all through his administration? Sit down a
                        moment and cool yourselves off and think over the matter, and then give us a
                        good reason, if you can, why you should rave against President Johnson for
                        turning out a renegade Democrat and putting a genuine old Whig and
                        Republican in his place. Are Democrats so much better than Whigs or
                        Republicans that you must needs get in a great passion and call upon
                        Congress to turn Andrew Johnson out of the Presidential chair because he
                        prefers the latter to the former? If you are of opinion that in order to
                        qualify a man for high public office he must be, or at least must have been
                        a Democrat, hadn't you better join us yourselves? You may someday be called
                        to fill high public offices, and it would mortify you very much to be
                        compelled to decline on the ground that, as you had never been Democrats,
                        you did not possess the requisite honesty and capability.</p>
                    <p>Thomas Ewing is an older and more experienced man than Edwin M. Stanton. He
                        is more distinguished and abler than Stanton, and has held more high public
                        offices. If he is not therefore fully as competent to administer the affairs
                        of the War Department, it must all be owing to the lamentable fact that he
                        never was a Democrat!</p>
                    <p>This is rather more than we were disposed to claim for the Democratic party.
                        We had supposed it possible for a lifelong opponent of our party to be
                        fitted for a Cabinet office, but the voice of the Radicals appears to be
                        unanimous in opposition to this supposition. Thanking them for the
                        compliment, it only remains for us to urge all of them who cherish political
                        aspirations to join the Democracy at once and qualify themselves for the
                        possibilities of the future.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mocks the Radicals because they want to keep Stanton and not Lorenzo Thomas
                    in the War Department, even though the former used to be a Democrat while the
                    latter used to be a Whig and Republican. Talks a lot about both men's
                    backgrounds and political affiliations. Even jokingly claims the Radicals,
                    because of their actions, must feel that only Democrats are competent to fill
                    government posts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Articles of Impeachment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints a synopsis of the articles of impeachment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Radical Fear of the Courts</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper asserts that the Radicals are attempting to prevent the courts
                    from ruling on the constitutionality of the Tenure of Office Act.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Dr. Tomkins</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tomkins</ln>
                        <fn>Fred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. Fred Tomkins lectured in Chambersburg's Lutheran Church on "Our Duty in
                    the Present Crisis of the World's History," and in Repository Hall on the
                    "Battle Field of Gettysburg." The paper pronounced his talks "excruciatingly
                    dull." He also delivered sermons in the Lutheran and Methodist churches.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Grant In Favor of Negro Supremacy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>General Grant has at length sold himself, body and soul, to the Radicals. He
                        comes out now, <emph rend="italic">not only in favor of negro-suffrage, but
                            also in favor of negro-supremacy.</emph> Not long ago, General Hancock
                        removed nine of the members of the City Council of New Orleans for
                        disobedience of his orders. Two of this number were white men <emph
                            rend="italic">and seven were negroes</emph>. General Grant has recently
                        revoked this order, and thereby re-instated these refractory colored
                        gentlemen in their positions as City Fathers. To what depths will a man sink
                        himself now-a-days, in order to gain popularity with the party whose
                        nomination he is courting. Citizens of Franklin County, you who desire white
                        men to rule America, will you support a man for President, who thus places
                        negroes in the high positions of the land to the exclusion of white men,
                        even when doing so, it becomes necessary to humiliate a gallant officer like
                        General Hancock?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Comments on Grant's revocation of Hancock's order suspending members of the
                    New Orleans City Council, most of whom were black. Claims this action proves
                    Grant is in favor of black supremacy over whites in order to gain the Republican
                    nominations for President.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>From South-West Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This letter from Abingdon gives a description of the natural resources of
                    South-West Virginia, a topic of particular interest to potential emigrants.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Message From the President</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints Johnson's address to Congress explaining his removal of
                    Edwin Stanton from the War Department.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.03.04.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>A New Police Officer</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Uglow</ln>
                        <fn>Nicholas</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Nicholas Uglow, Jr., has been appointed police officer for Wolffstown by
                    the Town Council.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Death of a Former Resident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevenson</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevenson</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sarah Stevenson, widow of John Stevenson and former resident of
                    Chambersburg, died on July 30th in Lexington, Illinois.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Rev. Henry Ward Beecher's Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Beecher delivered his lecture on "Work and the Workman" to a packed hall.
                    The paper declared it a "masterpiece," praising its "clear thought" and
                    "practical hints." "No one could rise from his seat, after listening to its
                    words of counsel and instruction without forming resolutions to act a better and
                    a noble part in life."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Important Action of the Town Council</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper applauds the Town Council's decision to hold elections to approve
                    construction of a Market House and purchase of a Steam Fire Engine. The paper
                    supports a Market House, and asserts that Chambersburg loses thousands each year
                    "by not having an excellent Market."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Rev. Dr. Talmage's Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Talmage</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. Dr. Talmage delivered his lecture entitled "The Rock on Which People
                    Split" to a packed Repository Hall. The paper declares him "one of the most
                    entertaining lecturers to whom it has been our pleasure to listen."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Railroad Meeting</head>
                <origin>Waynesboro Record</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The "best citizens" of Quincy attended a meeting to discuss a proposed
                    railroad from Scotland and Mt. Alto, via Waynesboro, to the Maryland line.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Sudden Death</head>
                <origin>Greencastle Echo</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frey</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Frey, wife of George Frey and daughter of George Cook of Upton died
                    suddenly on February 24th. She was interred in the German Reformed graveyard of
                    Upton. "She was a young and interesting wife and an affectionate daughter, and
                    her early demise will be mourned by a large circle of friends."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>Clara</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hassler</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John W. Elder and Miss Clara Huber, both of Chambersburg, were married on
                    March 3rd in Shippensburg by the Rev. J. Hassler.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holler</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Childes</ln>
                        <fn>Barbara</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Holler, of Fairview, and Miss Barbara Childes, of St. Thomas, were
                    married at Fisher's Hotel on February 27th by the Rev. James M. Bishop.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fortna</ln>
                        <fn>Curtis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Curtis Fortna died near Strasburg, Letterkenny Township, on February 24th.
                    He was 59 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lowry</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lowry</ln>
                        <fn>David M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Ann Lowry, infant daughter of David M. and Mary Ann Lowry, died on
                    February 25th in Quincy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.03.04.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote>Advertisements and agricultural information appear on this page.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
