<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1868/pa.fr.vs.1868.01.08">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/31/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1868-01-08">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day norm="">8</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.01.08.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.01.08.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Fearful Condition of the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The state of affairs in the South is becoming more terrible every day. The
                        picture presented is a dark one indeed. The heart sickens at the recital of
                        the wants of her people and the dangers to which they are exposed.
                        Starvation is staring many of them in the face. Labor does not meet with
                        proper remuneration. A man may work himself to death and still not earn
                        enough to subsist himself and family. Three millions of people, white and
                        black, are clamoring for bread, and are devoid of the means with which to
                        purchase it. The accounts of the necessities of the poor are becoming more
                        and more painful. The man in the North, surrounded by the comforts,
                        convenience and luxuries of life, blessed with an abundance of money with
                        which to procure all that his appetite craves, little appreciates the
                        horrible condition of those in whose bodies hunger is a never dying worm
                        which keeps gnawing at their vitals continually. His ears are not greeted
                        with the cry of despair which goes out from famishing bodies. He knows not
                        the anguish of heart which he endures who sees his own flesh and blood
                        perishing for want of bread, or shivering and freezing for want of fuel as
                        the cold wintry winds howl around his desolate home. And yet, in the South
                        this is all a painful reality. The necessaries of life cannot be had without
                        money and many have no money at all. They must either starve therefore, or
                        commit crime of some kind to maintain themselves. Hence stealing has become
                        so common. Society has become completely demoralized. Pilfering, petty
                        larceny, cattle-slaying, house-burning and murders are every day
                        occurrences.--Bands of thriftless, wandering negroes roam over the country,
                        seizing whatever lies to their way and converting it to their own use,
                        notwithstanding the fact that they are the only class for which the
                        government appropriates money. Whilst thousands of whites are suffering the
                        horrors of starvation, knowing no place to look to for assistance, the
                        Freedmen's Bureau is in full operation, supplying, as far as its money goes,
                        the wants of the blacks exclusively. The money by which this Bureau is
                        sustained comes out of the pockets of the taxpayers of the North. They have
                        thus the spectacle presented to their eyes of worthless negroes reaping the
                        sole benefit of the immense sums which Congress has appropriated, and which
                        the people must raise, while thousands upon thousands of the men of their
                        own race are in utter destitution and dying for the want of food.</p>
                    <p>This deplorable condition of affairs is undoubtedly the result of the
                        iniquitous legislation of Congress. When the war closed, the people of the
                        South went to work manfully. They ceased to discuss politics. They left the
                        settlement of the vexed questions flowing out of the war to the victorious
                        North, relying upon the magnanimity and sense of justice of its people. They
                        turned their attention to labor in order to supply themselves with the
                        necessaries of life, thinking that, by the speedy restoration of their
                        respective States to their former harmonious relations with their sister
                        Commonwealth, industry would be stimulated, domestic trade would be revived
                        and prosperity would flow in upon them. But soon Congress began to seek to
                        retard reconstruction instead of endeavoring to hasten it. The majority
                        party dreaded the return of <emph rend="italic">white</emph> representatives
                        to the halls of Congress, fearing that it might thereby lose its ascendency
                        and its hold on power. They therefore set themselves to work to manufacture
                        public sentiment against the representation of those States until such time
                        as they could be assured that men would be sent from them to Congress who
                        would adopt their own rule of political action. This <orig reg="program"
                            >programme</orig> has been persistently adhered to, and is to be carried
                        out, regardless of the suffering to which individuals may be subjected, or
                        the detriment which the nation will receive therefrom, socially and
                        financially. The whole machinery of government in the South has been
                        stopped. Emigration from the North has been prevented to an enormous extent,
                        for who feels like exchanging a government of law and order for one of
                        anarchy? That free <sic>intertercourse</sic> between neighboring communities
                        and States which is the very life of business is rendered impossible.
                        Meanwhile the people of the South, cut off from all the benefits of a free
                        interchange of opinions on measures which injuriously affect their interests
                        are burdened with taxation which exhausts the scanty returns of their labor.
                            <emph rend="italic">It is the crying shame of our nation and our
                            generation, that we are waging a vindictive war against not only the
                            men, but the helpless women and children also of the South--not a war of
                            gunpowder, bullets and bayonets, but one which cuts off the supplies of
                            bread from hungry mouths and exposes naked bodies to the extreme cold of
                            this inclement season--and all for the purpose of subjecting that fair
                            territory to negro supremacy, in order that the Radical party may
                            thereby continue to administer our National Government.</emph></p>
                    <p>It seems, too, as though this blistering disgrace is to continue. Congress
                        appears to be deaf to the wail which comes up from the South. Instead of
                        devising ways and means to minister to the wants of that famishing
                        people--instead of seeking to discover the cause of this distress and
                        attempting to alleviate it--the time of the representatives of the nation is
                        squandered in President making. The moves on the political chess board are
                        more important to them than the cries of millions in want. The remedy must
                        come from the people. These unfaithful servants must be dismissed. They will
                        not obey the behests of their masters. Already have the sovereign people
                        thundered their wishes and commands in their ears, but they have been
                        totally disregarded. How long shall they abuse our patience? How long shall
                        they resist and disobey our commands? These questions are important. The
                        affairs of the nation were never more terribly mismanaged.--General distress
                        in the South; thousands upon thousands out of employment in the North; want
                        of confidence among men in themselves, in each other, and in the government;
                        crime stalking all over the land; national bankruptcy threatening us;
                        repudiation of the public faith hinted at--surely all this should arouse us
                        to thought and action in order to remedy these gigantic evils. The
                        fundamental cause of all this trouble is the mistaken policy of
                        reconstruction of the Radical party. As long as it is continued, there can
                        be no hope of a better condition of things. As long as the South remains
                        unrepresented by men who know her wants and her resources, and who reflect
                        the wishes and sentiments of her people, so long will business remain
                        stagnant, trade continue paralyzed, financial affairs admit of no
                        regulation, terrible distress and want prevail, and the incentives to crime
                        exist.</p>
                    <p>But change the policy of reconstruction. Abandon the idea of legislating the
                        negro into an equality with, and a superiority to the white man, which is,
                        owing to his nature and the unchangeable decree of the Almighty, an utter
                        impossibility. Abolish the infamous military governments to which the South
                        is subjected. Wipe out the lines which bound the five military districts.
                        Let the civil law have unobstructed sway in all the States of the Union.
                        Admit representatives from the South <emph rend="italic">at once</emph> to
                        Congress, not black, but white. Let the cry for confiscation cease,and soon
                        will be witnessed a blessed change. Mutual confidence will be revived, and
                        with it will come a free interchange of the products of the several States.
                        All the markets of the Union will be open to everybody. The wealth of the
                        South will be developed. Her people will labor with a hope of seeing some
                        return therefrom. The negroes will see the necessity of working for
                        themselves in order to provide against want, and will thus contribute in
                        their proper spheres to the establishment of a new order of things, instead
                        of being pampered and encouraged in idleness and vice. The burden of
                        taxation will be lighter upon the people of the North because the South will
                        be able to share it. The Freedmen's Bureau will be swept out of existence
                        and an immense leak in the National Treasury will be thereby stopped. The
                        standing army can be reduced, for no soldiers will be needed to hold the
                        South under military rule. In this way also, the National expenses will be
                        diminished. Retrenchment will begin everywhere. Business will cease to
                        languish. Free trade will be established. Our commerce will be extended. Our
                        Flag will again be the symbol of a united people, and, underlying all, will
                        ere long be the feeling of good will toward each other, which is alone the
                        basis of a permanent Union.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A vicious indictment of Republican reconstruction policy. Blames it for the
                    sad state of affairs in the South, especially the lack of industry and commerce
                    crippling the region. Calls on the government to abandon reconstruction and
                    preferable treatment of black southerners, whom the editor considers lazy and
                    unfit to rule. Feels this course of action will stimulate commerce, end burdens
                    like taxation on the North, and bring prosperity to all.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Pope's Decapitation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Applauds President Johnson for removing General Pope from command of the
                    Third Military District of the South. "He is a brave, rough, honest soldier to
                    whom this semblance of war was doubtless disgusting."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>General Grant's Loyalty</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper asserts that General Grant aided the President in removing
                    General John Pope "who is one of the radical advance guard." The editors urge
                    Republicans to ponder that fact.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Starvation in the South</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia Ledger</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article reports a "gloomy state of affairs" in the South including
                    "murders, riots, robberies, and burnings."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>Extension of the Franklin R. Road</head>
                <origin>Hagerstown Mail</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on plan to extend the Franklin Railroad to Hagerstown.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.01.08.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Religious</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Magee</ln>
                        <fn>Irving</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. Irving Magee, pastor elect of the Lutheran church, will give an
                    introductory sermon on Sunday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Serious Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frey</ln>
                        <fn>Fredrick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A German named Fredrick Frey fell from his wagon and was run over near
                    Hamilton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Took Possession</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. George W. Skinner, a Democrat, took his position as County Treasurer.
                    The paper applauds the development, and is confident in his abilities and good
                    conduct.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>General Kenton Harper</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Kenton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper prints an obituary for Confederate General Kenton Harper who was
                    born in Chambersburg but moved to Augusta County, Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Price of Goods</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper urges buyers to take advantage of the low cost of goods in
                    Chambersburg, since news from New York suggests a general rise in prices soon.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf>M. D.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witherspoon</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witherspoon</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas Kennedy, M. D., and Miss Mary Witherspoon, oldest daughter of
                    William Witherspoon, both of Franklin, were married on December 28th by the Rev.
                    J. A. Crawford.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyner</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKee</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKee</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas Kyner, of Shippesnburg, and Miss Margaret McKee, daughter of James
                    McKee of Franklin, were married on January 2nd by the Rev. J. A. Crawford.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>Emanuel T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bash</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hessler</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Emanuel T. Anderson and Miss Elizabeth Bash, both of Shippensburg, were
                    married on November 14th by the Rev. J. Hessler.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nickles</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fortsky</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hassler</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Nickles and Miss Catharine P. Fortsky, both of Shippensburg, were
                    married on December 26th by the Rev. J. Hassler.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddle</ln>
                        <fn>James A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>E. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hassler</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James A. Waddle and Miss E. M. Allen, daughter of Jeremiah Allen, both of
                    Shippensburg, were married on December 26th by the Rev. J. Hassler.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cradler</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaffer</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John W. Cradler of St. Thomas and Miss Mary Ann Palmer of Hamilton were
                    married on December 31st by the Rev. J. Shaffer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leberknight</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leberknight</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leberknight</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Margaret J. Leberknight, daughter of Daniel and Elizabeth Leberknight, died
                    in Hamilton on January 1st. She was 9 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>A. Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. Wilson Skinner died near Dry Run on January 1st. He was 21 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ramsey</ln>
                        <fn>Sylvester</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ramsey</ln>
                        <fn>Brice</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sylvester Ramsey, son of Brice Ramsey, died near Dry Run on January 2nd. He
                    was 11 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bratten</ln>
                        <fn>James Hynton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. James Hynton Bratten died in Chambersburg of chronic bronchitis on
                    January 3rd. He was 59 years old. Bratten was "well known to the people of this
                    town" and "a man of noble and generous impulses, of great energy and
                    perseverance of character." After a conversion 20 years ago, he went into the
                    ministry. He first served the United Brethren Church before joining the
                    Lutherans. He leaves a wife and four children.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.01.08.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote>Advertisements and agricultural advice appear on this page.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
