<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1868/pa.fr.vs.1868.02.19">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/16/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1868-02-19">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day norm="">19</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.02.19.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.02.19.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Impeachment Squelched</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Reconstruction Committee met last week to make another effort at
                        impeachment. The arch-agitator, Thaddeus Stevens, submitted a report,
                        declaring it as the opinion of the Committee, "that Andrew Johnson,
                        President of the United States, is guilty of high crimes and misdemeanors,"
                        and insisting upon his arraignment at the bar of the Senate, to be tried for
                        the same. We give here, the proceedings of the committee, as related by the
                        Washington correspondent of the Philadelphia <emph rend="italic">Morning
                            Post</emph>, (Radical) and call special attention to the speech of "The
                        Great Commoner."</p>
                    <p>After some conversation on the subject, Judge Bingham moved to lay it on the
                        table, which was carried by the following vote; Yeas--Bingham, Paine,
                        Beaman, Hubbard, Brooks and Beck. Nays--Stevens, Boutwell and Farnsworth.
                        Before the vote was taken, Paine, who was in favor of Impeachment last year,
                        attempted to dodge the vote and, as he was moving to the door to go out,
                        Stevens called to him: "Stop, Paine; you have got to face the music!" Paine
                        hesitated; when Stevens said, "Clerk, put him down against impeachment."</p>
                    <p>Mr. Stevens, after the vote was declared, said:</p>
                    <p>SIR: <emph rend="italic">The Republican party has been killed to-day by the
                            action of this Committee at the instance of General Grant and his
                            friends.</emph> I have found that for the last two or three days, the
                        men who shouted the loudest, and threw their hats the highest, for U.S.
                        Grant, have been using every exertion to influence against Impeachment the
                        other members of this committee who were supposed to favor it; <emph
                            rend="italic">that Grant has been using his influence everywhere to
                            defeat the scheme</emph>, and that Andrew Johnson has to thank the
                        General that he remains undisturbed in the White House. I have been in
                        public life for forty years, and though I do not pretend to any gift of
                        prophecy, I have seldom been mistaken in any political predictions. I now
                        tell you that to-day's cowardly action will cost us New York, Pennsylvania,
                        and probably three or four other Northern States."</p>
                    <p>With what a lordly air does the old man crack his whip over the head of the
                        timid, dodging Paine! And how, with bold, prophetic voice, does he foretell
                        the overwhelming defeat of the Radical party. He sees the hand-writing on
                        the wall, distinct as that which startled Belshazzar in the midst of his
                        drunken orgies, and he does not hesitate to interpret it. But on whom does
                        he cast the blame? On poor Grant. Eviscerated by the President, despised by
                        all men who hate double-dealing, the General is now kicked <emph
                            rend="italic">when he is down</emph>, in the very house of his friends,
                        and that too, by the great Mogul of the Radical party. Did ever man commit a
                        greater error than he, when he sought to exchange the lucrative position in
                        which he was honored by the whole nation--where he could smoke his eternal
                        cigar in peace and quiet--for the Presidential chair, whose multitudinous
                        vexatious cares, and weighty responsibilities, produce endless disquiet in
                        the mind of its occupants? An error--because he has become the mere toy of
                        designing, selfish politicians. An error--because he has thus brought his
                        character for veracity into question, with the odds fearfully against him.</p>
                    <p>An error--because the veil has been lifted from his intemperate habits,
                        exposing him to public ridicule and contempt. An error--because he has been
                        compelled into insubordination to his superior officer. An error--because he
                        has thrown himself open to the charge of cherishing the ambition to fill a
                        position, which nobody asserts, or believes is, his competency to fill.</p>
                    <p>An error--because he has, according to the statement of Mr. Stevens, insured
                        the defeat of the Radical organization, whose cause he has shown himself so
                        anxious to promote.</p>
                    <p>For the last reason, we can pardon his error, but it is none the less an
                        error on his part. He will find the road to the Presidency a very rough one.
                        It is beset with thorns and brambles. He will be wise, if he hauls off from
                        the race.</p>
                    <p>And so, the impeachment humbug is again exploded. The Radicals have again
                        acknowledged that the President is <emph rend="italic">not</emph> guilty of
                        high crimes and misdemeanors.--Meanwhile, the people are getting ready to
                        hurl these impeachment agitators from their places. God speed the day.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Tells how a new move for impeachment was defeated in the Reconstruction
                    Committee by none other than Republicans. Quotes Stevens in saying it marks the
                    defeat of the Radicals and also outlines the errors Grant made in colluding with
                    Radicals. Ends by predicting the imminent defeat of Radicals in the next
                    elections.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Hancock and Grant</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper criticizes Grant for suspending an order of General Hancock
                    removing seven black and two white members of the New Orleans City Council. "By
                    the way, think of seven members of the New Orleans City Council being negroes.
                    Truly this is a progressive age, and the 'cullud bredern' are a progressive
                    people. White people are 'not worth shucks' any more."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Refreshing</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A colored girl, thirteen years old, was hung last week at Newcastle,
                        Kentucky, for killing a white child. Yet the Kentucky papers say "everything
                        went off with much propriety." When will these outrages cease?--<emph
                            rend="italic">Phila'd. Morning Post.</emph></p>
                    <p>Hang a <emph rend="italic">black</emph> girl for killing a <emph
                            rend="italic">white</emph> child? Shameful. "When <emph rend="italic"
                            >will</emph> these outrages cease?" In this enlightened land, when all
                        power is being placed in the hands of the colored race, stretch a negro's
                        neck for letting out the life-blood of "the white trash?" Infamous. "When
                        will these outrages cease?"</p>
                    <p>In this progressive age, when the hitherto down-trodden African is assuming
                        his rightful place as the equal of the Anglo-Saxon in every sphere of life,
                        inflict capital punishment upon a dark-hued sister, simply because she
                        scattered around loose upon the floor, the brains of a fair-faced, laughing
                        white child? Intolerable. "When will these outrages cease?"</p>
                    <p>A negro, in the State of Alabama, ravishes a young white girl of fifteen
                        years of age, cuts her tongue out, and leaves her in an almost dying
                        condition. An infuriated mob pursues him, and hangs him on the nearest tree.
                        Outrageous in the mob. The man was <emph rend="italic">black</emph>. He
                        ought not to have been hung. "When will these outrages cease?"</p>
                    <p>A few years ago, two colored fiends violated the persons of two aged white
                        women, one nearly seventy, in Lancaster county, and then murdered them in
                        cold blood. The officers of the law seized them. Court and jury condemned
                        them. They were gibbetted in the jail-yard. Beyond all forbearance. Their
                        skin was <emph rend="italic">black</emph>. They should not have been
                        executed. "When will these outrages cease?</p>
                    <p>On the streets of Harrisburg, no lady is safe alone at night. Outrages upon
                        women are committed, and attempted, almost every night in the week by
                        negroes. Some people are attempting to discover the perpetrators of these
                        fiendish deeds. Perfectly unjustifiable! Nobody has a right to investigate
                        the matter, for are not the offenders <emph rend="italic">black</emph> men?
                        Let the detectives keep off the track. "When will these outrages cease?"</p>
                    <p>The negro will never have secured his proper station in society, and in the
                        world, until he not only votes, sits in the jury-box, rides in whatever car
                        he pleases and on whatever seat he selects, intermarries with the whites,
                        holds every office in the government, frames our laws and interprets them on
                        the bench, but until he is also furnished with a wholesale license to commit
                        whatever crime he pleases--to rob us of our money--to violate the persons of
                        our wives and daughters--to perpetrate murder whenever he chooses, and in
                        the most atrocious manner he can think of. Any person who seeks to prevent
                        him from reaching this, his position in the world, throws himself into open
                        antagonism to the "great moral ideas," which govern the Radical party of
                        to-day. In view of the resistance which the Democratic party is making to
                        the extension of such high priveleges to the negro, we submit, that the
                            <emph rend="italic">Morning Post</emph> ought to apply its query to that
                        organization--"When will these outrages cease?"</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Responds to an article in a Republican newspaper about a lynching in
                    Kentucky in a very sarcastic manner. Details black crimes committed against
                    whites and claims they will only get worse.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Grant-Johnson Correspondence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The President has replied to the insolent letter of General Grant in a way
                        that is not calculated to elevate the General in the estimation of the
                        American people. Calm in the consciousness of right, and dignified in the
                        knowledge of his strength, he dissects the ambitious military chieftain with
                        the skill of a master surgeon. In the light of this correspondence, the
                        giant is shriveled into a pigmy. Grant, doubtless, feels inclined to crawl
                        into the smallest hole he can find, and draw the hole in after him.--But,
                        wriggle as he may, he can not conceal himself from public observation, or
                        escape public contempt. The people will forgive almost anything in a public
                        man sooner than a breach of faith. They will not tolerate a violation of his
                        plighted word. The testimony of the Cabinet officers settles the question of
                        veracity beyond dispute. Of course, there are some willfully blind fanatics,
                        who will affect to disbelieve this concurrent testimony of these five
                        eminent gentlemen, and say, that <emph rend="italic">they</emph> would,
                        willingly, swear to anything which the President asserts, but the masses of
                        the people will not believe this. They know, that there is nothing of which
                        honorable men are more careful, and jealous, than their reputation for
                        veracity. They will not credit the assertion, therefore, that five men as
                        distinguished as the gentlemen who have written these letters, so damaging
                        to Grant, would rush to the rescue of the President in such a controversy,
                        unless they know positively that which they have published to the world over
                        their own signatures.</p>
                    <p>It will be observed that Grant has brought this trouble upon himself. We do
                        not now refer to the deception which he practiced upon the President. That
                        was, undoubtedly, the first step to his disgrace. But we mean, that Grant
                        brought this <emph rend="italic">exposure of his duplicity</emph> upon
                        himself, by beginning a correspondence, which he should have had the
                        foresight to see, could result only in shame, and confusion to himself. He
                        has nobody to blame for it, unless, indeed, he has only been a supple tool
                        in the hands of able wicked men. This was, not unlikely, the fact. A trap
                        was set, temptingly baited, for the President. It was thought, that he could
                        be unwittingly drawn into an acknowledgement of such a palpable violation of
                        the Tenure-of-Office-Bill as would justify the Radicals in resorting to
                        impeachment.</p>
                    <p>The devilish cunning of Stanton's brain, doubtless, devised this plan. But
                        he, and his infamous co-conspirators have been completely foiled. The shot
                        which Grant fired, not only missed its mark, but rebounded, and struck the
                        gunner with terrific force.--Haman was hung upon the gallows which he had
                        prepared for Mordocai. How often it happens that a man falls into the pit
                        which he has dug for his neighbor!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises Johnson's reply to Grant's letter, though does not say what was the
                    content of either. Refers to the attempt at impeachment the year before and
                    hints that Grant is merely a tool for the Radicals, both of whom failed in their
                    quest to eliminate Johnson. Also claims five cabinet members back Johnson's word
                    over Grant's.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Alabama Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A majority of the registered voters in the State of Alabama, having failed to
                        vote in favor of the Constitution submitted by the Mongrel Convention, it
                        has been defeated. This is in perfect accordance with the Reconstruction
                        laws of Congress. The whole machinery was set in motion and run by the
                        Radical party, with the confident expectation of wheeling Alabama into line
                        in support of the Radical candidate for the Presidency. They have been
                        beaten at their own game. The Constitution has fallen to pieces by reason of
                        its own rottenness.</p>
                    <p>But fanaticism does not falter. Resolutions have been already introduced into
                        the Senate of the United States declaring the Constitution adopted, and
                        Alabama admitted to the Union. Congress thus not only disregards the
                        Constitution in framing the Reconstruction laws, but when they fail to suit
                        their purpose, they brush them out of the way, as so much rubbish. What a
                        farce is a popular election getting to be! It decides nothing anymore, for
                        Congress ignores, and disregards its teachings, and deliberately undertakes
                        to reverse its result. It is well for it that the American people are
                        long-suffering.</p>
                    <p>If the people of the other States of the South pursue the same policy, it is
                        probable that the Radical schemes will be thwarted, and their infamous
                        negro-equality measures defeated, in accordance with the regulations
                        prescribed, and the laws enacted by themselves. This is almost certain to be
                        the case, unless the hasty legislation of Congress is again hurriedly
                        altered to meet the difficulty disclosed by the Alabama election.--We feel
                        satisfied, however, that even though this step should be taken, all will
                        come out right in the end. A Higher Power than human agencies will yet curb
                        the madness of these families, and give us, in His own good time, a republic
                        governed by law.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the failed attempt to pass a new constitution in Alabama and
                    expected Radical responses. Calls on other Southern states to follow Alabama's
                    example and thwart Republican designs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Border Losses</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper applauds the introduction of a bill in the legislature for
                    reimbursement of citizens who sustained damage and loss of property during the
                    war. "We trust that the Democrats of that body will show themselves willing to
                    do justice to the plundered citizens of the border, and let the Radicals
                    shoulder the responsibility of defeating this bill."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Our Virginia Letters</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper announces it will publish letters from Virginia describing the
                    conditions there. "It is highly essential to the future harmony of the States,
                    lately 'dissevered, discordant, and belligerent,' that their people should
                    become thoroughly acquainted with each other."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Virginia Geologically Divided</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Abingdon, VA., Feb. 10th, 1868.</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">Editors of the Valley Spirit:</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>To a prejudiced mind, it might seem improper for the people of the North and
                        the people of the South, who were <emph rend="italic">quondam</emph>
                        competitors in numerous gigantic struggles, to commingle with that friendly
                        feeling, which is the only true method of securing the permanency of any
                        Republican Government; but the larger and more enlightened class of our
                        citizens, in both sections, are not chained by any such bigotry.</p>
                    <p>Certainly, the inhabitants of Pennsylvania, living in the counties south of
                        the Susquehanna, are too near to Maryland and Virginia, with whose citizens
                        they are in frequent communication, to entertain such opinions. It is true
                        that your country suffered by the fire and sword of the Confederate army,
                        and the substantial improvements of Virginia were laid waste by northern
                        soldiers, yet, I believe, that the people of these sections, who bore the
                        brunt of the battle, will be the first to shake hands of friendship.</p>
                    <p>The remark of that noble officer, General Hancock, upon introducing General
                        Longstreet to his staff, conveys the sentiment that should actuate all of
                        us. Said he: Gentlemen, this is the officer to whom I am indebted for an
                        ungraceful limp, and whom I had the misfortune to wing in the same
                        engagement.</p>
                    <p>The best mode of securing this friendliness of feeling is to induce a part of
                        your people to emigrate to some quarter of the Southern States, and I am
                        glad to learn that there is a growing disposition on the part of
                        Pennsylvanians to move to Virginia. In view of this propitious fact, I
                        apprehend that communications, giving accurate information of the soil,
                        climate, mineral resources, facilities for transportation, prices of lands,
                        &amp;c., in the State of Virginia, would be acceptable to most of your
                        readers.</p>
                    <p>As it would tax your columns too much to treat this subject in a manner
                        satisfactory to your readers and myself, in one issue of your admirable
                        paper, I purpose making this only the first of a series of articles.</p>
                    <p>The whole of the present State of Virginia is geologically divided into four
                        districts.--First, the Tide Water region extending from the Atlantic Ocean
                        to the head of steam navigation on the water courses. The farms along the
                        banks of the streams in this section are very productive. The bountiful, and
                        hospitable board of a James River farmer was an aphorism before the war, but
                        as the blacks have been recently <sic>metamorphosed</sic> from slaves to
                        suffragans, and as all of them have turned politicians, and each expects to
                        be a Congressman, and some of them President of the United States, the
                        industrial pursuits have been driven rapidly backward.</p>
                    <p>The influx of white immigrants will, I hope, soon restore this unfortunate
                        country to its former prosperity. Some colonies from Europe are now settling
                        in Eastern Virginia. These will be the means of inducing others to follow,
                        and the probabilities are that Tide Water Virginia will soon assert that it
                        will be ruled by white men. The chief products are wheat(of a very superior
                        quality) corn oats, potatoes, and tobacco.</p>
                    <p>Second, The Piedmont District, running north and south throughout the entire
                        breadth of the State, and reaching from the head of Tide Water to the Blue
                        Ridge mountain. This is the far-famed tobacco growing country. All of the
                        cereals, common to this climate, are cultivated with success, but grass,
                        neither here, nor in the Tide Water country, grows well. It is my opinion,
                        from an intimate knowledge of Piedmont Virginia, that it is destined to
                        become the grape and wine section for all of the Atlantic States. No better
                        evidence can be offered to support this supposition, than that,
                            <sic>whereever</sic> you may go through the fields and woods, wild grape
                        vines, generally bearing delicious fruit, will be met with. The whites and
                        blacks are nearly equal in numbers, with the preponderance, however, in
                        favor of the former. Were it not for the fact that so many of the whites are
                        disfranchised, the blacks would be largely in the minority.</p>
                    <p>Third; The Shenandoah Valley, between the Blue Ridge upon the east, and the
                        Alleghenies upon the west. This is but a continuation of that same strip of
                        land that is formed between the mountains above mentioned, and which extends
                        through the State of Pennsylvania, taking in your own town. The soil is
                        identical with ours, the topography is alike, and, making some allowances
                        for climate, the products are the same.</p>
                    <p>Fourth, South-west Virginia, extending from a point where the Blue Ridge and
                        the Alleghenies, in their alternate converging and diverging lines, touch
                        each other, to the State of Kentucky. This district comprises some dozen
                        counties, through the centres of most of which a railroad runs, in a
                        continuous line, from Norfolk to Memphis. Of this great grazing, and
                        agricultural region, I desire to write fully in several succeeding
                        communications. Yours, Respectfully,<lb/> VIRGINIUS.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An anonymous Virginian writes a letter to the Valley Spirit detailing the
                    topography of Virginia in the hopes of enticing immigration from Pennsylvania.
                    Has a tone of reconciliation and a desire for more whites in Virginia to counter
                    growing black political power in the state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.02.19.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Colonel McClure's Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Col. McClure spoke on Mormonism to a packed Court house. Everyone praised
                    the interesting nature of his lecture.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>A Woolen Factory</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper calls for investment in Franklin County's woolen factory. They
                    reprint a notice of plans to build one in Carlisle but argue that existing mills
                    should be subsidized first.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Rev. Henry Ward Beecher's Lecture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shryock</ln>
                        <fn>S. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>J. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Ward Beecher will lecture in the Lutheran Church on "Work and the
                    Workman." Tickets can be purchased from S. S. Shryock and J. N. Snider.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Hershberger's Panorama</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hershberger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Major Hershberger will exhibit his panorama of "The Invasion of
                    Pennsylvania" including the "Burning of Chambersburg and Scotland Bridge" in
                    Chambersburg's Repository Hall. "This Panorama will be of thrilling interest to
                    all of our people who witnessed the entrance of Rebel armies, and suffered the
                    horrors of the 30th day of July 1864."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Plea for the Schools</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">Editors of the Valley Spirit:</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>Whatever subjects are presented in the public mind, that which concerns the
                        interest of the whole community, is the one which should command the
                        earliest and promptest attention of every Philanthropist, and of every one
                        who regards his own welfare; especially since it not only affects those
                        around us, but also those who are to take our places when we and the
                        generation around us have passed away.</p>
                    <p>What more noble object can there be than the development of the human mind,
                        that precious jewel which is contained in many instances in a rough casket!
                        From whom have our citizens reaped the greatest advantages, but from those
                        who have cultivated their own minds, and have given the community the result
                        of their labors? To whom are we indebted for the use of steam, which has
                        brought places, hundreds of miles distant, within a few hours of each other,
                        but to Robert Fulton, who threw his mighty intellect in the scale against
                        ignorance, and prejudice, and achieved a victory, by the aid of which, other
                        skillful mechanics have advanced so far that the wilderness has been made to
                        "blossom as the Rose?" See what Morse has done with the Electric Telegraph.
                        I might mention others, but time would forbid. All we can say is, look
                        around and see what has been done in the last quarter of a century--the
                        improvements which have economized light, and fuel, and the many little
                        comforts around us, of which our forefathers had not so much as dreamed. To
                        whom are we indebted for our great military affairs? Disease has been made
                        to succumb to science. To whom are we indebted for all the Philanthropic
                        enterprises of the day, but to men, and I may say ladies also, of cultivated
                        intellects? How have the poor been made to rejoice, and bless God for such
                        and such persons? What has lessened crime, but the diffusion of knowledge?
                        Who are those who are the most degraded in life, but those who are ignorant,
                        who are unable to read God's holy word and commandments, and therefore, when
                        their daily task is done, seek the dens of infamy and disgrace?</p>
                    <p>From a table appended to the Report of the State Superintendent of Common
                        Schools, we have reports from 43 Counties in the State, where we find 1940
                        occupants of their jails, of whom 434 can not read; 540 read a little; 504
                        read well, and 123 are good scholars. Cost of support, $145,080; Expenses of
                        conviction, $175,702. Report of Poor Houses of 26 Counties--occupants 3,428.
                        Number over 10 years of age, 2,809; those who can not read, over that age,
                        1181; those who can read a little, 1189; read well, 412; good scholars, 80.
                        Franklin County, 411 in jail; cost of support, $7,046; other expenses,
                        $8,000. Occupants of poor House, 121; number over 10 years of age, 104;
                        number over that age who can not read, 59; read a little, 35; read well, 10.
                        Cost of support, $20,000. Total cost of Jail and Poor House, $35,045. Total
                        amount of tax levied for School purposes, $57,395. State Appropriation,
                        $3,820.74. Total amount for schools in County, $61,215.74.</p>
                    <p>This does not include what the community has lost through crime, which has
                        not been brought to punishment, which we all know is much greater that the
                        above, mostly from the uneducated. We may safely say, that not more than
                        one-third of the crime is punished. How much do we lose yearly by Pilfering,
                        Arson, and Fraud? We may, therefore, set the cost of crime and misery, at
                        about $105,000, leaving a balance in round numbers of about $44,000 against
                        crime and its accompaniments, without considering what education has already
                        done for us. The result is incalculable. In view of these facts, our duty is
                        plain and practicable. Let us give our teachers sufficient salaries to make
                        teaching an object, and also increase our school term. To carry out the
                        principle of the school law, let us be willing to assist the patrons of the
                        poorer schools in educating their children, and not seek to separate from
                        regular Districts, into independent ones, thereby establishing precedents
                        for others to do the same, and throwing too great a burden on the parts that
                        remain.</p>
                    <p>Our schools should be brought to that standard of excellence, that every
                        pupil may obtain as good tuition, as far as the branches of the Common
                        Schools are concerned, as can be obtained elsewhere, which can readily be
                        done, by due care being taken in the selection of teachers, by patrons
                        respecting the authority of teachers, and Directors enforcing it.</p>
                    <p>Since such great benefits are derived from knowledge, which "Is Power," the
                        General Government should not be backward in giving a helping hand to this
                        great work. She has done comparatively little for the cause. It is true she
                        has a Military Institution at West Point for the Army, and another at
                        Annapolis for the Navy, and has granted some land to Western Territories in
                        by-gone days. Would it not have a tendency to make her citizens more loyal
                        to see her benignant hand stretched out to assist them on behalf of their
                        children? Who would not feel a growing attachment for it, and wish the hand
                        palsied that would be raised against it? It is not the best parent, who
                        supports his family only by supplying them with food and raiment, but he who
                        teaches them to do for themselves. So that Government is not doing the best
                        for the governed which has an army of sinecures about it.--She wants men to
                        help her, working men.</p>
                    <p>We only ask what has heretofore been misappropriated. Our citizens have
                        expended much during the few last years for the Government, to the
                        disadvantage of the schools, and should have some back in return.</p>
                    <p>The money might be disbursed in such a manner as not to interfere with State
                        regulations. For instance, no district shall be entitled to a share where
                        the History of the United States is not read. A certain part, say one-fifth,
                        might be retained by the Government for general educational purposes;
                        one-fifth be disbursed by the States generally for Normal Schools, Lectures
                        on Natural Philosophy and other sciences. The rural districts have no
                        advantages of this kind. Many a rude, uncultivated urchin has a germ within
                        him, which, if developed, might astonish the world.</p>
                    <p>The population of the U.S. in 1860, was 31,443,321. Of Pennsylvania,
                        2,906,215, or 9.21 per cent of the whole. Supposed $10,000,000 were applied
                        by the Government, deducting $2,000,000 for general purposes, leaving
                        $8,000,000 for the States. Pennsylvania would be entitled to $736,800,
                        reserving one-fifth $147,350, leaving $588,440 to be divided amongst the
                        schools in proportion to the pupils. 789,389 scholars were registered last
                        year, making 74.5 per scholar.--School districts would receive as follows:</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Antrim,</cell>
                            <cell>1,023</cell>
                            <cell>scholars,</cell>
                            <cell>$761.14 1/2</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Chambersburg,</cell>
                            <cell>1,241</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>924.54 1/2</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Fannett,</cell>
                            <cell>575</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>428.37 1/2</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Greene,</cell>
                            <cell>942</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>701.79</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Greencastle,</cell>
                            <cell>301</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>224.24 1/2</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Guilford,</cell>
                            <cell>729</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>543.10 1/2</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Hamilton,</cell>
                            <cell>407</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>303.21 1/2</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Letterkenny,</cell>
                            <cell>614</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>457.43</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Lurgan</cell>
                            <cell>398</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>298.51</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Mercersburg</cell>
                            <cell>315</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>234.62 1/2</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Metal,</cell>
                            <cell>324</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>241.38</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Montgomery,</cell>
                            <cell>816</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>607.92</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Peters,</cell>
                            <cell>582</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>433.59</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Quincy,</cell>
                            <cell>666</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>496.17</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Southampton,</cell>
                            <cell>572</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>426.22</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>St. Thomas,</cell>
                            <cell>507</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>377.76</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Warren,</cell>
                            <cell>185</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>137.82 1/2</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Washington,</cell>
                            <cell>557</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>414.96 1/2</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Waynesboro,</cell>
                            <cell>246</cell>
                            <cell>..</cell>
                            <cell>183.27</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Total</cell>
                            <cell>11,000</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>$8,196.08 1/2</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>Quincy Tw'p, Feb. 3d. 1868.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A call for more money from the government to be spent on education. Gives a
                    lot of statistics about crime and the poor to argue for the importance of
                    schooling. Includes a table of school districts in Franklin.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Wednesday, Feb. 12th, in the Union Church, Waynesboro, Pa., by Rev. Wm. F.
                        Colliflower, Mr. GEORGE EOY, of Greencastle, to MARGARET A. COLLIFLOWER, of
                        Waynesboro.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Colliflower</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eoy</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Colliflower</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On the 6th inst., at the residence of Mr. Samuel Shew, by Rev. J. Keller
                        Miller, Mr. JOHN CONRADSITES, of Hamilton township, to Miss SARAH KATESHEW,
                        of St. Thomas township.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shew</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. Keller</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conradsites</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kateshew</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On the 11th inst., at the residence of the bride's father, by the same, Mr.
                        JACOB LARE, of Shady Grove, to Miss MARY LOHR, of St. Thomas township.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lare</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lohr</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On the 13th inst., at the Reformed Parsonage in Mont Alto, by the Rev. Cyrus
                        Cort, Mr. JOHN R. FRAKER, of Shippensburg, to Miss HANNAH M. COOK, daughter
                        of John Cook.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cort</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fraker</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Hannah M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Thursday, Jan'y. 30th by Rev. I.N. Hays, Mr. ANDREW GROSS, Jr., of Cumb
                        co., to Mrs. N. A. GOCHENAUR, of this county.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>I. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gross</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gochenaur</ln>
                        <fn>N. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Monday, the 13th inst., by Rev. I. N. Hays, Mr. R. HEMPHILL of Cumb. co.
                        to Miss MAGGIE J. BROWN, of Orrstown, Pa.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>I. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hemphill</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On the 11th inst., in Greencastle, by Justice J. Kauffman, Mr. WILLIAM
                        SANDERS, to Miss MARGARET TOPPER, both of Franklin co., Pa.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kauffman</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sanders</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Topper</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On the 21st ult., by Rev. I. G. Brown, Mr. DAVID N. DIVILBLISS, to Miss
                        HARRIET STINGZR, both of this county.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>I. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Divilbliss</ln>
                        <fn>David N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stingzr</ln>
                        <fn>Harriet</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On the 4th inst., by the same, N. WOLCAMOT, Esq., of Canton, Ill., to Miss
                        LAURA M. KEYSER, of Welsh Run.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolcamot</ln>
                        <fn>N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keyser</ln>
                        <fn>Laura M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On the 11th inst., by Rev. W. E. Krebs, Mr. JACOB C. ECKSTINE, of Washington
                        co. Md., to Miss MARIA LECKRON, of Waynesboro.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Krebs</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eckstine</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leckron</ln>
                        <fn>Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On the 13th inst., at Pleasant Retreat Parsonage, by Rev. J. Phillip Bishop,
                        of Mechanicsburg, Mr. JOHN R. PLOUGH, TO Miss EMMA C. eldest daughter of
                        Rev. Jas. M. Bishop.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>J. Phillip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plough</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>Emma C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On the morning of the 13th inst., at the residence of the bride's father near
                        Rocky Spring, by Rev Jas M. Bishop, Mr. HEILMAN HUBER, to Miss AMANDA, only
                        daughter of Jacob Plough, both of this co.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>Heilman</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plough</ln>
                        <fn>Amanda</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plough</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On the 30th ult., at Miller's Hotel in this place, by Rev P. S. Davis, Mr.
                        JOSEPH SHAFER, to Miss JANE V. FOHL, both of St. Thomas.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shafer</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fohl</ln>
                        <fn>Jane V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On the 6th inst., by the same, Mr. THADDEUS COOK, of Waynesboro, to Miss
                        MAGGIE LANCES, of Chambersburg.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Thaddeus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lances</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On the 13th inst., by the Rev. G. Roth, Mr. FRANCIS LUDWIG GERHOLD, of this
                        place, to Miss MARY HELMAN, of New Franklin.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gerhold</ln>
                        <fn>Francis Ludwig</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Helman</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On the evening of the 16th inst., by the same, Mr. WILLIAM SEIRUST, to Miss
                        ANNA MARY RIPPER, both of Chambersburg.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seirust</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ripper</ln>
                        <fn>Anna Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On the 13th inst., by Rev. F. Dyson, Mr. JOHN UNGER, of Franklin co., to Miss
                        JANE MYERS, of Greenvillage.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Unger</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Colliflower</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Colliflower died in Waynesboro on February 13th. He was 76 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wile</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wile</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elizabeth Wile, wife of Jacob Wile, Jr., died on February 12th in
                    Funkstown. She was 26 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ritter</ln>
                        <fn>Martha Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ritter</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Martha Jane Ritter, wife of James Ritter and daughter of Jacob and
                    Elizabeth Snider, died on January 30th in Chambersburg. She was 23 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sarah Gillan, wife of the late William Gillan, died on January 20th near
                    Orrstown. She was 72 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>Hannah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Hannah Johnson, aged 72 years, died in Guilford on February 8th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beaver</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beaver</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Mary Beaver, mother of Samuel Beaver, died near Quincy on February 3rd
                    after a lingering illness. She was 80 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scott</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Margaret Scott died near Mercersburg on February 10th. She was 74
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowan</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowan</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Cowan, wife of Joseph V. Cowan, died on February 12th near
                    Mercersburg. She was 75 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shetron</ln>
                        <fn>Hannah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shetron</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Hannah Shetron, wife of Jacob Shetron, died on February 11th in St. Thomas.
                    She was 74 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.02.19.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote>Advertisements and agricultural information appear on this page.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
