<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1868/pa.fr.vs.1868.07.08">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/07/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1868-07-08">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="">8</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.07.08.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.07.08.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The National Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the opening of the Democratic National Convention and early
                    balloting for presidential nominees.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Soldiers' and Sailors' Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the opening of the Conservative Soldiers' and Sailors'
                    Convention in New York. They cheered General George McClellan, resolved that
                    widows and orphans of soldiers and sailors should be viewed as "the special
                    wards of the nation," and made plans to march in the city streets.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Amnesty Proclamation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Andrew Johnson took the best possible way to celebrate the anniversary of the
                        Declaration of Independence. In the exercise of his clear constitutional
                        "power to grant reprieves and pardons for offences against the United
                        States," he issued an amnesty proclamation which removes all pains,
                        penalties and disabilities from all who were engaged, directly or
                        indirectly, in the rebellion, except those who are under presentment or
                        indictment for treason, or other felony. The wonder is that this step has
                        been so long delayed. The people of the South long ago manifested a
                        disposition to accept the result of the great contest in good faith, by
                        acknowledging the supremacy of the National Government. No opposition to the
                        enforcement of the laws has been shown since the surrender of the rebel
                        armies. Men who went into the war and fought for the establishment of the
                        Southern Confederacy with all the energy and enthusiasm of their fiery
                        natures, at the close of the struggle, went quietly to work to sustain
                        themselves and families and to rebuild their shattered fortunes.
                        Notwithstanding the sensational dispatches with which the people of the
                        North have been regaled--notwithstanding the false reports of numerous
                        outrages said to have been wantonly committed, the truth is that nowhere in
                        the Union has there been greater security for life than in the South. It has
                        been the constant aim of the Radicals to create the impression that the
                        spirit of rebellion has all along been nursed in that section and has only
                        been kept in subjection by the presence of the military forces.--Upon this
                        allegation, Congress has based its legislation so inimical to the interests
                        of the Southern people and so destructive of the most sacred principles of
                        the Constitution. It was high time, therefore, that the President should
                        disabuse the public mind of this impression wherever it has taken hold. We
                        apprehend that the admirable preamble to the proclamation will do this
                        effectually.</p>
                    <p>The Radical papers assert that it evinces a fresh disposition on the part of
                        the President to renew the quarrel with Congress.--The New York <emph
                            rend="italic">Times</emph> says that he should not have ventured on this
                        step without consulting Congress, although it admits that he is acting
                        within his constitutional power.--That is a rich idea, that the Executive is
                        to be such a puppet in the hands of the Legislative Department, that he dare
                        not exercise the authority clearly vested in him, and him alone, by the
                        Constitution without asking its permission. General Grant, if elected, will
                        be willing to demean himself to that extent, but it must not be expected of
                        a Democratic President. And especially would it have been refreshing to see
                        Andrew Johnson getting down on his knees to a Congress that has made use of
                        all the unparliamentary epithets towards him that the English language can
                        furnish--a Congress that has sought to strip him of all the powers with
                        which the Constitution clothes him--a Congress that in its madness and
                        fanaticism, sought to depose him for attempting to remove a Cabinet
                        officer--it would have been peculiarly refreshing to witness Andrew Johnson
                        bending as a suppliant at the bar of the House and making its gracious
                        permission to do what no power on earth can prevent him from doing.</p>
                    <p>Andrew Johnson has had the independence and moral courage to do what he
                        thought right in this matter. He has lifted a burden from the necks of the
                        Southern people. All honor to him for this proclamation.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises Johnson's recent action pardoning everyone who took part in the
                    rebellion. Also criticises Congress for opposing the measure, saying a
                    Democratic president would never be a puppet to Congress like Grant supposedly
                    would be. Claims all Radical propaganda about violence in the South are vicious
                    lies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Registry Law</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper praises Pennsylvania's Supreme Court for declaring the Registry
                    Law unconstitutional.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>General F. P. Blair's Position</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The letter of General Frank P. Blair which we print in another column will
                        well repay perusal. It surely gives out no uncertain sound. Its author is
                        frank and bold. He knows well--no man knows better--that the object of the
                        Northern soldiery in fighting the battles of the country, was not to
                        establish such bastard governments in the South as have been formed by the
                        Radical Congress. He sees, as all intelligent soldiers see, that instead of
                        the war preserving the "dignity, equality and rights of the several States
                        unimpaired," it has robbed the Southern States of their dignity, impaired
                        their equality, and stripped them of their constitutional rights. A set of
                        Northern squatters has assumed to control the negro population and, through
                        it, the State governments. This has been done in pursuance of the
                        Congressional policy. General Blair is in favor of uprooting this policy. He
                        desires the issue to be put plainly before the country so that the sovereign
                        people may declare whether or not they will tolerate such trampling under
                        foot of State rights. He believes the Reconstruction acts to be in palpable,
                        flagrant violation of the Constitution, and hence he would treat them as
                        null and void from the beginning, and all action taken under them as illegal
                        and consequently of no binding force. He asserts that it will be obligatory
                        upon the President elect, on account of the oath which he takes, to defend
                        the Constitution from the terrible attacks made upon it by Congress. Such
                        action on the part of the new President would make short work of the
                        carpetbaggers and place the State Governments under the control of the
                        citizens of the several states. The day of negro rule would soon be over and
                        the states of the Union would soon enter upon a new career of harmony and
                        prosperity. General Blair, in our judgment, strikes at the root of our
                        difficulties and strikes boldly. The same principle and spirit in Andrew
                        Johnson would have saved the country the ignominy into which the Radicals
                        and their proteges, the negroes, have plunged it. Had he treated the
                        Reconstruction acts as null and void on account of their
                        unconstitutionality, he would have rallied around him a great and strong
                        party which would have born down all opposition, whether wordy or warlike,
                        and ten chances to one, reelected him to the first office in the gift of the
                        American people.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Refers to a letter by Frank Blair denouncing the Military Reconstruction
                    Governments in the South. Editor agrees wholeheartedly, speculates that if
                    Johnson had vigorously stated what Blair said, he would have been reelected.
                    Repeatedly calls the Reconstruction governments unconstitutional and degrading
                    to the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Gen. Grant's Negro Governor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper denounces General Grant for appointing an African American
                    Governor of Louisiana.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>General Frank P. Blair Defines his Position</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter from General Frank Blair outlining his views on national politics.
                    He states that the best way to achieve reunion is to declare all the
                    reconstruction legislation null and void.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Is Grant a Drunkard?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article attacking Grant Grant for his drinking habits.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.07.08.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>To the Democratic Electors of Franklin County</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamsher</ln>
                        <fn>B. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>B. Y. Hamsher, the chairman of the Democratic County Committee, calls
                    Franklin Democrats to meet to select delegates for the convention that will
                    choose candidates for local office. Representation is set as follows: Antrim 6;
                    North Ward 3; South Ward 4; Concord 3; Dry Run 3; Fayetteville 4; Greenvillage
                    3; Guilford 4; Hamilton 3; Letterkenny 4; Lurgan 3; Metal 3; Montgomery 3;
                    Orrstown 3; Peters 3; Quincy 5; Southampton 3; Sulphur Spring 3; St. Thomas 4;
                    Washington 5; Warren 3; Welsh Run 3; Total number of delegates 81.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Attempted Burglary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brandt</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dechert</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that an African American man attempted to enter a house
                    occupied by Christian Brandt. The editors attack "the black rascal" and opine
                    that "the same scoundrel, in all probability, attempted to enter the house of
                    Mrs. Dechert."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Gone to California</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bard</ln>
                        <fn>C. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. C. L. Bard of Chambersburg left for California where he will
                    permanently relocate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Federal Hill Seminary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foster</ln>
                        <fn>A. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. A. S. Foster arrived in Chambersburg to begin planning the opening of
                    a Ladies Seminary at the Federal Hill property he recently purchased. Parents
                    interested in enrolling their daughters are encouraged to meet with the
                    Reverend.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>County Commissioner</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keyser</ln>
                        <fn>John K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter suggesting Capt. John K. Keyser of Welsh Run for the office of
                    County Commissioner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrmann</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>Mollie V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barns</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>B. Harrmann and Miss Mollie V. Boyd, both of Chambersburg, were married on
                    July 5th by the Rev. S. Barns.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Savage</ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hatton</ln>
                        <fn>Lucy J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hassler</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William M. Savage of Chambersburg and Miss Lucy J. Hatton of Shippensburg
                    were married on June 11th by the Rev. J. Hassler.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holtry</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yos</ln>
                        <fn>Lavina C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beckley</ln>
                        <fn>George H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Solomon Holtry and Miss Lavina C. Yos, both of Franklin County, were
                    married on June 18th by the Rev. George H. Beckley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Umsted</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Umsted</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Catharine Umsted, wife of Samuel Umsted, died on June 28th in Green
                    township. She was 79 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.07.08.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
