<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1868/pa.fr.vs.1868.08.12">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/08/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1868-08-12">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="">12</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.08.12.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.08.12.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Skies are Bright</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The drift of the tide is still toward us.--Every day accessions are made to
                        the Democracy. The Radicals are discouraged, despondent, utterly
                        disheartened. From every portion of the country comes condemnation of the
                        nefarious measures of the Radical Congress. The burden of misrule has become
                        so heavy that the people everywhere are moving to shake it off. Here and
                        there, prominent Radical politicians are dropping out of their party ranks
                        and joining the forces of the united, energetic Democracy. The overwhelming
                        defeats which Radicalism has experienced during the last year have convinced
                        the most sagacious among them that the party which grew fat and strong on
                        the blood and tears of the nation is about to receive its final rout at the
                        ballot-box in November. Kentucky ratifies the nomination of Seymour and
                        Blair by the tremendous majority of eighty thousand. With a voice of such
                        terrible volume that its sound will penetrate into the remotest places of
                        the land, she has uttered her withering denunciation of the atrocious
                        measures that have well nigh destroyed the American Republic. All the States
                        in which elections have been held since the last Congress convened have
                        united in proclaiming their impatience at, and their disapproval of, the
                        manner in which Radicalism has ruled the nation.</p>
                    <p>It was not enough to break the faith so solemnly pledged in the darkest hour
                        of the war. It was not enough to refuse to fulfill the promises made when
                        our people were longing for peace and a restored Union. It was not enough to
                        decline to quench the fires of sectional hatred which burned with such fury
                        during the struggle. No. Radicalism was not content with the Union
                        preserved, slavery abolished and the national honor vindicated. It was not
                        satisfied to go back to the quiet and prosperity which always mark an era of
                        peace. Excitement was necessary to its being. The crusade against slavery
                        gave to it its strength, and it imagined that Americans had become so
                            <unclear>enamored</unclear> of the negro, that they would be unwilling
                        to rest until the ignorant African was accorded all the rights of
                        citizenship. Hence they deemed it necessary to blockade the way of return of
                        the Southern States to the Union until the desires of their hearts could be
                        gratified. This has been the fruitful <del/> of all our woes. Instead of
                        harmony and unity they have given us discord and disunion. They have not
                        hesitated to commit the most flagrant outrages in order to accomplish their
                        purpose. They have deliberately shut their eyes to the fact of a rapidly
                        increasing debt. They have witnessed the paralysis of trade in its every
                        department and have heard the mutterings of discontented, suffering
                        workingmen who have felt the blight that has fallen upon our industrial
                        interests. They have made no effort to find a remedy for all this. It
                        mattered not to them that business was stagnant so long as State Governments
                        were being ground to powder, and loyal negroes were shaping affairs in the
                        South so as to prolong the rule of the Radical party at Washington.</p>
                    <p>But the people are getting ready to hold a grand indignation meeting at the
                        polls in November. They have grown weary of uttering feeble protests and
                        seeing them totally disregarded. They have framed an indictment against the
                        Radical Congress, charging it with having committed the most atrocious
                        crimes, and they mean to press it and obtain a verdict of guilty. And after
                        the verdict will come the judgment.</p>
                    <p>Courage, Democrats. The skies are bright. Radicalism is waning. Sensible men
                        are disgusted with its extreme dogmas. White men feel the pride of their own
                        race aroused within their breasts. The negro exhibits no capacity to rule.
                        In the South, his elevation to office has encouraged him to commit the most
                        frightful excesses. We must meet the question fairly and squarely. <emph
                            rend="italic">White men must rule America.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses confidence in a Democratic triumph in the upcoming presidential
                    election. Notes how Kentucky voted overwhelmingly for Seymour. Talks about the
                    issues which Democrats hate about Republicans, especially black equality,
                    military governments, and other "excesses". Insists the voters see eye to eye
                    with Democrats and will vindicate them at the polls.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Our Candidates</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn>Francis M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn>J. McDowell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>Calvin M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zollinger</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAllen</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKinstry</ln>
                        <fn>William D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Auld</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper introduces the Democratic candidates for local office: Francis M.
                    Kimmell for Congress, J. McDowell Sharpe for Associate Law Judge, Calvin M.
                    Duncan for State Senator, Col. B. F. Winger for State Legislature, William S.
                    Stenger for District Attorney, Frederick Zollinger for Sheriff, William S.
                    McAllen for County Commissioner, Jacob H. Smith for Director of the Poor,
                    William D. McKinstry for Auditor, and Hugh Auld for County Surveyor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Radical Slaughter House</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper gloats over divisions within Franklin County's Republican Party
                    over nominations for candidates for local office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.08.12.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Damage Commissioners</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The war damage claims assessors met at both Greencastle and Chambersburg in
                    the past week. They plan to return and also visit the other towns in Franklin
                    County. They were forced to adjourn in part because of fraud surrounding the
                    process. Swindlers from other counties claiming to be working with the
                    commissioners sold Franklin residents fake damage claim forms. The real
                    commissioners will process claims for free.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Republican Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingerd</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knisely</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Adams</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>S. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Downey</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruthrauff</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mackey</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wiestling</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>J. Allison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Suesserott</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bradley</ln>
                        <fn>S. Armstrong</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>H. X.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McMullen</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walter</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kendig</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eby</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>S. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonebrake</ln>
                        <fn>E. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGowan</ln>
                        <fn>Theodore</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>Lyman S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn>E. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Farland</ln>
                        <fn>R. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plough</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patton</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruthrauff</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn>D. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Adams</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cessna</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Jere</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gehr</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper prints the proceedings of the Republican County Convention. The
                    following candidates were nominated: Josiah W. Fletcher for Sheriff; John H.
                    Walker for Assembly; E. K. Lehman for Commissioner; John Bowman for Director of
                    the Poor; Capt. Joseph Winger for Auditor; Emanuel Kuhn for Surveyor; Col. W. D.
                    Dixon for State Senate; Col. D. W. Rowe for Additional Law Judge; John Cessna
                    for Congress. Resolutions were passed upholding the Republican National Platform
                    and the nomination of Grant. They also issued a call for thanks and recognition
                    to the soldiers of the republic.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Daily Prayer Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A Union Prayer Meeting will be held daily in the offices of the Young Men's
                    Christian Association.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Forthcoming Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Preparations are underway for Franklin County's first fair. Buildings and
                    the "best ever graded" track in the area are under construction. "When we
                    consider the extent and wealth of Franklin county, in agriculture, manufactures,
                    and all that goes to make up a community of thrift and industry, we know we
                    shall have a grand representation of the industry of her citizens, when the time
                    arrives."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bard</ln>
                        <fn>Harvey Denton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bard</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bard</ln>
                        <fn>Jennetta</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Harvey Denton Bard, son of Robert and Jennetta Bard, died in Chambersburg
                    on August 2nd. He was 2 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coble</ln>
                        <fn>Leah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coble</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Leah Coble, daughter of George Coble, died in St. Thomas on August
                    5th. She was 20 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickley</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Bickley died in Chambersburg on August 3rd. He was 80 years old. "The
                    deceased had been regularly admitted into, and died in full connection with the
                    'River Brethren' denomination, a fact not known to, and hence not mentioned by
                    either of the speakers on the occasion of the memorial. He was a man of
                    excellent moral character and genuine religious experience, and no doubt died
                    'in the Lord.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.08.12.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote>Advertisements and agricultural advice appear on this page.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
