<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1868/pa.fr.vs.1868.04.29">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/01/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1868-04-29">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day norm="">29</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.04.29.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.04.29.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Pressure for Conviction</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The trial of the President will soon be ended. All the immense machinery of
                        the Radical party is now in motion to procure his conviction. Orators upon
                        the hustings, Editors in their papers, and carpet-baggers in the privacy of
                        Senatorial closets are bringing every possible argument and influence to
                        bear upon the minds of the judges who constitute the "High Court," so as to
                        insure a verdict of guilty. Radical Senators are now under the pressure of
                        partisan clamor. They are asked to disregard the law and testimony, if they
                        are not sufficient to convict, and to look to the effect which a verdict of
                        not guilty would have upon the interests of the Radical party. It is boldly
                        avowed that the deposition of Andrew Johnson is a political necessity.</p>
                    <p>We have frequently seen, in trials in the Court of Quarter Sessions of our
                        own county, the rights of the most notorious criminals, charged with the
                        most trivial offences, more carefully and jealously guarded, then have been
                        the rights of the Chief Executive of this great nation, in the impeachment
                        trial now nearly concluded. How extremely careful are our judges to so act
                        as that no suspicion of the slightest partiality, or prejudice shall attach
                        to their conduct. With what precision does the Court lay down the rules of
                        law which govern the facts of each particular case. How earnestly is the
                        jury instructed as to the presumption of innocence with which they must
                        credit the prisoner at the beginning of their deliberations! How widely is
                        the door thrown open for the admission of evidence as to the intent with
                        which the offence has been committed!--With what marked solemnity is the
                        jury instructed, that the testimony must satisfy them beyond a reasonable
                        doubt of the guilt of the prisoner! And, at the last, with what caution are
                        our jurors admonished to allow no person to speak to them upon the subject
                        of his guilt, or innocence, or upon any matter pertaining to the issue which
                        they have been sworn to try!</p>
                    <p>But how stands the case against the President? It is an unquestioned and
                        unquestionable fact, that a large number of the Senators, now sitting as the
                        judges of the President, entered upon this trial with their "minds made up."
                        The extreme Radicals of the Senate have never entertained, for a single
                        moment, a thought of voting for the acquittal of the President. They saw
                        then, and still see in him an obstacle in the way of their political
                        schemes. Some of them, doubtless, secretly advised the impeachment agitators
                        in the House to prefer their articles of impeachment, assuring them that the
                        movement would be successful in the Senate. And now, although they may be
                        convinced that the testimony does not warrant his conviction, yet, having
                        pledged themselves in advance to vote against him, they will do it
                        regardless of law, testimony, and their oaths. They imagine, and truly too,
                        that, in so doing, they will find favor in the eyes of their Radical
                        supporters, and thus secure their hold on power for a long time to come.</p>
                    <p>Thus having prejudged the case, their subsequent action is no matter of
                        surprise. They have not hesitated to disregard the decisions of the Chief
                        Justice as to the admissibility of testimony, when they thought that it
                        might bear in favor of the President. The rules of evidence were not binding
                        upon them, they being, in their own opinion, "a law unto themselves." Men
                        who have taught the "higher law" doctrine so long, could not be expected to
                        be slow about acting upon it themselves. They have, therefore, overruled Mr.
                        Chase whenever his opinions militated against their preconceived actions of
                        the President's guilt. What possibility was there of an impartial trial when
                        a large portion of the Court had predetermined the case?</p>
                    <p>No presumption of innocence weighed in the President's favor. To each man, a
                        presumption of innocence was an impossibility. In their speeches they had
                        denounced him, by their votes they had condemned him, and by their
                        resolution of disapproval of his action in regard to Stanton, they had
                        officially prejudged him. Their minds were surely not, at the commencement
                        of the trial, like a blank sheet of white paper.</p>
                    <p>The enemies of the President have charged all along that he attempted to
                        remove Stanton with intent to violate the Constitution. How important,
                        therefore, did the question of <emph rend="italic">the intent</emph> become!
                        This, his Counsel offered to show. They <sic>attemped</sic> to introduce the
                        testimony of his Cabinet Officers as to their advice to him in relation to
                        the constitutionality of the Tenure-of-Office-Bill. This the Senate refused
                        to hear.--They well knew that, if it were admitted, the fact would be
                        disclosed that Stanton had advised Mr. Johnson to veto that bill on the
                        ground of its unconstitutionality, and he would thus be placed before the
                        country in the position of seeking to protect himself, and retain his
                        office, under a law which he had himself declared was in violation of the
                        Constitution. And more, that he had agreed that the officers appointed by
                        Mr. Lincoln were not placed by that bill beyond the power of the President
                        to remove, even if it should be held to be constitutional. And thus he would
                        have been put before the country as seeking to hold his office under a law
                        which he admitted would not protect him in endeavoring to retain it. The
                        evidence as to the question of the intent was therefore excluded.</p>
                    <p>In our Courts, so careful are jurors not to convict unless satisfied beyond a
                        reasonable doubt, that they frequently conjure up an unreasonable doubt in
                        order to acquit, preferring to err upon the safe side, upon the principle
                        that it is better that ninety and nine guilty men should escape than that
                        one innocent man should suffer. There need be no apprehension that the
                        Senate <sic>of of</sic> the United States will hunt long for a reasonable,
                        or unreasonable doubt for the purpose of acquitting the President. In making
                        up their verdict, there is no danger of them examining the evidence
                        critically. <emph rend="italic">They have made up their minds to convict,
                            and they will convict.</emph> We are of this opinion, for the reason
                        that we give the Radicals in the Senate no credit for any honesty in this
                        matter whatever. The whole scheme was devised to further the interests of
                        the Radical party, and a failure to convict would be ruin to that
                        organization.</p>
                    <p>And yet, the outside Radicals are evidently alarmed. Since the testimony has
                        been concluded, intimations have been thrown out that certain Radical
                        Senators can not be counted as sure to vote for conviction.--Whereupon, the
                        "highways and by-ways" of New England have been lined with Yankees,
                        carpet-bags in hand, hurrying on to Washington to exert their influence upon
                        weak-kneed Senators. The nutmeg-grater manufactures, and wooden-clock
                        vendors, who have squatted in the Southern <sic>Sates</sic>, are rushing to
                        the Capital, claiming to represent the people of that section, and are loud
                        in their exclamations of horror at the hopeless condition of "the Union men
                        of the South" if the impeachment project should prove a failure. All these
                        fellows--many of whom are fit subjects for the penitentiary and the
                        gallows--are closeted with Radical Senators, urging the imperative necessity
                        of convicting the President.</p>
                    <p>What a farce, what a lamentable farce is the trial of a President by a Senate
                        composed of his political enemies! The power to try a President, charged
                        with high crimes and misdemeanors, ought to be lodged somewhere else than in
                        the Senate. If the Constitution is defective in any particular, it certainly
                        is in this. At a time when party feeling runs high, no man can expect
                        impartial justice to be meted out to him by his political foes. And so, too,
                        the ends of justice cannot be attained when the Senate is composed of the
                        political friends of the President. The bias in favor of the accused would
                        then be so strong that it would preclude the probability--perhaps, indeed,
                        the possibility--of a conviction.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gives a view of the impeachment trial of Johnson. Predicts the Senate will
                    convict because Radicals had gone into the trial determined to convict
                    regardless of evidence. Says Johnson has no chance of justice with Republicans
                    from all over the country descending on Washington to pressure for a guilty
                    verdict. Ends by saying impeachment should not be carried out in the Senate at
                    any time because partisan feelings prevent impartial justice.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>In the Hands of the Black Man</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Philadelphia <emph rend="italic">Inquirer</emph>--Radical, of
                        course--says "the returns from South Carolina justify the belief that the
                        new Constitution proposed in that State has been adopted, that officers have
                        been elected, and that the government will be in the hands of the
                        Republicans." It adds, jubilantly, that "<emph rend="italic">The future of
                            South Carolina is in the hands of the black man.</emph>"</p>
                    <p>The government of South Carolina "will be in the hands of the Republicans"
                        because South Carolina "is in the hands of the black man." The black man has
                        become a very important element in the Republican party. The <emph
                            rend="italic">Inquirer</emph> rejoices in it--the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Press</emph> rejoices in it--and hundreds of other Republican journals
                        rejoice in it. But what say the masses of the Republican party? Does it
                        gratify them that some hundreds of thousands of ignorant negroes have been
                        admitted to membership in their party? Does it gratify them that these
                        ignorant negroes will henceforth rule the destinies of States that have
                        heretofore been ruled by white men? Does it gratify them that these ignorant
                        negroes will be represented in Republican National Conventions? Does it
                        gratify them that there is a prospect of a negro being nominated some day
                        for President or Vice President?</p>
                    <p>Let no man laugh at the idea of a negro being nominated for President or Vice
                        President by the Republicans. To reach that point the Republicans have only
                        to advance as rapidly in the next four years as they have advanced in the
                        last four. And they <emph rend="italic">will</emph> advance if not checked
                        by a defeat at the coming Presidential election. The only safe course for
                        any member of the Republican party who does not wish to be called upon <emph
                            rend="italic">to vote for a negro</emph> four years hence is to vote
                        with the Democracy now.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Responds to Republican newspapers rejoicing in the adoption of a new
                    Constitution in South Carolina. Asks Republicans if they are now happy to share
                    their party and power with "ignorant negroes". Stirs up race hatred by
                    predicting the Republicans will nominate a black man for President in four years
                    unless they are defeated in the next election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>A Temperance Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cessna</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A temperance meeting will be held at the Court House in Bedford. John
                    Cessna, Chairman of the State Committee appointed to draft a Prohibitory Liquor
                    Law, will be present to explain why no such law was drafted. "We wonder whether
                    he will be candid enough to say that the reason why he did not draft the bill
                    and press its passage, was because he feared to put the Radical members of the
                    Legislature on record on that question."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.04.29.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Democratic Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The "Democratic and Conservative citizens of Chambersburg" will meet in the
                    Court House to nominate a ticket for borough offices.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Whitesy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The renowned magician will perform at Repository Hall. He will combine
                    magic displays and science experiments.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Frescoed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elmer</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Chambersburg Lodge of the International Order of Odd Fellows was
                    painted and frescoed. William Elmer of Carlisle did the work.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Presbyterian</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerr</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creigh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rex</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blair</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howland</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keel</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Austin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Presbytery of Carlisle met at Greencastle. Rev. Dr. Creigh, of
                    McConnellsburg, announced his intention to step down from his ministry. Churches
                    in Cumberland and Fulton counties dissolved their ties.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Town Officers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>L. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>S. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snesserott</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kreichbaum</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillespie</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wood</ln>
                        <fn>T. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kaufman</ln>
                        <fn>A. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houser</ln>
                        <fn>M. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Chambersburg's Republicans made the following nominations for town office:
                    Burgess, L. S. Clark; Town Council--South Ward, S. F. Greenawalt, Dr. J. L.
                    Snesserott, P. Kreichbaum; North Ward, F. S. Gillespie, T. B. Wood; Auditor, A.
                    D. Kaufman; High Constable, M. W. Houser.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Officers Elected</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powders</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kendig</ln>
                        <fn>D. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn>H. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Golden</ln>
                        <fn>S. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knisely</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Metcalfe</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waidlich</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McConnell</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frederick</ln>
                        <fn>A. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waidlich</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tabler</ln>
                        <fn>S. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilkins</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>A. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Atherton</ln>
                        <fn>I. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shatzer</ln>
                        <fn>John K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Selser</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spangler</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Silck</ln>
                        <fn>M. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pensinger</ln>
                        <fn>O. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whetstone</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Orrstown and Mercersburg Lodges of Odd Fellows elected officers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Franklin County Bible Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J. Agnew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>All the churches in town closed to attend the meeting of the Franklin
                    County Bible Society in the Presbyterian Church. The Rev. J. Agnew Crawford,
                    pastor, addressed the group. The paper complains that though the society is one
                    of the oldest of its kind in the state, its work has been rather slow and sparse
                    of late.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The first day of last week was taken up entirely with hearing motions of
                        counsel, and disposing of cases upon the argument list. On Tuesday morning
                        the jury trials began, and continued until Saturday afternoon. The following
                        cases were disposed as follows.</p>
                    <p>Frederick Foreman vs Isaac Cushwa. Capian and respondendum. The jury failing
                        to agree was discharged. Sharpe for Plff; Brewer and Kimmell for Deft.</p>
                    <p>Samuel Baker, use of John Miller, vs W. S. Everett Ex'r of David Everett
                        dec'd. Summons in assumpsit. Deft. confessed judgement for $300 and costs.
                        Brewer for plff.; Everett and Sharpe for Deft.</p>
                    <p>John W. Skinner vs Oliver S. Brown.--Summons for Covenant. Jury discharged,
                        being unable to agree. Cessna and Sharpe for plff; Kimmell and Stenger for
                        Deft.</p>
                    <p>C. H. McCormick &amp; Bro. vs Joseph Lochbaum. Amicable Action. Settled
                        by the parties. Sharpe and Kimmell for plff; McClure &amp; Stewart for
                        Deft.</p>
                    <p>John S. Wallach vs William M'Neal and Jacob Wentling. Summons in debt on
                        promissory note. Verdict for the Defendant. Kimmell and M'Clellan for plff;
                        Sharpe and Brewer for Defts.</p>
                    <p>John G. Miller's Executors vs James Null, Charles W. Stine, and Joseph
                        Sickell. Summons in Debt founded on three single Bills. judgement for Plff.
                        for $148.55. Sharpe and Stenger for Plffs; Kimmell and M'Gowan for Defts.</p>
                    <p>Same vs James Null. Summons in Debt. Plaintiffs suffer non-suit. Sharpe and
                        Stenger for Plffs; Kimmell and M'Gowan for Deft.</p>
                    <p>Joseph Snively vs The School Directors of Antrim Township. Summons in
                        assumpsit. Suit discontinued.</p>
                    <p>Jacob Shank vs Same. Summons in assumpsit. Suit discontinued.</p>
                    <p>Jacob Hargleroad vs Adam B. Wingerd &amp; Henry Sellers. Summons case in
                        deceit. Verdict for Defendants. Kimmell and Sharpe for Plff; Cessna and
                        Kennedy for the Defts.</p>
                    <p>Wm. P. Weagly, for the use of the minor children of C. T. Weagly deceased.
                        Summons case in assumpsit founded on promisory note. Judgement confessed for
                        $774.39. Kennedy and Sharpe for Plff; Kimmell and McClellan for Deft.</p>
                    <p>The Commonwealth of Pennsylvania for the use of Mary Eyster vs Chas. W.
                        Eyster with notice to Chamb'g Woolen Manufacturing Company Terre Tenants
                        Sci. Fa. Sur Recognizance recorded in Orphans Court Docket. The Woolen Co.,
                        confessed judgement for $2657.94. M'Clure &amp; Stewart for Plff; Sharpe
                        for Deft.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foreman</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cushwa</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Oliver S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cessna</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCormick</ln>
                        <fn>C. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lochbaum</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallach</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Neal</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wentling</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>John G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Null</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stise</ln>
                        <fn>Charles W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sickell</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Gowan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shank</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hagelroad</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingerd</ln>
                        <fn>Adam B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sellers</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weagly</ln>
                        <fn>William P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weagly</ln>
                        <fn>C. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClellan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>Charles W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Summary of proceedings of the county court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Col. McClure's Lecture</head>
                <origin>Lancaster Intelligencer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Col. A. K. McClure's Lecture on Mormonism and the Far West was enjoyed by a
                    large audience.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Bedford Inquirer</head>
                <origin>Bedford Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Stewart of Chambersburg is the elector for the Radical ticket from
                    this Congressional District. The article mocks Republican claims that he is one
                    of the best campaigners in the area: "No doubt of it whatever. He stumped
                    Franklin County last fall in favor of negro suffrage, the principal plank in the
                    Radical platform, and succeeded in giving the county to the Democrats by nearly
                    200 majority. We hope Mr. Stewart will give us some of his stumping up this
                    way."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deihl</ln>
                        <fn>Michael L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hummelbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>H. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKaby</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Michael L. Deihl and Miss Mary Grove, both of Chambersburg, were married on
                    April 23rd by H. Y. Hummelbaugh in the home of J. McKaby.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roseman</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hale</ln>
                        <fn>Barbara</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hummelbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>H. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Peter Roseman and Miss Barbara Hale, both of Chambersburg, were married on
                    April 23rd in the U. B. Parsonage by H. Y. Hummelbaugh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lebernight</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shatzer</ln>
                        <fn>Annie C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hummelbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>H. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel C. Lebernight and Miss Annie C. Shatzer were married on April 26th
                    by H. Y. Hummelbaugh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watson</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foust</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John W. Watson, of Cumberland County, and Miss Susan Foust of Roxbury,
                    Franklin County, were married on April 23rd at the Pleasant Retreat Parsonage by
                    the Rev. James M. Bishop.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.04.29.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote>Advertisements and agricultural advice appear on this page.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
