<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1868/pa.fr.vs.1868.06.10">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/04/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1868-06-10">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day norm="">10</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.06.10.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.06.10.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Grant and the Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The argument pressed upon the Radical party in favor of the nomination of
                        General Grant was, that he would carry with him all the soldiers. Upon this
                        supposition, all the eminent civilians of that organization were thrust
                        aside to give place to a military man who is, confessedly, possessed of no
                        brains. Life-long service in the party, the most exalted talents, and
                        untiring energy counted as nothing against this newly-fledged candidate for
                        popular favor.</p>
                    <p>The nomination of Grant exposes not only the weakness of the Radical party,
                        but it discloses, also, the fact that the Radical party is sensible of its
                        weakness. Had it been strong and conscious of its strength, it would never
                        have tinkered its platform as it has done, or tendered its nomination to
                        such a nincompoop as General Grant. Go where you will, you will hear
                        sensible Radicals saying, "I would much rather vote for Colfax for
                        President." Why? <emph rend="italic">Because Grant is notoriously unfit for
                            the position</emph>. The boy who displayed no preferences for
                        intellectual pursuits, but, according to his doting father's statement, was
                        only delighted with the amusements of the circus and was especially fond of
                        horse-flesh, could not be expected to ripen into a statesman. And nobody has
                        ever pretended that he has yet exhibited any qualifications for the highest
                        office in the gift of the American people. Expediency secured his
                        nomination--nothing else. The cry was, "the soldiers must be propitiated.
                        Hundreds of thousands of voters were in the army. We must throw out a bait
                        for them. That bait is General Grant.--When he is nominated and elected, we
                        can easily manipulate him. Washburne knows him like a book. He can easily
                        manage him. Grant talks about his respect for the will of the people.
                        Washburne will have him under his care. He can easily convince him that our
                        policy is the will of the people.--We would rather have some other able man,
                        but we are in a critical condition and we must endeavor to better it. Our
                        sickness is nigh unto death, and we must cast about for a physician and a
                        remedy. Grant is the highest military officer in the land. In honoring him,
                        we do honor to all our soldiery, living and dead." This was the argument
                        that nominated Grant. Alas for the Radical party, it will not answer their
                        purpose.--The soldiers of the country who love the Constitution will not
                        support Grant.--They know that he has identified himself with the party
                        whose leaders have openly avowed that they are "acting outside of the
                        Constitution." They know that, if elected, he will be only a tool in the
                        hands of unscrupulous Radical politicians. They know that the men who are
                        his masters and trainers, are seeking to elevate the negroes, who worked in
                        the trenches at the bidding of Rebels, into heroes more valiant and loyal
                        than white men who bared their breasts in behalf of the Union in every
                        bloody battle in the late war. They know that the leaders of the Radical
                        party have become fanatics--that they are controlled by one idea, and that
                        is the Equalization of the races.--Hence, the real soldiers of the country
                        are protesting against Grant's election. Not Butler, of course, who voted
                        fifty-seven times in the Charleston Convention in 1860 for Jeff. Davis for
                        President--not Logan who threatened to raise a small army in Egypt to cast
                        in their fortunes with the Rebel army--not Governor Brown of Georgia, who
                        took his State out of the Union and fought with all the fury of the most
                        virulent Rebel for the dissolution of the Union--not one of these is found
                        in opposition to General Grant. They are all loud-mouthed Radicals now,
                        because they imagine that the Radical party will be successful and that they
                        will rise to the surface of political affairs then. But the rank and file of
                        our gallant soldiery entertain no sympathy for this negro-loving clique.
                        They do not admire the dispositions to exalt colored troops above white
                        soldiers. They know that the labor of the great contest devolved upon the
                        whites. That they endured the hardships of the camps and were exposed to the
                        dangers of the battle field--that the bravery of white soldiers invariably
                        rolled back the tide of battle and caused victory to perch upon our banner.
                        They know, too, that out of morbid love for the negro, thousands and
                        thousands of their brave comrades were left to die in the prisons of the
                        South. Under such circumstances, appreciating, as they do, the utter
                        worthlessness of the negroes, and entertaining, as they do, an unconquerable
                        aversion to the idea of placing negroes upon an equality with the whites,
                        the white soldiers of the country, who have a proper appreciation of the
                        dignity of the race to which they belong, will go to the polls and cast
                        their votes against the man who represents the two ideas of negro suffrage
                        and military despotism.</p>
                    <p>Our volunteer soldiers are as bitterly opposed to the latter as to the
                        former. When they enlisted in the late war, it was for the avowed purpose of
                            <emph rend="italic">preserving the Union of the States</emph>. They
                        believed in a republican form of government. They desired to maintain the
                        honor of the National flag for the reason that it is the banner of the
                        Republic. And now, since the war closed in a complete triumph of the
                        National arms, they can not understand why certain States should be held
                        under military rule until they adopt constitutions framed to suit the
                        purposes of the Radical party. They are sharp enough to see that the negro,
                        and the hope of attaining power through the negro, lie at the bottom of the
                        whole policy.</p>
                    <p>What a terrible commentary it is upon our free institutions! We fought four
                        years to keep eleven States from going out of the Union, and triumphed, and
                        yet three years after the war closed those States are not represented in the
                        Congress of the United States. Why? Simply because the Radical party has
                        refused to admit them, and thus give peace to the country, until they allow
                        the negroes to frame their State Constitutions, and make their laws. The
                        soldiers of the country see this, and hence has sprung the call for the
                        Soldiers' and Sailors' National Convention which is to meet in New York on
                        the 4th day of July next. Meeting as they do upon the anniversary of that
                        glorious day on which was declared the independence of the American
                        Colonies, let them say to the world, in the spirit of freemen who "know
                        their rights and knowing dare maintain them," that all the States which have
                        hitherto formed this Union, "are, and of right ought to be, free and
                        independent States," and as such, entitled to representation in the National
                        Legislature. The people will respond nobly to this declaration, and the
                        election of a Democratic President will, at last, give peace and quiet to
                        the country.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Tries to blunt the potentially huge soldier vote for the Republicans after
                    the nomination of Grant. Plays on white soldiers' racist feelings, claims Grant
                    is only a tool of the Radicals. Expresses outrage that the Southern states are
                    still unrepresented in Congress because of Republican Reconstruction programs
                    and supposed favoritism towards blacks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Grant's Letter of Acceptance</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Grant has not only accepted the Radical nomination, but he has actually been
                        induced to unseal his lips, and to talk something else than horse. He has
                        written a letter accepting the position of standard bearer of the Radical
                        party. The Tribune gives it out as a remarkable indication of genius, that
                        he wrote it in ten minutes. This is thrown out for the purpose of combating
                        the universal idea that he was incapable of writing a letter at all.</p>
                    <p>There is nothing remarkable in the document itself. Any man of ordinary
                        talent could write such a letter in five minutes.--After speaking of the
                        proceedings of the Convention having been "marked with wisdom, moderation
                        and patriotism", he says, "<emph rend="italic">I endorse their
                        resolutions.</emph>" Now everybody who has read the resolutions knows, that
                        they are all as evasive as they could possibly be made. With the exception
                        of the two relating to the reconstruction policy and negro suffrage, they
                        are all empty claptrap. When General Grant, therefore, says that he endorses
                        the resolutions, we don't know what he means in regard to anything except
                        that he approves of the <emph rend="italic">military governments established
                            in the South, and favors negro suffrage in the South</emph>. At any
                        other time, we might feel inclined to ask him to commit himself further, but
                        we are satisfied that this is enough to damn him or any other man who is
                        looking to political preferment.</p>
                    <p>Grant would doubtless, have liked to evade these issues also, but the
                        resolutions are composed of too much milk and water to suit the Radicals as
                        they stand, and nothing but an unqualified endorsement of them would at all
                        satisfy them. Thus he was obliged to "face the music" and commit himself
                        just as far as the Radicals thought fit to commit themselves.</p>
                    <p>Of course, General Grant would approve of the military despotism established
                        in the South. He is military dictator of the ten States which are held under
                        his iron heel.--He can so handle his soldiery in that section as to give the
                        negroes the absolute control of the State Governments. Those negroes, if
                        properly manipulated by the Radical tools, can be made to run the machinery
                        of the State Governments in the interest of General Grant. Why should he not
                        favor such a condition of affairs? But think of it, fellow citizens. Shall
                        one man, in a republic, be permitted, by virtue of the position which he
                        holds as General of our armies, <emph rend="italic">to elect himself
                            President of the United States?</emph> The American people entertain a
                        deadly hostility to anything which smacks of despotism. Let them arise in
                        their might, therefore, and arrest this movement which may make one man
                            <emph rend="italic">Dictator of the American Union.</emph></p>
                    <p>General Grant says, "I endorse their resolutions." He therefore subscribes to
                        the second resolution which says: "The guarantee by Congress of equal
                        suffrage to all loyal men at the South was demanded by every consideration
                        of the public safety, of gratitude, and of justice, and must be maintained;
                        while the question of suffrage in all the loyal States properly belongs to
                        the people of these States." In other words, suffrage for the negroes of the
                        South <emph rend="italic">at once</emph>--suffrage for the negroes of the
                            North<emph rend="italic">whenever it becomes expedient.</emph> Let every
                        man who is in favor of the negroes voting in the South vote for General
                        Grant, but let him shut his mouth and not pretend that he is opposed to
                        negroes voting in the North. It is impossible to make the distinction and
                        preserve a reputation for common sense.</p>
                    <p>It is a noticeable feature that in constructing the Chicago platform, its
                        framers meant to frame it and did frame it so as to conform to the idea
                        expressed by Grant in his letter, that "in times like the present, it is
                        impossible, or at least eminently improper to lay down a policy to be
                        adhered to right or wrong, through an administration of four years," and yet
                        so that a departure from the policy seemingly announced, or the adoption of
                        an antagonistic policy, may be construed to be perfectly consistent with the
                        wording of the resolutions.</p>
                    <p>Thus the latter part of the resolution given above, says "the question of
                        suffrage in all the loyal States properly belongs to the people of these
                        States"? "Properly" belongs. Why did the Convention not say <emph
                            rend="italic">constitutionally</emph> belongs? Who is to judge of the
                        time when it shall cease to "properly" belong to the people of the loyal
                        States? Undoubtedly this is meant to give Congress an opportunity whenever
                        it deems it expedient, to declare that equal suffrage must be maintained in
                        all the states. The framers thought of this adroit scheme to deceive the
                        masses.</p>
                    <p>Nothing is more certain than that Congress has no power over this question of
                        suffrage. The right to regulate it belonged to the States before the
                        Constitution was formed. In framing it, the States granted certain rights to
                        the General Government, and all others were reserved. The reader of the
                        Constitution of the United States will search in vain for any grant there of
                        the right to regulate the suffrage. The right, therefore, unmistakably
                        remains vested in the States. But the leaders of this party which acts
                        "outside of the Constitution" would not commit themselves squarely to this
                        doctrine as a <emph rend="italic">constitutional</emph> doctrine.--They know
                        well that it is a right which belongs to every state, and that it would have
                        been simply ridiculous to pretend that Congress could constitutionally
                        exercise the right to regulate suffrage in one state, and admit that it had
                        no right to regulate it in another. To this doctrine General Grant stands
                        committed. And should he be elected President, which may Heaven in its
                        kindness prevent, the time will then have come when, in the
                        <sic>judgment</sic> of Congress the question of suffrage will have ceased to
                        "properly belong to the people of these States" of the North. <emph
                            rend="italic">The negro will then become a voter by Act of Congress, and
                            General Grant will say, "I endorse the law."</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes Grant's acceptance speech as a lead-in to more criticism of the
                    Republican platform. Particularly condemns the Republican reconstruction and
                    black suffrage planks. Insists only states have a right to regulate voting
                    rights, and a Grant victory will mean the end of state liberty.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Letter No. 4 From Robert Criswell</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Honey Locust Farm, L. I., Near Brooklyn, May 30th, 1868.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Gentlemen:</emph>--I closed my last letter to you, of
                        March 11th, thus: "The President will not be found guilty, the Radical party
                        is DEAD; so that they can not elect their candidate in November next." Two
                        of the prophecies are verified; the last will be also. But what desperate
                        efforts the party makes to live a little longer, how it clings to
                        impeachment and how it anathematizes those Senators who would not perjure
                        themselves for party purposes. Those persons who condemn them on this
                        account, of course would not hesitate to commit perjury themselves to gain
                        their ends. They talk a great deal about bribery and corruption; but, such
                        men as Fessenden and Trumbull could not be bribed for a million each. "Chief
                        DEVIL Chase," as they call him, does not escape their <emph rend="italic"
                            >foul abuse</emph> either; because he would not perjure himself and
                        lower his high office and show partiality for the Radicals. I suppose they
                        put the great <emph rend="italic">concussion</emph>, Gen. Butler, foremost
                        on the smelling committee, on the principle that "it takes a thief to catch
                        a thief." As he is so <emph rend="italic">fond of the</emph> BAG a great
                        many think he could be bribed to almost any thing for from $500 to $5,000.
                        This is the man, when Governor of New Orleans, Admiral Faragut found, in
                            <sic>connexion</sic> with his brother, loading vessels to run the
                        blockade. This is the man that voted fifty-seven times to nominate his
                        friend, Jeff. Davis at the Charleston Convention in 1860, for the
                        Presidency; and, when he could not succeed, he afterwards helped to nominate
                        Jeff's right hand man, Breckinridge, at Baltimore. And, yet, this is the man
                        they put on the track of honorable men--men of principle. The memory of
                        these men will live to be held in grateful remembrance; while that of their
                        accusers will be lost, or held in contempt. This is the great hero of Fort
                        Fisher NOT CONCUSSED; but, I must not give him the credit of giving himself
                        this title, for he wants part of the inscription on his monument to read
                        thus: "He saved the lives of his soldiers at Fort Fisher." It would be well
                        if some of the successful Generals of the war could say, "I gained a battle
                        with great economy in killed and wounded, according to the results
                        attained:" (this is what General Scott called the economy of life, by means
                        of head work): instead of which it should read thus: "I gained a battle with
                            <emph rend="italic">little</emph> results by <emph rend="italic"
                            >recklessly sacrificing thousands of my brave soldiers</emph>." A
                        General should be court martialed, instead of honored, for gaining a battle
                        in this way. This applies to some of Grant's battles in the Wilderness and
                        around Richmond.</p>
                    <p>There are many widows and mourners, many empty sleeves, and many crutches in
                        use in the land, on account of some of these battles. Soldiers were forced
                        to meet certain death with as little feeling as if they were cattle or dogs,
                        (of course he would have more feeling for his own horse or dog). We don't
                        hear of his visiting the hospitals; or, of his being very careful for the
                        comfort of his soldiers, either sick or well; however, his battles will be
                        all ably criticised by military men before next November. Grant gained most
                        of his reputation at Fort Donelson, Vicksburg, Chattanooga, &amp;c. The
                        reason he did not add to his reputation in his last battles was on account
                        of the terrible straits of the rebels, and the half-starved condition they
                        were in, and because his army was three times as large as theirs: and yet he
                        kept telegraphing almost constantly to his <emph rend="italic">great
                        friend</emph> Stanton for more men for the front--more men for the
                        slaughter. Like Oliver Twist he called for "more, more." As he lost five men
                        in these battles to the rebels one, the North would have become depopulated
                        of its able-bodied men if the war had continued much longer.</p>
                    <p>Stanton got the credit of doing good service during the war; but, he has now
                        the credit of being the meanest Cabinet officer since the Government was
                        founded; any high-toned, honorable man would have resigned when there was a
                        coolness between himself and the President; but he would not, even when
                        asked by the President to do so, and when turned out he forced himself in
                        again by means of the Radicals.--Suppose a man visits your family, and by
                        your coolness you tell him his presence is not agreeable, but he will not
                        take the hint, but, comes again; you then tell him his company is not
                        wanted, but, he still persists in coming; what is then left for you to do,
                        but to <emph rend="italic">set him up in the boot business</emph>. And yet,
                        the Pennsylvania Legislature stultifies itself by recommending Stanton for
                        the Treasury in Wade's Cabinet, thus endorsing his meanness. O, wise
                        Legislators, did you not like thousands of others, "count your chickens
                        before they were hatched" that time?</p>
                    <p>In hunting up evidence to impeach the President they forgot, or overlooked,
                        one thing on which they could have found him guilty without much trouble,
                        viz: his getting drunk. This was the greatest high crime and misdemeanor he
                        committed; but, I believe the reason they did not have another article
                        relating to this conduct, was because so many of the impeachers and members
                        of the high court were guilty of the same thing, and they did not want to
                        condemn themselves.</p>
                    <p>If your party thinks of having A.J. for your candidate you must get him to
                        sign the pledge before you nominate him; and it would be well for the
                        Radicals to get Grant to do the same also, for if he is so <emph
                            rend="italic">very temperate</emph>, as Senator Wilson says he is, he
                        will make no sacrifice in doing so.--Wilson should get him to join his
                        society. President Johnson says, "Grant is small in mind as well as body." I
                        have seen the General in New York several times. His looks are not much in
                        his favor, they kindle no enthusiasm, he has a kind of a dull, foxy look. If
                        the Radicals would take him around through the country, and get him to make
                        speeches, the other party would gain thousands of votes by it. If he is
                        elected, I supposed he will be called the dummy President, for he could not
                        even make a respectable speech on receiving a Foreign Minister. Some will
                        say that he can make a speech if he wishes to do so. I am afraid not, I
                        think he is like an old empty bottle corked up.</p>
                    <p>I hope your party will nominate Chase, and it would be unnecessary to ask him
                        to sign the pledge. He is a Saul among the Philistines, as he stands head
                        and shoulders above any other man you can find in statesmanship,
                        &amp;c., &amp;c. We Conservatives would join you in electing him by
                        a large majority over Grant. A man looking for office, even if it is only a
                            <emph rend="italic">one-horse office</emph>, is afraid to leave his
                        party, but, as I do not want any office from that of road-master up to the
                        Presidency; and lest my friends should, peradventure, at some time in the
                        future, pester me half to death to accept a nomination for the latter, like
                        the illustrious Horatio Seymour, I decline in advance. I will vote for the
                        best man, and the one which I think will do the best for the country; as I
                        think it is high time we had a change from the present radical policy. It is
                        now costing us about $100,000,000 a year for a standing army in the South,
                        and $30,000,000 more for the Freedmen's Bureau.--These millions should be
                        going to pay off the national debt instead; and, if they had been going in
                        this way since the war closed, as they should, the debt would have been
                        reduced at least $500,000,000 more than it has been. John Q. Adams carried
                        on the Government for about $15,000,000 per annum; but, now under Radical
                        rule in time of peace, it costs about $500,000,000.</p>
                    <p>If the Radicals are continued in power, we may soon expect universal suffrage
                        and equality of races, in the North as well as in the South, and the time no
                        doubt will soon come when we would have to take our places in the jury box
                        surrounded by perhaps half a dozen culled pussens; to be thus situated in a
                        hot August court would not be very agreeable. But, perhaps the Radicals
                        intend to put a very high tax on perfumes, and by thus creating an
                        extraordinary demand for them, to pay off the national debt in this way: who
                        knows?</p>
                    <p>It seems to be the will of Providence that there should be always, in this
                        republic, two parties, in order for one to watch and be a check on the
                        other; one to be in power awhile and then the other. But since the beginning
                        of the Government neither party has been in power longer than two terms,
                        eight years at a time, and there have only been four Presidents elected for
                        two terms, viz: Washington, Jefferson, Jackson and Lincoln. So that the
                        Radicals' time is out on the 4th of March next. The hand-writing on the wall
                        is against them, and they will be weighed in the balance next November and
                        found wanting. For if they succeed in remaining in power another term,
                        making twelve years for them, <emph rend="italic">good bye Republic!</emph>
                        They would form a consolidated despotism. But if the people are alive to
                        their dangers and interests, they will not succeed. As a lawyer once said to
                        the judge, may it please the court I have nineteen reasons for the
                        non-appearance of my client this morning; the first is, that <emph
                            rend="italic">he is dead</emph>, the second--"hold," shouted the judge,
                        "one such reason as that is sufficient." So there are a great many reasons
                        why Ulysses will not be elected; the first is, "it can't be did" because
                        why? he can't get votes enough. Peradventure, I may give you the other
                        reasons at another time. In the mean time, I remain yours, as usual.<lb/>
                        R.C.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Another opinion article contributed by Robert Criswell, who claims to be a
                    Conservative Republican from New York. Criticises and ridicules men like Butler,
                    Grant, and Stanton as typical Radicals. Predicts the defeat of the Radicals in
                    November and gives many reasons why the current Congress should be voted out of
                    office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.06.10.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Democratic County Committee Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Lellan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Democratic County Executive Committee will meet in the offices of
                    M'Lellan and Kimmell to plan the County Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Soldiers' Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plale</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf>Capt. 21st Pa. Cav.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brand</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf>Capt. Co. K, 107th P. V. V.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf>77th P. V. V.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Senseny</ln>
                        <fn>B. Rush</fn>
                        <sf>A. A. Surg., USA</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peiffer</ln>
                        <fn>John F.</fn>
                        <sf>Sergt. 11th Pa. Cav.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hyssong</ln>
                        <fn>D. H.</fn>
                        <sf>Sergt. 21st Pa. Cav.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michaels</ln>
                        <fn>V.</fn>
                        <sf>Lieut. Co. K, 107th Pa. Vol.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunovan</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detrich</ln>
                        <fn>J. L. P.</fn>
                        <sf>Private, USA</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Varner</ln>
                        <fn>Johnson</fn>
                        <sf>77th Pa. Vol.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eaker</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Lieut. 77th Pa. Vol.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunavon</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf>Sergt. 77th Pa. Vol.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Speer</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf>Private USA</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Householder</ln>
                        <fn>Fred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harmon</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf>11th Pa. Cav.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harmon</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf>O. Sergt. 201st Pa. Vol.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hasson</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Humelaine</ln>
                        <fn>Manaris</fn>
                        <sf>Sergt. 108th Pa. Vol.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henneberger</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>11th Pa. Cav.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Emmet</fn>
                        <sf>79th Pa. Vol.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Widely</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cummins</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf>Lieut. Bat. A. Pa. Res.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morehead</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf>11th Pa. Cav.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Givens</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf>Corp. 103d Pa. Vol.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowers</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf>107th Pa. Vol.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Washabaugh</ln>
                        <fn>E. D.</fn>
                        <sf>16th Pa. Cav.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Danner</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf>2nd Pa. Vol.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An appeal for conservative soldiers to meet with the intention of forming a
                    Soldiers' Club. "Come and join us in an effort to put men in power who will
                    honestly carry out the object for which we took the field, and maintain the
                    government of the United States as it was made by the patriots of the
                    Revolution, a White Man's Government."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Attention Soldiers and Sailors of Franklin County!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt. Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nimmon</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burk</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhea</ln>
                        <fn>A. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Noah M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>French</ln>
                        <fn>T. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reymer</ln>
                        <fn>M. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barkley</ln>
                        <fn>R. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Serg.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Serg.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kent</ln>
                        <fn>Alfred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Serg.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn>Matthew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Cor.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>A. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Cor.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kegerris</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Embich</ln>
                        <fn>Milton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mort</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crouse</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunkle</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wineman</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Owings</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woods</ln>
                        <fn>T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mort</ln>
                        <fn>A. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Call for conservative soldiers to meet at the Court House to select
                    delegates to attend the National Convention of Conservative Soldiers and
                    Sailors.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Proceedings of Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A special session of the Court of Common Pleas for the trial of civil causes
                        began on Monday, the 1st inst., and continued until Thursday evening, His
                        Honor Judge Rowe being on the bench. The following cases were disposed of:</p>
                    <p>David Kuhn vs. Samuel Stumbaugh and Wife. Summons to recover a tract of land
                        lying in Antrim Township, containing two acres. Verdict for the Plff. for
                        the land and $58.50 damages for the detention. Clarke for Plff; Sharpe for
                        Defts.</p>
                    <p>Hazelett, Middleton &amp; Co., vs. The Chambersburg Woolen Manufacturing
                        Company owner, and John Middleton contractor. Sci. Fa. Sur Mechanic's Lien.
                        Verdict for Plff, for $665.65. Stenger for Plff; Sharpe and Brewer for
                        Defts.</p>
                    <p>Amos Slighter vs. School Directors of Southampton Township. Summons case to
                        recover $100 local bounty. Verdict for Defts. Sharpe and McGowan for Plff;
                        Kimmell and Orr for Defts.</p>
                    <p>Elizabeth Mellinger vs. Dr. Henry Langheine. Summons case on promissory note.
                        Deft. confessed judgement for $134.90 and costs. McGowan for Plff; Stenger
                        for Deft.</p>
                    <p>The Chambersburg Manufacturing and Building Association vs. William A.
                        Fulmer, owner. Sci. Fa. Sur Mechanic's Lien. Verdict for Plff. for $313.21.
                        Stewart for Plff; Sharpe and Brewer for Deft.</p>
                    <p>James F. Byers, by his next friend, vs. Peter Cook. Summons in Debt. Deft.
                        confessed judgement for $565. Stumbaugh &amp; Gehr for Plff; Everett
                        &amp; Cook for Deft.</p>
                    <p>Jacob Nusbaum vs. John E. Jones Administrator of William Everett. Amicable
                        action. Verdict for Plff for $120. Kimmell for Plff; Everett for Deft.</p>
                    <p>Argument list Obed Gsell &amp; wife, Plffs in Error vs. John Ealey and
                        Solomon Ealey partners. Dets. in Error. Certiorari to S. M. Armstrong Esq.
                        Judgement reversed at the costs of Deft. in Error for want of jurisdiction
                        in Justice. Stumbaugh &amp; Gehr for Plffs; Reilly for Defts.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Middleton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Slighter</ln>
                        <fn>Amos</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGowan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mellinger</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Langheine</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulmer</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>James F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gehr</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nusbaum</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>John E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gsell</ln>
                        <fn>Obed</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ealey</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ealey</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Summary of Court proceedings.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Ex-President Buchanan</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The bells in Chambersburg's Court House, Market House, and churches tolled
                    during the hours of Buchanan's funeral in Lancaster.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Young Men's Christian Association</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Saturday night last, a union meeting of all the religious denominations of
                        this Borough, was held in the Lutheran Church in behalf of the Young Men's
                        Christian Association. All the ministers of the town were present and took
                        part in the exercises. Very interesting and instructive addresses were
                        delivered by J.M. McClure, Esq., Rev. Mr. Wills of Macon, Georgia, Rev. Mr.
                        Barnes of the Methodist Church and Rev. Mr. Magee of the Lutheran Church, of
                        this place. We are informed that subscriptions to the amount of two hundred
                        and fifty dollars were procured.</p>
                    <p>This association was organized in this place some months ago and now numbers
                        sixty-one members. It has procured a room and has it partly furnished <emph
                            rend="italic">on credit</emph>. It aims to fit up this room more
                        comfortably, and also to procure religious newspapers and religious,
                        political, scientific, and literary periodicals, for the entertainment and
                        instruction of its members. It also contemplates buying books for the same
                        purpose.</p>
                    <p>This is certainly a most laudable undertaking. No better way could be devised
                        for giving opportunities to the young men of our town to improve their
                        leisure hours. Some of them are sadly deficient in the knowledge which is
                        requisite to make them useful members of society. Others never look into a
                        monthly journal, and some are never even known to read a weekly newspaper.
                        They have given themselves up to idleness, smoking, gaming and drinking. To
                        all such, this association throws out an earnest invitation. It asks them to
                        leave these pleasures which will prove injurious to them in every way, and
                        give their leisure time to reading and study. Life will have greater and
                        purer attractions for them then. They will feel that they are living for
                        higher and nobler purposes.</p>
                    <p>It seems to us that the association would do better for the present by
                            <sic>contining</sic> its efforts to the procurement of newspapers and
                        periodicals only. They can thus give reading every week to a large number of
                        persons for a small amount of money. After the association gets a firm
                        foothold, it can obtain books. We trust that our citizens will all look with
                        favor upon the efforts of these young men to establish this association.
                        Parents ought to feel the warmest solicitude for their children. They should
                        naturally be gratified to know that their sons are innocently and profitably
                        engaged during their absence from their homes, and in no way can they be
                        better assured of this than by bringing them within the pale of this
                        organization. Let it be furnished with all the means necessary to its
                        successful operation.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wills</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Magee</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Records a meeting of Church figures working to get the local YMCA a reading
                    room and reading materials. Endorses the move and says such an endeavor will get
                    youth out of idleness. Urges the YMCA to obtain a lot more newspapers and
                    periodicals.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Grant Ratification Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our Radical friends held a pow-wow in the Court House on Tuesday evening of
                        last week to get up a little enthusiasm over the nomination of Grant and
                        Colfax. The Court-room was about two thirds filled, at least one third of
                        the assemblage being composed of small boys and about one-sixth being
                        Democrats. As we cast our eyes over the small audience, the pleasing fact
                        occurred to us that Radicalism is waning, fast waning in this old Radical
                        borough. It was the poorest Radical meeting we have ever seen here. And not
                        only the numbers.--There was no <emph rend="italic">enthusiasm</emph>. The
                        best strains of Radical eloquence--the wildest flights of Stewart's
                        imagination--the most <unclear>incetious</unclear> questions in McCanley's
                        catechism, and the boldest feats of Stumbaugh's valor, all failed to excite
                        the patriotic feelings of the audience. The meeting was dull, flat, stale
                        and unprofitable. It was uninteresting in itself and it failed to create any
                        interest in the candidates of the Radical party. Its speakers rehashed the
                        old charges against the Democratic party. It is evident that they intend to
                        carry on this campaign upon the same material that they have been using for
                        the last eight years, with the exception that they are coming out
                        flat-footed for the negro. Mr. McCauley, in the course of his speech, stated
                        that there was no use in attempting to disguise the fact that the Radical
                        party is fighting to give the ballot to the negro everywhere. He said that
                        the issue may as well be made now as at any other time. This is right.--It
                        is but just that the people should know what they are to vote for. Mr.
                        McCauley removed the screen behind which the Radical party has been hiding.
                        He tore off the mask which has concealed its real features. We admire his
                        candor, and with the issue thus made, we expect to beat his party this fall,
                        in this county, at least three hundred votes.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Stewart, usually so extreme, distinguished in this County as the most
                        Radical of Radicals, seems to have surrendered his position to Mr. McCauley.
                        He twisted and wriggled so as to keep himself, if possible, upon the Chicago
                        platform. He tried to persuade the people that there is no nigger in the
                            <emph rend="italic">Northern</emph> wood-pile, whilst everybody knows
                        that he is in favor of negro suffrage in the North as well as the South. We
                        are for the utmost latitude of speech.--We are opposed to the gag and the
                        muzzle. Let the Radical speakers be permitted to talk their sentiments.</p>
                    <p>The last speaker was Col. F. S. Stumbaugh. Being a military man himself, he
                        was of course expected to "do" the military part of the entertainment. And
                        he did it with a vengeance. We admire the Colonel's devotion to his party.
                        He certainly exhibits an uncommon degree of unselfishness in his admiration
                        of General Grant. The General has unquestionably failed "to do the clean
                        thing" towards the Colonel, for although, according to the speaker's
                        account, the Colonel performed an extraordinary feat of valor at Shiloh and
                        that, too, under the express command of the General, yet the General has
                        failed, up to the present moment, to issue any public order, or even to
                        write a private letter, in recognition of the Colonel's distinguished
                        services. And, what is still more ungrateful, the pages of history are
                        entirely silent as to his exploits. The Colonel is, therefore, to be excused
                        for "blowing his own trumpet," especially when the narration of his gallant
                        deeds was intended to incite his political friends to action in behalf of
                        his ungrateful chief. For the purpose of placing the Colonel right upon the
                        record, and showing our readers what an Ajax we have among us, we give the
                        Colonel's peroration.</p>
                    <p>Said he, "Fellow citizens, when General Grant said to me at Shiloh, 'Colonel,
                        take that battery,' I went and <emph rend="italic">tuck</emph> it, and so
                        when he says to you, forward along the whole line, move forward in obedience
                        to his command." Had our quondam magisterial friend been present, we fear he
                        would have exclaimed in accents denoting overpowering astonishment and awe,
                        O Shi-Shi-Shi-loh!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports on a Republican rally at the Courthouse. Notes with glee the lack
                    of enthusiasm among the crowd, seeing it as a sign of waning Radical influence.
                    Also expresses dismay that one of the speakers, Colonel Stumbaugh, was ignored
                    by Grant even though the former praised him immensely.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Damage Commissioners</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wood</ln>
                        <fn>T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ely</ln>
                        <fn>W. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woods</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Governor appointed T. Wood, W. J. Ely, and W. S. Woods commissioners to
                    investigate the war damage claims of border county residents.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Books</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alleman</ln>
                        <fn>Leonard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Leonard Alleman, a citizen of Antrim, is selling subscriptions to
                    Alexander Stephen's book on the "Causes, Conduct, and Results of the Late War."
                    He also has a book entitled "The Blue Coats" available.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Scotland and Mont Alto Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Citizens will meet at the Mount Alto works to discuss construction of a
                    railroad from Scotland to Waynesboro. The paper criticizes Chambersburg
                    residents for not taking a lively enough interest in funding railroad ventures.
                    The editors endorse making Chambersburg the junction with the Cumberland Valley
                    road.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn>John D. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flack</ln>
                        <fn>Nettie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Magee</ln>
                        <fn>Irving</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John D. T. McGrath and Miss Nettie M. Flack, both of Chambersburg, were
                    married on April 29th by the Rev. Irving Magee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sierer</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fortney</ln>
                        <fn>Annie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houck</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Edward Sierer and Miss Annie M. Fortney, both of Shippensburg, were married
                    at the home of the bride's parents on Railroad Street, Shippensburg on June 4th.
                    Rev. W. A. Houck presided.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fenstamacher</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shilleto</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houck</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Cyrus Fenstamacher and Rebecca E. Shilleto, both of Shippensburg, were
                    married on June 4th at the residence of the bride's mother. The Rev. W. A. Houck
                    presided.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creamer</ln>
                        <fn>Anna M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hassler</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel K. Lehman and Miss Anna M. Creamer, both from near Strasburg, were
                    married in Shippensburg on June 2nd by the Rev. J. Hassler.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCardell</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>Eleanor A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. Keller</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles McCardell of Williamsport, Md., and Miss Eleanor A. Skinner, of St.
                    Thomas, were married on June 1st by the Rev. J. Keller Miller in his residence.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gift</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Gift died on June 3rd in Guilford. He was 76 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ortt</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Ortt died on June 1st in Marion. He was 70 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.06.10.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote>Advertisements and agricultural advice appear on this page.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
