<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1868/pa.fr.vs.1868.12.09">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/15/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1868-12-09">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day norm="">9</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.12.09.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.12.09.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Present Session of Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Last Monday the second session of the Fortieth Congress began. What a
                        blessing it would be if every member had gone to Washington imbued with an
                        earnest desire to legislate for the best interests of the country. Can this
                        be expected of the men who compose this body? We fear not.--After indulging
                        in the wildest fanaticism last winter, that fanaticism culminating in the
                        attempted impeachment of the President, it is idle to expect that its
                        proceedings during the coming session will be characterized by any
                        conservatism whatever. The majority of its members are the champions of the
                        so-called progressive ideas enunciated by Wendell Phillips and Thaddeus
                        Stevens. Their chief aim is to enfranchise every colored man in the Union. A
                        few desire this because of an honest belief in the capacity of the negro to
                        assist in carrying on our government. Some regard him as fully qualified to
                        govern. But the great body of these men hold to this doctrine, and advocate
                        it, in order to strengthen the hands of the Radical party and insure a
                        permanent retention of power. Take away from them the prospect of securing
                        the negro vote, and they would become the bitter enemies of the proposition
                        to put the ballot into the hands of the black man. Their recent experience
                        in manipulating this class of voters in the Southern States has confirmed
                        their views as to the element of Radical strength. They will, therefore,
                        favor an extension of negro suffrage in the Northern States. We anticipate a
                        lively agitation of this subject during the coming session. Emboldened by
                        the result of the Presidential election, they will push this doctrine to the
                        extreme. An amendment to the Constitution will be introduced into Congress
                        and submitted to the States, by which the negro will be clothed with the
                        right of suffrage in every State of the Union. The States through their
                        Legislatures will be called upon to adopt the amendment. And inasmuch as the
                        Radicals have a majority in three-fourths of the State Legislatures, the
                        danger is that three-fourths of the States will respond affirmatively to the
                        call. It will not surprise us in the least, if, before General Grant is
                        inaugurated President of the United States, the right of suffrage be
                        guaranteed to the negro in every State, by an amendment to the Constitution.</p>
                    <p>Can any one conceive of a greater outrage than this would be? Take for
                        instance the Legislature of Pennsylvania. A majority of its members are
                        Radicals. These men were elected without any reference to this question of
                        negro suffrage. It was not involved in the canvass. Many of them made
                        distinct denials of any disposition to favor this doctrine. The constituents
                        of some privately demanded positive assurance that they would oppose any
                        such proposition.--Many votes were cast by Conservative Republicans with
                        fear and trembling in regard to this issue. With what horror will such
                            <unclear>people</unclear> now regard the notion of these very men if
                        they allow themselves to be governed by the <del/> of party leaders and
                        betray the confidence reposed in them by their constituents! How can any one
                        regard such neglect on the part of the Legislature as just to the people of
                        this Commonwealth who have never had an opportunity to give expression to
                        their opinions and wishes upon the question? Are we to have negro suffrage
                        forced upon us in spite of our hostility to it? Is there to be an
                        opportunity afforded to the people to vote upon this question? We very much
                        fear that Congress intends to constitute itself a Directory to regulate the
                        domestic affairs of each State.</p>
                    <p>And if this conduct would be unfair in relation to Pennsylvania, how much
                        more unfair would it be toward a State whose people have rejected negro
                        suffrage at the polls? Take Ohio as an instance, where the proposition to
                        strike the word "white" out of the Constitution was defeated by fifty
                        thousand majority. It is true the Ohio Legislature is Democratic and need
                        not be expected to ratify the proposed amendment. But if three-fourths of
                        the State Legislatures ratify the amendment, it will be law in Ohio as well
                        as in the other States. As well blot out all State lines and State
                        institutions and convert "the United States" into "the American Government"
                        at once. if the expressed wishes of a people of a Sovereign State can be so
                        utterly disregarded and trampled upon. The same is true of Kansas and
                        Minnesota except that in those States the Legislatures have Radical
                        majorities and will ratify the amendment in defiance of the will of the
                        people. Can such things be? Eight years ago the proposition would have
                        astounded the whole nation.--But now, alas! the people have become so
                        accustomed to the innovations of the Federal Government that they have
                        ceased to wonder at anything, and the great danger is that they have become
                        willing to surrender their most sacred rights and dearest liberties to the
                        custody of a set of fanatics, who, by their "progressive" ideas, are driving
                        the country to ruin as rapidly as it can possibly be done.</p>
                    <p>But the legislation of the present Congress is not only to be feared in
                        relation to negro-suffrage. The danger is that it will undertake to keep
                        three States of the South out of the Union for an indefinite period. In his
                        annual report, Grant says that the troops are still needed in the South. For
                        what? If civil governments are to be restored in Virginia, Mississippi and
                        Texas, what necessity will there be to have those States overrun with
                        military forces? It looks very much as though they are to be yet held as
                        conquered territories, thereby affording a rich opportunity for experimental
                        legislation on the part of Congress.</p>
                    <p>But even in those States of the South which have been restored nominally to
                        their rights under the constitution, the military power still rules. The
                        peace which Grant longed and prayed for is theirs, and that peace is the
                        silence of the laws amid the clangor of arms. An effort will be made by some
                        of the Radical members of Congress to prevent all Democrats elected from the
                        South, from taking their seats. Whilst the negro from Louisiana will be
                        received with open arms, the Democratic whites will be turned back or turned
                        out by the fanaticism which rules the hour. On such evil times have we
                        fallen, that the men in high places have no regard for the expression of the
                        people's will if it be in opposition to their own political theories.</p>
                    <p>Elections held in accordance with all the forms of law are treated as
                        nullities unless they subserve the purposes of the Radical party. The
                        election of Grant has put deliverance from all these evils beyond the reach
                        of the American people for four years to come. That result furnishes the
                        Radicals all the encouragement they desire to proceed with their
                        "progressive" ideas. They claim that the people have endorsed their action
                        thus far, and that this is an assurance that they are willing to trust them
                        further, and are desirous that they should go ahead in the way in which they
                        have begun. We are prepared, therefore, for all sorts of wild, Radical
                        propositions. It would not surprise us much to see a bill introduced into
                        Congress to abolish the Constitution of the United States. It is practically
                        superseded at any rate, and it might as well be put out of the road
                        altogether.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Comments on the opening of the 40th Congress, gives much commentary on a
                    possible amendment which would enfranchise all blacks across the country. Says
                    the amendment would be a clear violation of States rights, especially for states
                    which have already voted against such measures. Also fears Radicals will keep
                    Democratic Southerners out of Congress and retain some Southern States under
                    military rule indefinitely.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Secretary McCulloch's Report</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports the contents of Secretary of the Treasury McCulloch's
                    report in which he calls for an end to paper money as legal tender, discusses
                    the lack of internal revenue, and remarks upon rising public debt. The Spirit's
                    editors criticize the government on the last two points.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>School Houses for Night Meetings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit criticizes a resolution passed by the Chambersburg Teachers
                    Institute discouraging the practice of allowing night meetings to take place in
                    school houses.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Co-operation &amp;c. Continued</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>CHAMBERSBURG, PA., Nov. 28, 1868.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Messrs. Editors:</emph>--In my last communication, I
                        spoke of co-operation among the laboring classes, as one of the great needs,
                        if not the greatest, of the present time. I think that there can scarcely be
                        two opinions among the thinking portion of the community on this point.
                        Surely there are none to be found foolish enough to prefer giving 18 cents
                        per pound for Sugar, when they can buy it for 16 cents per pound. Surely
                        there are none blinded enough to their own dearest interests to prefer
                        giving 25 cents per pound for Cheese, when that same Cheese can be bought at
                        wholesale for 14 or 16 cents per pound. We must bear in mind that it is not
                        the government alone that taxes us. Storekeepers tax us also. And not alone
                        the Storekeepers, but the man who rents him the store comes in for his share
                        of these profits. If store rents are high, the storekeeper must necessarily
                        saddle the burden upon the backs of his customers, or else he himself must
                        suffer. So he wisely charges the consumer an extra dime, and "saves his own
                        bacon." We do not blame the storekeeper for looking out for number one--it
                        is his interest to do so but it is not the interest of the consumer to allow
                        himself to be fooled in this way. We therefore say that Co-operation would
                        meliorate the condition of those who have to toil for their daily bread. It
                        has benefited already tens of thousands in the Old World, and it will yet
                        benefit as great a number here.</p>
                    <p>We were speaking of large profits. Let us examine the subject further; for it
                        needs probing. Some years ago we, (the writer of this, and his family)
                        happened to live in a Town where large profits were the order of the day. It
                        was not unlike Chambersburg in this respect. The people grumbled a good deal
                        about the high prices of almost everything they had to buy, but they saw no
                        remedy but to pay the storekeeper whatever he thought fit to charge. However
                        there is an old saying, "that every dog has its day," and the saying proved
                        true in this instance,--at least so far as the storekeeper's dog was
                        concerned.</p>
                    <p>A number of workingmen, myself among the number, resolved to see how
                        co-operation would work. We thought it advisable not to rent a storehouse at
                        the start, but to try the experiment on a small scale; so that if it should
                        prove unprofitable after a short trial, we could then back out without much
                        loss. We commenced by subscribing (cash down) for about 20 pounds of Coffee.
                        We sent the order to New York. The goods came in due season, and everyone
                        was satisfied with his investment. We saved from 50 to 75 cents per pound on
                        our Tea. Flushed with victory, we sent again, with an augmented list of
                        subscribers. I think we sent orders for Tea and Coffee exclusively, three
                        times, before we branched out into Sugar, Molasses, Currants, Raisins, Rice,
                        Soap, Lard, Butter, Kerosene Oil, Flour, &amp;c., &amp;c. We now
                        hired a storehouse to transact our business in. So long as we dealt in Tea
                        and Coffee only, these articles came to my house for distribution, but now
                        that our business was getting so large, we must needs have a store room. Our
                        Storekeeping was conducted on one of the most economical plans. Those who
                        transacted the business of the association charged nothing for their labor.
                        The principal part of that labor for the first three months fell to my own
                        lot. After we had got fairly under way, to use a nautical phrase, the labor
                        was shared pretty evenly among the various members of the association. We
                        adopted a constitution, with rules and by laws, so that we could conduct our
                        business systematically, and in order. The officers consisted of President,
                        Vice President, Secretary, and Treasurer, and their time of service was
                        three months. As I said before, all labor was performed by these gentlemen
                        without any <sic>renumeration</sic> save and except that derived by having
                        cheaper and better goods. Besides, it was a labor of love. Indeed it proved
                        something more than a labor of love by bringing together people in all the
                        various stages of ignorance--it proved a school of instruction also. Like
                        other institutions, we gave it a name. We called it the "Working Men's Union
                        and Provident Society." It was a distributive society properly speaking, for
                        there was nothing sold to those who were not members of the association. Our
                        goods came about once or twice a week, and we met about two evenings per
                        week to distribute such goods as had been ordered and paid for at a previous
                        meeting.</p>
                    <p>We had Molasses by the Hogshead, or Puncheon. Sugar by the Hogshead, or
                        Barrel. Lard and Oil by the barrel. Dried Hams Ditto--In fact our
                        association became so large as to become rather unwieldy on account of our
                        setting apart only one or two evenings per week for the distribution of
                        goods.</p>
                    <p>Storekeepers about this time became dark visaged. Their ready money custom
                        had fled. They depended on their "Book Custom" almost entirely. Book
                        Customers looked grave and sad when they discovered that they were
                        hopelessly wedded to high prices. Some of them made desperate efforts to
                        balance their accounts in order to join the Workingmen's Union.</p>
                    <p>Storekeepers will sometimes tell you, and truly, that they "do not make much
                        money by their business." We do not wonder. They are not economical enough.
                        They have too many Clerks and Hangers on around them for the small amount of
                        business they transact, to leave any marginal profits for themselves.
                        Besides, they are getting altogether too numerous. Storekeeping more than
                        keeps pace with the growth of the population. It steals a march upon the
                        population in every new Settlement, because, as the Storekeeper supposes, it
                        furnishes an easy life; besides being far more profitable than dirty toil.
                        We do not wonder at them seeking to escape the burden that long hours of
                        labor impose; but we do wonder as we said before, that workingmen should be
                        so blind to their own interests as to pay them such outrageous prices for
                        their goods; when, by co-operation, they can purchase all they require at
                        whole-sale prices, and save from 20 to 25 per cent on their investments. But
                        Grocers do not stand alone in this matter. Dry Goods men, Butchers, Bakers,
                        &amp;c. &amp;c., are no less guilty. Each one tries to live and save
                        money by his business, no matter how little besides. If one price will not
                        pay, another must. He has no conscientious scruples about his charges. He
                        does not keep store on religious principles. He is guided in his dealings
                        with the world, by lower considerations than a love of right. He says to
                        himself, "<emph rend="italic">I must</emph> have a living anyhow, no matter
                        what stands in the way. I should much prefer doing what is right, but it is
                        such a hard road to travel." In view of these facts, what course should the
                        hard workingmen take? Should they continue to throw away one fifth, or one
                        fourth of their hard earnings in order to keep a large "Storekeeping
                        Aristocracy, and then cry out excessive Government <sic>Tacation</sic> is
                        ruining us;" or should they try the co-operative principle? A great deal
                        more might be said on a subject that ought to engage more of the attention
                        of laboring men, but space will not allow.</p>
                    <p>Pardon me, Messrs. Editors, for saying that I quite overlooked in my list of
                        Business occupations that ought to be conducted on the co-operative
                        plan--the Printing and Publishing Business. But perhaps that is too much to
                        expect yet. I fear that your occupation is too high up the ladder for us
                        workingmen to reach. Let us therefore try our green hands on something
                        nearer ground.<lb/> WORKINGMAN.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial from an anonymous workingman extolling the advantages of a
                    cooperative system in place of merchants. Explains how his own experiences with
                    cooperatives have proved successful, decreasing the prices workers have to pay
                    for goods. Urges all workers and even storekeepers to give it a try.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.12.09.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Medical Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The physicians of Franklin County will hold a meeting for the purposes of
                    establishing a medical society.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Washington Hotel</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lantz</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rupert</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Lantz of Quincy is leasing the Washington Hotel from Mr. Rupert.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Died at the Asylum</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jarret</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Jarret died at the Harrisburg Lunatic Asylum. The Franklin County
                    resident had displayed severe signs of mental illness and was sent to the
                    asylum. His symptoms did not improve before death. He had been a member of the
                    Columbus Lodge of Odd Fellows.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Lecture Before the Young Men's Christian Association</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. H. H. Williams will give the first lecture in a series hosted by
                    the Chambersburg Y.M.C.A. He will speak about "Trifles: their littleness and
                    their greatness." Admission is free since the young men of the association wish
                    to reach as wide an audience as possible.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Serits</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Christian Serits of Maryland and Miss Mary Lehman, daughter of John Lehman
                    of Green Township, were married on November 26th by the Rev. Dr. Schneck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>Amelia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Abraham S. Lehman and Miss Amelia Stouffer, daughter of Christian Stouffer,
                    were married near Stoufferstown on December 3rd by the Rev. Dr. Schneck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Singer</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>Susan C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>W. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Singer and Miss Susan C. Young, both of Antrim, were married on
                    November 24th by the Rev. W. F. Eyster.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hockensmith</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Emma</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Hockensmith of Mount Hope and Miss Emma Miller of Shady Grove were
                    married on November 24th by the Rev. W. S. Eyster.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Stouffer died in Chambersburg on November 27th. He was 63 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pugh</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Belle</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pugh</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pugh</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Belle Pugh, infant daughter of John and Mary E. Pugh, died in
                    Chambersburg on November 30th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snausst</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Snausst died at the residence of Henry Greenawalt near Chambersburg on
                    November 17th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Gowan</ln>
                        <fn>Stuart</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Stuart M'Gowan died at his home in Fayetteville on November 30th. He was 19
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles Byers died near Greencatle on December 1st. He was 76 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.12.09.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote>Advertisements and agricultural advice appear on this page.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
