<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1868/pa.fr.vs.1868.01.15">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/2/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1868-01-15">
            <year>1868</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day norm="">15</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.01.15.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.01.15.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Bolters Brought to Terms</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The state legislature met recently. A radical majority controls the
                    lawmaking body. Nine "incorruptible patriots" bolted the chamber upon nomination
                    of Elisha B. Davis of Philadelphia as speaker, but later swung into line and
                    supported his nomination.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Geary Snubbed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The State Convention of the "Boys in Blue" overwhelmingly elected Andrew
                    Curtin for Vice President over Geary. "Like republics, soldiers are ungrateful.
                    The valiant warrior has been set aside, snubbed by his gallant comrades, to give
                    place to a man who never smelled powder upon the battlefield."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Losses of the Border Counties</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We call the attention of our representative in the Legislature to the article
                        which we publish to-day, taken from the <emph rend="italic">Valley
                        Sentinel</emph>, entitled "The War--What the Government should do--What the
                        People Want." We know that he has the disposition to do everything in his
                        power towards procuring some remuneration for the losses which the people of
                        the border counties have sustained by the war. We call upon him <emph
                            rend="italic">to agitate the subject.</emph> There is a duty incumbent
                        upon the representatives of the border counties, and that is, to keep before
                        the people of the Commonwealth, until their mouths are stopped by payment,
                        the fact that this section of the State was overrun, and its inhabitants
                        plundered for the sole reason that it was most accessible to the enemy. The
                        raids that were made upon us, the invasion, and the terrible conflagration
                        which laid Chambersburg in ashes, have impoverished many of our citizens,
                        and imposed loads of debt upon others, under which they will stagger into
                        their graves. Our misfortunes and calamity were the salvation of the rest of
                        the State. Surely, there ought to be a general disposition to appropriate
                        money to relieve us of our burdens.</p>
                    <p>And, notwithstanding our misfortunes and losses, our people paid their share
                        of taxation without a murmur. They contributed their fall quotas of men to
                        the ranks of the Army. They were "loyal" to the government of the United
                        States. They did not falter in their allegiance to the State. The State owed
                        them protection. It did not, or could not extend it. Ought it not, now, out
                        of the common treasury, eagerly pay the losses sustained by reason of its
                        failure, whether owing to neglect or inability, to afford us the requisite
                        protection? this subject demands <emph rend="italic">agitation</emph>,
                        AGITATION, <emph rend="italic">AGITATION!</emph> Let our representative put
                        the ball in motion.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The newspaper demands that the legislative representative of Franklin
                    County get the legislature to issue damage payments for those who suffered
                    losses from Confederate raids. The editors call on the people of the county to
                    agitate for the same. They Repeatedly stress the loyalty and sacrifice of the
                    people of the county and that reparation payments are not only fair but just.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Radical Desperation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Radicals are becoming more desperate every day. They seem determined to
                        strain the patience of the people to its utmost limit. Wherever they
                        discover a weak place in their infamous reconstruction bills, they set
                        themselves to work to bolster it up. Their whole reconstruction scheme has
                        in this way become a patched up job. They are now bent on taking the power
                        of removal of the district commanders from the President and lodging it in
                        General Grant. The Constitution makes the President, by virtue of his
                        office, commander-in-chief of the Army and Navy of the United States, but a
                        bill has just been introduced into the House which, if passed, will rob him
                        of all authority over his subordinates and leave them free to overturn
                        republican governments as fast as they please and erect military despotisms
                        upon their ruins.</p>
                    <p>And this bill not only seeks to rob the President of this his rightful power,
                        but in one sentence, it wipes out all the civil governments now existing in
                        the late rebel states. It refuses to recognize them as valid and legal and
                        seeks not only to usurp the province of the Judiciary, but to subordinate
                        that co-ordinate branch of the government to it, by declaring <emph
                            rend="italic">that the Judiciary shall not recognize them as
                        legal.</emph>--Could fanaticism go further? yes, strange as it may seem it
                        can.</p>
                    <p>Cases are now pending before the Supreme Court of the United States which
                        involve the constitutionality of the reconstruction laws passed by Congress.
                        Rumors are afloat that that high body is likely to frustrate the whole
                        infamous scheme of the Radicals by declaring their reconstruction laws
                        unconstitutional. So nervous and fearful have they become under the
                        operation of these reports, that a telegram to a Radical paper informs us,
                        that the Judiciary Committee is preparing a bill which provides that <emph
                            rend="italic">two thirds of all the Judges of the Supreme Court shall be
                            necessary to render a decision, instead of a bare majority as the law,
                            as it now stands, requires.</emph> These men are bold and bad enough to
                        upset our whole system of government in order to accomplish their nefarious
                        objects which the people have branded with the seal of their condemnation.
                        To them, written constitutions solemnly enacted laws, time honored customs
                        and republican institutions are nothing. They respect not the rights of the
                        coordinate departments of our government.--They would infringe upon the
                        authority of the Executive and the Judiciary. Nay more, they are confessedly
                            <emph rend="italic">"acting outside of the Constitution.</emph></p>
                    <p>Forbearance will ere long cease to be a virtue, and these revolutionary
                        designs, if persisted in, must be met by a majestic uprising of the people
                        in behalf of popular government.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Outlines and denounces the recent move by Radicals to transfer the power to
                    remove district commanders from President Johnson to General Grant. The paper
                    also abhors a bill prepared by the Judiciary Committee to require a 2/3 majority
                    by the Supreme Court to pass decisions on reconstruction bills. The editor
                    considers both these moves infamous and desperate schemes to keep Radicals in
                    power by usurping proper government protocol.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Governor's Message</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper comments on the governor's "exceptional" confession of radical
                    corruption in the state legislature.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The War--What the Government Should Do--What the People Want</head>
                <origin>Valley Sentinel</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article calling for the entire nation to share in the expense of paying for
                    losses sustained in the war in both the North and the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.01.15.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Festival</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Fayetteville Union Sabbath School will hold a festival in
                    Fayetteville's Town Hall to raise money for a library.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Hotel Sold</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rupert</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sellers</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Rupert of Fayetteville purchased Chambersburg's Washington House
                    from Jacob Sellers for $12,000.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Lectures by Dr. Talmage</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Rev. T. DeWitt Talmage of Philadelphia lectured in Chambersburg's
                    Repository Hall to raise money to benefit the Baptist Church. His lecture on
                    "the Grumbler" proved "a delicious treat." Attendance was so low, however, that
                    no money was raised.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Graeffenberg Springs Sold</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Secrist</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Secrist of Quincy purchased the popular "watering place" ten miles
                    east of Chambersburg from Daniel Miller. Graeffenberg Springs is "a very
                    desirable place of resort during the Summer months. The wild romantic scenery,
                    its proximity to the mountains, the excellent properties of its water, the
                    beautiful stream winding its way through the mountain filled with speckled
                    trout--all these would certainly attract numerous visitors if they could be
                    assured that they would be made comfortable when in-doors."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Horse Thieves About</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berger</ln>
                        <fn>Lawrence</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A horse was stolen from the stable of Lawrence Berger of Hamilton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Chambersburg Manufacturing and Building Association</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shepler</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>W. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ebersole</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>Calvin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carlisle</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Chambersburg Manufacturing and Building Association, which employs
                    "about fifteen hands" and plans to increase that number to "twenty or twenty
                    five," elected officers at its most recent meeting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Lectures for the Poor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>S. H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Magee</ln>
                        <fn>Irving</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. S. H. C. Smith delivered a lecture at the Court House to raise money
                    to benefit the poor. "The lecturer dwelt upon the duties of the community in the
                    way of general benevolence, referring eloquently and pointedly to duties very
                    frequently overlooked." The Chambersburg Coronet Band also performed. $63.56 was
                    raised and entrusted to treasurer Jacob S. Nixon to apply to "the wants of the
                    poor and suffering." Irving Magee will give the next lecture in the series.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rebuck</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eckenrode</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hassler</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John A. Rebuck and Miss Mary Jane Eckenrode, both of Shippensburg, were
                    married on January 1st by the Rev. J. Hassler.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snoer</ln>
                        <fn>Aaron F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoemaker</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Halfleigh</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Aaron F. Snoer and Miss Sarah Shoemaker, both of Lurgan, were married on
                    December 26th by the Rev. J. Halfleigh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wetzel</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stonehouse</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Wetzel, of Franklin County, and Miss Elizabeth Baylor of Adams, were
                    married in Waynesboro on December 26th by the Rev. H. Stonehouse.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hocklander</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finaprock</ln>
                        <fn>Isabella</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>W. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Hocklander and Mrs. Isabella Finaprock, both of Antrim, were married
                    on January 2nd by the Rev. W. F. Eyster.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhodes</ln>
                        <fn>J. Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holliday</ln>
                        <fn>Mellie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holliday</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. Frank Rhodes and Miss Mellie J. Holliday, daughter of Samuel Holliday,
                    were married on January 8th by the Rev. William A. West. All hail from Dry Run.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mills</ln>
                        <fn>John M. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John M. C. Mills, aged 51 years, died in Shady Grove on January 1st.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Grove died at age 45 on December 27th in Shady Grove.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Overcash</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Philip Overcash died in his residence near the Canebrake School House on
                    January 6th. He was 84 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weaver</ln>
                        <fn>William W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William W. Weaver of Chambersburg died on Januray 6th at age 22.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jane Palmer died in Chambersburg on January 9th. She was 54 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhoades</ln>
                        <fn>John N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhoades</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhoades</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John N. Rhoades, son of Benjamin and Mary Rhoades, died in Chambersburg on
                    December 31st. He was 13 years old. "Why weep for our little Johnny, that he's
                    laid in the tomb?/Why weep that he's gone to a happier land?/Tis true that the
                    flower was cut ere its bloom,/But still it will grow in a pleasanter strand./Why
                    weep for our friend in the blue vault of heaven/On snowy white wings ever more
                    will he move,/The giver has given but what he had given,/He's nestled him to his
                    bosom in love."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1868.01.15.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote>Agricultural advice and advertisements appear on this page.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
