<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1869/va.au.vv.1869.12.02">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/03/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-12-02">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day norm="">2</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1869.12.02.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1869.12.02.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>"Skies Bright and Brightening"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We cordially congratulate our readers upon the success of Col. Baldwin and
                        Gen. Wickham in negotiating a contract with wealthy New York capitalists
                        which will ensure the speedy completion of the Chesapeake &amp; Ohio
                        R.R. from Richmond to the Ohio River. We hail this auspicious result as the
                        harbinger of innumerable benefits not only to the counties along the line of
                        the improvement, but to the whole State--indeed we may say to the Nation. It
                        is, in fact, a work of national importance. It will bind together the East
                        and the west by bonds of iron. It will stimulate agriculture, manufactures
                        and commerce, not only in the country through which it runs, but will
                        develop an inter-State trade, the magnitude of which can hardly be imagined.
                        When the road reaches the Ohio, it will form connections with roads
                        diverging, in all directions, Northwest, West, and Southwest, and we hazard
                        little in predicting, that, at no distant day, it will be the acknowledged
                        continuation of the great Pacific railway from San Francisco to Richmond and
                        Norfolk. Any one who will take a map of the United States and apply one end
                        of a string to San Francisco, and stretch the other to Norfolk, will find
                        that these two points are in almost the same latitude, and that the
                        Chesapeake &amp; Ohio Railroad is nearly on a direct line between the
                        two points, and therefore destined to be the eastern link in this wonderful
                        chain of inter-Oceanic communication. Thus the best port on the Pacific
                        coast will be brought into intimate relations with the best port on the
                        Atlantic. In a few years the trade between the East and West, in obedience
                        to laws which are as immutable and as irresistible in the commercial world,
                        as gravity is in the material universe, will settle down, in regular
                        currents, along the line of this national thoroughfare. And, strange as it
                        may now seem, the day is not far distant, when we shall see cars whistling
                        through our town, freighted with silks, spices and teas, from China, Japan,
                        and the East Indies, destined for European ports!</p>
                    <p> But we regard this great enterprise as the pioneer of a still greater. The
                        Chesapeake &amp; Ohio railroad is the <emph rend="italic">avant
                        coureur</emph> of the James River &amp; Ohio Canal. The railroad will
                        open the way for the canal. It will develop the intermediate country, and
                        exhibit to the great West, the necessity for and advantages of this
                        admirable central route through Virginia. </p>
                    <p> Passing, as the Railway will, parallel to, and not distant from the route of
                        the proposed canal, all who travel over the road, will be enabled to see the
                        inexhaustible supplies of salt, coal, iron and timber which are now locked
                        up in the fortresses of the Virginia mountains. The Farmers of the West,
                        too, will have an opportunity of seeing with their own eyes, the advantages,
                        on the score of cheapness, exemption from snow and ice, and diminution of
                        distance, which will be secured by the construction of the J.R.&amp;R.
                        Canal. Ohio, and all the States along the Ohio and Mississippi, want cheap
                        and convenient access to the salt wells and coal fields, and timber forests
                        of the Kanawha, and the iron deposits of the Alleghenies. The grain and the
                        pork and the beef of the West, will want a speedy and cheap means of
                        transportation, at all seasons of the year, to the markets and deep water of
                        the East. These considerations will prompt the people of the West, through
                        their representatives in Congress, to demand, that this great <emph
                            rend="italic">national work,</emph> shall be made by <emph rend="italic"
                            >national means</emph> and <emph rend="italic">national
                        authority.</emph></p>
                    <p>Already the prospect of the construction of the Chesapeake &amp; O.R.R.
                        is exerting a sensible influence on the value of property along the line.
                        Within a few months, enterprising men from Pennsylvania, New York and
                        Maryland have brought valuable iron properties and vigorous operations. The
                        large furnace in Buffalo Gap, under the management of Mr. L. Sibert, will be
                        in operation in a few months. A company from New York have bought the
                        McBride survey, a few miles west of the gap, and we understand will, during
                        the next season, erect the largest furnace in Virginia. Messrs. Furmstone,
                        Clymer, &amp; Co., have bought four iron properties between Goshen and
                        Covington, at a cost of $84,000, and are now negotiating for a fifth at
                        $30,000. And we hear of other parties, who have it in contemplation to
                        purchase the old Bath Iron Works, two miles from Goshen, with a view to
                        large operations. In a few years the line of the Railway from Buffalo Gap to
                        Covington will be illuminated by the blaze of an unbroken line of furnaces.</p>
                    <p>Rolling Mills and foundries, and manufactories of every kind will follow, as
                        certainly as day follows night, and our whole country will flourish like, "a
                        green Bay tree."</p>
                    <p> Nor will the other portions of our country be deprived of their just share
                        of this general and newly created prosperity. The thousands upon thousands
                        of operators, in the employment of these manufacturers, must be fed and
                        clothed. The country around them is too sterile to produce grain, grass, or
                        meats. They must look to the fertile fields of the Valley for food. We
                        venture to say, that during the next summer, the course of trade at the
                        Valley will be reversed. Instead of seeking its outlet <emph rend="italic"
                            >eastward,</emph> it will go <emph rend="italic">westward.</emph> The
                        vast number of hands, who will be employed in the construction of the road,
                        must draw their supplies from Augusta. Staunton will be the base of supply
                        for every thing that is needed. All our surplus flour, corn, oats, rye,
                        bacon, beef, whiskey and hay will find a ready market. And besides these
                        articles, groceries, clothes, shoes, mules, horses, cart, &amp;c., will
                        be needed in large quantities. </p>
                    <p> Nor will this <del/> temporary demand. The hands engaged in the construction
                        of the road will furnish it, for the first two or three years, and after
                        that, there will be a greater, and ever increasing demand to supply the
                        operators in the iron works and other manufactories.</p>
                    <p>And here, let us pause for a moment to reflect what the White Sulpher will be
                        when these lines of railway are finished to the Western world! It is
                        extravagant to suppose that in ten years from this time, instead of one
                        thousand visitors, there will be twenty thousand! All these people must be
                        fed, and Augusta must feed them!</p>
                    <p>Verily! A new Era is dawning upon us! The people of the North, in a spirit of
                        wrath, sought to crush us by destroying our labor system. But a benign
                        Providence has ordained, that what was intended to destroy us, should give
                        us new life and power; and by a just retribution, the blow that was intended
                        to crush us, has fallen on their heads.</p>
                    <p>New fields for enterprise have been opened. Our mountains have been made to
                        unlock the doors of their mineral treasures--Rival manufactories of all
                        kinds are about to spring up, which, by their superior advantage, are
                        destined to compete successfully, with those of the North, and transfer the
                        seat of power and wealth to the South! In a few years it will be found, that
                        New England cannot compete successfully, with the Southern States in the
                        manufacture of cotton and wool, and earthen wares; and, at no distant day,
                        Virginia and Western Virginia are destined to take the lead of Pennsylvania,
                        New York and New Jersey, in the iron business, and in all branches of
                        industry dependent on it.</p>
                    <p>If such be the fact, we shall have no tears to shed, but our hearts will
                        overflow with gratitude to that great Being, who, in mercy, brings
                        prosperity and happiness and power, out of the very measures intended for
                        our overthrow.</p>
                    <p>We therefore offer to our readers, our hearty congratulations, on the
                        brilliant prospects ahead of us. Let us be of good cheer! Let no one be
                        despondent! Let every one bear patiently the evils that press upon him, in
                        the assurance that they are but temporary! Day is breaking! The dawn already
                        tinges the East with a roseate hue! The skies are bright and
                    brightening!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Looking forward to a prosperous future, the author outlines the various
                    manufactories and railroads in the planning stages. Factories, canals, roads,
                    and various business endeavors all are described, and Augusta stands to profit
                    in the area of supplying the thousands of workers that will flood the area. The
                    author concludes that industry will be the base for the reemergence of the South
                    as the most powerful region in the country. Ironically, it is was the same
                    industrial might that crushed the South's bid for independence that will now
                    work in its favor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Prompt Action</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Gen. Echols received notice to go to New York on December 1st to formulate
                    an action plan for the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad. New York capitalists
                    purchased control of the road and now wish to proceed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1869.12.02.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Staunton Academy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>Charles E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Staunton academy is flourishing with 63 enrolled students. Mr. Charles
                    E. Young and Mr. William Waddell are responsible for the revival of the school.
                    "The Principal, Mr. Young, is a gentleman of high character and peculiar
                    qualifications as an instructor, uniting to thorough acquaintance with the
                    branches which he teaches, great urbanity of manner, and firmness of discipline.
                    Mr. Young was educated at the University, where he attained distinction,
                    especially as a mathematician. Mr. Waddell, the associate of Mr. Young, is well
                    known to the citizens of his native town, as a gentleman of exemplary character,
                    and peculiar aptitude and qualifications for the vocation which he has chosen.
                    We congratulate those gentlemen on the success which they have achieved in their
                    honorable field of labor; and in the name of the community, we thank them for
                    affording to the rising generation, the opportunity of acquiring instruction in
                    the branches of knowledge which are necessary for usefulness in life."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>Mitchell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hultz</ln>
                        <fn>Ellen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryland</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mitchell Gordon of Bath county and Miss Ellen Hultz of Augusta, were
                    married near Deerfield, Augusta Co. by the Rev. J. W. Ryland on November 11th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Merritt</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Green</ln>
                        <fn>Sue E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Green</ln>
                        <fn>James S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marvin</ln>
                        <fn>E. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Bishop</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John W. Merritt of Staunton and Miss Sue E. Green of St. Louis were married
                    at the residence of the bride's father, James S. Green, on November 4th by the
                    Rev. Bishop E. M. Marvin.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamner</ln>
                        <fn>Jesse B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jesse B. Hamner died near Horeb Church, Augusta County, on November 21st.
                    He was 71 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1869.12.02.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
