<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1869/va.au.vv.1869.09.09.01">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/29/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="">9</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1869.09.09.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1869.09.09.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>To the Readers of the Virginian</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hewitt</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John H. Hewitt takes leave of Valley Virginian readers as he resigns his
                    position on the editorial staff of the paper.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Prospects of the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> Day after day we are gathering evidence that the South will at no distant
                        period become the creditor and the North the debtor. The day of her
                        greatness is beginning to dawn and a brilliant future is awaiting her, not
                        only in successful agricultural pursuits, but in the manufacture of staples.
                        The Charleston <emph rend="italic">News</emph> predicts that for 1869 the
                        cotton States will show more true prosperity than any other section of the
                        world. It estimates the present cotton crop at 3,000,000 bales.--The average
                        value of all the crops will amount to sixty four dollars per head of the
                        population. South Carolina, with all her drawbacks, will yield products this
                        year to the amount of $50,000,000, or an average of $74.62 per head in a
                        population of 670,000. The same journal remarks: "There are now no less than
                        200,000 whites cultivating cotton with their own hands;" probably referring
                        to the uplands, as the seaboard and island cotton plantations are mostly
                        worked by negroes. Years ago it was a rare thing to see a white laborer in
                        the fields of South Carolina; it is different now, the white has become the
                        competitor of the black, and a powerful one, too. The rice crop also bids
                        fair for a rich yield, and sugar cane is flourishing. </p>
                    <p>Now to these rich annual products add the fact that cotton and woolen
                        factories are springing up in all parts of the South, producing large
                        amounts of fabrics from the material, as it were, at their very doors, who
                        will deny that the manufacturing interests of the North will not suffer? It
                        is the vision of this growing greatness of the Southern States that has
                        given birth to the undying hatred, the offspring of jealousy of the people
                        of the New England States. The State of Virginia, though desolated by the
                        iron car of war--her garden spots made waste places, and her cities burnt,
                        is again springing up phoenix like from her ashes, and developing her
                        greatness. Her agricultural and mineral resources are exhaustless, and make
                        her of commercial importance of the world. Oppression may do its worst--she
                        will develop herself, for the genius and energy of her people cannot be
                        shackled. The State of Georgia is already competing favorably with the New
                        England States in her cotton and woolen fabrics, saying nothing of her iron
                        works; in fact, the attention of capitalists is being turned toward the
                        South with her numerous power working streams, rich soil and balmy climate;
                        and it is not unreasonable to suppose that even the money of the speculative
                        Yankees will ere long be invested in Southern factories and foundries.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Citing numerous economic advantages of the southern states, the author
                    claims that the South is once again on the rise. If fact, according to his
                    figures and other evidence, the South will soon not only rival, but surpass the
                    New England states in manufacturing and agricultural pursuits. This prosperity,
                    despite current oppression and the devastation of farms and cities, proves that
                    the southerner will "not be shackled" and will once again rise to greatness.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Important</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that Attorney General Hoar decided that the test-oath
                    should not be given to members of the Virginia legislature.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Lo, the Poor Workingmen!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> Horace Greeley is of the opinion that the working people are doing well when
                        they receive two, three or four dollars per day. So they would be doing well
                        if articles of consumption were at a reasonable price and the paper trash of
                        the government equal to gold. A laboring man can now buy less for four
                        dollars than he could for two in <sic>anti</sic> bellum days.--The poor
                        fellow is starving even with good wages, and all Greeley's philosophy can't
                        "make the pot boil." The worst of it is--his poverty is gaining on him every
                        year, while the rich bond-holder doubles his golden income. Is this the
                        government that holds up to the world equal rights and equal privileges?
                    </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Citing Horace Greeley's assessment of the prosperity of the working man,
                    the author rejects any notion that workers are doing "well." Rather, he claims
                    that increased wages make no difference when the cost of living has exceeded
                    earning potential. Further, the author shows resentment for the rich
                    "bond-holder," whose wealth only grows while the worker is denied "equal" rights
                    and privileges.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Test Oath. Attorney General Hoar's Opinion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints Attorney-General Hoar's decision in the Virginia test-oath
                    dispute. Hoar holds that since the election has been conducted,
                    legislators-elect are the legal representatives of the people. It is too late to
                    impose additional obligations upon them. Congress may decide not to admit the
                    state under the current legislature, but military authorities cannot demand
                    test-oaths.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1869.09.09.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>County Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The tournament to be held at the next county fair will be "an extra
                    splendid display of ladies and knights in costume." A coronation and fancy ball
                    will be conducted "according to the customs of the age of chivalry."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Our Schools</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Staunton's excellent schools will open soon for the fall term. Three are
                    for young ladies: The Virginia Female Institute, Rev. R. Phillips president; The
                    Augusta Female Seminary, Mary Baldwin principal; and the Wesleyan Female
                    Institute, Rev. W. A. Harris president. "All these schools have strong corps of
                    instructors and enjoy much popularity with the public. They hold out many
                    inducements to parents and guardians, not only for the intellectual improvements
                    of the pupils but their health and moral well-being. Staunton possesses
                    attractions itself; it is beautifully situated, romantic scenery, pure air and
                    refined society. There are churches of almost every denomination--all of them
                    well attended."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bush</ln>
                        <fn>Charles R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pierce</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neel</ln>
                        <fn>A. A. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles R. Bush of Rockingham and Miss Virginia Pierce of Augusta were
                    married near Pleasant Grove on September 2nd by the Rev. A. A. P. Neel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hazel</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garner</ln>
                        <fn>Mary M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garner</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lockridge</ln>
                        <fn>John N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel J. Hazel and Miss Mary M. Garner, both of Augusta, were married near
                    Sherando at the house of the bride's father, David Garner, by the Rev. John N.
                    Lockridge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Key</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baskins</ln>
                        <fn>Cornelia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas Key and Miss Cornelia Baskins were married in Staunton on September
                    5th by the Rev. George B. Taylor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>H. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pence</ln>
                        <fn>Julia Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hensel</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. H. B. Christian and Mrs. Julia Ann Pence, both of Augusta, were married
                    on August 19th by the Rev. J. C. Hensel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>James L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Clark, son of Dr. James L. and Martha Clark, died in Mt. Solon on
                    August 29th of typhoid fever. He was 17 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huff</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Susan Huff died near Sangersville at the residence of her son-in-law,
                    Daniel Miller, on August 29th. She was 86 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>Robert E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>Mary J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert E. Bishop, son of Robert E. and Mary J. Bishop, died in Staunton on
                    August 28th. He was 13 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1869.09.09.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
