<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1869/va.au.vv.1869.07.08">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/27/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-07-08">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="">8</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1869.07.08.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1869.07.08.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Valley Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Now that the strife and confusion of the campaign are over, and farmers,
                        mechanics and professional men have returned to their usual avocations, let
                        us hold calm and familiar communion with our readers as of old, and discuss
                        questions of importance to the prosperity of the State which has just passed
                        through a tremendous struggle for its existence as a member of the Federal
                        Union. We shall now see whether the men who have been chosen to represent us
                        in the National and State Legislatures, and who profess to be such warm
                        friends to the interests of the State, among which internal improvement
                        stands foremost, will adhere to their oft-repeated promises to build up new
                        structures, repair the old ones and smooth down the rough places which the
                        iron heel of war has made. We have a prospect of soon being freed from
                        military despotism; a rule which ever stops the progress of Improvement in
                        every branch; our social relations will be restored and with them confidence
                        between man and his fellow man.</p>
                    <p> The late uncertainty of our position has been one of the great causes of the
                        trouble in raising capital for the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad, and has
                        also had no little influence on the subscriptions to the Valley
                        Railroad.--The Baltimore <emph rend="italic">Gazette,</emph> in an editorial
                        article of some length, says: </p>
                    <p>"So far, the principle subscriptions to the latter have been from the
                        counties and towns along the route, amounting, in the aggregate, to
                        $700,000. One of the conditions of the ordinance recently passed by our City
                        Council, voting aid to the road, was that this subscription should be
                        increased to $1,000,000, either by the municipal corporations themselves or
                        by their citizens, not an unreasonable demand for a road which will cost
                        nearly five millions, and which is to pass through a country now without
                        railway communication, for 113 miles, developing its resources, and in many
                        parts, at least doubling the value of property.</p>
                    <p>In addition to that there is to be a further stock subscription of
                        $1,200,000, after which the company, having a solid capital of $3,200,000,
                        including the subscription of Baltimore city for $1,000,000, has the
                        privilege of raising the balance of the required capital by the issue and
                        sale of its bonds. The question is, "where is this $1,200,000 to come from?
                        Is this road, which forms the great connecting link on the New Orleans
                        route, of sufficient importance to the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad to
                        warrant that company in making such an investment? Is it probable that its
                        effect upon the trade and prosperity of this city will be so marked that aid
                        can be expected form our capitalists? Is it likely that the benefits to be
                        derived by our Bremen Steamship Company from the opening of this road will
                        be so decided as to make it their interest to subscribe? Does the
                        development which will soon be given to the iron trade of the Valley, by the
                        introduction of coal from the Kanawha and the Cumberland regions promise to
                        afford sufficient attraction, for capitalists and to insure pecuniary aid to
                        this road on their part?</p>
                    <p>To all of these questions we unhesitatingly answer, yes! The Valley Road is,
                        for the country between Baltimore and New Orleans, simply a great national
                        road. It must eventually become, in all probability, the most important
                        branch of the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad. Taking Winchester, as its
                        commencement, which virtually is, it passes through a region far more
                        fertile and destined to be, within a few years after the restoration of
                        political order, far more populous than any other district, of anything like
                        the same length, through which the main stem of any other branch of our
                        great road passes. It is a road which must not only sustain itself, by its
                        way traffic, but which by striking for distance and rich regions, must plant
                        its roots, in accordance with the great policy which has marked the whole of
                        Mr. Garrett's railroad career, in new and untouched soil. It must make
                        Baltimore the seaport for more grain and more tobacco and more cotton. It
                        must make it the most available point on the Atlantic coast for an immense
                        agricultural country. It must open up vast fields, uncultivated for want of
                        labor, to the German immigrants, who now crowd the steamships, which make
                        this their American harbor. It must tend to develop the exhaustless beds of
                        iron ore, which fill portions of the Valley of Virginia, and of which the
                        great fields of Pennsylvania, so terribly overworked, are said by geologists
                        to be but the outcroppings. Already large iron men from the North, looking
                        forward to future operations, have made purchase along and near the line of
                        the road, and the day will come when districts, now almost desolate, will be
                        alive with the blast of huge furnaces and the busy hum of men, and will
                        resound with the clanging stroke of the huge steam hammer.</p>
                    <p>Can anyone doubt for a moment what is going to be the effect of the building
                        of this road on the interests which we have referred to? Can anyone doubt as
                        to who would reap a rich reward from the subscription required? The city of
                        Baltimore, as far as the amount of its subscription is concerned, has acted
                        a liberal part, and it proposes to give its aid in a shape which will allow
                        it to be used as a credit. In other words, it authorizes the Company, so
                        soon as it is satisfied that the whole money can be procured, to make this,
                        together with other stock subscriptions, a second lien, thus allowing the
                        issue of the first mortgage bonds, and thereby virtually securing the
                        raising of money to complete the road, after the stock is once subscribed.</p>
                    <p>It remains now to be seen, where the other subscriptions are to come from.
                        The Valley of Virginia, still suffering from the effects of a disastrous
                        war, will do all that can be reasonably expected of it. The city of
                        Baltimore will do its part. If after this, parties who are most directly
                        interested will not come forward and take stock, and see that their money is
                        properly appropriated and economically expended, how can they expect to
                        secure the construction of the road? If they will not help themselves, have
                        they any right to ask assistance from other sources? We can only hope that
                        the restoration of civil order in Virginia will speedily remove the feeling
                        of distrust which has checked the operations of capitalists, and that the
                        required subscription will be before long an accomplished fact.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Having been absent for some time, the issue of the Valley railroad
                    reappears in this article compelling Virginians of Augusta County to subscribe
                    to the road. Discussion of this most momentous fundraising has been
                    overshadowed, says the author, because of the recent elections to the Federal
                    and State Legislatures. Now that that is over, adverse feelings can be put aside
                    and the issue of future prosperity can be once again addressed. As always, the
                    paper recommends support of the road's construction. Pointing out that the road
                    will connect the Valley to vital economic centers, the author urges subscription
                    for the sake of the region's future. Further, united work towards the road's
                    construction has the added benefit of possibly smoothing down some feathers
                    ruffled by the recent political contest.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Enough is known of the State election to justify us in shouting Lo! The noble
                        old mother of States is regenerated! The glorious Old Dominion has risen in
                        her majesty and shaken off the vermin that gathered around her loins.
                        Carpet-bags are out of fashion, and Secret Leagues will no more hold their
                        nightly orgies and bind free men down by oaths and pledges. Honor to the
                        patriotic Southerners who accomplished this great revolution; the men whose
                        vigilance never tired, who aroused the sleepers and urged the lukewarm to do
                        their duty. Honor to the colored men who opened their eyes to their own
                        danger, though at the eleventh hour--and who were made to see that the
                        rights of their own race were endangered by the rapacity of unprincipled and
                        office seeking carpet-baggers. "We have met the enemy--and they are
                    ours!"</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This piece briefly praises those who have "shaken off the vermin"
                    carpetbaggers. Both white and black southerners are honored--whites for urging
                    the "lukewarm" to do their duty, and blacks for opening their eyes to the
                    dangers of "unprincipled" office seekers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1869.07.08.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Augusta Fire Company</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Augusta Fire Company celebrated the 4th of July with a trip to Goshen
                    on the C. and O. Railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Templeton's Operetta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Templeton's Operetta Company is on tour through the Valley. It earned rave
                    reviews in Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sears</ln>
                        <fn>Edward H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noon</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Edward H. Sears has taken over as Staunton Post Master. John A. Noon has
                    been retained as an assistant.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Gutters</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper calls on the street commissioners and health commissioners to
                    examine the town gutters. "In many of the streets rains have displaced the slabs
                    and immense pits have been formed; in these the offals of yards and sinks
                    collect and there become gangrened, throwing off a very offensive smell. Either
                    replace the slabs or let loose the hydrants at least once a day. If these hints
                    are neglected, there is no knowing how soon sickness may visit us."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>County Returns</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Precincts</cell>
                            <cell>For</cell>
                            <cell>Governor.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>Walk'r.</cell>
                            <cell>Wells.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Staunton,</cell>
                            <cell>906</cell>
                            <cell>484</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Waynesboro,</cell>
                            <cell>853</cell>
                            <cell>118</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Sherando,</cell>
                            <cell>50</cell>
                            <cell>52</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Swoopes,</cell>
                            <cell>104</cell>
                            <cell>24</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Parnassus,</cell>
                            <cell>52</cell>
                            <cell>14</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Mt. Solon,</cell>
                            <cell>251</cell>
                            <cell>45</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Craigsville,</cell>
                            <cell>135</cell>
                            <cell>00</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Middlebrook,</cell>
                            <cell>279</cell>
                            <cell>61</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Greenville,</cell>
                            <cell>353</cell>
                            <cell>51</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Midway,</cell>
                            <cell>78</cell>
                            <cell>14</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>New Hope,</cell>
                            <cell>207</cell>
                            <cell>80</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Mt. Meridian,</cell>
                            <cell>115</cell>
                            <cell>16</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Churchville,</cell>
                            <cell>258</cell>
                            <cell>78</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Deerfield,</cell>
                            <cell>80</cell>
                            <cell>9</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Springhill,</cell>
                            <cell>78</cell>
                            <cell>14</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Mt. Sidney,</cell>
                            <cell>278</cell>
                            <cell>28</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>____</cell>
                            <cell>____</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>3695</cell>
                            <cell>1115</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>1115</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Walker's majority</cell>
                            <cell>2580</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This table illustrates election results from the various districts in
                    Augusta County. Walker emerges the victor over Wells by a 2580 vote majority.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Virginia Female Institute</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>R. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ide</ln>
                        <fn>E. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ide</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Upshur</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>M. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Ms.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hansbrough</ln>
                        <fn>V. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Ms.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pendleton</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dawson</ln>
                        <fn>L. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Ms.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finlayson</ln>
                        <fn>G. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Ms.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>R. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Ms.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leavell</ln>
                        <fn>M. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Ms.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lowry</ln>
                        <fn>Lina</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Ms.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nelson</ln>
                        <fn>Mattie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Ms.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paul</ln>
                        <fn>Ella</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Ms.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shackelford</ln>
                        <fn>G. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Ms.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stringfellow</ln>
                        <fn>Mollie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Ms.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>M. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Ms.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yancey</ln>
                        <fn>M. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The commencement exercises of the Virginia Female Institute, Rev. R. H.
                    Phillips principal, were observed on the 24th of June. Music under the direction
                    of Professor Ide and addresses by Judge H. W. Sheffey and others marked the
                    occasion.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Election Day</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Much to the credit of Staunton, the election on Tuesday last, which everybody
                        presumed would be an exciting one, went off with perfect quiet. Good humor
                        seemed to prevail between the opposing parties--a stray joke now and then
                        would create a peal of laughter at the expense of one or the other, but no
                        harsh bickering or angry words were bandied.--The colored people also
                        behaved well, some of them, it is said, fought under the motto, "vote early
                        and vote often," and took passage on the excursion train of "Monkey Chunk
                        Railroad," but, otherwise they came up to the scratch. All this good order
                        is attributable to the closing of the bar-rooms, by which means King Whiskey
                        was perfectly powerless, and his agents Riot and Tumult had nothing to do.
                        At night there were some very long faces as well as some very broad
                        ones--the reason of this will be seen by consulting another part of our
                        paper, where the returns, up to the time of our going to press will be
                        found.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The author praises Staunton voters for a well organized, altercation free
                    election. He reports that competitors exchanged no hostilities or even angry
                    words. Black voters also "behaved well," although he implies a few were suspect
                    of voting multiple times. All of this is thanks to the closing of drinking
                    establishments--"King Whiskey" was "perfectly powerless" during this election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Enthusiastic Celebration of the Fourth of July</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports celebration of the fourth of July in Staunton with
                    speeches and toasts. Though much of the sentiment was "E pluribus Unum," they
                    denounced the tyrannical government and the new Virginia constitution while
                    praising the Confederate dead, Virginia, and liberty.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Stay-Law Extended</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following important order extending the provisions of the stay-law until
                        the first day of January, 1870, was issued from military head quarters on
                        Tuesday last:</p>
                    <p>HDQRS, &amp;C., STATE OF VIRGINIA, RICHMOND, VA, June 29, 1869.</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">General Orders No. 80</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>1. Paragraph 1 of General Orders No. 149, dated December 12, 1868, from these
                        headquarters, is hereby modified to read as follows:</p>
                    <p>"That the stay of executions against personal property, so far only as the
                        same exists under laws lately in force, and which, by the provisions thereof
                        expired on the first day of January, 1869, shall be and is hereby extended
                        until the first day of January, 1870, provided that the debtor shall have
                        paid subsequent to January 1, 1869, and before August 1, 1869, one year's
                        interest upon the principal sum due; but if before last named date such
                        payment of interest shall not have been made, no execution shall be further
                        stayed against personal property as provided for in this order;" and
                        provided further, that in cases where the principal debt is due to the
                        estate of any minor, widow, unmarried woman, or insane person as the
                        beneficiary of a trust, whether in the hands of executors, guardians,
                        administrators, trustees, commissioners in chancery, or other fiduciary, or
                        invested by any such in his or their fiduciary capacity, in addition to the
                        payment of one year's interest as above required, one third of the whole
                        arrears of interest on the principal sum due shall be paid by the debtor on
                        or before the first of September, 1869, and one half of the remainder of the
                        said arrears of interest on or before the first of November, 1869, to
                        entitle such debtor to the stay of execution provided for by this order.</p>
                    <p>II. At any sale of real estate by virtue of any decree or order of any court
                        of this State, if the highest amount offered or bid at such sale for such
                        real estate shall be less than two-thirds of the amount of the valuation of
                        such real estate as assessed in the last preceding assessment for State
                        taxes, and a minute of which assessed valuation shall be certified on the
                        process by the officer holding the same, then in every such case, it shall
                        be the duty of the sheriff, commissioner or other officer or person
                        conducting such sale, at the request of either or any party to the record
                        then and there to adjourn and postpone such sale for the period of two
                        calendar months, provided that the provisions of this paragraph shall not
                        apply to any case in which the debt or liability sought to be enforced was
                        contracted or incurred since the 2d day of April, 1865, or in which the
                        Commonwealth is the creditor or party beneficially entitled, or taxes,
                        levies or assessments due to a county or corporation.</p>
                    <p>III. General orders No. 24, dated March 12, paragraphs 2, 3 and 4 of general
                        orders No. 149 from these headquarters, dated December 22, 1868, are hereby
                        continued in force and made applicable to this order.</p>
                    <p>By command of Brevet Major General Canby. LOUIS V. CASIARC, A.D.C., Acting
                        Assistant Adjutant General.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The assistant Adjutant General to General Canby issued an order detailing
                    changes to the Stay-Law valid until January of 1870. Most of the changes dealt
                    with personal property and real-estate transactions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1869.07.08.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
