<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1869/va.au.vv.1869.02.11">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/15/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-02-11">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day norm="">11</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1869.02.11.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>Pay Your Small Bills</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper stresses the importance of paying off small bills and debts. It
                    can mean the difference between success or failure for a tradesman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1869.02.11.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>More Territory</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper supports annexing St. Domingo as "the very best place in the
                    world for colonizing our new citizens."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Judge H. W. Sheffey</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper praises Judge H. W. Sheffey as one of the greatest in the state.
                    They hope party prejudice will not cost him his job.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Examples Worthy of Consideration</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>That influential journal, the Republican Banner, of Nashville, says:</p>
                    <p>"There is but one key to the solution of the reconstruction problem. The New
                        York Tribune has found it, and urges upon Congress its immediate
                        application. It lies in the simple, lucid comprehensive platform of
                        universal amnesty and impartial suffrage."</p>
                    <p>As Tennessee has preceded Virginia in having to endure disfranchisements,
                        negro suffrage, a State militia, and the like, her experience is worth
                        something to the people of Virginia. The counsel of her leaders and her
                        press ought to be weighed by the Old Dominion. The people of Tennessee would
                        be only too happy to day to secure relief from State disfranchisement in
                        consideration for universal suffrage.</p>
                    <p>So, too, Virginia has the advantage of Georgia's experience, both what she
                        gained in a good State constitution by conceding the demand for impartial
                        suffrage, and by what she has risked by running against the will of Congress
                        in the matter of negro eligibility to office. This experience ought to have
                        its uses for other communities in like case; We observe that the Macon
                        Telegraph--a most judicious and able paper--warmly endorses the new movement
                        in Virginia, and says that by it the authors, if they succeed, will "save
                        their State."</p>
                    <p> The meaning of this is, that the capital and industry of the people of
                        Virginia will be "saved" from the rapacious exactions of the carpet-baggers
                        who wish to eat up their substance. With a keen instinct, the latter class,
                        as soon as they heard of the "new movement," saw in it death and ruin to all
                        their schemes of oppression and plunder; they rushed to Washington,
                        carpet-bag in hand, to counteract the efforts of the committee of nine, and
                        for weeks have been working their game as well as they could. The principle
                        weapon in their armory is the persistent opposition of the "last ditch" men,
                        and their reiterated allegation that the new movement does not receive the
                        support of the Virginia people. This was the main point relied on by
                        Governor Wells to induce the Reconstruction Committee to adopt his views;
                        but it may be doubted, after all, whether, in case of his success in
                        attaining power, he will require those who have rendered him, at a critical
                        pinch, such very effective aid. <emph rend="italic">National
                        Intelligencer</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article uses examples of other states to show the difficulties with
                    disfranchisement. The author suggests, as do papers form other states, that the
                    "new movement" can save Virginia from the rapacious carpetbaggers. Although some
                    say that most Virginians do not support the movement, the author claims this is
                    merely the argument of Governor Wells and a few of his carpetbagger supporters.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>A Southern Scalawag on Carpet-Baggers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Hunnicutt, the Richmond chief of the Virginia scalawags, expresses his
                        opinion of carpet baggers in this fashion:</p>
                    <p>These miscreant adventurers, having no character of their own to lose, and no
                        property to tax, and no responsibilities resting on them, meanly, basely and
                        cowardly seek to build up a reputation with the colored people by lying and
                        defaming and trying to pull down the good names of gentlemen who would scorn
                        any association with them whatever. Beggars, they seek their fortunes by
                        whining and crying for office. Producing nothing, they would suck the last
                        drop of blood from the veins of every Virginian to fill their own empty
                        pockets, and then, in justification of their own base acts, would filch from
                        them that which is worth more than all the sordid wealth of the earth--their
                        fair reputation, their good name.--These ravenous, devouring wolves in
                        sheep's clothing, who go poking about throughout the country, whispering,
                        writing, publishing and circulating infamous lies and slanders against the
                        true and tried men of Virginia, merit the execration of all good men and the
                        eternal anathemas of a just and righteous God. Their sins will find them
                        out, and they will be brought to shame and infamy at last.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This writer, a Virginia scalawag, suggests that carpetbaggers are the most
                    vile, base individuals in Virginia. They are concerned only with personal self
                    interest, they have duped blacks into supporting them, and will not hesitate to
                    slander a gentleman's good name for their benefit.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Great Endorser</head>
                <origin>Norfolk Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The article supports A. H. H. Stuart who asserted in his speech in Staunton
                    that Robert E. Lee endorsed the "New Movement." "He knows that negro suffrage
                    exists now, and that it can never be taken away. He would save the honor of his
                    State from degradation; he would prevent her from being trampled under foot by
                    the negroes and the plunderers who have been thrown into power by a revolution."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Value of Virginia Bonds</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The rise in Virginia stocks is to be attributed to the prospect of the old
                        Commonwealth being delivered from the despotism of the negro. They rose the
                        moment that it became even probable that the propositions of the Committee
                        of Nine would be accepted.</p>
                    <p>How different is the result in the case of North Carolina, whose stocks have
                        under her reconstruction exhibited a downward tendency, as well as they may,
                        when the capitalists of the country behold the reckless manner in which
                        Holden and his Radicals are running her in debt.</p>
                    <p>If such is the case in North Carolina, where the Radicals constitute a far
                        more influential and respectable class than they do in Virginia, what will
                        be infallibly the result in the latter State should Bayne's Constitution be
                        carried?</p>
                    <p> It does seem to us strange indeed that any can be found in Virginia directly
                        or indirectly concerned in maintaining the credit of the State, who are so
                        insensate as to oppose the plan of some of the old Commonwealth's most
                        patriotic and distinguished sons. If the old fogies, by the help they are
                        giving Wells and Underwood, should succeed in subjecting Virginia to the
                        negro, the bonds of the State will not be worth the paper they are printed
                        on; while if the committee succeed in their efforts, in a few months they
                        will rise to par.<lb/><emph rend="italic">Norfolk Journal</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article illustrates an important consequence of radical rule, the
                    "Bayne Constitution," and old fogeyism. Essentially, if the Committee of Nine's
                    propositions are rejected, white Virginians will fail to wrest control from
                    those promoting "negro rule." Thus, as in North Carolina, state stocks will
                    plummet.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1869.02.11.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Baptist Church</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Broaddus</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The revival continues in the Baptist Church. A large number have professed
                    and been baptized. The Rev. Dr. Broaddus is aiding the pastor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Vote of Thanks</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fifer</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Augusta Fire Company passed resolutions of thanks to the black and
                    white citizens of Staunton for their assistance at a recent fire.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Produce</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper notices that many shipments of bacon, lard, and produce that used
                    to be handled in Staunton are now being made from Harrisonburg. The editors urge
                    construction of the road to Staunton to stop the economic damage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Card</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weed</ln>
                        <fn>J. Ambler</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. Ambler Weed, pastor of St. Francis Church, Staunton, thanks the Augusta
                    Fire Company and the citizens of the town for their help during a fire at the
                    church's school rooms. "The services of the colored men present deserve special
                    notice."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Liberal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The members of Staunton's Catholic Church subscribed $250 to rebuild their
                    school house that was destroyed by fire. They raised $50 at a recent tableaux,
                    and $30 from citizen contributions. "The work of rebuilding has already
                    commenced, and by the latter part of March it is hoped to have the building
                    ready. In the mean time, the Fire Company, with marked charity, have given use
                    of their Hall, so that youths of the congregation will lose no time."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Corporation Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At the February term of this court for the town of Staunton, Thos. C. Elder,
                        Esq., was duly admitted to practice.</p>
                    <p>Henry Jackson (colored) on an indictment of petit larceny, sentenced to
                        thirty days in the county jail.</p>
                    <p>Geo. W. Hardeman, on an indictment for obtaining property by false pretense,
                        sentenced to thirty days in county jail.</p>
                    <p>On two several indictments for petit larceny, Margaret Marshall (colored),
                        was found guilty--sentenced in one case to 20 days and in the other 30 days
                        in county jail.</p>
                    <p>Alex. Patterson (colored), on indictment for petit larceny, found guilty and
                        sentenced to six months imprisonment in jail.</p>
                    <p>Michael Sullivan on indictment for selling obscene books, found guilty, fined
                        $200 and sentenced to twelve months imprisonment in jail.</p>
                    <p>Also for selling cards with obscene prints, he was found guilty, fined $100,
                        and sentenced to 6 months confinement in jail.</p>
                    <p>The Grand Jury found 42 indictments.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jackson</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardeman</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marshall</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sullivan</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This piece is a brief list of criminals, their infractions, and
                    punishments. Included are those who have committed petit larceny as well as a
                    man who was convicted for selling obscene material.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Another Fire</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cleary</ln>
                        <fn>Nick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Briggs</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Venerable</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Account of the fire at St. Francis Catholic Church's School House. Col.
                    Nick Cleary made early efforts to stop the fire from growing to dangerous size,
                    but failed. The Fire Company and many helpful citizens could not save the
                    building, but they did prevent the spread of the fire. "It gives us more than
                    ordinary pleasure to notice the almost superhuman efforts of several colored
                    men, and more especially John Briggs and William Venerable, blacksmiths, each of
                    whom done the work of any five men." The editors say the incident draws
                    attention once again to the need to properly fund and outfit the Fire Company,
                    and suggest holding a public meeting for those ends.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Libscomb</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>N. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maupin</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Staunton Council, Number 47, Friends of Temperance, passed resolutions
                    of sympathy and respect upon the death of their fellow-member William H. Wilson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Obaugh</ln>
                        <fn>William W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ferren</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grant</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William W. Obaugh, formerly of Mt. Solon, and Miss Maggie E. Ferren of Ohio
                    were married in Ohio on January 7th by the Rev. J. Grant.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coiner</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ewing</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tallhelm</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George A. Coiner and Miss Mary E. Ewing, both of Augusta, were married at
                    the residence of the bride's father on February 4th by the Rev. H. Tallhelm.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Drumheller</ln>
                        <fn>Darius Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gochenour</ln>
                        <fn>Mollie Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Darius Edward Drumheller and Miss Mollie Ann Gochenour, both of Augusta,
                    were married on January 28th by the Rev. Martin Garber.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmer</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmer</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Margaret B. Whitmer, wife of Samuel Whitmer, died near Parnassus on
                    January 1st after a short illness. She was 62 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Murray</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander Fountaine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alexander Fountaine Murray, a native of Augusta, died in West Virginia. He
                    was 88 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel J. D. Fisher, formerly of Staunton, died in West Virginia at the
                    house of his father, John Fisher. He was 24 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1869.02.11.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
