<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1869/va.au.vv.1869.06.03">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/23/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-06-03">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day norm="">3</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1869.06.03.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1869.06.03.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Buy at Home</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Virginia papers are justly complaining of the practice, too common, by
                        universities, colleges, academies, banking institutions, railroad
                        corporations, agencies, and individuals, of sending the printing they want
                        done, to be executed in the Northern cities. It is the old error of refusing
                        to "buy at home." The proper way is constantly to encourage home industry.
                        Every now and then a dollar or two may perchance be saved. In the long run,
                        nothing is saved. If properly encouraged, book and job printing could be
                        done in the South on a large scale, and with as much elegance of style, as
                        in the North. Give us a fair chance, and give us the work that is sent
                        abroad, and the South would soon show.</p>
                    <p> We clip the above form the Alexandria <emph rend="italic"> Gazette, </emph>
                        and cordially second the suggestion. It was well enough years ago for our
                        people to purchase at the North, for <emph rend="italic"> then </emph> the
                        South was strictly agricultural in its pursuits. It is widely different now;
                        the two sections of the country stand in antagonism, and the acts of the
                        Radical Government since the surrender have done anything but conciliate the
                        opposite parties. The South must become independent of the North if she
                        wishes to thrive. Thomas Jefferson wished that there was a wall of fire
                        between Europe and America. Were that wall of fire to swell up between the
                        North and South now, they would both be happier and more contented people.
                        Since the war the Southern people have turned much of their attention to
                        manufacturing: Cotton factories are looming up, and it does not acquire much
                        far seeing to prophecy that, before many years have passed, Southern cotton
                        will pass through Southern looms. It is the duty then of every one who has
                        the prosperity of the down trodden Southern States at heart, to encourage
                        Southern industry--to aid Southern enterprises and spend their money on
                        Southern soil. We will bring this argument nearer home--we will speak to the
                        people of Staunton--which is said to be a thriving little city embedded amid
                        the mountains of Virginia. The reputation we have abroad invites mechanics
                        and artisans to make so desirable a place their home and help to increase
                        our importance. We have first class workmen here in almost every branch of
                        mechanical industry. Can any one give us a reason why those men who have
                        come among us should not be sustained? Who builds up cities and towns? Is it
                        not the mechanic? Then, we argue that the citizen who sends his money abroad
                        to purchase articles that may be had equally as good and equally as cheap in
                        Staunton, throws barriers in her way and consequently impedes her progress.
                        The argument has still more force when it bears on mechanics who were born
                        and raised on the soil of Virginia. The result of the war has made us all
                        laborers--we have no aristocrats now, and the F.F.V's are among the things
                        of the past. How much more, then, must we not be bound in duty to support
                        those whom we claim as our own countrymen? We could wish that those of our
                        citizens who have money to spend, (we are all aware that the number is
                        rather limited) would, by their example, put an end to a ridiculous idea
                        that has prevailed ever since the days of colonists, that it is
                        unfashionable to buy anything at home, and that domestic manufactures should
                        always give place to foreign. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The author of this article urges all southerners to buy products
                    manufactured in the South. This is the only way the South can pull itself out of
                    the economic ruin caused by the war. Interestingly, while the author describes
                    the prewar South as primarily agricultural, he in no way suggests that the
                    postwar South is simply a copy of the industrial North. In fact, he implies that
                    southern industry developed independently, and only needs time to develop and
                    prosper on its own. Unlike others who recommend industrial bonds be formed with
                    northern neighbors in the name of prosperity, the author recommends further
                    disunity and invokes Jefferson's "wall of fire" principle to keep North and
                    South separate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Magnanimous</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The graves of the Federal dead at Arlington were decorated last Saturday.
                    Post Number One of the Grand Army of the Republic passed resolutions declaring
                    that they had no malice toward the Confederate dead, but would not decorate
                    their graves "and thereby taint the character of those who sacrificed their
                    lives 'that their country might live.'" A marine guard was placed around the
                    Confederate graves to ensure that no flowers were placed there.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Letter from Hon. A. H. H. Stuart</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have received from a distinguished gentleman in Albemarle county the
                        following letter addressed to him by Hon. A.H.H. Stuart. He sends it with
                        the request that we publish it, which we do with pleasure.--Our own position
                        has been taken on the questions discussed. We are always glad, however, to
                        lay before the readers of the Enquirer the views from leading public men:</p>
                    <p>Staunton, May 24th, 1869.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic"> My Dear Sir-- </emph> When I casually met you a few days
                        ago you requested that I would express to you in writing my views of the
                        course the people of Virginia should pursue in regard to the questions about
                        to be submitted for their decision under the President's proclamation. I now
                        proceed to do so. </p>
                    <p>There certainly was much disappointment felt when it was ascertained that the
                        President had failed to include the "county organization," classes of the
                        constitution among those which were to be submitted to the people to be
                        voted on separately. It was known that the President had expressed strong
                        opposition to these clauses as tending to segregate the white and colored
                        population by a geographical line, and to impede the productive power of the
                        State, by separating the labor of the country from the capital of the
                        Commonwealth. Hence a confident expectation was entertained that he would
                        afford to the people an opportunity of striking those objectionable features
                        form the proposed constitution.</p>
                    <p>In the first excitement occasioned by this disappointment, some persons
                        expressed their purposes to try and defeat the whole instrument by voting
                        first, to strike out the disfranchising clauses and the test-oath, and then,
                        against the instrument thus expurgated.</p>
                    <p>This disposition was not unnatural under the circumstances. Within the four
                        years which have elapsed since the close of the war, the people of Virginia
                        have been subjected to so much disappointment, annoyance, and obloquy, they
                        have become sensitive, and in some degree soured. But, unfortunately, we are
                        in no condition now to take counsel of our wishes. We are not in that happy
                        state, in which we can afford to indulge in the luxury of a little
                        ill-temper.--We are bound by inexorable necessity to confront the stern
                        realities of our situation, and to make the best we can of them.</p>
                    <p> After giving to the subject the best consideration, I have satisfied myself
                        that it is the true policy of the people of Virginia to vote to strike out
                        the test-oath and disfranchising clauses, and then to vote <emph
                            rend="italic"> for the adoption </emph> of the residue of the
                        constitution. I admit that it is a painful necessity, yet it is not the less
                        a necessity. It is true that we will not get all that we had expected to
                        get, yet I think it obvious that by so doing we gain a great deal. The
                        constitution, even when expurgated, will be a very objectionable instrument,
                        but it is certainly much better than in its original form, and, in my
                        judgment, it is infinitely preferable to no constitution at all. We can at
                        least live under it for a time, with no certain assurance, that after a
                        while, we can greatly improve it.</p>
                    <p>It would tax my time and your patience too largely to give all the reasons
                        which have brought my mind to this conclusion.--But I will state one or two
                        of the most prominent:</p>
                    <p>It seems to me that in casting their votes under the President's
                        proclamation, the people are called on to decide where the political power
                        of the State is to rest hereafter, and who are to control her destinies in
                        the future, they will have to elect between three competing propositions,
                        neither of which is entirely acceptable, but there is no other open to us.
                        These propositions are:</p>
                    <p>1st. To take the Underwood constitution pure and simple.</p>
                    <p>2n. To vote the whole constitution down.</p>
                    <p>3d. To adopt it with the disfranchisement and test-oaths stricken out.</p>
                    <p>Let us now consider what is the practical bearing and effect of each one of
                        these propositions. Let us see how it will effect the future status of the
                        political power of the Commonwealth.</p>
                    <p>If we allow the Underwood constitution to be adopted with all its
                        disqualifications it is obvious that we voluntarily disfranchise ourselves
                        for a generation to come, and place the political power--the power to
                        control our lives, liberty and property--in the hands of the carpet-baggers
                        and the worst classes of our own people. I presume there are few intelligent
                        and upright men in the State who will favor this proposition, and I will
                        therefore pass it by without further commentary.</p>
                    <p>Let us now consider the second. Suppose we vote the whole constitution
                        down--what follows? Some contend that matters would stand as they are.
                        Assuming such to be the fact, I ask is not that enough? We would have wells
                        for our nominal Governor, and all other offices filled by aliens and
                        strangers. We would have justice administered under military supervision and
                        by appointees of a military commandant. But what assurance have we that
                        matters would remain as they are? How do we know whether our situation will
                        not be rendered more intolerable than it now is? By voting down the
                        constitution altogether we in effect re-commit the whole political power of
                        the State to a radical Congress. Has the past action of that body been such
                        as to render it desirable they should again assume unlimited control over
                        our destiny? I must acknowledge I think not. If we virtually decide that we
                        will have nothing to do with shaping our future, we compel Congress to take
                        upon itself that office.</p>
                    <p>The third proposition is, then, the only one that offers any hope of escape
                        from the terrible evils by which we are threatened. If we strike out the
                        restrictive features and then adopt the residue of the instrument, while we
                        do not gain all that we want, we at least place the political power of the
                        State in the hands of the better classes of the people of Virginia. We
                        snatch it from the grasp of the carpet-baggers and their political allies,
                        and we withdraw it from the control of a Radical Congress.</p>
                    <p>We will entitle ourselves to a restoration to our rights in the Union, and to
                        the withdrawal of military supervision and control over us. We can elect
                        officers and enact laws of our own, and within a year or two after the
                        excitement incident to these political struggles shall have passed away, we
                        can call a new convention and form a new constitution adapted to our
                        existing condition. By striking out the disfranchisements and test-oaths
                        almost the whole body of our population will be clothed with the power to
                        vote and be rendered eligible to office. The principle of popular
                        sovereignty will be established on a firm basis, and the voice of our own
                        citizens will be potential in framing our future organic law, and shaping
                        our future policy.</p>
                    <p>I have thus stated, I think fairly, the three propositions, between which the
                        people of Virginia are compelled to chose. If there be any other open to
                        them, I am not aware of it.</p>
                    <p>Ought the people of Virginia to hesitate between them? I think not, I think
                        they ought to expurgate the constitution and then adopt it.</p>
                    <p>But it is all important that we should spare no pains to insure a good
                        Legislature and a good Constitution. The reasons are too obvious to require
                        enumerations. They will readily suggest themselves to every intelligent
                        mind. If we expect good laws we must elect a good legislature. If we desire
                        and wish an honest execution of the laws we must choose a wise and honest
                        Governor. And, while this is, at all times, necessary, it is especially so
                        now. The new legislature will have to enact all laws necessary to put the
                        new government into operation. The constitution is not self-enforcing, it
                        requires legislation to give effect to it. The new governor will be clothed
                        with the veto power to check hasty and improvident legislation. Need I say
                        any thing to show to the people the necessity of making a wise selection of
                        those who are to wield powers fraught with so much of weal or woe to the
                        State!</p>
                    <p> Very truly yours, &amp;c. <lb/> Alex. H.H. Stuart </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Alexander H.H. Stuart writes of three options before the voters of Virginia
                    regarding the proposed Underwood Constitution. He points out that none of the
                    options will entirely satisfy the lot of (white) Virginians, but recommends one
                    course that, in the long run, will best suit all. His suggestion, rather than
                    letting the constitution pass in its entirety or rejecting it altogether, is to
                    vote it through with a number of items stricken. Specifically, clauses
                    pertaining to disfranchisement and the test-oath should first be removed and
                    then the constitution passed. In the future, once the political struggles have
                    settled, Virginians can reconvene and pass a more favorable constitution. This,
                    according to Stuart, is infinitely better than allowing the Radical Congress to
                    continue to govern Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1869.06.03.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Appointment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Town</ln>
                        <fn>F. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Brevet 1st Lt. F. E. Town has been appointed military commissioner and
                    superintendent of registration and elections for the district including
                    Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper praises the concert given at Tinkling Springs under the direction
                    of Prof. Evans. Discussions have begun on establishing a music school in
                    Staunton or Harrisonburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Memorial Day</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Saturday next it is expected that every good Southerner of Staunton will
                        assist in swelling the crowd of those who wish to honor the graves of the
                        brave who fell in defence of their liberty and homes. Bring flowers to
                        decorate their resting places. We understand that detailed members of the
                        Musical Association will sing an ode prepared for the occasion by Dr. J. L.
                        Brown, and also a poem written by Father Ryan will be read</p>
                    <p>"They have fought for their rights, for the land of their sires<lb/> Their
                        forms have stood up like a bulwark of might;<lb/> They knelt at the altar
                        where burn Freedom's fires,<lb/> And thrust back the foe in her glorious
                        light<lb/> No bright stars for them, plucked from Fame's diadem,<lb/>
                        Unnoticed, unheeded they acted their parts,<lb/> Mid the clashing of arms,
                        and battle's alarms<lb/> They fell with the love of home deep in their
                        hearts.<lb/> Let the requiem be sung, let the sad prayer be said<lb/> For
                        the heroes forgotten--the unknown Dead."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announcement of plans for upcoming Confederate memorial services.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Staunton Musical Association</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article asserts that there is much musical taste and talent in
                    Staunton, and all that is needed is a music school.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Temperance in Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>H. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bear</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fall</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>L. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dudley</ln>
                        <fn>A. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bear</ln>
                        <fn>G. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Quidor</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bear</ln>
                        <fn>E. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hodge</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>H. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rusmisell</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morgan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Murry</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Helms</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kunkle</ln>
                        <fn>Cooper</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fix</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clemmer</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Helms</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ross</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Churchman</ln>
                        <fn>V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Muller</ln>
                        <fn>S. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>R. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schriver</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trice</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donahoe</ln>
                        <fn>L. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pitch</ln>
                        <fn>C. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schultz</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Supple</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thacker</ln>
                        <fn>N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rice</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Connell</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>R. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nell</ln>
                        <fn>N. A. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yarbrough</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerr</ln>
                        <fn>I. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerr</ln>
                        <fn>W. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Borden</ln>
                        <fn>U. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kothwell</ln>
                        <fn>E. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>R. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The temperance lecturer Rev. James Young has been having success throughout
                    the county. Everywhere he speaks, large numbers have signed a temperance pledge.
                    Chapters were organized in Churchville, Greenville, New Hope, and Middlebrook,
                    and officers elected. "At Churchville, 34 signed the pledge and 16 joined the
                    Order. At Middlebrook, 73 signed the pledge and 22 joined the Order. At
                    Greenville, 58 signed the pledge and 18 joined the Order. At New Hope, 53 signed
                    the pledge and 15 joined the Order. At Mt. Sidney, 45 signed the pledge and 8
                    new applications were made to join the Order which had just about expired. These
                    signers of the pledge, with 108 in this place, make 271 in this county since the
                    12th of April last. 1900 persons in the Valley have signed the pledge and
                    several hundred have united themselves with the Order of the Friends of
                    Temperance."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berry</ln>
                        <fn>Charles B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bear</ln>
                        <fn>Ella D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles B. Berry and Miss Ella D. Bear were married near Churchville on May
                    26th by the Rev. P. Fletcher.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smiley</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lucus</ln>
                        <fn>Hannah A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shreckise</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Smiley and Miss Hannah A. Lucus, both of Augusta, were married on
                    May 20th by the Rev. J. M. Shreckise.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>Maglin M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Maglin M. Cochran died in Staunton at the residence of her father on
                    June 2nd. She was 39 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ackerman</ln>
                        <fn>David R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David R. Ackerman died in Staunton at the residence of his father on May
                    31st. He was 19 years old. "In the death of this young man society has lost an
                    ornament, the community a useful member, and his parents a dutiful and loving
                    son."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1869.06.03.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
