<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1869/va.au.vv.1869.08.26">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/29/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-08-26">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="">26</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1869.08.26.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1869.08.26.02" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1869.08.26.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Oration</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Munsey will deliver an oration in the Methodist Church on Friday. He comes
                    with a reputation for eloquence and graceful oratory.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Funeral of Young Scherer</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The funeral of Jacob Scherer proved "highly flattering to the memory of the
                    young man and gave evidence of the high estimate he was held in by all classes
                    of society." The procession left his house escorted by the Augusta Fire Company.
                    "A long cortage of vehicles and a procession of people of all sexes and classes
                    followed. The melancholy affair has made a deep impression upon our community."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Tribute of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waters</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morris</ln>
                        <fn>W. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardy</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fifer</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Augusta Fire Company prints a tribute of respect upon the death of
                    Jacob Scherer, a fellow fireman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>The Homicide of Jacob Scherer</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A fatal occurrence took place at a house on Market Street, in this city, on
                        Saturday night last, which threw a gloom over the entire community, and has
                        caused much excitement up to the present time. We shall relate the
                        particulars as far as they have come to our knowledge.</p>
                    <p>The house in question, it seems, has been occupied by an octoroon by the name
                        of Ginnie Sorrel and has been the resort of loose characters, who at times
                        annoyed the neighbors by their obscene language and indecent exposures. A
                        number of young men associated themselves together for the purpose of
                        breaking up this nuisance by driving the inmates out. They organized and
                        determined to catch the girl Sorrel and duck her in the creek, and also, as
                        it appeared in evidence, to administer the same cold bath to her paramour,
                        if occasion required it. With this object in view, they repaired to the
                        house between the hours of eleven and twelve at night with their faces
                        blackened and otherwise disguised, and without any kind of offensive
                        weapons. Three of them went to the rear of the building, while the others
                        remained in front. They knocked at the door, and were asked from within by a
                        female voice, "who is there?" One of them pushed the door and it opened. A
                        woman then screamed murder, and fled. The party entered, and were in but a
                        few moments when in the pitchy-darkness the flash of a pistol accompanied by
                        a report, revealed the fact that Jacob Scherer, (son of Mr. John B. Scherer)
                        was shot. The perpetrator of the deed immediately made for the door followed
                        by the wounded man who, after running about ten yards, fell, and never spoke
                        afterwards. The man that fired the pistol escaped over the yard fence.
                        Scherer's friends gathered round him, and attempted to move the body towards
                        his father's house close by--but the unfortunate young man died before they
                        had reached the street.</p>
                    <p>The crowd which by this time had become great, immediately made a rush toward
                        the house of John M. Stanley, which they surrounded, with the intention of
                        preventing any one from escaping until a warrant could be issued. Chief of
                        Police, J.T. Parent, armed with a warrant issued by Mayor Allen charging
                        Stanley with the killing of Scherer, in a short time demanded admission to
                        the house. When the door was forced open, Mrs. Stanley endeavored to oppose
                        the officers of the law. She affirmed that her husband had come home earlier
                        than usual, and that he was then in bed. This, however, did not deter the
                        officers, they pushed forward and found Stanley with a pistol in his hand;
                        this Parent got from him--although the prisoner observed that he had a right
                        to protect himself from a mob. He said that he knew nothing about the
                        affair, and could prove an alibi. It was afterwards shown that the pistol,
                        which was a four barreled repeater, had one empty barrel. Stanley was
                        arrested and lodged in jail. The evidence brought before the Coroner's
                        inquest held at an early hour in the morning charged John M. Stanley with
                        being the perpetrator of the dead.</p>
                    <p>On Tuesday morning the case was brought before the court of Magistrates
                        acting as an examining court.</p>
                    <p>The Court House was crowded, and there appeared to be no small amount of
                        excitement among the people. Justice Pierce, Clinedinst and Anderson,
                        appeared on the bench, the former presiding.</p>
                    <p>James Bumgardner, Jr., acting Commonwealth Attorney and Hugh Scheffey, Esq.,
                        appeared for the State; and J.B. Baldwin and Geo. M. Cochran, Esq'rs, for
                        the prisoner. The grand jury occupied their seats.</p>
                    <p>The first witness examined was Dr. B.B. Donaghe, who testified as to the
                        nature of the wound, assisted by Dr. Fauntleroy, having by request of the
                        coroner, performed an post mortem examination showing that the ball had
                        entered between the forth and fifth ribs shattering the latter and taking an
                        upward course passing through the lungs and heart and lodging under the arm.</p>
                    <p>James O'Brian was next called to the stand.--He was one of the party who
                        entered the rear of the house. Got over the fence and knocked at the
                        door--heard "Who's there?" from within.--Scherer pushed against the door,
                        and it opened. Heard a female scream--went into the room which was quite
                        dark. Saw by the flash of the pistol that there were more persons in the
                        room besides himself; two, he recognized as Scherer and White; he could only
                        see the form of the other, the person who had fired the pistol; knew it was
                        Stanley. Scherer was stooping when the pistol was fired. As soon as he heard
                        the report, he left the house. The man that fired the pistol ran out first,
                        with the weapon in his hand. Scherer ran, or rather reeled after the
                        assassin--and fell about ten yards from the door. The party were all
                        disguised, with faces blackened. Scherer died without uttering a word. The
                        examination of this witness was pretty close; he seemed pretty positive as
                        to the identity of Stanley.</p>
                    <p>Cross-examined by Col. J.B. Baldwin, as to his connection with the
                        trespassing party. Witness said there were ten or eleven in the party, that
                        himself with Scherer and White were detailed to enter and seize the girl,
                        and, if needs be, Stanley, who they supposed was in the house.</p>
                    <p>Col. Baldwin--Who did you receive your orders from--who was your captain.</p>
                    <p>Witness (hesitatingly) We held a meeting, and by agreement each was detailed
                        for a certain duty. We only intended to have a little fun, and drive the
                        people out of the house. At first we intended to duck the girl Ginnie Sorrel
                        and Stanley too--but then, on reflection we thought we'd only punish the
                        girl alone. We had no particular leader.</p>
                    <p>Judge Scheffey--Is Stanley a married man?</p>
                    <p>Witness--I believe he is.</p>
                    <p>Judge Scheffey--Who did he marry?</p>
                    <p>Here Col. Baldwin objected to the question as entirely foreign to the case
                        under consideration; and a spirited debate took place between the two
                        eminent lawyers as to the propriety of such testimony. G.M. Cochran also
                        took part in the debate. The Court decided that the evidence was not
                        admissible, and the examination proceeded.</p>
                    <p>White was then called to stand and questioned by the Commonwealth's Attorney
                        and cross examined by the Council for the prisoner. He saw the woman and
                        heard her cry "murder." In an answer to a question of the Court, he said he
                        did not recognize any deadly weapon until the explosion, which was close to
                        his ear,--the pistol was fired by a person whom he presumed to be Stanley.
                        He was closely cross examined by Col. Baldwin. His general evidence was
                        pretty much the same as that of O'Brian.</p>
                    <p>Dr. Fauntleroy testified as to the nature of the wound and the direction of
                        the ball, which he produced with a piece of shattered rib.</p>
                    <p>J.T. Parrent, Chief of Police, testified as to the arrest of the
                        prisoner--the finding of a four barreled repeater in his possession, and
                        that one barrel had been discharged. The ball was tried and found to fit the
                        discharged barrel.</p>
                    <p>Robert Campbell recognized the pistol as belonging to him. He offered it to
                        Stanley for sale--who took it on trial.</p>
                    <p>James Hess identified the pistol as one that he borrowed from Campbell before
                        Stanley had taken it on trial.</p>
                    <p> Henry Hyer identified the pistol as the one in the possession of
                        Stanley--who requested him to show him how to load it, which he did. He also
                        showed the <emph rend="italic">mysteries</emph> of the fatal instrument. </p>
                    <p> An argument here arose between counsel as to the nature of the evidence
                        produced by the Attorney for the Commonwealth; Col. Baldwin contended that
                            <emph rend="italic">all</emph> the witnesses that appeared before the
                        coroner should be produced in this Court. Mr. Bumgardner, replied that he
                        had caused the girl Ginnie Sorrel to be summoned, that he did not care to
                        examine her, but that she was at the service of the court, if their worships
                        wished to question her. The Court ordered her presence, but, at the
                        suggestion of the counsel for the prisoner, she was set aside. After some
                        discussion, the Court concluded to adjourn until five o'clock in the
                        evening. </p>
                    <p>At 5 o'clock the grand jury again assembled, and the Court proceeded to
                        examine Col. M.G. Harman, who testified to the ownership of the house where
                        the homicide was committed. He stated that the premises were rented by
                        Stanley, and the rent paid by bonds, with the exception of a few dollars.</p>
                    <p> Augustus White was called to the stand. He stated that Stanley had been
                        warned as to the threatened ducking, unless he abandoned his vile
                        associates. His testimony had a bearing on the character of the house. The
                        testimony, &amp;c., was strongly objected to on the part of the
                        prisoner's counsel, who contended that as Stanley had rented the house, he
                        was lord of the manor, and, no matter what was the business of the
                        occupants, it was his castle, and he had a right to repel intruders, who, no
                        matter what might be the <emph rend="italic">morality</emph> of their
                        trespass, were neither more nor less than "regulators," who under a
                        disguise, had taken the law in their hands, and made themselves liable to be
                        killed by the proprietor. Capt. Bumgardner and Judge Scheffey made eloquent
                        replies to the speech of Col. Baldwin. Mr. Cochran made a spirited
                        rejoinder. </p>
                    <p>During the examination the question as to the manner in which the case was to
                        be decided by the Grand Jury, came up. The counsel for the prisoner
                        contended that the magistrates sitting were to certify as to the nature of
                        the case, and that the jury were to make out their indictment on their
                        certificate. Counsel for the State opposed this mode strenuously, and some
                        powerful arguments were used on both sides. The Court was adjourned until
                        Wednesday morning at 8 o'clock.</p>
                    <p>At a quarter after eight the prisoner was brought into Court. The attorney
                        for the Stare, Capt. Bumgardner, opened up with an able speech, laying down
                        the law provided in such cases, and instructing the magistrates as to their
                        duty, he spoke for about an hour.</p>
                    <p>Geo. M. Cochran, Esq., followed on the defense in a speech of about 85
                        minutes. He said that the Commonwealth's Attorney had failed in his opening
                        argument to specify upon what charge he was prosecuting the prisoner at the
                        bar. From the evidence adduced the prisoner was entitled to be discharged as
                        prayed for by his counsel. Saw no grounds on which the learned gentlemen
                        should argue that the sitting justices should not do so. That Capt. B.
                        admitted the deceased was in the commission of an unlawful act. If the
                        justices thought the prisoner had done anything against the law as had been
                        shown by the testimony in the case, it was right that they should discharge
                        him. Mr. Cochran's arguments were able and directly to the point.</p>
                    <p>Col. Baldwin closed the defense in an able and eloquent argument, reviewing
                        the entire testimony, and declaring that under the law the prisoner was
                        justifiable in committing the homicide</p>
                    <p>Judge Scheffey closed the examination in a powerful and ingenious speech of
                        about two hours which was listened to with intense interest by the crowded
                        auditory. The line of his argument was that the prisoner was in adulterous
                        intercourse with the woman, Ginnie Sorrel, at the time the deceased entered
                        the room, and that he was in no danger of bodily harm from the trespassers;
                        but that Stanley had fired the pistol deliberately and "picked his man," and
                        that his flight immediately after firing was proof that he knew that he had
                        committed a felony, and that the justices were in duty bound to send him on.</p>
                    <p>A few moments after the closing of Judge Scheffey's argument, the presiding
                        justices decided that from the evidence brought upon the Court, he was of
                        opinion that the prisoner should be sent on to stand his trial before the
                        Criminal Court; and he therefore remanded him to the custody of the jailor.</p>
                    <p> During the examination, the Court House was crowded to its utmost capacity,
                        and the <sic>intensest</sic> interest was observable in the countenances of
                        all. The old walls rang with the eloquence of past days, as the Counsel on
                        both sides are men of fine forensic endowments. Every one of them paid a
                        handsome tribute to the character of young Scherer, who was popular with all
                        classes of our citizens. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sorrel</ln>
                        <fn>Ginnie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stanley</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parent</ln>
                        <fn>J. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mayor</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pierce</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Justice</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clinedinst</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donaghe</ln>
                        <fn>B. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fauntleroy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Brian</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hess</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hyer</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>Augustus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This lengthy article recounts the story of the killing of a young man and
                    the subsequent trial of the accused killer for murder. As the story unfolds in
                    the courtroom, evidence mounts that the accused--Stanley--fired the weapon that
                    ended the life of Scherer, a young Stauntonian. The question presented to the
                    court is whether the accused was justified in this killing. Circumstances
                    suggest that Stanley was indeed threatened by the unlawful entry of several men,
                    including Scherer, into his house, where not incidentally, "questionable" acts
                    were taking place. While the defense argues that Stanley killed only in
                    self-defense, the prosecution maintained that Stanley acted in haste, and then
                    fled the scene for fear of prosecution. Intense debate between counselors, some
                    of the most prominent in Staunton, creates great interest among Staunton's
                    citizenry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1869.08.26.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
