<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1869/va.au.vv.1869.11.11">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/30/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-11-11">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day norm="">11</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1869.11.11.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1869.11.11.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Way to Build Up Our Town</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Every one who visits Staunton must be impressed with the idea that we have a
                        live population. The spirit of progress is evidently abroad among them. New
                        buildings are going up in all quarters, and many others are being projected.
                        Our streets are crowded with vehicles of all kinds, and the side-walks
                        obstructed by barrels of flour and other products of our fertile soil, in
                        process of delivery to, or shipment by traders. In a word, the whole town
                        wears an aspect of activity, thrift, and prosperity.</p>
                    <p>In contemplating this pleasing spectacle, we are naturally led to examine
                        into the sources of this prosperity, and to enquire how it can best be
                        extended and perpetuated.</p>
                    <p>Our improved agriculture has certainly much to do with it. The public
                        Institutions located in our midst also contribute a good deal to it. But
                        these, by themselves, would be insufficient to bring about such results. As
                        proof of this, we need only refer to the fact, that these sources of
                        prosperity have existed for many years, while the rapid improvement of which
                        we speak, is of comparatively recent date.</p>
                    <p>Two causes, more than all the others, have, we are persuaded, stimulated the
                        development of our town. One is the disposition of our people to give more
                        attention to manufacturers, and the other is the intelligent appreciation by
                        them of the necessity of fostering the admirable female schools which have
                        been established among us.</p>
                    <p>Commerce is a very good thing, but, in an inland town like ours, it cannot be
                        a primary interest. The field is too small to afford employment and support
                        to a great number of persons engaged in trade, and we must look to other
                        means of enlarging our population and business. Commerce, from its very
                        nature, requires but few hands to carry it on. It consists merely in buying
                        and selling, or exchanging the products of industry. The profit of the
                        trader consists only in the difference between the price he gives and the
                        price he receives. And even this profit is subject to large deductions for
                        rents, taxes, clerk hire, &amp;c. The larger part of the merchant's,
                        receipts go abroad, to replenish his stock from jobbers or importers. Upon a
                        final settlement of a merchant's annual business, it will be found his gains
                        are not large, and most of the money which he has received as been sent to
                        the Northern cities, thus leaving the county comparatively stripped of
                        currency.</p>
                    <p>A merchant with an active capital of $20,000 gives employment to but two or
                        three clerks, a porter &amp;c., and in the course of the year, he sends
                        abroad, probably $50,000.</p>
                    <p>But how is it with a manufacturer? With a similar amount of capital, he
                        would, probably, employ in one way or another, fifty people, thereby
                        affording support to them and their families. Take for example our two
                        Foundries, and compare their operations with those of our largest merchants,
                        and see how the balance will stand. The merchants employ, say, six unmarried
                        men, as salesmen and clerks--the manufacturers employ--say 50 men, most of
                        whom have families. The merchants send annually, say $50,000 out of the
                        country, while the manufacturers, annually bring $50,000 into it! The office
                        of one class is to sell and exchange, while that of the other is to combine
                        and create. The manufacturer gives a concrete form to the labor of his
                        employees--he incorporated that labor with the new material, and thus makes
                        it an element of wealth. The manufacturer also affords a market to the land
                        owner for his timber and his minerals, in his workshop and for the products
                        of his farm, in the support of his workmen and their families, gives
                        employment to the tailor, the shoemaker, the school teacher, the grocer, the
                        merchant and others. And the manufacturer, when he sells his fabrics, brings
                        the money into the country, to be disbursed in a way to vivify business in
                        all its departments.</p>
                    <p>Other things being equal, we therefore regard manufacturers as contributing
                        more largely than those of any other occupation, to the general prosperity
                        of the community. And we think it is to the interest of our people to
                        encourage and foster every enterprise of the kind, by extending liberal
                        patronage to home industry. We think, also, that inducements should be held
                        out to persons disposed to engage in manufactures, by exempting their
                        machinery and capital, for a limited time, from taxation.</p>
                    <p>But we find our subject grows upon us, and we must therefore content
                        ourselves, for the present, with these general views. In another issue, we
                        shall take occasion to say something upon the advantages, and prospects of
                        Staunton as a manufacturing town. And we shall also offer some suggestions
                        as to the advantages, and feasibility of making Staunton the centre of
                        female education in the South. We see no reason why the Baptists, the
                        Lutherans and the Catholics, should not each have a first class female
                        school in Staunton. Their enterprising neighbors of the Episcopal,
                        Presbyterian and Methodist churches, have set them a good example. Let the
                        other sects see that they are not left behind in the laudable race for
                        knowledge and enlightenment.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article outlines two reasons for the stimulated development of
                    Staunton. First, manufacturers have done a great deal to increase economic
                    prosperity by providing direct employment to many Stauntonians, as well as
                    indirectly creating the need for a number of supportive industries such as
                    tailors and shoemakers. Further, while many merchants make money and invest it
                    elsewhere, manufacturers bring money into the area. Second, educational
                    institutions are on the rise, especially the female academy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Death of George Peabody</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper announces the death of philanthropist George Peabody.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1869.11.11.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The London Miltonian Tableaux of "Paradise Lost" was exhibited in the
                    Masonic Building in Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stanley</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The trial of John M. Stanley for the murder of Jacob Scherer resulted in a
                    verdict of not guilty. Mr. Bumgardner and Mr. Sheffey argued for the
                    Commonwealth, and Mr. Baldwin and Mr. Cochran for the defense. Judge Fultz
                    presided.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pitzer</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dolly</ln>
                        <fn>S. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rice</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. W. E. Hill of Richmond and Miss Jennie K. Pitzer of Covington were
                    married at the residence of the bride's father on October 28th by the Rev. S. B.
                    Dolly. The Rev. James M. Rice assisted.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Runnells</ln>
                        <fn>William D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Terrell</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William D. Runnells and Miss Virginia A. Terrell of Waynesboro were married
                    at the residence of the bride's father on November 2nd by the Rev. C. Beard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCune</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ramsey</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Col. Samuel McCune and Miss Mary E. Ramsey, both of Augusta, were married
                    near Waynesboro on October 28th by the Rev. C. Beard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fawber</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>Mollie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bushong</ln>
                        <fn>A. A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph M. Fawber and Miss Mollie J. Baylor, both of Augusta, were married
                    on October 28th by the Rev. A. A. J. Bushong.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Larew</ln>
                        <fn>William J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Graham</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lambeth</ln>
                        <fn>S. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William J. Larew and Miss Elizabeth P. Graham, both of Augusta, were
                    married in Greenville on November 2nd by the Rev. S. S. Lambeth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchell</ln>
                        <fn>J. Tuley</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>Bettie W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witherson</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. Tuley Mitchell, Jr., of Augusta, and Miss Bettie W. Young of Nelson were
                    married at the residence of the bride's brother on November 4th by the Rev. J.
                    Witherson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coffman</ln>
                        <fn>Jefferson P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cupp</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Follanshee</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jefferson P. Coffman and Miss Catharine M. Cupp, both of Augusta, were
                    married on November 2nd by the Rev. James M. Follanshee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trueheart</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prof. Trueheart and Miss Sallie Myers, both of the Wesleyan Female School,
                    were married on November 10th by the Rev. William A. Harris.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1869.11.11.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
