<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1869/va.au.vv.1869.03.04">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/15/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-03-04">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="02">March</month>
            <day norm="">4</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1869.03.04.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1869.03.04.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Inauguration Day</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper announces that today is inauguration day for General Grant. "We
                    shall soon know our fate. In other words, it will be 'sunshine or shade' in the
                    South."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The New Movement</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> The Richmond <emph rend="italic">Whig,</emph> in speaking of this "special
                        privilege," gives Congress a rather severe rap upon the knuckles. Wonder if
                        some of the recently "converted" hereaways do not envy "friend" Monard in
                        his "special privilege"--stink, money, and all? </p>
                    <p>Monsieur Monard, the colored gentleman who claimed a seat in Congress from
                        Louisiana, made a speech the other day in support of his pretensions. He
                        concluded by the condescending assurance that he <emph rend="italic"
                            >"claimed no special privileges on account of his color."</emph> We are
                        not told what effect this complimentary assurance and self-denial had upon
                        the House; but while he was refused the seat to which he had no shadow of
                        right, he was allowed $2,500--for what? For waving the <emph rend="italic"
                            >privilege of his color?</emph> Well, what is that privilege? This is
                        becoming an important and practical question. Some of the Wendell Phillips
                        school tell us that the original man was black, and that, being made in the
                        image of God, God himself was black, and that consequently the pale faces
                        are degenerates, or, according to the Cincinnati philosopher, not human
                        beings at all. We know not the authority for all this; but if true, we had
                        better take back seats at once, and frankly recognize the <emph
                            rend="italic">privilege of color.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Despite the title, this article digresses from a discussion of the new
                    movement to a condemnation of the black Congressman from Louisiana. Monard, the
                    author claims, rejects any special privilege due to color, yet acts on these
                    privileges by taking financial compensation when his seat has been denied.
                    Privilege of color has become an important question and includes what the author
                    thinks of as the preposterous idea that God himself is black.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Another New Movement</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A group of gentlemen met in Washington to discuss plans for development of
                    the South. Captain Hotchkiss attended. They called for putting material interest
                    over political difference.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Southern Prosperity</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article describing the abundant natural resources of the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Newest "New Movement"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>When Henry A. Wise acted with the Whig party, his motto was "the union of
                        Whigs for the sake of the Union." Now under existing circumstances would it
                        not be well for the people of Virginia to rally under a banner bearing the
                        motto, "the union of Virginians for the sake of Virginia."</p>
                    <p>The recent action of Congress in removing all the officers of the State who
                        could not take the test oath was intended for a set of Carpet-baggers, and
                        no sooner was the resolution passed in the House than thousands of them
                        rushed to Richmond, ready to enjoy the feast prepared for them. And what has
                        been the result so far? In nearly every instance all the offices that were
                        supposed to be worth anything in the way of pickings had been given to the
                        Carpet-baggers.--The native Union men and the Scalawags have been left out
                        or put in such little and inferior offices as no Carpet-bagger would have or
                        none could be found to fill. This is the case all over the State so far as I
                        have been able to learn. And such will continue to be the case as long as
                        the State remains under the present Carpet-bag dynasty.</p>
                    <p>Our native Union men, and even the Scalawags must see this, and feel it too,
                        so far as their hopes and aspirations for office are concerned, and I submit
                        this question to them: Is it not better to unite with your friends and
                        neighbors--those whom you have known long and well--and who have respect for
                        you and your honest opinion, than to longer affiliate with a set of vultures
                        who have come down here from everywhere to prey upon the very vitals of your
                        State and to eat up the substance of yourselves and neighbors?</p>
                    <p>These Carpet-baggers care not a whit for you or the fate of your State and
                        people.--Their whole object is to plunder and they care not from whom so
                        they get it. They own no property to be taxed or suffer in depreciation by
                        the bad government they put upon us. Plunder is all they are here for and
                        plunder they will have as long as they can get it.</p>
                    <p> The present seems to me the proper time for a reconciliation among those who
                        have differed as to the proper course to pursue in regard to the
                        reconstruction of the State.--A large portion of the conservative party has
                        been forced to the conviction that negro suffrage is bound to be the basis
                        upon which any reconstruction we can get must rest, and our entire people
                        will soon come to the same conviction. What is the use then of any portion
                        of our people uniting themselves with the Radical party, and playing into
                        the hands of the Carpet-baggers? It is like "cutting off your nose to spite
                        your face." --<emph rend="italic">Correspondence of Fincastle
                    Herald</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Fervently attacking carpetbaggers, the author suggests Union men,
                    scalawags, and other white southerners unite against the plundering "set of
                    vultures." This is the best path to reconstruction. Following new movement
                    logic, the author concludes that black suffrage is a political fact and should
                    be accepted through making the best from bad circumstances. The carpetbagger is
                    the real enemy, and those who give in to the radical party are only playing into
                    the hands of vultures.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1869.03.04.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Temperance</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James W. Baldwin will speak before Staunton's Temperance Council, No. 47.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Sibert Co.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that ground has been broken at Buffalo Gap for one of
                    three furnaces that will make up Sibert Steel. Workers are chopping wood, "ore
                    is convenient and abundant, and friend Sibert in the best of spirits. What a
                    change in the appearance of things in that section may we expect."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Valentine</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burgess</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John C. Valentine of Augusta and Miss Sarah F. Burgess of Albemarle were
                    married on February 18th by the Rev. Mr. Bowman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>William B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William B. Garber and Nancy J. Grove, both of Augusta, were married on
                    February 18th by the Rev. Martin Garber.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>Mattie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Mattie Byers died in Staunton at the residence of her father on
                    February 22nd. She was 25 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Butler</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas Butler died in his Staunton residence on February 22nd. He was 66
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>Ann E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Ann E. Walker died at her residence near New Hope, Augusta County, on
                    February 5th. She was 53 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCreary</ln>
                        <fn>John L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John L. McCreary died in his residence in Augusta on February 15th. He was
                    36 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1869.03.04.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
