<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1861/va.au.rv.1861.02.22">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Colleen Doody</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/7/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1861-02-22">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>22</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1861.02.22.01">
            <pageNote>Speech of Hon. John T. Harris, columns 3-7</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1861.02.22.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Rev. J.W. Greer of Charlotte will preach in the Baptist Church for several
                    nights beginning next Tuesday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Party Complexion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Party Complexion</p>
                    <p>It is known to every one that in the recent canvass for Delegates to the
                        State Convention, everything like old party lines was obliterated. By this
                        means, it happens that a majority of those elected are of the Whig party.
                        Instead of carrying out the catholic spirit by which they were sent to
                        Richmond, the Convention has been organized upon the strictest party policy,
                        and Democracy considered an insuperable disqualification for any important
                        position. It is emphatically a <emph rend="italic">Whig or Opposition
                            Convention,</emph> indebted for its success, however, to an ingenious
                        and well concealed deception of the people. And, mark the prediction, the
                        legislation of this Convention will have a more immediate reference to the
                        supremacy of the party faith of the dominant political sentiment there, than
                        to the primary object for which the body was convened. Whilst, by the
                        irresistible influence of events, it may be <emph rend="italic"
                        >forced</emph> to take position [sic], it will not be until precious hours
                        have been consumed in an attempted effort to consolidate a powerful party
                        against the Democracy, and resurrect the fossil remains of the various
                        competitors slain upon the political highways of the country by the
                        shibboleth of Democracy. We warn Democrats in advance. The thing must be
                        strangled in its infancy.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes the Whigs, who have made the State Convention into a party
                    vehicle.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvfeb61.html#2.22a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Position of Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Position of Virginia</p>
                    <p>It will be seen by the proceedings of the Convention that the resolutions of
                        Mr. Marr of Fauquier, and Mr. Flournoy, of Halifax, partake of the right
                        spirit. These gentlemen were elected as Union men, and are looked upon
                        abroad as submissionists. The resolutions indicate the character of their
                        submission. They take precisely the position we now occupy, and that which
                        we have advocated ever since the Convention bill passed. It is the position
                        to which the Convention <emph rend="italic">will be driven</emph> by the
                        force of circumstances; and call it <emph rend="italic">secession,
                            revolution,</emph> or whatever it may please the fastidious, Virginia
                        will be <emph rend="italic">forced</emph> to separate from the Northern
                        States, if security, ample and comprehensive, is not given for the future.
                        It is useless to talk about <emph rend="italic">preserving</emph> the Union,
                        we again repeat. It is gone, so far as the six States are concerned, and if
                        the causes which made them leave are not removed, Virginia will also go.
                        This fact, the people might as well look full in the face.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>States that two delegates to the State Convention have expressed the view
                    of the Vindicator--that "Virginia will be forced to separate from the Northern
                    States, if security, ample and comprehensive, is not given for the future."</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvfeb61.html#2.22b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Southern Confederacy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Claims that the Confederacy will soon have $14 million and fifty regiments
                    of soldiers at its command. If Lincoln attempts to blockade the Southern ports,
                    the Confederate army will capture Washington, D.C.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Look at the Figures</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Look at the Figures</p>
                    <p>S. McD. Moore, Esq., one of the delegates in the State Convention from
                        Rockbridge, in some remarks the other day, intimated, or rather stated, that
                        the reason for the extreme submission views he entertained was the
                        probability of the Southern Confederacy re-opening the African slave trade
                        and establishing free trade and direct taxation. Had Mr. Moore read the
                        fundamental law of the New Confederacy, he would there have found a clause
                            <emph rend="italic">forever prohibiting</emph> the African slave trade.
                        Had he read the proceedings of the Convention he would there have seen that
                        a revenue tariff is to be adopted, sufficient for the support of the
                        government. We must attribute Mr. Moore's remarks to ignorance of these
                        facts, and not a wilful intention to misrepresent actual history.</p>
                    <p>But suppose the cotton States were disposed to open the African slave trade
                        and adopt free trade, would not they be at the mercy of the other slave
                        States, were the entire South to unite? Look at the figures: South Carolina,
                        under the new apportionment, in Congress, would have 4 representatives;
                        Georgia 7; Florida 1; Alabama 7; Mississippi 5; Louisiana 4; Texas 4. Total
                        31.</p>
                    <p>The other slave States would stand thus: Virginia 11; Delaware 1; Maryland 6;
                        North Carolina 7; Tennessee 8; Kentucky 8; Missouri 9; Arkansas 3. Total 52.</p>
                    <p>It will be seen that there would be a majority of twenty-one against the
                        Cotton States, even supposing that the seven States first named were
                        unanimous for opening the slave trade, and for free importations. How would
                        any proposition for such a purpose be treated? We leave it for the common
                        sense of the reader to determine. If Mr. Moore bases his position alone upon
                        his assumption, he must forsake his submission ideas, for the facts are
                        against him.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Rejects the assertion of Mr. Moore, a delegate to the State Convention from
                    Rockbridge, that the Southern Confederacy wants to reopen the slave trade.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvfeb61.html#2.22c</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Mr. Harris' Speech</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator directs its readers attention to the speech of the Hon. John
                    T. Harris, Congressman from the local district, printed elsewhere in the paper.
                    However, the paper states that it must "express our unqualified dissent from
                    some of the positions it assumes and the arguments advanced."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Treason and Traitors</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The New York Courier and Enquirer, the organ of the conservative,
                    anti-abolitionist wing of the Republican party, has called for Lincoln to arrest
                    and try as traitors Jefferson Davis and Alexander Stevens. The Vindicator
                    believes that this is clear evidence that the coercion policy is to be
                    "vigorously adopted" by the administration.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Baltimore Conference</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>As the time for the assembly of the Baltimore Conference draws closer, many
                    Methodists are anxiously awaiting its actions on the question of slavery. The
                    actions of the General Conference of the M.E. Church last spring have "laid the
                    seeds of a revolution."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Relief for Editors</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator urges the state Legislature to authorize the banks of
                    Virginia to issue bank notes of denominations less than five dollars. The lack
                    of small bills has made it difficult to transact ordinary business.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Inauguration of President Jefferson Davis</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Text of Jefferson Davis' inauguration address.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator calls on the Virginia State Convention to take a "firm and
                    decisive stand" if Virginia is to maintain her honor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1861.02.22.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Scene in Hades</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An allegory about Union and secession featuring the Devil and his minions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arnold</ln>
                        <fn>D.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pool</ln>
                        <fn>Richard N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hite</ln>
                        <fn>Josie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on February 14.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blakemore</ln>
                        <fn>J.L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bazzel</ln>
                        <fn>Reuben B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Horn</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on January 31.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lushbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Horace Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lushbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>William Dorsy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lushbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Horace and William, ages 6 years and 3 years respectively, died of Scarlet
                    Fever on February 17 and Febuary 19.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Minutes of the Virginia State Convention, columns 1 and 2</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1861.02.22.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
