<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1861/va.au.rv.1861.03.08">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Colleen Doody</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/7/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1861-03-08">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="08">8</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1861.03.08.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Inauguration of President Davis</head>
                <origin>Montgomery Advertiser</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the inaugural procession and ceremony of Jefferson Davis in
                    Montgomery, Alabama.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Speech of Col. Geo. Baylor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprint of the text of Col. Baylor's lengthy speech at the State
                    Convention. In his speech, Baylor argued that Virginia should not leave the
                    Union. He stated that, while Southern states should demand the repeal of
                    Personal Liberty laws, these laws are not sufficient reason to destroy the
                    Union. He also questioned the constitutionality of secession.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Report of the Peace Conference, column 3</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1861.03.08.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Dedication of the M.E. Church</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Dedication of the M.E. Church</p>
                    <p>The new M.E. Church in this place will be dedicated on Sabbath next. Several
                        distinguished Ministers from a distance are expected to be in attendance, by
                        whom the exercises will be conducted.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The new church will be dedicated next Sunday.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmar61.html#3.8a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Col. Baylor's Speech</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator directs its readers' attention to the text of Col. Baylor's
                    speech, reprinted on page one. The paper completely disagrees with Col. Baylor,
                    arguing that his policies would be fatal to "the honor, the prosperity, and the
                    independence, not only of Virginia, but the entire South." However, the
                    Vindicator believes that "when the bugle blast of the Democracy sounds the
                    rallying note for the conflict with Federalism, we expect to stand side by side
                    with him, as in days gone by, in battling against our lifelong foe."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Action of the Peace Conference</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We regard it [e.g. the Peace Conference] as a significant verification of
                    the fact that the free States do not mean to make any concession to the just
                    demands of Virginia and the South, but to seek by every agency to seduce us into
                    fatal delay, and when too late for successful resistance, to plant the iron
                    [illegible] of power upon us to compel submission to Black Republican iniquity
                    and out- [illegible]."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator rejects the report of the Peace Conference. The report
                    proposed to prohibit slavery north of 36 degrees 30 minutes, prohibit the
                    acquisition of any more territory that could be made into a slave state, forbid
                    the passing of slaves through free territory, reaffirm the prohibition on the
                    slave trade, and provide that all the states would pay for any escaped slaves
                    who had been seized by abolitionists to prevent them from being returned South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"The Spectator attempts . . .</p>
                    <p>The Spectator attempts to be very severe on Senators Mason and Hunter,
                        because they opposed in the Senate the report of the Peace Conference, and
                        says they "paid no respect to the voice of Virginia, recently expressed in
                        thunder-tones at the polls." Our neighbor is not authorized, as we conceive,
                        to assume as a verity in advance, that the people of Virginia are willing to
                        enslave themselves by adopting or acquiescing in the proposition of the
                        Peace Conference. That body originated at the suggestion of the Virginia
                        Legislature, which at the same time endorsed the Crittenden amendments as
                        the basis of adjustment, and nothing like the ambiguous and jesuitical
                        emanation of the Peace Congress. We, as every one who reads our paper, well
                        knows, have no especial partiality for either Mr. Mason or Mr. Hunter, nor
                        is it our purpose or inclination to defend their past course, but in this
                        instance we think they represented the sentiment of Virginia. If they did
                        not, then Virginia ought to array herself under the black flag of Lincoln,
                        and exclaim, Allah is great and Mahomet is prophet. <emph rend="italic"
                            >Libertad y deos.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Disagrees with the Spectator's criticisms of Mr. Mason and Mr. Hunter and
                    argues that these men accurately represented the sentiment of Virginia when they
                    opposed the report of the Peace Conference.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmar61.html#3.8b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"Judge Jno. W. Brockenbrough . . . "</p>
                    <p>Judge Jno. Brockenbrough, one of the Commissioners from Virginia to the Peace
                        Congress, passed through Staunton on the 4th, on his way to his home in
                        Lexington. In a brief conversation with the Judge, he expressed it as his
                        opinion that there was very little hope of an adjustment of our national
                        difficulties. He regards the amendment to the Constitution proposed by Mr.
                        Corwin, and the report of the Peace Commissioners, as mere patch work, and
                        falling immeasurably short of a remedy, or a just and fair basis of
                        settlement. The Judge seemed to feel exceedingly despondent for the country,
                        and loth to contemplate the sad disasters which loom up in the future for
                        the only truly free government in the world.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Judge Brockenbrough, one of the Commissioners from Virginia to
                    the Peace Congress, passed through Staunton on March 4th. He told the editor of
                    the Vindicator that "there was very little hope of an adjustment of our national
                    difficulties."</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmar61.html#3.8c</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Chicago Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Times claims that John Brown, Jr. and Fred Douglass plan to enlist
                    8,000 black residents of Canada.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter to Mr. Yost, editor of the Vindicator, that expresses the writer's
                    agreement with Yost's view that Virginia should join the Southern Confederacy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1861.03.08.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Inauguration of Mr. Lincoln</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Text of Lincoln's inaugural address.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Military Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Randolph</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>A.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruff</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>W.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sterrett</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A meeting was held for all the officiers of the local Volunteer Companies.
                    At the meeting a motion was passed to form a volunteer regiment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheeler</ln>
                        <fn>J.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gregory</ln>
                        <fn>Nicholas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on February 28.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wetzel</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Landes</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alexander</ln>
                        <fn>Delila E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on February 28.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nicholson</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nicholson</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nicholson</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Nicholson died on February 14 at age 6.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>Washington</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Margaret Patterson died on February 4 near Fishersville. She was a member
                    of the Evangelical Lutheran Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>David W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on February 19.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1861.03.08.04">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
