<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1861/va.au.rv.1861.03.15">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Colleen Doody</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/7/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1861-03-15">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>15</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1861.03.15.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Peace Commissioners</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator reprints a lengthy communication from Judge Brockenbrough to
                    the President of the Peace Conference. In it, Brockenbrough expresses his
                    preference for the Crittenden plan over the Peace Conference report. He
                    expresses his objections to two major parts of the Peace Conference report: the
                    first section, which dealt with the question of slavery in the territories, and
                    the seventh section, which "provides for the payment of the full value of
                    fugitive slaves by the United States in all cases where the officers, charged
                    with the duty of making the arrest, is prevented from so doing by violence or
                    intimidation, or when after arrest, the slaves are rescued." This final section
                    would force the public treasury, including the Southern states, to pay for the
                    actions of abolitionists.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Lincoln's War Policy</head>
                <origin>Richmond Examiner</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Lincoln's War Policy</p>
                    <p>The Washington correspondent of the Richmond <emph rend="italic"
                        >Examiner</emph> says:</p>
                    <p>In Southern circles here little doubt is entertained as to the policy and
                        purpose of the Inaugural address. It is believed Mr. Lincoln will proceed,
                        without delay, to adopt hostile measures against the South. A collision in
                        less than a week is quite possible. This may grow out of an attempt to
                        collect revenue at the South, to reinforce Forts Sumter [sic] and Pickens,
                        or to retake other places. The words, "hold, occupy and possess," in
                        reference to the forts and other coast points in the South, coupled with the
                        special reservations made as to <emph rend="italic">interior</emph> places
                        where residents cannot be induced to hold offices, are full of meaning. They
                        teach us to be prepared for war at a moment's notice, and those recreant
                        Virginians whose base hearts throb with sympathy for the North may at once
                        prepare their cartridges for a fight with their own neighbors.</p>
                    <p>In army circles the reinforcement of Fort Sumter is proposed to be effected
                        in a stealthy mode at first, by sending down a ship provided with good seat
                        boats, who are to go in by night from the sea, take advantage of bad
                        weather, fogs and an imperfect vigilance of the South Carolina steamers
                        posted on the look out, and thus get men enough in Fort Sumpter to resist an
                        assault. After this is done, four or five war vessels will then essay to
                        force their way in, and Major Anderson will open fire to sustain them.</p>
                    <p>It is not unlikely this plan may be hit upon, but I am included to think a
                        prior step will be the repudiation by the Government of agreement made at
                        Pensacola by the late Administration. Orders will be sent to Lieut. Slemmer,
                        commanding Fort Pickens, to take men from the slip to reinforce the
                        garrison, to bring in the war vessels, and to demand a surrender of the Navy
                        Yard by the officers of the Provisional Government.</p>
                    <p>Such are some of the steps likely to be taken by the Government to bring on
                        the war they covet. They rely upon their ability to whip the South, and
                        count extensively on help from Andrew Johnson and the men like him in your
                        Convention. Lincoln does not know these men. Their treason lies in hatching
                        plots, and will shrink from the open field where they will have to confront
                        the brave and true men of the South.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Washington correspondent of the Richmond Examiner believes that Lincoln
                    will adopt "hostile measures against the South" very soon.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmar61.html#3.15a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1861.03.15.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>To the Democracy of Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that there will be a meeting of the Augusta Democratic party on
                    the first day of March court for the purpose of appointing delegates to the
                    Harrisonburg District Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>District Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We are favorable to this policy solely for the purpose of uniting the
                    Democracy of the District, and presenting to the voters a candidate who can beat
                    back the wave of Federalism that threatens to overwhelm the dearest rights of
                    the States and the people."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator expresses its support of the plan to hold a convention of
                    the Augusta Democrats in Harrisonburg for the purpose of nominating a candidate
                    for Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Convention and Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Whenever the utterance of Black Republican sentiment in the Virginia
                    Convention is met by merited rebuke, forthwith the threat is made that the
                    collection of fossils and ghosts will be removed to Staunton."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator denies that the people of Augusta sympathize with the
                    Republicans, although the paper recognizes that the statements of the county's
                    delegates to the State Convention "has created the belief that we are a people
                    who would quietly submit to any insult to our section, however outrageous."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Augusta in the Legislature</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises Bolivar Christian for being an influential and efficient member of
                    the state Legislature. The paper also lauds Col. McCue and Mr. Massie for being
                    "gentlemen and representatives of high standing and character in Richmond."
                    Augusta thus should be proud of the character of her representatives in the
                    lower house.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Dedication</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phelps</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooks</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The new M.E. Church was dedicated on the last Sabbath.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Convention Committee Report</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator directs its readers' attention to the report of both the
                    majority and the minority of the Committee on Federal Relations, printed on page
                    three. The paper praises the report written by James Barbour, who argued that
                    Virginia should enter into negotiations with the Confederacy, now that the
                    state's peace offerings had all been rejected by the Federal government. The
                    Vindicator strongly condemns the report of Col. Baldwin, which is believes is an
                    "abject submission to Black Republican insult, outrage and oppression."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls for the State Convention to either act or adjourn.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>A Virtue of Necessity</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>The movement of troops into Washington is akin to "holding the lash of
                    abolition power and hate over the back of Virginia, and telling her that any
                    attempt on her part to assert her independence or resume her original
                    sovereignty, will call down upon her the vengeance of a mercenary army. . ."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the rumored order to evacuate Fort Sumpter is not an act of
                    pacification by the Lincoln administration. Instead, according to the
                    Vindicator, the administration realized that it was impossible to re-enforce the
                    fort. The editor points to the administrations actions on the frontier to prove
                    that the administration is in fact preparing for war. Troops have been ordered
                    to leave the western territories and reinforce Washington.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Southern Confederacy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Southern Confederacy.</p>
                    <p>The Southern Confederacy is gradually progressing in a career of eminent
                        success. With the flower of the American Army in command of 50,000 well
                        drilled troops; the most gifted and experienced statesmen of the age in
                        charge of its civil departments; a treasury well supplied with funds; and
                        sustained by the hearts and hands of a united people, the new Confederacy
                        bids fair to become one of the most successful and prosperous governments on
                        the globe. Its foundation are being carefully and firmly laid; its columns
                        erected to meet all the shocks and throes incident to new enterprises, and
                        its arches formed to bear the weight of an empire baptised in blood, if
                        needs be. The idea of this government ever again uniting with a people whose
                        entire education is enmity and whose highest ambition is oppression,
                        aggression and outrage, is simply preposterous. Such a thing is not dreamed
                        of by the statesmen who are directing the affairs of the Confederate States.
                        Every act is looking directly to the establishment of a firm, united and
                        powerful government, sufficient for all the exigencies of peace or war.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the foundations of the new Confederacy are being firmly laid.
                    This Confederate government will never unite with "a people whose entire
                    education is enmity and whose highest ambition is oppression, aggression and
                    outrage."</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmar61.html#3.15b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The People Pay It</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The State Convention has cost the people of Virginia sixty thousand
                    dollars, and yet it has done nothing, according to the Vindicator.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Virginia--the Battle Ground</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Virginia--the Battle Ground</p>
                    <p>We have good reason to believe that our State has been selected as the <emph
                            rend="italic">grand</emph> arena for the display of Black Republican
                        prowess--that our people have been marked as the victims for Black
                        Republican vengeance. The concentration of forces about Washington city--a
                        point convenient to Fortress Monroe and the Virginia line--the unusual
                        precaution exercised in reference to points over which federal authority
                        extends in Virginia--the increase of federal soldiery in our midst--are all
                        prominent facts of evidence driving us to the conclusion that the State
                        which gave the soldier who won our liberties, and the statesman who
                        fortified them with constitutional barriers, is to be the first to meet the
                        shock of Black Republican invasion. The people's representatives in Richmond
                        perceive this--some acknowledge this--and yet there has been no act passed,
                        nor movement effected, calculated to detach Virginia from the anaconda folds
                        of this hideous centralism, and place her where she can resist the
                        machinations and devices of her enemies. </p>
                    <p>Lincoln threatens coercion, yet our Convention hesitates to secede; the Peace
                        Conference patch-work is repudiated by Congress, yet the Convention
                        hesitates to secede; the starved forces of the Government are whistled from
                        Fort Sumpter, and thrown into Fortress Monroe or Washington city, yet the
                        Convention hesitates to secede; the brand of infamy and inequality is ready
                        to be impressed, hissing hot, into our flesh, yet the Convention hesitates
                        to secede; the Southern Confederation opens wide its gates and beseeches
                        Virginia to take her stand under the folds of that banner which bears upon
                        it the blessed motto of Constitutional freedom and State equality, yet the
                        Convention hesitates to secede. Are the Freemen of Virginia ready to
                        acknowledge the inequality and inferiority of their State? Have they
                        prepared their minds to witness the most revolting spectacle ever yet
                        presented to the gaze of civilization--the voluntary abandonment, by
                        representatives of a free people, of all that ennobles humanity and elevates
                        social existence? Honor, freedom, justice, good faith, all are to be crushed
                        under the Juggernaut of abolition villainy. We put it to the farmer, the
                        mechanic, the professional man, to men of every grade of wealth and every
                        occupation, if this deed shall be perpetrated by the Convention with
                        impunity? We can answer for the people of the country that they are not now,
                        and never will be, willing to pass from a state of freedom to a condition of
                        vassalage--to bend their necks to the yoke of abolition servitude. The
                        Convention cannot consign us to Northern despotism. The programme may be
                        made out--the gyves all finished and furnished to conventional order by
                        abolition hands. Yet ultimately Virginia is as certain to disconnect herself
                        from the North, and unite with her natural allies of the South, as that
                        infamy attaches to the one, and honor is the controlling principle of the
                        other. The Convention may delay--the Convention may jeopardize our
                        safety--the Convention may put to useless sacrifice many valuable lives, but
                        the people of Virginia, in the strength of that integrity and power and
                        patriotism, high above all Conventions, will force their representatives to
                        strike the blow in behalf of that civil, religious and political liberty
                        which constitutes the chief glory and pride of our beloved Commonwealth.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator believes that Virginia has been chosen as "the grand arena
                    for the display of Black Republican prowess" since the federal government has
                    been amassing troops around Washington.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmar61.html#3.15c</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Baltimore Conference</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Baltimore Conference.</p>
                    <p>This body has new under consideration the propriety of an immediate
                        withdrawal from the General Conference, in consequence of the "New Chapter"
                        of the Buffalo Conference in 1860, antagonistic to, and denunciatory of
                        slavery. The Rev. Mr. Griffith, a man grown gray in the cause of Methodism,
                        characterized the Chapter as immoral, false and heretical; whilst Rev.
                        Norval Wilson, in a speech of signal ability, replete with the most cogent
                        argument, advocated an immediate separation from the Methodists north of
                        Mason and Dixon's line. We write this at the conclusion of Rev. Mr. Phelp's
                        advocacy of a continued union with the General Conference. The effort of
                        this gentleman was as ineffective and impotent, as the course which he
                        advised is impolitic and suicidal. An analysis of his speech would present
                        excitability, fustian sophistry and error. We do not propose to assert that
                        the gentleman embraces wrong intelligently--we have no means of
                        understanding if this is the case; but assuming the most charitable view in
                        reference to his position, we must express our sentiments of regret that the
                        Church and its prospects are to be afflicted, perhaps blighted, by ignorance
                        so obtuse. Mr. Phelps, at the same time that he resists the plan of
                        separation, attacks it from the masked battery of Southern devotion.
                        Pretending to esteem the continuance of slavery as essentially right and
                        proper, he still prefers to remain in connection with a Church which
                        denounces it as infamous. Assuming to shelter and protect his erring
                        brethren of the North under the wing of an enlarged virtue, he would also
                        embrace the institution of negro slavery as eminently wise and proper. The
                        strong point of his argument, if any point could be found weaker than
                        another, was, that the Baltimore Conference should rather seek to throttle
                        vice than evade it--that the errors of the Northern mind should be
                        dissipated by the light of Southern reason, and not be deprived of that
                        light forever. We acknowledge that virtue should seek vice for the purpose
                        of correcting it; but when vice, as in the present case, establishes its
                        most infamous propositions as important principles of a Church creed, and
                        requires virtue to endorse and propagate them, then the good and true and
                        just men, whether in the pulpit or in the congregation, must refuse an
                        alliance so revolting to human nature--so subversive of the teachings of an
                        enlightened morality and Biblical precept.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Baltimore Conference of the M.E. Church is currently considering
                    whether it should withdraw from the General Conference, which adopted the "New
                    Chapter" on slavery in 1860.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmar61.html#3.15d</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Baltimore Conference</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator reprints the minutes of the annual sessions of the Baltimore
                    Conference of the M.E. Church, which is being held in Staunton. The prime topic
                    of discussion was the new chapter on slavery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Why the Deception</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes A.H.H. Stuart for deceiving Augusta voters. During the election
                    for the State Convention, Stuart claimed that his duties as a delegate to the
                    Convention would not conflict with his legislative duties. However, both the
                    Convention and the Legislature actually meet at the same time in different
                    buildings. As a result, Stuart is giving short shrift to Augusta's concerns,
                    even as he is drawing salaries for both positions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>States that a mistake was made--a letter was printed in last week's paper
                    that was intended for Mr. Yost's private consideration only.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Correspondence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newman</ln>
                        <fn>James C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mullinax</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waggoner</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharp</ln>
                        <fn>Jos.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nicholas</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gum</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newman</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mullinax</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waggoner</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gum</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wimer</ln>
                        <fn>Nicholas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waggoner</ln>
                        <fn>Solo</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newman</ln>
                        <fn>Salisbury</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The men listed above request that James H. Skinner make his "views upon the
                    present distracted condition of our country" known to them. They ask because
                    some members of the "Union Party" have called Skinner an extreme secessionists.
                    In his reply, Skinner states that he is supports the Union, but he believes that
                    a perpetuation of the Union requires the slaveholding states to support a
                    concert of action. He argues that a united South might have checked
                    abolitionism. He believes that the Union has been "irreparably dissolved" and
                    that the North will never provide adequate protection to property [i.e. slaves]
                    in the territories.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1861.03.15.03">
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Spectator and Coercion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Spectator and Coercion.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Editor: Your neighbor of the Spectator, in his zeal to bind us to Black
                        Republican misrule, has been laboring to show that the <emph rend="italic"
                            >"chief object"</emph> had in view in the formation of the present
                        Constitution of the United States was to <emph rend="italic">"preserve the
                            Union,"</emph> and that the <emph rend="italic">"great defect"</emph> of
                        the old Confederation consisted in its <emph rend="italic">"inability to
                            preserve it"</emph>-- the Union.</p>
                    <p>This, in a certain sense, is true--but not as the editor seems to understand
                        it.</p>
                    <p>The old articles of Confederation proved wholly inadequate to secure an
                        efficient government for the special purposes designed by the States. Hence
                        it was falling rapidly into popular disfavor, and <emph rend="italic">in
                            danger of dissolution.</emph></p>
                    <p>[Illegible], and in this sense alone, <emph rend="italic">the present
                            Constitution became necessary for the preservation of the Union.</emph></p>
                    <p>The idea of the Spectator, however, appears to be that the object was simply
                        to clothe the Federal Government <emph rend="italic">with power to coerce
                            the States to its authority.</emph> This, he argues, indeed, was the
                            <emph rend="italic">"chief object"</emph>! The "common defense" and
                        "general welfare" of the States, were of course secondary and subordinate!
                        The absurdity of such a proposition (to say nothing of its monstrosity,) is
                        too palpable for serious refutation.</p>
                    <p>The editor reads history to little purpose, if he can see, in the extracts
                        which he makes, any support for the Black Republican doctrine of Coercion.
                        Ours is emphatically a Government of Opinion, not of Force; and the only
                        ligaments of Union between the States are interest and affection.</p>
                    <p>The Federal Government is a mere emanation from the Sovereignties of the
                        States, and the present Constitution was designed simply to create a more
                        efficient Agent for management of their general interests; one which would
                        work unobstructedly in its distinctly prescribed sphere, free from the
                        delays and cumbrous clogs of separate State cooperation. So jealous, indeed,
                        were the framers of the Constitution in guarding against the idea of
                        Consolidation, that the word "National" was stricken out of the Constitution
                        as originally drafted, without a dissenting voice.</p>
                    <p>STATE RIGHTS.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter to the editor in which the writer argues against the Spectator's
                    interpretation of the Constitution and the Articles of Confederation.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmar61.html#3.15e</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Who's Afraid?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Who's Afraid?</p>
                    <p>The advocates of "Reference" previous to the election of delegates to the
                        Convention, delighted to dwell on the Sovereignty of the people and their
                        right to determine by their votes the future destiny of Virginia. The
                        proposition has been made in the shape of a resolution that the people shall
                        have the opportunity of determining whether Virginia will continue to hang
                        on to the abolition States of the North, or will unite her fate with her
                        sister States of the Southern Confederation. This brings the question
                        immediately before the people. We ask that they may act for themselves on
                        this important question. They are honest and capable and patriotic, their
                        interests are immediately concerned. Which member or members of the
                        Convention will vote against this resolution, and record himself as fearing
                        to trust the people in the management of their own business?</p>
                    <p>Put this question, gentlemen of the Convention, to the people who made you
                        members of that body and our word for it that Virginia will no longer be the
                        hanger-on of Black Republican States, but will soon become a member of the
                        Southern Confederation, that the star of our destiny will no longer be
                        dimmed by the sombre clouds of fanaticism, but will shed its genial rays
                        over every point of our social surface,</p>
                    <p>"Not as in Northern climes obscurely bright,</p>
                    <p>But one unclouded blaze of [illegible] light."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator supports the proposition that the people of Virginia should
                    be allowed to vote to determine whether Virginia should secede.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmar61.html#3.15f</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Protracted Meeting and Baptism</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Protracted Meeting and Baptism.</p>
                    <p>During the past two weeks religious services have been held twice every day
                        in the Baptist Church in this place, in which the Pastor has been assisted
                        by Rev. T.W. Greer, of Charlotte. Twenty-three persons have been baptized,
                        and several others are awaiting the ordinance.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Twenty-three people have been baptized in the last two weeks at the Baptist
                    Church, which has been holding services twice a day.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmar61.html#3.15g</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>State Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints of the Majority and Minority reports of the Committee on Federal
                    Relations of the State Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bolls</ln>
                        <fn>Harrison T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on March 5.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cline</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on March 11.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1861.03.15.04">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
