<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'-->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1861/va.au.rv.1861.03.29">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Colleen Doody</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/7/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1861-03-29">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>29</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1861.03.29.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Permanent Constitution of the Confederate States</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides a detailed comparison of the Federal Constitution with the
                    Confederate Constitution. The article points out that the latter Constitution
                    gives more power to the states while lessening Congress's ability to pass high
                    tariffs and taxes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Appointments of the Baltimore Conference for 1861</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists the names of all the people appointed by the Baltimore Conference to
                    fill positions throughout Virginia and Washington City. Robert Smith and C.H.
                    Joyce were appointed in Augusta and Joseph R. Wheeler was appointed in Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4-5</column>
                <head>East Baltimore Conference M.E. Church</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprint of the resolutions adopted by the committee on the State of the
                    Church of the East Baltimore Conference. The committee rejected the new chapter
                    on slavery and asked the several annual conferences to request that the General
                    Conference repeal the new chapter on slavery. They instead want each annual
                    conference to make its own regulations.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Col. Baldwin's Speech</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summarizes a lengthy speech given by Col. Baldwin at the State Convention,
                    in which Baldwin claimed that the "agitation of the slavery question at the
                    North was the only grievance of which Virginia had to complain."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1861.03.29.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Speeches on Monday</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Strongly criticizes the speech given by Mr. Harris to the Democrats of the
                    district. The Vindicator believes that Harris sounded like a Republican and
                    foolishly praised Lincoln. In contrast, Mr. Skinner gave a good speech to the
                    large crowd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Judge John W. Brockenbrough</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Judge John W. Brockenbrough.</p>
                    <p>On Saturday evening last, about ten o'clock, it having been ascertained that
                        Judge Jno. W. Brockenbrough was at the Virginia Hotel, Turner's Cornet Band,
                        at the request of a number of our citizens, complimented him with a
                        serenade. In response, Judge B. made a few remarks on the condition of our
                        country. Having but recently returned from Washington, he gave a succinct,
                        yet interesting allusion to the efforts of the Peace Commissioners sent by
                        Virginia (of whom he was one) to devise some means by which the
                        Constitutional rights of the South might be more fully assured, and, as a
                        consequence, the Union preserved. Those efforts having failed of all
                        desirable issue, he saw no other course for Virginia to pursue with honor,
                        than to immediately separate from the Northern States, the <emph
                            rend="italic">animus</emph> of whose every action is intense hostility
                        to the institutions and equality of the South. </p>
                    <p>The short speech of Judge B., although entirely impromptu, was delivered with
                        that ease and grace and beauty of diction peculiar to the distinguished
                        gentleman. But few persons possess in a more eminent degree the power of
                        presenting their thoughts in so perspicuous a manner as Judge B.--His effort
                        on Saturday night was one of his happiest, evidencing that thorough culture
                        of mind and concentration of thought which has made him one of the most
                        profound jurists of the age.</p>
                    <p>The audience, numbering over two hundred of our citizens, received his
                        remarks with manifestations of the highest gratification, evincing their
                        hearty concurrence in the patriotic sentiments uttered, by frequent
                        applause.</p>
                    <p>It was the first time we had ever heard the Judge other than on the Bench. A
                        voice clear and harmonious, enunciation distinct and musical, and gestures
                        appropriate and graceful, he combines the elements of the popular orator
                        possessed by but few. Take the occasion altogether--the delightful music,
                        the orator, and his interesting theme--we have seldom enjoyed a more
                        agreeable and entertaining half hour.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Judge Brockenbrough gave a brief impromptu speech to the citizens of
                    Staunton. He stated that all efforts to assure the South of its constitutional
                    rights have failed. As a result, he claimed that he "saw no other course for
                    Virginia to pursue with honor, than to immediately separate from the Northern
                    States."</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmar61.html#3.29a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Come Home</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls upon Baldwin, Baylor, and Stuart, the Augusta delegates to the State
                    Convention, to come home because the Convention has accomplished nothing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Mark the Prediction</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The property holders of the east and many of the west, will never consent
                    to sustain a national relation that makes their lands and negroes profitless,
                    and bankrupts them as well as the State."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator predicts that a revolution will occur in Virginia if the
                    state does not leave the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Spectator on Judge Brockenbrough</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes the Spectator's "discourteous and uncouth" attack on Judge
                    Brockenbrough.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Taxes! Taxes!!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The State Auditor has advised the Legislature that taxes will have to be
                    increased to sixty cents on one hundred dollars, up from forty cents. The
                    Vindicator argues that, if Virginia stays in the Union, her slaves will be
                    removed South and taxes on land and property will have to be increased to make
                    up the lost revenue.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Col. Baldwin's Speech</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator points out that it has reprinted a summary of Col. Baldwin's
                    three-day-long speech, which it feels was a "rehash of his speeches during the
                    last Presidential canvass."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Rev. Geo. G. Brooke</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Rev. Brooke, formerly the pastor of the M.E. Church in Staunton, has been
                    moved from Harper's Ferry to Frankfort Circuit, Greenbrier county.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"Mr. Bennet, one of the financial . . ."</p>
                    <p>Mr. Bennett, one of the financial officers of the State, has already called
                        for an increase of 20 cents in the one hundred dollars on the present rate
                        of taxation. If the policy of the submissionists is adopted, and Virginia
                        becomes a part of the Northern Confederacy, her negroes will be transported
                        South. This will remove one source of revenue, and then the taxes on lands,
                        &amp;c., will be doubled! Think of it, farmers--"Submission," or what is
                        called "Union," will drive four hundred millions of taxable property out of
                        the State, and force your farms and stock to bear the increase of taxes
                        consequent thereupon. Do not be deceived, people of Virginia! We must go
                        with the South as against the North, and the sooner we take our position the
                        better.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>One of the financial officers of the state has called for a 20 cent per
                    hundred dollar increase in taxes. According to the Vindicator, " If the policy
                    of the submissionists is adopted, and Virginia becomes a part of the Northern
                    Confederacy, her negroes will be transported South. This will remove one source
                    of revenue, and then the taxes on lands, &amp;amp;c., will be doubled!"</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmar61.html#3.29b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We ask you further, do you not feel humiliated in the attitude you occupy
                    of lending yourself to the Whigs to break up the Democratic party? Can three
                    thousand dollars a year satisfy your conscience and sense of honor in this
                    fearful and awful crisis in your country's history?"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes Mr. Harris for selling out to the Whigs and for failing to
                    recognize the seriousness of the present political crisis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"Col. Baldwin . . ."</p>
                    <p>Col. Baldwin has addressed the Convention, and as all his personal friends
                        here anticipated, made a good speech--the best it is thought, on his side of
                        the question. None who know him expected less. Our regret is that he
                        occupies a position so temporising and indecisive--so ill judged and
                        injurious. The great necessity of the crisis--a necessity from which there
                        is no safe or honorable escape--is utterly ignored by him in the idle
                        pursuit of an impracticable idea. The question is <emph rend="italic"
                        >not</emph> "Union." That is irretrievably, hopelessly broken up. No
                        compromise of right--no palliation of wrong, or denunciation of its
                        resistance, can restore its fallen columns. Nor can past glory reconcile to
                        a future of degradation. The only question is, where shall we go? With the
                        North or the South? If with the North, what are we to do with our Negroes?
                        Converted into pests and vampyres as they soon must be in such connexion,
                        they will suck out the very lifeblood of the Commonwealth. And there will be
                        no help for us. The North would gloat over our distresses, while the South,
                        in self-defense, would be compelled to close her doors against us. The
                        "irrepressible conflict" will then be upon us with all its horrors. Such
                        must inevitably be our condition. And who will not say, give us war, give us
                        anything, extermination itself, rather than such a consuming life of
                        degradation and ruin.</p>
                    <p>Let us accept, then, at once, and without delay, the sad alternative thus
                        forced upon us. Our Christian Churches are yielding to the necessity; and if
                        bonds so sacred and endearing are rent by it, how vain is the hope that
                        other ties, less hallowed, can hold us together in peace.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator claims that Col. Baldwin made a fine speech, but his
                    position is untenable. The paper argues that Virginia must decide whether it
                    will go with the North or the South. If it goes with the North, Virginia must
                    decide "what are we to do with our Negroes? Converted into pests and vampyres as
                    they soon must be in such connexion, they will suck out the very lifeblood of
                    the Commonwealth."</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmar61.html#3.29c</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Proceedings of the Baltimore Annual Conference</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Minutes of days nine and ten of the M.E. Conference.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1861.03.29.03">
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Why I Cannot Support the Hon. J.T. Harris</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Union Men</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes Harris for abandoning his party and for refusing to abide his
                    party's decision in the Convention. The authors believe that the Opposition is
                    using Mr. Harris so that they can "carry out their party designs."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript><p>Our Street Commissioners have gone to work, and are inaugurating our 
                    pavements.  We thank them for their kindly consideration of the people.  
                    Let them not "weary in well doing."</p></transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Staunton Street Commissioners have begun work on the pavement.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmar61.html#3.29d</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Land and Negroes for Sale</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript><p>I will sell privately the LAGRANGE FARM containing 418 Acres, lying 3 
                    miles West of Staunton.  The Central Railroad runs through it.  I will 
                    also sell<lb/>
                    Nine Young and Likely Negroes,<lb/>
                    belonging to the heirs of Col. 
                    Jos. Tuley, dec'd.--A Women 33 years of age, who is a good Cook, Ironer 
                    and Washer, with a pleasant disposition; a Man 21 years of age, who is a 
                    No. one hand; the remainder are from 3 to 14 years old, all stout and 
                    well grown.  The Negroes are healthy, robust and likely. TERMS CASH, or 
                    a negotiable note at thirty days, well endorsed, with interest added.  
                    For the land, terms as usual. Any one wishing to buy will apply soon, as 
                    I will leave for Clarke County in a few weeks.</p></transcript>
                <trailer>JOS. T. MITCHELL <date value="1861-03-20">March 
                    20, 1861</date></trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Advertisement for nine slaves and a farm near Staunton.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmar61.html#3.29e</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruhr</ln>
                        <fn>Albert C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cullen</ln>
                        <fn>Catherine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on March 13.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dinkle</ln>
                        <fn>Chas. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crickenbarger</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on March 21.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Henry E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Bell died of diphtheria on March 9 at age 7.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Warden</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. Warden, formerly of Staunton, died in Butte county, California on
                    February 6th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1861.03.29.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
